I'm Tory trades and if you guys have
been following along my journey you know
that I've made the transition from day
trader to swing Trader what a journey
that was guess what we're going back
we're going back to being a day trader
now not fully I'm experimenting I'm eing
my way into it but I want to get back to
the five minute time frame that's where
I've actually spent most of my trading
career if you guys don't know I've been
trading for nine years now I'm going to
say like six or seven of those years was
the F minute time frame I moved from the
5 minute to the 1 hour and the 1 hour to
the 4H hour time frame trading Apex I
need to be day trading we have to close
our trades now you don't have to you can
still be that 4-Hour Trader close your
trade before 4:59 p.m. Eastern and then
reopen but I'm going to say I'm excited
about the 5 minute time frame and this
is something that I want to commit to so
I'm I'm going all in I don't want to you
know have positions open on the 4our
time frame close them then reopen I want
to place my trades in that 5 minute time
frame a lot of my students trade the 5
minute time frame and my community does
so let's just let's get all into it
let's go right on in all back in BO
now why would I even want to consider
going back to the 5 minute time frame
the first thing is oh my gosh when you
can close that trade and be done with it
not have to think about it anymore
that's enticing is it not that sounds
great to free up that mental space that
you have been drained with the 4our time
frame where you go to sleep and guess
what you wake up you're still in a trade
you go to sleep the next day you wake up
you're still in a trade imagine how
exhausting that is 5 minute time frame
you close that trade you are done close
the computer you're done don't even
think about it anymore so that is one
thing that I do miss about the 5-minute
time frame is being able to close that
trade and truly separate it's not in the
back of your mind it's not in the back
of your head thinking am I making money
am I losing money right now for days on
end no you're in that five minute time
frame you trade during your session and
then you're done spitting facts over
here another reason why I'm excited to
go back to the 5- minute time frame is
that instant gratification you get that
profit and loss right then and there
there's a lot more volatility what price
does within the 5 minute time frame
versus the 4-Hour time frame is just so
different they're completely different
Traders they're seeing completely
different things that 4H hour time frame
you're looking at one candle just move
up and down in 4 Hour versus the 5
minute time frame they get to see so
much you get to kind of and actually
look we've got the charts open right
here this 4H hour time frame we're
looking at one candle one candle has
four hours worth of price movement let's
go ahead and move to the five minute
time frame look how different this looks
there's just so much more going on we
can capitalize on all of this in between
so how cool the 4-Hour Trader they never
got to see any of this they had no idea
this was going on they saw one candle
moving up and down a little bit the
5-minute Trader gets to capitalize on
all of these movements okay there's also
drawbacks to the 5 minute time frame and
that is essentially you're making a lot
more decisions in a shorter amount of
time so there's a little bit more
anxiety involved and that could lead to
emotional trading also be aware of the
volatility involved in the 5- minute
time frame things could look like
they're making rapid movements or
aggressive moves in the 5- minute time
frame when really we're just getting
maybe it's a news day you're getting a
sporadic move here whereas okay maybe
we're on the higher time frames
nothing nothing actually crazy is
happening now it also requires a little
bit more skill now it seems like that's
the the place where you start you start
in the 5 minute time frame and I do
recommend people starting in the five
minute time frame because it is a little
bit tricky if you start in that 4H hour
time frame things are comfortable you're
not making very many decisions you're
holding your trades for a few days it
feels very relaxed and low paced but
that five minute time frame requires
your attention at all times so it does
require more skill so that's just
something I I recommend people start in
the five minute time frame get used to
that higher volatility making quick
decisions in a short amount of time and
seeing much more noise which you know in
the higher time frames you're not seeing
all that so it does require more skill
but I I recommend mastering that first
before moving up time frames so now
let's play some trades I haven't placed
a five minute trade dude in like I think
over a year uh maybe it's been like six
months but let's do it here we go right
now I'm looking at the inq I don't want
to play a trade on the inq in the 5
minute that looks ugly uhuh let's go to
crude oil maybe no let's go to Gold okay
we can trade gold it's looking a little
volatile we got some movement here let
me just take a peek at platinum and
silver and copper all right dude we're
doing it I'm in a live account right now
let's see if I can find a setup okay we
we need to do some chart analysis first
let's start on our higher time frames
and then work our way down monthly time
frame I can't see my computer screen I'm
going to have to scoot it just a little
bit free you guys that are watching I am
going to scoot my computer screen so
that it doesn't look abrupt I just need
to be able to see it better okay all
right so we're in the monthly time frame
it's looking good let's delete some of
our lines if you guys know I'm a trend
line Trader I'm making decisions based
on lines on on a chart lines on a screen
this is Arts okay so we're on the
monthly let's go down to the weekly
weekly is looking good let's go down to
the daily daily is looking good let's
come in with some steeper lines here I
love that you guys get to just see this
beautifully simple strategy which is not
easy but very simple simple to apply all
right 4 hour time frame let's come in
some more so in the 4our in the daily in
the weekly copper is up now let's go to
a 1 hour ooh we're getting we're getting
down and dirty here going to the 1
hour okay I would have gotten signals to
go shorten the 1 hour but we're not
doing the 1 hour today we're going to
the 5 minute time frame so we're in the
1 hour let's come down even closer all
right we won't go straight to the 5
minute let's look at the 30 then the 15
then we'll go to the five 30 minute time
frame I need to come in with some
downward trend lines boom boom let's
change the color to Red love it we need
to come in even steeper okay I'm going
to come in with my steepest line here on
the 30 minute time frame I'm going to
adjust this to this last pullback and
let's look in the five see if we can
find an opportunity to go short which I
that's the only move I see here so 5
minute time frame let's take a short
position we're in a live account we're
doing it you guys all around me you
seeing this we're doing it we're maybe
maybe we'll come in light though we'll
come in light in position size we're
going to create a new order let's do one
I haven't traded one contract in so long
we're taking a sell position Market
order we're in we're in a short position
real live money right now let's pull up
the profit and loss wow I haven't done
this in so long this is exciting am I
making money or am I losing money let me
pull up the profit and loss so we can
see dollar amounts here I am losing 85
cents wow this this is a little more
antil climatic than I thought it would
be maybe I need to go in heavier I'd be
losing $85 that'd be a little bit oh
okay we're up 12 bucks 12 buckaroos 12
doll hairs this is fun okay let me at
least walk you through the strategy as
we're waiting for some of these 5 minute
candles to populate which I don't know
if we're going to wait that long but
maybe we will we'll see let's see okay
first of all what am I expecting in this
trade why am I even in a short position
I am in a short position right now
because price has crossed this upward
green line it has shown me that we may
not be trending upward anymore we may be
trending down now how long am I going to
stay in this trade how long am I willing
to to give this trade where am I willing
to take a loss it's going to be on the
other side of this downward line so if
price can show me that it showed me that
it's no longer trending up so I like
that we're taking short positions if it
can show me that it's no longer trending
down either then I'm thinking of closing
this short position so let's see where a
stop loss would go let's come in a
little bit closer the stop loss is
always going to go on the other side of
the opposing trend line that got crossed
so the line that got crossed is the
upward Green Line love that for me we're
in short positions it's going to go on
the other side of the opposing trend
line so we took short positions because
it crossed an upward line we want the
stop loss to go on the other side of the
downward line do you see how smart I
sound like I'm so confident in this
because this is just what I do talking
to you guys all right so short positions
here let's take our stop loss we're
going to have to put our position size
on the screen so that we can see how
much we're making if we need to put in a
stop loss or a take profit here we go
we're going to go to our settings we're
going to go to trading here and turn the
positions on and let's see dollar
amounts money okay there we go I'm down
12 bucks right now it's pulled back now
here we can add a stop loss we're going
to take that stop- loss and drag it to
the other side of the safety line so I'm
willing to lose
$137 in this trade now it also went
ahead and moved my takeprofit as well I
don't trade with a takeprofit you guys
know that I am essentially trying to
stay in the trend for as long as
possible so if this trend does continue
down I don't know how long it's going to
Trend down for I don't know where that
takeprofit should be I'm essentially
going to let the price tell me when to
take my profit now when trading an apex
account we want to take profit as much
as we possibly can and as soon as we
possibly can so I want this stop to
Trail along my profit so as soon as
profit starts turning around I want to
take that so let's see if we can get as
much of this profit as as we can in this
5minute time frame now this trade may
take longer so you guys may not be able
to see this whole trade play out since
we're going to have to sit here for at
least 15 minutes just to see three
candles and I don't know if we want to
do that but this was essentially me
getting into a trade so this is the
first time I've placed a trade in the 5
minute time frame that's exciting it's
fun I'm getting used to it I'll be going
full force in the 5 minute time frame
we're down 50 bucks already here we go
are we coming up are we do I need to go
ahead and take this this loss here but
this is essentially kind of walking you
guys through my strategy in the lower
time frames when you're in lower time
frames like the 5 time frame you're
going to be making a lot more decisions
as well so this trade may not work out
within 5 to 10 minutes I may need to
reverse my position and think long
positions very soon here so there's just
a lot more decisions to be made in those
lower time frames you just get so much
more noise so much more volatility so
I'm trying to find out which one of
these Trends is actually going to follow
along I want to catch something like
this this was a beautiful move down and
right now we very well could be in
consolidation it is 800m at night and
I'm trading copper so we might not get
price to go anywhere but essentially I
am trying to find which Trend it's which
trend is true which trend is actually
going to follow along right now we're
down 37 bucks so this is fun maybe I'll
try the one minute next cuz this just
isn't doing it for me thank you guys for
hanging out I will keep you updated on
this trade don't forget to like
subscribe drop a comment what time frame
do you trade uh do you trade the five
minute do you trade the 4 Hour do you
trade the one minute let me know drop it
in the comments and I'll will see you
guys in the next video