hi everyone my name is christina and
welcome to my forex channel
so in today's video i would like to show
you how you can make money using price
action combined together with moving
average indicators
so without further ado let's just jump
into the video
so before i will jump into explanation
how you can learn how to make money
using this
strategy i would just like to tell you
that this strategy works the best for
usd jpy
or in general any usd currency pairs as
you know the usd has the most in
volatility in any way that's the
strongest currency
worldwide the second thing i would like
to tell you about that this
strategy doesn't work on consolidation
market
that's it it just simply doesn't work
okay so let's begin our session
so for this strategy you also need
to analyze your chosen currency pair as
you can see
i have chosen the euro usd and i have
one
hour time framed open so as you can see
i already have my downtrend line
we have a one two three touch
pattern simply because any time it
touched our trend line
towards the downside and the second
thing you have to do after you identify
your trend line your next tip is to
find some sort of area of a support
or resistance so in my case i have
identified
one as well simply because of multiple
touches in this zone so
as you can see we have four touches in
this
zone okay guys so we have our trend line
we have
our area of sensitivity in this case i
have
my support because based on the previous
price um action moves in the past
the third step is to have a moving
averages because that's what the video
is all about
so all you have to do right now is just
press on indicators
and type in m a which stands for moving
average you have to press it twice
because we will need to two moving
averages so as you can see the moment we
have a
moving averages of period nine what we
have to do
we have to change it to eight
and another one needs to be changed to
fifteen when you have your trend line
you have your areas of sensitivity and
you handed your moving average
indicators
all you have to do right now wait for
the break through our
downtrend line and wait for that bullish
engulfing candle
above our moving averages
so you should also know that moving
averages can potentially act as your
support and resistance it just basically
help you to have a right setup before
you
entering the trade all we waiting right
now
is that for that break so we will have
the confirmation we can
enter a trade and we can make money so
let's just play
right now and see what's gonna happen so
as you can see it's kind of going up
going up coming up and boom we
have our break it broke our
downtrend and it also broke our
area of a resistance yeah you can
enter over here and then you will
be able to make money until this zone
because
you never know maybe the market will
decide to turn around
simply because of one hour downtrend in
our area of
resistance if you will be an aggressive
trader you will probably have to close
your trade over here
as you can see we are being patient and
we are waiting
for a bullish engulfing candle and as
you can see
we have this strong push and we have the
little exhaustion
with the bullish engulfing candle so
what we are doing right now
is we are entering a trade because
we have bullish engulfing candle above
our moving averages
let's just take a look how much money we
could possibly make if we would enter a
trade
over here so you want to have your
stop loss just above moving averages
just in case if the market will decide
to turn around and we want to have
our take profit levels up to
here so our take profit levels be in a
round of
this zone so let's just take a look how
many pips
you could possibly make if you enter a
trade on this bullish engulfing candle
above our moving averages
as you can see just playing along with
the moving averages
and
[Music]
and boom we definitely reached our
profit levels
and as you can see we were definitely
taking home 24.5
pips we are closing the trade when
our moving averages been crossed
so after we took the pips home we have
to close
our trade look for a new setup okay so
as you can see we have a bullish
engulfing
candle over here it's good because it's
not breaking our moving averages
just when we're entering long position
so
once again the stop loss should be in
around
just below moving averages and profit
levels
should be in around this zone so let's
just play a tool and see what's going on
as you can see it's playing very nice
along with our moving averages
we would be nicely taking 30 pips home
okay so as you can see after we
done our one try we will be looking for
another opportunity to
enter it and because it's five minute
time frame it's like a scalping you in
and out of the market you keep
constantly looking for a entry for it
right you know you're closing you're
opening you're taking money
you're looking for another opportunities
and as you can see we had
so many opportunities to enter one
two three
so you had a very good chance if you
kept an eye on if you kept an
eye on of your charts um at that time so
let's take a look how much money we
could possibly make
if we would enter a trade over here as i
said
your stop loss should be just a little
bit below of the moving averages if the
market will decide to
bounce back to a different direction
your
stop loss should be you know above this
level okay
as you can see you could possibly make
eight so as you can see you can
potentially make
another entry and you could take 27 pips
home so as you can see this strategy is
super
simple and easy to use all you have to
do is just to have
a right setup you can either be
aggressive if you like to
it's up to you or you can either wait
for the right moment
and enter so as you can see we would be
closing
our trade over the zone because the
candlesticks broke
our moving averages and in this case we
will be losing money so we don't want
that
we want to be winners we finding the
right entry points and we
exiting at the right time just for our
own benefit so after this you will
probably have to
analyze everything from one hour to 30
minutes 15 minutes and then
enter one five minute time frame to make
a profit but
this strategy is just super simple so as
you can see this
strategy is super simply to use all you
have to wear
so as you can see this strategy is super
simple
and easy to use all you have to do is
just to be patient
have a right set up analyze your
chosen currency pair make it more better
for you to
understand what's actually going on and
the last step you do is just
taking the money home so that's it for
today's video i hope you enjoyed it and
it was valuable to you
if you have any questions leave a
comment down below or contact me through
my social media so if you enjoyed this
video
smash that like button it helps me a lot
subscribe to my youtube channel for the
future videos
and i will talk to you later bye
[Music]