How to choose the right strike price When
we are trading options in Bank Nifty, Nifty, Fin Nifty,
or any
index,
Sensex, or any other, there is always
confusion as to which strike
price should I choose where I get maximum profit. The
problem that arises is that the
Nifty chart is moving but
our premium is not increasing, we are
not making money, and the chart is
moving in our favor,
both in the case of Bank Nifty and Nifty. So
how to do that? First of all, if we
talk about strike price, there are three types
of strike prices. The first is
ITM, the second is ATM, the third is
OTM. Now this may seem confusing, but it is
very easy. Look, ITM means in the
money. In the money means whatever contracts have been done in the past.
Now,
if I break it down in simpler words, then understand
that from where the price has moved forward in the past,
all the contracts of the past
or whatever
prices there are in the past are all in the money.  Let's say at
the money means present, everything is
in the present, so present means whatever is the current
price of Nifty Bank Nifty,
if Bank Nifty is running at
46500 then the
strike price of 46500 will be at the money only,
OTM means out the money, whatever is going to come
in the future has become out
the money, now like in the case of call, if
we assume that the market is going to go up
and the price of Bank Nifty is currently running at
46500 then 466500 becomes at the money, now
what will be the future price from 46500,
where will Bank Nifty go, from
46500 to
46600, it will go to 700, then from 700 to 800,
so these 600, 700 and 800 are all out the
money and the more you move forward, the more you will keep increasing, the more you will
move towards the future, it will become
deeper out the money, now
461500, so at the money, you understand
466001 500 which is at the money, what was there before that, the
price came from 46400 to 46500, then
after that it will go further, so the prices that have happened in the past,
463, all these are in the money contracts, this is
in the case of call, now what is there in the case of put,
when the market falls then you are going to
profit, at the money for both
remains the same, so in the case of put,
46500 will remain at the money, but
what is the future price of put, if the market is
running at 46500 right now, then it will fall from 500 to 400
and then it will fall further below that to 400 to
300, so these future prices
463, these are all out the money contracts and due to
which the market has fallen, it has come to
466001 500 and before that it was
467, so the past at the money
contracts, in the case of put  All of them are in
the money. I hope you have understood it
very well. Let me revise it once again.
At the money, present, in the money,
past, the contracts that have been done in the past
or the market has moved ahead by
increasing the strike price.
And out the money means future. Now after understanding this, let us
see on the screen
when you should use out the money, when you should use at the money
and when you should use in the money.
Now I am explaining it to you on the phone because
most of the people use the phone only, so the
layout of the phone will be easy for them.
This is a sensible app. When you open it in the home, it will
look like this. After that, I
clicked on analyze, clicked on option chain and
after that clicked on Greeks. Now
after clicking on Greeks,
all the values ​​came to me. Right now this Nifty
chart is open. The current price of Nifty is
22434. So you see, here 20
is kept blue at 2450, that means this is
our at the money contract because
Nifty  You will get contracts at a distance of 5050 points on Nifty
and at
100-10000 points on Bank Nifty.
So, this 450 here, you will see
all the things on the call side and there you can
see the put. In case of call,
22450 is at the money,
22400 is in the money,
22350 is in the money because what call means is that
when the market goes up, there will be profit,
so after 450 the future price is going to come,
500 will come after 500, 550 will come after 550, 600 will
come after 550, so after 450, all the
contracts above 500, 550, 600, all these
are out of the money and all the
contracts below 450, 400, 350, 300, all these are in the
money. This is what happens in the case of call. Now,
in case of put, the
price of 22450 which is prevailing from 24450,
whatever is in the future  The upcoming price is
450, if it falls from 450 then it will go to 400 and if it falls from 400 then it will go to
350, so the
contracts above 450 are out of the money and the
contracts before that have fallen from 500 to
450, so 500 has happened in the past, so it has become
500. Now in the case of in the money put,
when we trade intraday, there is
no expiry day and we are trading daily, so
in intraday trade we always have to choose in the money
contract or deep in the
money contract. Now why do we have to choose,
if we look at the call side, for example,
next to 450 you will
see a value of 0.46 here, this is the
value of 0.46, now
in 400 you will see 0.6, in 350
you will see 0.72, now what does this mean
if you take a 450 contract and
Nifty  If the price moves by ₹1, your profit will not be ₹1;
your profit will be only 46 paise.
If you buy a 400 rupee contract,
your profit will be 60 paise in that one rupee.
If you buy a 350 rupee contract,
your
profit in that one rupee will be 72 paise in the same momentum. And if you
buy a 300 rupee contract, your profit in that one rupee will be
81 paise. Now
suppose we buy a 450 rupee contract and
Nifty moves 100 points, then
after moving 100 points, our profit on the 450 rupee will be ₹
446.
Our profit on the 400 rupee will be
₹2. Our profit on the 350 rupee will be ₹
81. Now the point here is
that when we are doing normal intraday trades,
where we know that the market is moving at
some times, we can also take BTST. So,
in such a situation, we should always keep these in mind.
Money or deep end should be available because the delta
is high. Due to this, in which case do
we take out-of-
the-money put? For example, if the price is currently trading at 450, then
we can take 500. In which case, on the day of
expiry, the strike price is
high. I know,
in the market, that strike price can quickly go to
zero, but you can either choose at-the-money
or you can go a little out-of-the-money.
If there is sudden momentum from this, then
you will see a gamma spike very fast. For example,
if we talk about today,
today was the expiry of Bank Nifty,
today is 4th April. If you
look at the chart of Bank Nifty and the option chart, it was
forming parallel candles on the time frame of 477001, that is, in a sideways zone, but the
premium of the put was moving from ₹10
in one stroke to 40, then back to 20, then back to 40, so
why is this happening?
Majorly working.  Because of the axe, in such a situation
you can choose slight out of the money or at the money,
otherwise for normal day trading it is
better that you always choose in the money
contract. What is in the money
contract? It is the place from where the
price has come in the past. In case of call,
if the price is 500 then
in the money 400-300 strike price will be in the money
and in case of put then 600-700 will be in the
money. I hope you must have understood the video of strike price very well. It was a very
detailed explanation, whatever it is,
tell me in the comment section and do share it with everyone
and see you in the next one.
All the best.