Cory Trades is one of the fastest
growing traders on YouTube. This is
thanks to her simple trading strategy
that replaces the complex world of
trading algorithms and indicators with
simple trend lines. Tori claims that
just by drawing a few lines on a chart,
you can find edge and make money
trading. As one of Wall Street's top
traders with over a hundred million in
verified profits, I feel uniquely
qualified to talk about how I use trend
lines and compare that to Tori's
strategy and see if it actually works.
Over the last few years, Tori has
absolutely exploded onto the trading
scene for her trendline trading
strategies, which she has been trading
for over a decade. Particularly because
she tries to make it extremely simple
for others to apply. She admittedly has
way more followers than me and is way
more entertaining than me. But what I
lack in clout, I more than make up for
in humor. Right, traders? Okay, I don't
think there's much debate as to whether
she has the best looking charts on the
game. In fact, I might even need to
steal her style and cop me some sleek
charts with my patented the One Lance B
superhero blue color. Production team,
make it happen. But more important than
the aesthetics, what do I, an elite top
Wall Street trader, think of the
substance of her material?
>> Trend lines are the foundation of
technical analysis. They represent the
direction and speed of a specific
instrument, and they ultimately help
traders identify trends and possible
reversals. So, what types of trend lines
do we have? We have two types of trend
lines. We've got an upward trend line
which connects higher lows indicating
bullish movement. And we've got a
downward trend line which connects lower
highs and signals bearish movement.
Bullish trend lines, bearish trend
lines. Upward trend lines, downward
trend lines.
>> Okay, that basic overview is great. In
fact, it matched a ton of what my own
summary would hit on. I was going to
lose it if I saw a bunch of randomly
placed trend lines that are right
through the middle of all the candles.
So many people use these lines and
levels, but are using them in a way that
they are just total noise. What
separates them from being traditional
support or resistance lines is that
unlike those which have a slope of zero,
these are angled upwards or downwards.
Uptrend lines are drawn along the lows
in a rising chart with a slope greater
than zero. Always use the lows, not the
closes of the bar. And if the line keeps
getting pierced, it's invalid. Downtrend
lines are drawn along the highs of the
bar in a falling chart with the slope
less than zero. Again, use highs, not
closes. And if the line gets breached
multiple times, throw it out. As I
always teach, technicals are fractals.
So these work on any time frame. And
I've used and seen them used on
everything from tick charts on up to
yearly charts. By the way, while trend
lines might so far seem simple to trade,
trading is always hard. Watch this video
on why 95% of traders fail. There are
two traditional ways to play a trend
line, and it mimics the way we play
support and resistance lines. You could
either buy ahead of an uptrend line or
short the break of it much like we do
for a support line. Similarly, you can
short ahead of a downtrend line or buy
the break of it much like we do for a
resistance line. Now, let's also dismiss
one of the biggest traditional technical
analysis myths. A lot of traders
traditionally believe that the more
times a trend line is touched, the
stronger it becomes. That's half right.
The more touches make it more
significant as it becomes more apparent
and more and more traders might use it
as a stop over time. That being said,
the more times that the trend line gets
touched and price can't push away, the
more likely it is to break. So for me,
the more accurate saying would be the
more touches, the more relevant a trend
line is. But if price can't push away
over time, the more likely it is to
break. Let's listen to what else Tori
has to say about them.
>> So now we have our very first upward
trend line. Point A, point B, point C.
Three touch points. But when using the
ray tool, it only gives us two points to
adjust. All right, we have drawn our
very first upward trend line. Now, this
isn't the end. So, we have just simply
drawn one trend line on the monthly time
frame. We need to continue doing our
topd down analysis. So, that means we
need to work our way down to the lower
time frames. So, we're at the monthly.
Let's go down to the weekly. And
essentially, what I'm trying to do is
modify my lines to make sure they're a
little bit more accurate. As you can
see, it's a little bit off now. So, I
need to adjust it to this new low. And
then what I'm doing is I am capturing as
much of the movement of the price as I
possibly can. So I'm going to continue
to connect these trend lines and it will
start to look like a fan of trend lines.
Each new line will use the previous
point B as its new point A.
>> So this part was interesting to me.
Essentially what Tori is doing is
aligning her technical analysis across
multiple time frames. Many technical
traders, including myself, try to make
sure their setups align across multiple
time frames. Meaning for me, my absolute
best setups are a long on the daily
chart and a long on the intraday chart
or a short on the daily chart and a
short on the intraday. What aligning
multiple time frames does is it gets
more and more traders on your side. I
want every player across every time
frame to be thinking the stock is a long
if I'm long or every player thinking the
stock is a short if I'm short. Brian
Shannon has a fantastic book on this
concept, technical analysis using
multiple time frames, which I read in
college. So overall, I love this point
that Tori made onwards.
>> My favorite way to do it is allow the
trend to play out. Allow the trend to
move. If the price of the Dow continues
in our favor, which I'll do a little
path tool just to give you an idea. If
it continues down, pulls up a little
bit, comes up, comes down, continues
along this downward trend line, we're
able to take our stop-loss and trail it
into profit. So, it's no longer at that
negative $51. Now, we trail it and we
move it along that trend line. But as
soon as price breaks the downward trend
line that we're anticipating it to
follow, then we know it's time to take
that profit. So now, let's say that
price does finally break. That means we
would have been able to move our stop
all the way down to 43,358,
knocking us out of our trade with a
profit of $129. So just think of it like
manually moving your stop into profit as
price progresses, as price moves in your
favor along that trend line, and then
you simply just wait for the price to
break out of that trend line and take
your profits. or if the trade doesn't
work out, you'll know pretty quickly,
especially when trading the bounce by
putting that stop on the other side of
your trend line where we originally had
it here at this 43,719.
>> Okay, I actually also love this point as
well. And for the traders that really
want to understand trading, it leads to
an important teaching lesson she didn't
dive into that I'll expand on. One of my
favorite parts about using a trend line
as a trailing stop is exactly what she
mentions. as the position works in your
favor. In a way, you're actually locking
in profits because your stop is trailing
in your favor as the move progresses.
This is different from when you play a
normal support or resistance level. Now,
ready for some very advanced analysis on
a conceptual level. That trailing
dynamic is also why the default
technical analysis method for trading
trend lines is the way it is. I don't
want to be buying just above a downtrend
because then my stop keeps moving lower
and my risk grows as the trade moves
against me. We don't want that, right?
There's another huge benefit to what
Tori discussed there that is also worth
me mentioning. Your profit- taking rules
are very explicit with how Tori
described them. So many beginner traders
need very explicit trading systems where
they know if X happens, do Y. In a
traditional break of support or
resistance, what is the default
take-profit rule? Many people don't have
a clear, simple, easy answer. Beginner
traders in particular are mostly trading
on vibes. Just because the system is
simple doesn't mean it doesn't work. In
fact, for a ton of my trading, I use a
default stop in trending moves of prior
bar lows or prior bar highs. For all
those reasons, I can't emphasize enough
how much you can learn from deeply
thinking about what I'm discussing here.
Whether you trade trend lines or not,
how we think about effective trading
systems is incredibly important. In
general, you want a trailing stop that
locks in profits. You want explicit rule
sets. You want simple rules that reduce
subjectivity so that you have less
processing to do in the heat of the
moment. Many might be wondering what my
criticisms are of Tori's system so far.
Now, keep in mind I am not an expert on
her system and I'm only speaking from
the videos of hers I've watched. But I
think the most critical aspect of simple
effective trading systems that I haven't
seen her quite address is the criteria
regarding the need to be highly specific
with when and to what tickers you should
apply those simple systems. Very simple
systems like how I often use trailing
prior bar lows or prior bar highs work
exceptionally well, but all of the
nuance exists in when you apply it and
under what conditions. Especially with
futures, which I believe she only
trades, I personally find those markets
extremely efficient except for when the
instrument is very inplay. What do I
mean by that? I only want to trade
stocks or instruments that have fresh
breaking news or exceptional technical
setups on the daily. For example, gold
recently had both a news catalyst in the
form of dovish Fed comments while also
having a beautiful breakout of a long
consolidation. As a result, I traded
gold futures, but normally I tend to
avoid them. Markets overall are very
efficient most of the time. If you
overlook the criteria of when to apply a
simple system, you're going to find
yourself with no edge. So, my chief
concern for traders looking to replicate
Tori's system is that they would not be
nuanced enough in their application of
it. If I were mentoring Tori, I have a
sneaking suspicion that she would
greatly improve her own performance by
further refining those application
criteria. Another huge unlock for her
would be if she were to consider
applying her system to other products,
particularly equities or even options.
In fact, there are options on futures,
which while complex and not for
noviceses, can greatly amplify a
trader's expected value when used in the
right situations and by someone who
already has edge like Tori. Without a
doubt, there is a learning curve and
there are risks to growing into those
other areas, but that would be a good
long-term goal over a few years to
consider. The beauty of using futures
like Tori is doing, for the most part,
futures tend to have a ton of liquidity,
low commissions, and you can scale
positions into the millions of dollars
or sometimes more with minimal slippage.
Tori most likely has room to grow to
become a seven-figure trader with some
minor refinements. So, how do I use
trend lines in my trading? Two main
ways. First, more broadly, trend lines
help me define the overall trend, which
shapes the rules I follow. For example,
I won't short a stock in a clean uptrend
unless it capitulates in both price and
volume. That discipline prevents me from
fighting strength. Second, trend lines
give me structure for executing my
trade. I'll buy close to an uptrend
using it as support or short the break
just like I would a support line break.
On the other side, I'll short into a
downtrend using it as resistance or buy
the break once it confirms the trend is
flipped. One of my favorite setups is
buying the break of a downtrend line on
the right side of the V. When momentum
shifts aggressively, take this example
of Nicola from a few years back. It was
selling off after hours on a piece of
news. A huge volume exchange occurred at
the lows. We then break the downtrend
line for our entry and start to sharply
bounce. Let's summarize my take on trend
lines. Trend lines are one way of
visualizing market sentiment and trend.
When applied properly using the right
criteria, they can add huge clarity to
your setups and help you execute your
trading system. For me though, they are
just one tool I use in my playbook. Did
you enjoy this critique style of video?
If so, let me know. Give a subscribe and
I'll see you for the next one.