if you want to be profitable trading
market pullbacks the best way to do is
to catch a pullback so in today's video
we will discuss trading the initial
pullback in a new trend and i will
reveal my strategy for determining the
optimal entry point there are numerous
strategies for trading the market that
make use of the exponential moving
average however trading with a trend is
the most common way in which these emas
are employed by traders and the concept
is very simple as an example consider
two exponential moving averages with
different periods it is assumed that the
market is an uptrend when the lower
period ema crosses above the higher
period ema and vice versa if the lower
period ema crosses below the higher
period dma the market is deemed to be in
a downtrend so a lot of beginner traders
see the crossover as the signal to
either go long or short on the market
they go long when the lower period dma
crosses over the higher one and vice
versa you can see it in the chart that
if you went long or short each time the
ems crossed you would be stopped out of
your trades all the time so instead of
entering a trade when the ems cross use
it as a signal that an uptrend or
downtrend is forming so you might be
wondering right now how can i then use
emas to enter a trade the solution is to
trade pullbacks so what exactly are
pullbacks and why would you want to
trade them as i mentioned previously one
of the most popular trading strategies
when training any market is to trade
pullbacks during an uptrend or downtrend
pullbacks are also commonly known as
retracements and in addition one of the
reasons they are so popular is that when
the markets turn upward they do not
simply rise in a straight line there is
always a period of recovery before the
trend may be continued it's very similar
to taking a long road trip and then
stopping at the rest stops every now and
then before continuing on the journey
but markets are in an uptrend they do
make high highs and low lows which
indicates that the market is gaining
momentum and those high lows are the
pullbacks and when the markets are in a
downtrend they do make lower lows and
lower highs and as you probably know
market always has these pullbacks when
trending and that's a great opportunity
for the traders to get into the trade
before the market resumes its trend
while there are many different forms of
moving averages the ema and simple
moving average are the two most widely
utilized so why do we want to trade
pullbacks with dma rather than sma i
want to highlight that both moving
averages can be used to trade pullbacks
however here is why i love emas so let's
say if you would plot ema and sma on the
chart you will notice that ema tends to
stay closer to the price and as a result
when trading pullbacks or retracements
using exponential moving averages they
will tend to make that market appear as
if they are bouncing of the emas while
the smas can be used to trade pullbacks
they are not that sticky as the
exponential moving average and therefore
exponential moving averages would be the
optimal for our trading strategy before
i go any further i just want to tell you
that this strategy works on most time
frames but for today's session i really
wanted to demonstrate how to generate
some quick profits by utilizing this
strategy only smaller time frames so for
this strategy we are going to use the 20
and 50 exponential moving averages and
as always you can follow me along on how
to add it to your chart all you have to
do is simply press on indicator section
and type ema that will be the moving
average exponential and all you have to
do is basically double click on it
because we will need two of them so once
you add them on the chart they will come
up with default settings but you will
have to change them so you can simply
click on the setting bar go into input
section and choose the length of 20 and
the second one will be in the value of
50. so this time i made an extra effort
to make these lines more visible because
i know that some of my subscribers are
watching me on their phones which makes
it harder to see those thin lines so
this time i made them thicker to be more
visible for you guys now we want to
enter long only when 20ma is higher than
50 ema and we want to enter short
positions only when 20 ema is lower than
a 50 ema so first and foremost we want
to check a higher time frame such as one
hour to indicate the overall trend and i
would like to mention one key factor
that you should bear in mind let's say
you have a long trade open on a 50
minute time frame or even on a 5 minute
time frame but then it suddenly starts
to slightly move in a different
direction so guys please do not start
panicking because we know that your one
hour chart and his trend are much
stronger than the trend on 50 minute
time frame or even on a 5. as a result
the trade is most likely in this push
exhaustion cycle before continuing its
move towards your direction so once you
have your trend in place what you need
to do next is to wait for the emas to
cross over another one and once the 20
ema has crossed above the 50 ema we want
to look for the first bounce of the 50
ema don't worry if the market didn't
bounce off the ema and just went through
it then we want to wait until the bounce
occurs before considering that the first
bounce one eternity later so let's say
you have been waiting and we have a nice
bounce of the 50 ema from there you
would be looking for a second bounce to
get into a long trade it might sound
confusing but trust me once you've put
this into the practice everything will
fall into place so then we would enter
at the closed candlestick so in this
case at the closure of the bullish
engulfing candle we would place our stop
loss below the low of the previous swing
low and of course your risk reward ratio
depends on your account and whether you
are following your money management
sometimes i don't use any stop loss when
it comes to scalping due to the fact
that i'm constantly watching the market
and i can instantly close off my trades
but having a stop loss if you're unable
to watch the market all the time is the
best decision you can make when it comes
to trading so what you're about to hear
next supposed to be a secret but it's
not gonna be secret anymore because i'm
gonna share it but i have found a great
website that i want to share especially
if you're a beginner or you are even
more advanced trader and you just need a
little confirmation before your entry
what you can do on this is actually you
type any currency pair you are planning
to use so for example i have your usd
right now what you can do is to have an
overview of the currency pair
performance whether the market is
overbought or oversold was the actual
trend for that currency pair but it does
say buy or sell over here and what you
can actually do is to choose the time
frame let's say from daily one hourly to
four hourly to 15 minute time frame and
you can see whether the market is
bullish bearish or in neutral this is
such a great website to help you with
that extra confirmation before you
entering your trade of course you cannot
rely only on the website telling you
whether the market is bearish or bullish
or he don't know what to do you must do
your own analysis before you considering
any confirmation from this website here
is my trade and its profits using this
strategy so let me break down for you
how i ended up trading this currency
pair first things first as i mentioned
previously we have to go to a higher
time frame which in this scenario is one
hour chart and on one hour chart we can
see that we do have a nice resistance
going on with the multiple rejections
and we also have a nice bullish trend
which ended up breaking towards a
downside so all we have to do right now
is to go on a smaller time frame such as
15 minutes so back on a 15 minute time
frame as i said what you're looking for
is for a first bounce of the 50 ema
which has occurred over here and then we
had the second bounce over here as well
of the 50 ema and this is where i
entered my trade short so currently my
profits running in a round of 200
dollars so far which i'm quite happy
about it because it's scalping so you
kind of in and out of the market but i
believe that this trade will go even
further down so i will keep that running
so again this bearish engulfing candle
closed next to the 20 ema which also a
good sign then we have another bearish
engulfing candle actually bouncing off a
nice area of the sensitivity so this
candlestick will close as well as a
bearish engulfing i will definitely keep
this train running so here is a little
update 360 dollars into the profit which
i'm super super happy about it i mean 20
and 50 emas in scalping are very good
especially if you know how to use them
correctly there is a little update i am
on 50 minute time frame i have aud usd
and my trade reach take profit 1 which
is around 20 pips in the profit so in
this case of course if you want you can
move your stop loss to an entry or near
it so in this case you will have a
risk-free trade and in this case you
will be able to maximize your pip again
and here is the final update i have 600
into the profit by only scalping with
these simple indicators and the most
simplest pullback strategy that i ever
showed you in my youtube channel and if
you enjoyed this video make sure you
watch this video next because this one
is pretty damn good