the second time i scraped it that one
actually really [\h__\h] hurts
what's pop and snake gang welcome back
to another video if you guys are new
here hit that like button so you don't
mind no matter who the [\h__\h] you are hit
the like button
it's free it helps me out it helps you
out get this video to other people help
other people out make other people's
days hit that subscribe button because
you do not want to miss any videos i
drop because they're very very helpful
they've helped a lot people out over the
years my knee is still burning jesus
i really don't want to say too much i
want to bore you guys if you guys are
not following me on instagram follow me
at mambafx trading my only instagram
people are getting scammed every day
from people pretending to be me i will
never reach out to you on instagram i'll
never reach out to you on telegram just
[\h__\h]
who the
[\h__\h] they're done with the carpet all
right you guys are lucky you're going to
get a sneak peek before we get into the
video let me just show you guys the
theater room
up here
wow
that's crazy
wow it's not even the same room
doesn't look like that oh crazy this is
gonna be so cool back to the featured
program
[Music]
so back to where i was what we're gonna
be going over in this video is six
different rules that's one
six different rules that i have learned
over the years of trading that will
actually help you guys grow smaller
forex accounts bigger medium any sized
accounts really but it's gonna be really
really good tips and tricks for smaller
forex accounts and all the rules that
i've learned over the years of losing
winning the ups the downs all the [\h__\h]
that comes with training for it i don't
want to bore you guys i have nothing
else to say i love you guys i appreciate
you guys more than you'll know i know
i've been inactive i'm back my office is
finally here and we're just we're back
in the building and we're gonna get
things popping right so lesson number
one and this is a huge one that's why i
have it first so pay attention
scalping
is
key
now a lot of people don't like the scout
people like the day trade they like the
swing trade of course you can do these
things and you can be successful you can
be profitable of course it's not like
you're limited to just scalping but let
me tell you guys something scalping is
key for growing small accounts fast if
you want to grow a small account swing
trading is not going to get you there
very fast think about it you're taking
one or two trades a month maybe one
trade a week whatever the case may be
two trades a week at the most that are
going to take weeks to even profit from
so as that small account's growing
you're literally doing nothing you're
waiting and you're waiting and you're
waiting of course you can add positions
and do this and that trust me when i
tell you this is the slowest way to grow
a small forex account now when it comes
to scalping the way i scalp and if you
guys want to know how i trade and all
that good stuff you guys can always
download my free clarity forex app or
you guys can just look at all my youtube
videos it's all free i have so much
content for free that teaches you how i
scalp but anyways scalping
opposed to swing trading is going to
allow you guys to take multiple trades
throughout one day gaining lots of
profits on the account over and over and
over again and i know you're saying oh
you know
[Music]
if you're growing a small forex account
you can't risk more because it's a small
forest account if you have a 100 forex
account you don't get to just let me
just put two standard lots on this swing
trade and i'll hold it for two weeks you
can't do that you can put a 0.10 on it
but you can also put a 0.10 on a scalp
and do five of those in one day so like
i said you can swing trade you can day
trade but if you want to grow a small
account fast scalping is the way to go i
could teach you how to scout go through
my youtube channel get the clarity forks
out for free it's all there for free i
don't want no money from you guys lesson
slash rule number two a broker does
matter i'm gonna say it again it does
matter all brokers are different i've
just messed around with so many brokers
in my trading career but i have
officially found that the best trading
forex broker ever like literally ever
for small accounts big accounts no
matter what account size you have
they have what you need now if you guys
are interested in following this broker
using this broker all that good stuff go
down below click the link in my
description it'll be at the very top and
get started with the best trading broker
i've ever seen when i tell you guys that
these spreads are so raw see there's no
spread like it's pretty much zero it's
as close as you can get to zero spreads
getting to buy on gold you're going to
enter exactly where you enter there's no
[\h__\h] entering here or entering all
that [\h__\h] you see from other brokers
you're not going to get that with this
one so it's uh it's very important
especially for scalping you don't want
spreads trust me you do not want any
spreads when scalping or growing a small
account you can't afford it rule number
three lesson number three is do not over
trade have yourself a limit set that
limit and stick to that limit whether
it's three trades in one day or five
trades in one day whatever your limit is
if you're really successful and you're
winning three out of five trades with
like a one to four ratio well then only
five trades per day my personal rule is
three trades per day the reason for this
is i will have days where i'll take a
loss right be a 10 pip loss and then
boom markets are still going the way i
knew they were going to go but i got
stopped out i need to re-enter this
trade i'm going to re-enter this trade
have major gains on the trade and then
end up you know having a successful
night even though i took one loss i need
to take another one to get that overall
win for the night this is why i'm able
to take three trades per day but if i
take three trades and they all lose i
have to stop i have to end the night
there okay my average wins are 50 pips
my average loss is 10 pips so after 10
or 3 losses i should say that's 30 pips
right there i want to stop i don't want
to continue i don't want to damage
myself anymore damage the account
anymore so i'm going to go ahead and lay
low and wait till the next day to trade
again now this was pretty important guys
you're going to want to stick to one
strategy and one plan do not go around
looking at all these different
strategies all these different moving
averages and all this crazy [\h__\h] is
going to confuse you and it's going to
make your life a lot harder when trading
because you're going to see different
strategies you know going against each
other this one says buy but then this
strategy on the hourly says sell i
wouldn't do it i do not recommend it i
personally trade the higher time frames
for overall confluence which way are we
moving and then i'm gonna go down to my
five-minute charts to see okay let's get
an entry that's all i do i have a very
simple breakout strategy again it's on
youtube free clarity forex app you guys
can go see that it's all for free but
i'm teaching you guys you know pretty
much how i trade do not switch your plan
up switch your strategy up find one good
strategy one plan and when i say plan i
mean three trades per day is my max
right that's my plan my plan is when the
breakout happens i'm gonna get in here
that's my plan i'm gonna stick to that
for the entire year for the rest of my
life that yes you are gonna take losses
but your wins are going to eat those
losses up crazily stop mixing stuff up
because it's going to affect you long
term now rule number five this is a very
important one stick to only three pairs
or less stop looking at every single
pair going down boo boo boo boo boo
yourself literally focus on a few pairs
i focus on three number one during tokyo
session i'm trading cad jpy
london session i'm trading gdp jpy and
during new york session i am trading nas
100 that's all i'm focused on those
pairs during those time zones and that's
it i'm not looking at nas 100 at night
looking at it during new york session
which is 5 am for me i'm not looking at
cad jpy during london session i'm
looking at it during tokyo session at 3
pm for me and it's the same stuff every
single day i focus on the same pairs i
really just pay attention to those pairs
during those moving hours and that's it
that's why i'm so successful because i
focus on those pairs i master those
pairs and i stick to it i stay true to
myself i stick to my plan that's what
you guys need to start doing you guys
will then be able to grow small forex
accounts and it's going to be very easy
you guys are going to see after a while
like wow this is easy i should have been
listening to mama doing this [\h__\h] that
he said because wow i'm actually making
money it's that easy rule number six
very important please take breaks you
need to take breaks from live trading
trading in general thinking about
trading like you have to take breaks
like give yourself time to breathe
you're going at it 24 7 going crazy
sprinting sprinting sprinting sprinting
let's say you know an example like half
but you're just sprinting and sprinting
and sprinting and sprinting are you
actually gonna get better i mean not
really you're gonna kill yourself before
you get better before you get better
you're gonna be dead right you can't get
better if you're dead it's the same
thing in trading you cannot mentally
kill yourself by just going and going
and going and going take a break relax
it's okay to take a few losses if the
losses start to pile up don't keep
fighting the markets and going crazy and
trying to get those wins that's where a
lot of traders go wrong but relax sit
back take a break view the markets on
demo view the markets on trading view
back test relax and when your mind is
ready and you feel calm and collected
you're ready to get back in there then
you can trade again but until then you
need to relax you need to chill and you
need to just take it easy people do not
like that people don't like to take it
easy like to go crazy so just take a
break go easy it's gonna be all right
you gotta just take breaks sometimes now
those are my six main rules slash
lessons that i have learned over the
years while losing and winning these are
the rules that i stick to every single
day which has made me an absolute god at
trading gave me a [\h__\h] ton of money one
of the best in the game and yeah i just
put in the work i put in the hours but i
also stuck to these plans figured these
plans out figured these rules out i
should say i started to implement them
and it worked you guys can do the same
thing take it from me i'm trying to
teach you guys i'm trying to help you
guys out with that being said man i love
you guys i appreciate you guys if you
guys are not subscribed make sure you
guys hit that subscribe button because i
got videos like this coming all the time
i want to show you guys the office and
you guys are dying to see it next video
you'll probably end up seeing that i got
nothing to say i love you guys get the
clarity forks out follow my instagram
and i'll see you guys in the next video