in this video we will take a look at the
one minute scoping trading strategy that
uses free trading view indicators and
claims to achieve 1, 57% profit gain so
of course we will have to put this
strategy to the test by applying it to
200 traes to see whether it's profitable
or not and to prove to ourselves how
this strategy works I will open an
account with an initial deposit of
$11,000 and we will back test it on EUR
US dollar so first things first let me
walk you through the indicators and how
to set them up on your chart so go ahead
open a trading platform and once that
step is done navigate to the indicators
section and the first indicator we will
need to add is called UT bot alerts so
make sure you choose this one over here
now once it's on your chart click on the
settings icon over here and now inside
the input section change the default
value from one to the value of three now
this indicator will be like a base for
the strategy based on the signals we are
going to receive so placing a buy or a
sell order the next indicator required
for this strategy is called the higher
high lower low strategy so simply search
that in the indicators tab again and
once it's on your chart we will have to
do some slight adjustments so go over to
the settings into the style section and
uncheck everything except for the higher
high and lower low and for the final
indicator let's add Ballinger bands so
once it's on your chart make sure that
you go over to the settings because you
will have to change this value so from
20 to 30 and standard deviation will be
changed to the value of three and click
okay so for cell signal the following
conditions must be met first of all the
utot alert must indicate a new cell
signal second at the time we have that
new signal the price action must break
below the most recent low below and the
third step is wait for the Candlestick
to close below the Ballinger band base
line which is this middle yellow line
but it must not exceed the lower band
and once these conditions are met we
will go ahead and place a cell order and
the closure of the current Candlestick
setting the stop loss just above the
recent swing high now here is a key rule
for managing your money in trading when
the trade reaches certain profit levels
like one to one rest through or 2 to1
3:1 you should move your stop loss to
protect your trade so let me explain if
your trade hits one to1 profit level
which means your profit is equal to your
initial risk you should move the stop
loss to where you enter the trade and as
your trade becomes more profitable keep
moving stop loss to secure your profits
so if the price reaches a profit twice
or three times your initial risk adjust
your stop- loss to maintain a balance
and protect your earning so this money
management strategy is extremely
powerful because it helps you secure big
vins and lck in substantial profits
efficiently now for a Buy Signal first
of all the UT bot alerts must show a new
Buy Signal second the price action must
break above the most recent higher high
and the third step is to wait for the
Candlestick closure above the Ballinger
band Bas line yet it must not exceed the
upper band and once these conditions are
met we will be entering a long position
setting the stop loss at the recent
swing low or slightly below it and just
like with a short rad we are going to be
adjusting the stop- loss to previous
Target every time the price action
reaches a new one okay so let's start to
do some back testing and see what we can
come up with so I just finished the back
test and the results were not as good as
I thought they would be the strategy was
tested over 250 trades resulting in a
veng rate of 45
.6% however despite an impressive Edge
score of 96 the number of the losing
streaks exceeded the winning ones and
15% draw down in sculping especially on
a one minute time frame is quite high so
it's already hinting that it might be
wise to review and tweak the strategy
rules so I believe that we could
definitely build a more profitable
strategy to make it work better and see
if we can also increase the overall
performance but in order for for this to
happen we will need to get rid of the
higher high and lower low strategy
indicator because by removing it we can
simplify this one minute scaling trading
strategy and we will only enter if the
UT bot alert will issue a Buy Signal and
the Candlestick will close above the
Ballinger band Baseline so like for
example over here and then we will apply
the reverse rules for a cell but once
again it should not exceed the upper or
the lower balling B line so let's run
some back testing and let's hope for at
least better results so I have just
finished another back testing session
and the results are significantly better
than before I back tested 200 trades and
achieved an impressive V rate of 60%
which is quite good for your high
frequency trading strategy I had 11
consecutive wins with the maximum losing
streak contain at just five trades so we
can also see a notable Improvement in
the draw down which reduced
substantially from a concerning 15% in
the previous test to a more manageable
6.28 this time around Additionally the
reward to risk ratio averaged out at a
favorable 3.58 to1 so it's clear as day
that removing the higher high and lower
low indicator played a very pivotal role
in refining this strategy resulting in
the more streamline signals and an
uplift in the overall performance so
before we wrap things up there's
something special that I want to share
with you all over the past 5 years I
have learned so much from Trading and it
wasn't an easy Journey just like many of
you I started as a beginner made
mistakes and had my fair share of trial
and error but every stumble taught me
something new and now I compiled all
those lessons techniques and strategies
into one and ultimate price action guide
I have putting countless hours and my
heart into this guide to make sure that
every aspect I shared inside this book
is actionable and impactful because I
genely want to see each one of you to
succeed so if you ever felt like you
could use a little guidance or sharpen
your skills I think this guide could
make a huge difference in your trading
journey and I will leave a link in my
description box down below and as always
if you enjoy this video make sure to
like and comment down below which
strategy I should back test next and I
will see you next time bye