I'm ready to spit some facts tonight we
got the microphone moving we're ready to
roll whatever we got to do wherever we
got to go I just got done teaching
tonight the adrenaline is
there here we go here we go folks I had
an energy drink I wanted to talk about
two things I don't think many Traders or
Educators or influencers talk about that
play such a huge role in trading the
first thing is the importance of
developing a relationship with the
instrument that you're trading let that
sink in for a minute developing a
relationship with the instrument that
you're trading what does that mean to
you what does developing a relationship
with a chart mean well first of all
let's think of it like dating like a
literal relationship so if I want to
start trading platinum or I want to
start dating Platinum I need to get to
know Platinum I need to just watch it
for a little while let's just get
ourselves familiar with the movement of
platinum let's watch Platinum for a
little while and that results in just
truly watching the movement of platinum
every day as many days as you possibly
can let's just watch let's start to get
to know it let's see what the movement
looks like does it move x amount of
ticks in a day you know is it massive
moves does it respect trend lines when
is their volume when is there no volume
you truly understand that by watching it
and I don't mean by watching it a few
days you need to get the chart timing
you need to truly sit back and watch
Platinum now that is just us kind of
eyeballing if we even want to get into
into a relationship if do we even want
to start dating Platinum let's just sit
back and watch it first let's look at
the movement let's get an idea for how
much it moves when it doesn't move when
is it kind of consolidating when does it
break out of these moves just watch it
just watch it for a little while like
come on guys now another thing is if
we're thinking of this you know in
relationship wise the end goal is to get
married maybe for some of you guys I
don't know maybe not but let's just say
the end goal is to get married to find
that one partner well we do have to
watch a few instruments how know which
one is the right one we got to at least
watch a few let's make this like
realistic let's make this tangible we're
not looking at 20 instruments how could
you possibly get to know an instrument
by looking at 20 at a time there's no
freaking way could you really go on 20
dates with 20 different people at a time
if you can I don't believe you how can
you truly know with 20 different
instruments that's a massive amount of
instruments to watch consecutively
enough to be able to get to know or to
get a feel for or to know the amount of
ticks or Pips or sents that it moves in
a day or what's normal what's not normal
what does it do when there is a lot of
volume when there's not a lot of volume
at what times does it get volume how can
you do that how can you get comfortable
with something if you're watching so
many so I think if we can maybe make
that watch list a little smaller a
little shorter let's not watch so many
let's say that you guys take my advice
you know what Tor I think I can do five
I think out of five options I can find
my partner I can find the one maybe it's
not a soulmate we can make it work to be
honest if you guys watch any videos from
Jordan Peterson his views on soulmates
versus just the ability to truly make
things work with another human being is
possible it is a matter of just
resolving conflict getting to know the
person understanding their triggers you
can totally have an incredible
relationship with someone that isn't
quote unquote your soulmate but it's
just your partner that you have made it
work with and that you got to know long
enough all right bringing it back to the
stock market to the markets in general
maybe it is gold Platinum crude oil corn
the es which is this guy look what it
did today oh my God so we're watching
five instruments let's get our chart
time in I'm not talking a week I'm not
talking two weeks you need to get some
time in maybe even months I know that's
not fun to hear watch these for a few
months until you figure out you know
what whatever strategy you trade these
are the few now let's start to narrow it
down even more let's say That Corn based
on your strategy it doesn't have enough
volatility there's not enough volume it
doesn't really do much of anything and
then when it does it's just like random
and sporadic it's hard to capitalize on
profits so or it's hard to apply my
strategy to Corn so okay we can kick
corn to the curb now we're moving on now
we've just got gold Platinum oil and the
es now let's take a little bit more time
watching these and then out of those
let's make it even smaller now let's try
to start to narrow down our watch list
and if we can make it to just one I
think that's going to help you be
successful in the long run to be honest
yes you can continue to watch multiple
instruments which I do but right now I
am trading for the most part one
instrument and that's platinum and I've
married Platinum now we're in a
relationship I've committed it's the one
but I still watch oil I still watch the
es the point here is is just you got to
develop a relationship with the
instrument you got to get to know it and
so much so that you can say okay you
know what based on my strategy it works
best with these few instruments so mine
is crude oil Platinum I don't trade the
es much I don't trade the NQ much and I
don't trade gold much there are times
where I will but for the most part it
has been crude oil and platinum it just
it works they resonate with me I've put
in the chart time we have been in a
long-term relationship both of them but
I have just watched them enough that I I
get a feel for it and then this this is
the second point that I want to make is
intuition intuition people don't talk
about intuition it actually plays a role
in your trading it's not something you
can teach so maybe that's why it's not
talked about much it's not something
that you can have replicated you can't
you know have somebody sign up for a
course and teach them intuition so maybe
that's why it's not talked about or it's
not taught it's not you know many people
don't talk about how much of a role it
plays in your trading but it absolutely
does but where it comes into play is the
relationship that you have with the
instrument that you've traded or that
you have been watching for so long so
now I have been watching crude oil and
platinum for years now you guys need to
be watching it for minimum at least
months don't tell me that you have been
watching something for a few weeks or
even back tested for a few weeks and
said okay this is the one no I need you
to watch realtime price movement day
after day after day for months and then
you come back and tell me okay I have
developed a relationship with this
instrument now then I will believe you I
have watched platinum and crude oil for
years and this is where intuition comes
into play which is being pickier about
your trades about your entries when you
become more reserved when you go heavier
in positions or knowing when to pass up
on a move these are the things that come
into play with intuition so Platinum I
have watched for so long it has shown me
how much it respects trend lines oh my
gosh does it respect trend lines I'm not
talking three touch point I'm not
talking four touch points I'm talking
like five touch points on the regular on
trend lines and then when it breaks a
trend it continues it will retrace it
will go in the opposite direction and
then it is easily tracked by yet another
trend line in the opposite direction
when I get a signal in Platinum I feel
very confident about it I am more
inclined to go heavier in positions in
Platinum I am more inclined to take
entries earlier in Platinum than I would
in crude oil crude oil has shown me that
we get a lot of fake outs very often
will it break a trend line retrace and
then go in the other direction so when I
get into trades in crude oil I'm a
little bit more reserved I am a little
bit later to entries I want to be really
convinced if I'm getting into a trade in
crude oil because of intuition because I
have watched it for so long and I know
yes we've got a break of a trend line
but the odds of this being a fake out
are probably pretty high so why don't we
go ahead and put some things in place to
help us get into our position maybe just
some checklist items maybe something to
give us just some added confirmation so
that we can truly be convinced in this
position let's say for example you're
trading a 5- minute time frame on crude
oil and we get a lot of fake outs what
is something that we can put into place
to help us give us some confidence and
Confirmation in the signal that we're
getting we're breaking out of a trend
line on a 5 minute time frame what can
we do first things first we could wait
for the candle to close it could be as
simple as that if the candle closes on
the other side of the trend line okay
I'm feeling good let's take this
position but maybe we're we're still
skeptical and we're coming in light in
our position size or maybe we are even
more hesitant we are even more reserved
we need more confirmation it could be a
retest let's wait for the retest of the
trend line now you may not get very many
signals if you're waiting for the retest
you might not be able to take many
opportunities CU maybe you don't get as
many retests in oil but maybe when oil
does retest a trend line you know that
this probability or the odds of this
being a fake out are a lot less and you
can get into that position these are
some things that come along with
building intuition and knowing an
instrument very well I don't wait for
the r test on Platinum to be honest I
watching Platinum for so long I don't
know how many retests we actually get in
Platinum but in crude oil I know that we
do get a few retests and when we do I
feel a lot better about the position
instead of getting in upon break I trade
the 4 Hour so I get in upon break but
let's say for lower time frames maybe
waiting for the candle to close could be
all the confirmation I need for a break
in Platinum maybe when it comes to crude
oil I'm a little bit more reserved this
goes along with like developing a
relationship with a human being if you
can tell that your partner is a little
bit off today maybe they are a little
quieter than usual you know the signs
before they even say anything before the
words come out of their mouth you can
tell the signs because you know that
person so well you already know you know
what Tori got home from whatever she's
doing today I was going to say from work
but she doesn't work Tori got home from
work today she's a little bit quiet
she's sitting on the couch watching TV
hasn't said a word I'm going to go make
her a coffee it could be any time of the
day it could be 2:00 in the morning I
make her a coffee she's usually pretty
happy I already can tell I can read the
signs I'm getting her a coffee boom
she's happy she didn't have to say
anything I already knew because I've
been a Rel in a relationship with Tori
for so long that I can already read the
signs and the only way that you know
that about someone is being with them
for so long knowing what makes them tick
knowing their triggers that plays such a
huge role in trading I promise you and
that's knowing the movement of platinum
or the movement of crude oil knowing
that this is a very extended move it
doesn't usually move this many ticks in
a day I'm going to go ahead and take my
profit here because that's a massive
move that's extended that's not average
I'm going to go ahead and take that
profit or but maybe that same move
happens in crude oil and you're like no
it's moved four times that amount in a
day on a regular basis I'm going to hold
this one I'm going to let it ride that
comes into play with your trading so
much so and I don't know if many Traders
talk about you know developing
relationship with the instruments that
you're trading and the role that
intuition plays taking profits and
taking entries and knowing when to go
lighter or heavier in a position size
and maybe that's why my strategy is so
freaking weird or people can't really
understand it is because it's not an A
plus b equal C every time and I
understand that maybe that's hard for
some people to grasp like they need the
formula they need the this is my set art
art every time I get into a trade or
this is my set position size every time
I get into a trade or this is my set
this or that or this or that a plus b
equal C every time but I understand that
the markets are incredibly Dynamic like
a human being maybe I'm going too deep
maybe I should back off I don't know
this is how I feel about trading I truly
feel like the instruments that we're
trading here are like people you got to
get to know them they have personalities
you've got to get to know them and
you've got to understand what makes them
tick what makes them move how much much
do they move when do they not move when
do they move when do you go heavier in a
position when do you not when do you
take your profit when do you let it ride
and I think so much of that comes into
play with just developing a relationship
get to know somebody get to know the
instrument you're trading put in the
chart time I'm going to say it's so much
easier said than done because I
guarantee you it's going to take months
and people don't want to commit that
much time months I mean to be honest you
guys I've been trading for 9 years I
still have a long way to go in my
trading I'm only making $100,000 a year
out of trading I need to be making so
much more this year I'm going to try to
double it I'm already up 50 60 70 80
damn that's so [\h__\h] cool but working
on holding those profits longer just
hold a little bit longer increasing that
position size but doing it gradually
enough to know that okay when it does
start going against you you know exactly
you've got fire extinguisher if you guys
have taken any of my pre-recorded
courses or any of my accelerators you
guys know what that analogy means but
you just have things set in place for
when price goes against you you know
what to do we got an alert hold on on
Platinum ooh okay
o i closed this Platinum trade hold on
come with me get over here wow I closed
this
trade right over here I was in a long
position from back here to up here now
we are thinking short positions we may
get a retest of this line here but to be
honest it looks like it's breaking
through we are thinking short positions
in Platinum but I hope that made sense
to you guys understanding that
developing a relationship with the
instrument you're trading plays a huge
role in your trading maybe I'm a weirdo
maybe I have too much of a holistic
approach when it comes to trading and
maybe that's okay but I've I've gotten
this success from Trading by thinking
that way I've been doing this for 9
years that this is the conclusion I've
come to knowing that you do have to
develop a relationship and that
intuition does play a role in trading
let me know if you guys agree or
disagree with anything I'm saying or
everything I'm saying but I hope this
was helpful for you guys if you have not
yet subscribed to my channel do so we
got some serious knowledge being dropped
here maybe it's knowledge or information
that you don't normally hear from
Traders or from influencers or from
Educators but this is my true genuine
honest approach to trading and it's
worked for me and what's cool is I'm an
influencer a Trader that has the
receipts and the statements to back up
my trading and my profitability and my
consistency and it's cool to see okay
you know what she can back up her trades
she can back up her consistency her
profitability and she's got the
knowledge here to back it up as well I
feel more qualified to to share my mind
or to share my ideas or my approach to
trading because I do have these things
to back it up that's all I have for you
guys today don't forget to subscribe to
my channel hit the like button drop a
comment if you agree with everything or
if you disagree with everything or maybe
some things what do you agree with and
what do you disagree with that's all I
have today thank you guys so much for
hanging out and I will see you in the
next video