I found an indicator that seemed almost
too good to be true claiming to predict
exactly where the price will be headed
next so it took me 30 days to test it
out and honestly the results they were
something I never expected before so
after 6 years of warx trading I kind of
found myself in a search of something
new because let's be real it's very easy
to fall in a routine and I was craving a
bit of innovation you know an extra
spice to my day-to-day trading basis so
on a Sunday afternoon and yes that's my
idea of relaxation I was actually
browsing through trading view strategies
and indicator section because well the
markets are closed so it seemed like the
perfect opportunity to explore what I
have been missing in this trading world
now while I was searching through I
stumble upon an indicator and you know
it wasn't just any indicator it claimed
to predict future Market movements with
surprising Precision so to say I was
skeptical would be an understandment but
as always curiosity got better off me so
what's left to do I actually added to
the Chart wondering if it could really
live up to this promise of revealing
future price Direction and I remember I
had to go somewhere so I just left the
charts open and when I came back I was
taken back because the actual Market
Behavior mirrored the indicator's
predictions with remarkable accuracy so
you know that laugh turned into a raised
eyebrow because I couldn't help but be
amazed when I I actually for saw what it
could do so guess what I got to the work
you know tweaking and testing until I
came up with a solid strategy around
this indicator because you know it's not
every day you're going to find something
that challenges your trading assumptions
and actually delivers so here I am I
just couldn't keep it to myself and had
to spill the beans and share with the
good stuff with you all so first things
first if you're not already using
trading mu you will want to get that and
I have put a Link in the description box
down below to make it easier for you so
once you are in just head to the
indicator section and search for Mac
dbased price forecasting by Lux algo and
click on that once you do this the
indicator will be added to a chart and
you will see this shaded area that
starts to form basically showing you the
potential future price movements now to
really get this indicator to work
wonders we have to mix it up with
another tool and I will explain in how
in just a second but now I'm pretty sure
you're wondering so how does this
indicator actually work well you
probably know that when the magd
indicates a potential shift in the
market which means you see a crossovers
just like that then this tool uses its
history and your settings to draw a
projected area of where the price might
head next in the near future and as you
probably know history often repeats
itself especially in the markets and
even if you take a look at this example
exle you can see that it works pretty
well because for example this trade
would be especially right now around 17
Pips in the profit but like I mentioned
before there is a bit more to this
trading strategy and I mean this
indicator looks amazing already but as I
always say any indicator shouldn't be
used alone and I mean just because
something happened in the past doesn't
guarantee it will repeat in the future
so we need to sprinkle a little extra
into our trading strategy to really amp
up the success of this indicator so let
me remove this macd and all you have to
do right now is to go back in the
indicator Tab and type in SMA and we
will be using moving average symol so
make sure you click on this one okay now
once it's on your chart go to the
settings by clicking this gear icon and
change the default value from nine to
the value of 25 and just to make it more
clear I always make it yellow just like
that and let's make it thick and nice
and the reason we will use Simple moving
averages and don't come at me saying you
know oh you have been using it all the
time yes I'm using it all the time
because it freaking works and you know
worldwide Traders and you know big
institutions using it on a daily basis
so there's no need to reinvent the wheel
but let's just use what have been proven
to work for decades okay so let's go
over the strategy rules so the 25 period
SMA that we added to the Chart can
actually help help to confirm the trend
direction that is indicated by the magd
based price forecasting indicator so if
the forecast suggests an uptrend and the
price is above the 25 period SMA this
can actually serve as additional
confirmation of a bullish momentum on
the other hand if the forecast suggest a
downtrend and the price is below the 25
period simple moving average it actually
reinforces a bearish sentiment so with
that said for a long trade you're going
to follow these exact steps I'm about to
show you so first of all you want to
confirm that a price is above the 25
period as ma because it actually
indicates that the short to you know
medium-term trend is upward and it
actually suggests you that the market
structure is favorable for going long
and if you can manage to catch a series
of higher highs and higher lows that's
even better and all you have to do next
is to wait for the magd based price
forecasting indicator to provide a
bullish forecast which actually would be
an area highlighted in this blue color
and ideally you want a Candlestick
closure to fully close above the SMA 25
just like that so if all of these
conditions are met then it means you are
good to go to end the trade so for
example we will go ahead and enter on
this bullish engulfing Candlestick
closure so now you're going to set your
stop- loss just below a recent low or
you can actually place it below the SMA
25 So Below this yow yellow moving
average and of course you're going to
set realistic profit targets so it could
be based on previous resistance levels
you know or you can even use this
forecasting tool so for example in this
case it will be set just around that
which actually gives you a nice risk
toward ratio and yeah you can even use a
fixed risk rad ratio based on your risk
management strategy so that's absolutely
okay and you can use whatever way you
want to go now for a short trade you
basically need to reverse everything I
just explained so first of all you want
to ensure that the price action stays
below the simple moving average just
like in this example because it clearly
indicates a bearish market structure so
if you see a series of lower highs and
lower lows being formed that's even
better because you will maximize your
profits by riding the overall strength
momentum so if all of these conditions
are met you are going to set your stop
loss right above the SMA 25 or you can
even use the previous High or even in
this case if we have take a look we have
this small resistance level over here so
you can set it right just above it if
you want to be extra safe and of course
you're going to take your profit maybe
at a recent low or maybe you have
identified the next support level or you
can even use fixed RIS your ratio that
you are applying on a daily basis so you
know the ways to take your profit and
manage the trade are unlimited so please
use it what works for you the best okay
guys so here is a snippet of the trades
I took took following this exact same
trading strategy and as you can see the
results are pretty amazing so we are
starting strong but then of course I had
one loss and this was ad Swiss and it
was minus $63 but after that as you can
see I had a pretty nice winning streak
again and back on the track so as you
can see guys I'm currently
$2,143 in the total profit which I'm
super happy about considering that all
you need is the right Market structure
patience and the right moment to enter
the trade and of course well planned
risk management in place so I think this
indicator and the strategy itself is
amazing especially when it's combined
with the simple moving average so try it
out yourself and let me know how it
works for you in the comments I hope you
guys learned something new but let's not
forget that even with the best tools at
our fingertips preparation is the key
speaking of which if you're wondering
what steps I take before I consider
entering the trade make sure to check
out this video right over here where
basically each step is so easy to
understand and digest and can be applied
immediately