to show you guys obviously i mean
there's a withdrawal right there but
live account really count pro account
[Music]
all right you ready to go shopping yeah
all right
1800 tip move i'm holding out you know
the biggest secret here that a lot of
people won't tell you is you don't
i was just casually withdrawing two
hundred thousand dollars start my
[\h__\h] weekend in today's video
what i want to do for you guys is break
down the trades i took to get me here
show you guys the live proof withdrawal
[\h__\h] but before that i gotta go let my
girl know we're about to go louie
shopping gucci shopping car shopping
house shopping it's gonna be a good
video you don't want to miss it trust me
i like the video too sucky [\h__\h]
not like [\h__\h]
okay
[Music]
all right you ready to go shopping yeah
all right okay
haircut whatever you girls are doing
little curls i'm not gonna pull one of
those fake forex gurus [\h__\h] scam
videos where they don't show you to
withdraw they don't show you nothing so
i do want to show you guys the exact
withdrawal and all that good stuff and
then we're gonna go ahead and break down
a couple of the trades i took going to
some secrets and things that you guys
can learn for trading forex to get
results like this of course i will never
sit here and tell you guys you're gonna
make 200 000 in one week very very
unlikely especially in the beginning of
course you can do this long term but
compound your money up get yourself a
nice large sized account of course i
have a six-figure and seven-figure
account so i am able to make a lot of
money but there's always funded
alternatives and all that good stuff so
it's not out of the possibility of doing
realm right you guys can do it it is
possible just not gonna happen overnight
so don't take this like i'm doing this
next week you're not gonna do it next
week but you could do it though so don't
don't get your hopes down or anything
and maybe you don't make 200k in a week
but you can make [\h__\h] 10 grand all
right guys so here's pretty much how
last week went we had a 21 thousand
dollar win 8 000 win then we had a
couple losses here pretty much break
evens close to break evens a really big
nasdaq win that i want to go over with
you guys really bad gj nightmare losing
about 11 grand that night nasdaq again
saved the day 53 000 and then four
thousand dollar again a loss on gj
finally a fifty four thousand dollar win
on nasdaq nasdaq made us a lot of money
man it made us a lot of money we're
profiting 197 thousand dollars this week
i withdrew 197 000 as well just because
at the end of the day i like to withdraw
what i make that week especially if my
account size is already large enough and
i can just continue to you know profit
and then withdraw i'll do this every
single week just to show you guys
obviously i mean there's a withdrawal
right there but live account real
account pro account all good man all
good as you guys can see i don't hide
nothing man
legit so again you're gonna get a lot of
people who you know will show you their
they've made this amount of money i mean
they have my money if they cannot show
you a withdrawal or show you to really
count then they didn't make nothing and
if you don't withdraw the money even if
it is a real account again you haven't
made anything you can't make money until
you withdraw money always remember that
so i love you guys i appreciate you guys
once again please smash that like button
it does a lot for me and if you haven't
done so already you're [\h__\h] i'm just
literally joking you don't have to like
it it doesn't mean nothing to me
regardless i want to help you guys out
so let's get into the [\h__\h] break if
you guys want more breakdowns like this
or what you're about to get you know
breakdowns courses free stuff create
free content all that good stuff
download the clarity forex app it's 100
free you got free content like i said
strategies breakdowns i'm always
updating stuff on there so if you are
not on the app which is 100 free you're
missing out so download the app it is in
the description if you guys are
interested in trading with the broker i
trade with the same broker i withdrew
200 000 from trusted um and all that
good stuff fast withdrawals really good
spreads all that good stuff down in the
description you can find a link to that
broker as well go ahead and click that
and get started trading with them one
thing i do want to mention before i
break down these trades is all these
nasdaq trades are took in during new
york session i recommend you only trade
nasdaq during new york session i trade
gj during london session these pairs
move the most actively during these
sessions it's going to help you guys out
a lot stop looking for all these moves
during tokyo session if you're trading
the wrong pair
it's just it's not what you want to do
so you know like i said make sure you
guys trade the right pairs during the
race session okay let's get into this
trade man it's a very simple trade
overall we have bullish market structure
it looks like consolidation but
realistically we are moving up overall
it's taking a while but we are moving up
this is bullish market structure when i
look for breakout pairs there's a couple
of things i look for okay now when we're
looking at a bullish market structure
what i need to see to take a buy is
either a break of a resistance which
would be like right here or the break of
a counter trend what that means is even
though we have a bullish market
structure overall we are temporarily
seeing a bearish trend coming in now as
you can see we have lower lows and lower
highs being created but we still have
not broken overall market structure
because we have not broken through
that support zone so if price would have
pretty much created you know a move like
this
and we would have saw it go under
well then hey now we're in a bearish
market structure we no longer want to
look for buys but we didn't break that
we were still very bullish right we
pretty much created support slash demand
here came back up and well did exactly
what i waited for
a trendline break as you can see we had
that line start you can draw however you
want to draw you want to draw tops and
bottoms you sure can but we had the
break of it this bullish candle here
broke right through this temporary
downtrending cycle not only that we have
that resistance zone which is also being
broken through and especially on this
candle here we really started to break
through the resistance
so i took my buy position
um i can put this in replay mode a
little deeper to show you guys kind of
how it felt what it looked like but we
took our buy position right about here
we had a one to four ratio almost a one
to five ratio on this trade i always
have good risk rewards
um it's very important so that way if i
win this trade i can then go lose four
trades in a row and still be profitable
but we pretty much took this trade off
of this very bullish candle here love to
see candles like that price kind of
scared me here when we started to come
down but we did retrace actually uh you
know re-test these trend lines and this
resistance zone and we boomed out from
there i mean at that point i'm very
confident in this trade we're already up
with one to one um i wouldn't put my
stops to break even not yet just because
it's just one candle i don't recommend
moving stop losses until you know prices
actually really shows you that it's
moving up and it's staying up then you
can start moving your stop-loss but
don't get crazy and move your stop-loss
right away just because you're up a
one-to-one it's only been five minutes
from the five-minute time frame and it's
been one kick there's a good example of
that as you can see price is really
booming at this point at this point
stops can be moved or break even stops
can be moved up to here however you want
to do it everybody trades differently me
personally i really want to hit this
take profit so i do end up holding this
trade up until about there
take profit did not get hit
unfortunately and when this candle came
back down to this area i closed my trade
kind of lost out on maybe 200 pips slash
20 points this is nasdaq but
uh unfortunately you know sometimes
trades get away from you
profit to get away from you but overall
we still made a lot of money on this
trade i think we end up making 50 000 on
this trade alone so really really solid
trade but let's go ahead and move on to
the next trade which is now bearish
market structure so as you guys can see
we are showing bearish market structure
we're coming down prices pretty much
broken through these major support we
have resistance and support here so
prices start to break through that zone
and overall we are turning to the
downside again what i need to see for
this to actually be an active or a good
trade i want to see a quick bullish
relapse in the markets so i could take
that breakout trade same thing you know
we have support we have uh resistances
we have different things that tell us
it's a breakout but that trend line
mixed with the support is really what
tells me hey we really can take this
trade and be confident in it
so again i don't take trades based on
closed candles i take trades based on
moving candles so as this candle started
to become you know really down in here
and get really really bearish i'm taking
the cell position i'm not waiting for
this candle to close because if i would
have done that
whoop would have lost out on 310 pips
otherwise known as 3 31 points which is
just a lot a lot of money to miss out on
nasdaq moves like crazy so you got to
get in and out especially if you're a
scalper i mean
it can get really uh stressful and fast
but
again as we start to break this support
zone slash trend line i'm getting in the
cell position
um and i'm pretty much holding this
trade down to take profit this one ended
up hitting take profit for me this was a
one to four point eight see almost a one
to five again i don't know why i just i
can't get to one to five it's a really
big trade for us and i'm making you know
fifty thousand plus dollars on this
trade back-to-back new york session
really good trades again this trade too
i'm not gonna break down all of them but
this trade i actually ended up trying to
hold right for this one to seven i
really wanted to make a lot of money on
this trade
uh ended up not hitting it and i held
all the way down to here like i
literally
just
very unfortunate but from here i said
you know what price is going to hit take
profit i'm going to hold out because
this is a
182 it's an 1800 pip move i'm holding
out and uh unfortunately price did come
back down
down to here actually and then as it
came back up i closed
the rest is history all right so i want
to break down to you guys the last and
final trade again
you know
the biggest secret here that a lot of
people won't tell you is you don't
always need higher time frames you don't
need to go down from your daily to your
hourly to your 10 minute you know what
i'm saying these trades are based off of
only a five minute chart
during active sessions with active pairs
that's all i took that's all i did
instead of going from the h4 and the
daily to see oh what are we doing are we
you know polish bearish i don't need to
do that i can look for bullish and
bearish market structure based on a five
minute chart
you gotta understand something all of
the big players all the big you know the
people who make the most amount of money
they scalp and they look at smaller time
frames everybody who does the hourly and
the h4 i'm not saying that
they're all terrible at trading or
anything by any means but what i'm
saying is they're doing the same thing
that everyone else is doing and the
banks can see that if you're trading
against the banks you're losing always
remember that the banks are the winner
they win 300 times out of the year 300
days out of the year i should say
you know so trade with the banks do what
the banks are doing trade people stop
losses you know what i'm saying we're
going off of supply and demand we're
going off you know breakouts you know
you have to think about what is a
breakout if you're breaking out of a
support slash resistance zone uh you
know a lot of people are probably buying
on that support zone but you're trading
against that buy and you're breaking
through it just like the banks when
they're targeting people stop losses so
you know that's just something for you
guys to think about
but anyways i want to show you guys this
gj trade
very simple trade man very simple trade
we developed bullish market structure
here uh we ended up having a resistance
zone pop up in this area price closed
very bullish above that resistance zone
right about we'll go and draw arrow for
you guys
right about here we have a
right there we have a beautiful bullish
move i'll put this in replay mode just
to kind of show you guys but on this
move we end up taking our buy position
whereas this move started to be created
because we're already you know in that
resistance zone so as this move pretty
much starts to come up we're taking our
buy position you go down the one-minute
chart here you're going to see it a lot
better the market structure looks a lot
more bullish so just so you guys know i
do trade the five minute and the one
minute chart one minute is more clear
here you'll see exactly what i'm looking
at we took our buy position over on this
candle as this candle starts to move up
i shouldn't say
and we pretty much held out man 10 pip
stop loss 50 pip take profit i hit 50
pips exactly on this trade made like 21
grand
although this is a one minute time frame
trade as you guys can see we pretty much
came back came back when i came back i
mean we did a lot of like
crazy movements here but i held out man
i wanted that 50 pips we came really
close
jesus
um and then take profit was hit so it's
one of those trades where you do
you know you do feel very good at the
end when you don't adjust your stop-loss
which i adjust my stop loss here and
there but a lot of times i won't i do
want those 50 pips because if you can
catch those 50 pip moves again let's say
i'm trading one time per night let's
just use gj as an example here's another
little secret for you guys
trade gj right one time per night every
london session i'm looking for that
breakout okay
if i can catch a 50-pip move on sunday
night right a 50-pip move on sunday
night
i can then lose monday night tuesday
night wednesday night and thursday night
for a total of negative 40 pips because
i have a 10 pip stop loss 50 pip take
profit four times i can lose in a row
for a total of negative 40 pips but
because that first night was a win i'm
still going to leave the week on gj
alone with 10 pips profit
i also want to mention this i don't lose
that much so
two nights let's say 100 pips and unless
the last three nights we lose it's still
70 pips profit which you know if you're
a scalper and you have high lot sizes
which you should
think about it 70 pips can be
potentially a lot of money and just to
break down exactly what that would be
okay i had a pretty a pretty bad week
medium week i'd say medium to bad week
just the last uh week before this week
on gj
and i i ended up catching about you know
50 pips here 50 pips here another 50 pip
win here but then i had you know 10 pip
loss 15 pip loss uh 10 pips and 20 pips
profit so
you know it's not the best week i like
to have at least three to four 50 pip
wins with just small losses after that
overall i only got 105 pips for the week
if you're trading on one standard 105
pips is gonna get you a thousand dollars
five standards are gonna get you five
thousand dollars and ten standard is
gonna get you 10 000 with just 100 pips
if you can just catch 100 pips scalping
gj
you know per week just in one week
you could potentially make a thousand
five thousand or ten thousand dollars or
even more depending on your account size
you don't get funded
and you could easily make ten thousand
dollars in just one week you know
for those of you guys who are interested
in taking my gj trades uh link in the
description on the clarity forex app
actually you can
buy signals there's a signal option and
every single trade that i take on gj is
sent out so as you can see if you were
in the signal room you could have still
made a thousand five thousand or ten
thousand it's an option you know i'm not
saying you gotta join but it's an option
you guys are seeing it with that being
said man i do appreciate you guys i love
you guys uh thank you for showing all
the support that you guys show support
has always been crazy since day one and
i do appreciate it if you guys are new
here and you enjoy what you see the
subscribe button hit the like button it
helps me out a ton really appreciate
when you guys do that
oh
one of the kids doing something crazy
upstairs i said i appreciate you guys
following me on instagram we just hit a
hundred thousand i'm super duper proud
of that we have a hundred thousand on
two platforms now you guys are literally
the best
so i'm gonna keep grinding for you guys
clarity forks app is loaded with free
content or there's a signal option if
you guys are interested it's all there i
love you guys i'll see you guys later
peace
i need a boat