hi everyone and welcome back to my forex
channel so in today's session i will
show you how you can use an
ema strategy in the forex trading and
how you can become very very profitable
so if you like to learn my secret just
keep on watching
so as you know the ema is perhaps one of
the oldest and the most common indicator
used by
thousands of traders when it comes to
forex trading this exponential moving
average indicator helps you to
understand
what goes behind computation but it can
also provide you support and resistance
level to execute your train so how
amazing this tool is pretty cool isn't
it
so without bothering me too much let's
start
this session so the first step is to set
up your chart properly with the correct
moving averages so in today's strategy
we will use
20 and 50 ema it works for
all the currency pairs so far so you can
use which one you
like to all you have to do right now is
to go on indicators in the training view
or any other platform it should be no
problem to add this indicator and just
type in
mma it will be the first one will come
up we just have to double
press it because we will need two of
them and in this session we will
definitely need to amend the settings so
instead of 9 we
will use 20 and other one will be
50. so once we have our indicators ready
to go
let's look more closely to the price
action so in this
strategy at the moment i am looking for
a buy signal
and now what we need is to wait for the
price to trade
above both 20 and 50 ema and then we
have to wait for that crossover which
will add more strength to the bullish
case so just quick tip for you guys the
base
or the general rule for the strategy is
that if with the price
trades above the moving averages it's an
uptrend
vice versa if that's below moving
averages we
are in a downtrend so as you can see i
have marked
area of a support and resistance the
boat had been respected couple of times
this is the resistance and we have a
support
it's been multiple touches over the zone
and even if you will take a look more
closely we had this strong bearish
pressure from the seller's side there
was some sort of consolidation before
the buyer stuck with the full
force you know like bull mood and they
went strong with the full momentum
towards the upside
so when we had this strong fire pressure
towards the upside this is when actual
crossover happened if you will take a
look more closely
so once the buyers stepped into the
market after this consolidation
this is when the ema crossover happened
so by looking at this moving average
crossover we can definitely generate a
buy trade but we have to do
one more thing to avoid the false
breakout we need to have a multiple
evidence and a simple crossover
i do have a replay tool right now just
pretend that we are on live trading and
i will carry
on by explaining this strategy so what
we are waiting for and what evidence we
require
basically we need to wait for two
successful retests to confirm that we
can definitely
enter the long this is where we can
start looking for your buy opportunities
there is test should
be happening above our 20 and 50 moving
averages because we are going to buy
so if you will take a look over here
this is when the retest happened
basically the buyer stepped into the
market and this is when we have the
second
retest so if we see that the price
successfully retested the zone between
20 and 50 ema and we see the most
important
third pre-test which is over here
we go ahead to dubai because we have
enough proof
that the bars are in the market and even
if you are a beginner or advanced trader
you know
that there is a push and exhaustion and
as you can see we had another
bullish engulfing candle on the previous
area of sensitivity
and now it's shooting again towards the
upside so we do have this strong bullish
trend at the moment so as i said
once we have that third re-test on the
zone we can definitely enter it right
now in regards to placing stop-loss on
private level we need to place our stop
loss just below the 50 ema
simply because we never know how this
market will decide to play or even
if he decides to do the false breakout
so
lastly let's just talk about the exit
strategy again
it's based on ema but it's not the same
approach
as an entry technique we will take our
profit in different levels
just to lock in at least take profit one
or take profit two
because bear in mind exponential moving
averages are lagging indicator
it just helps us to still take profits
at that time in the market
when it's about to reverse so as you can
see my wrist stereo void ratio is 2.34
we are entering on the bullish engulfing
candle and let's just take a look
how it went
and as you can see we would definitely
will be taking 569 pips
in total as i said we will be taking the
profit in the different levels
so as long as you can see the moving
averages just helps
us a lot in regards to the training just
to execute our
trade so this strategy is super simple
to understand even for the beginners in
the forex or even for the advanced ones
just to you know have an addition
in their forex trading that was it for
today's session i hope
you enjoyed it and it was valuable to
you if you don't have any questions for
me leave a comment down below
or just contact me through my social
media all the information in the
description box
so thank you once again for joining me
today and i will talk to you later
bye
[Music]
oh