what is fomo fomo is the fear of missing
out and you probably have experienced
that a lot with social media a lot with
Bitcoin and just your everyday trading
when you see a big move this is
something that a lot of Traders struggle
with it's an emotion that maybe you you
can't identify very quickly but the
quicker you can identify the better
because then you can go ahead and put
some coping strategies in place to help
you and prevent you from engaging in
that fomo and this is something I'll
give you guys a story of the fomo that
I'm experiencing even as a Trader who's
been doing this for 9 years the fomo
that I experienced just this past week
was I'm trading on the 4-Hour time frame
I have to wait a lot longer for my
setups I have only placed three to four
trades and we're already in March so if
you could imagine the time in between
these trades waiting for these setups
it's very far and few between cut hi
guys Tori here interrupting Tori in my
own video I wanted to talk to you guys
about Apex if you were a Trader looking
for Capital Apex Trader allows anywhere
between 25 to 300K accounts if you pass
their evaluation you can become a funded
Trader don't forget to inter code Tory
for the best possible promotion I missed
some moves and that as a swing Trader is
a very frustrating thing because you
have to wait so long for these moves and
the fact that I missed them made me
really frustrated and the fact that I
hadn't traded for most of March also
made me very frustrated and the fact
that I saw these big moves happening as
I missed them now we're getting some
fomo we're getting some traction here
and the feelings are not good and the
result of this is taking bad entries
getting in too late making mistakes in
your trading there are a lot of things
that fomo can cause in trading So the
faster we can identify that feeling the
better let's figure out first of all how
we can identify that if we're getting
into a trade and it is not according to
the strategy your entry is too far away
it's already passed your entry let's not
trade let's pass up on that trade if you
are making decisions too quickly and
they're you're leaving room for mistakes
let's not trade let's take a step back
so these are just some things to
identify okay here is the fomo if you
are on social media and you're reading
that Bitcoin is literally at 70,000
again already okay that's what I see
here on my screen all right and you're
wanting to buy in do not take that trade
you cannot act on the fomo so just
identifying it and feeling it let it
happen feel it because it's natural it
is human nature we get these emotions
for a reason feel it sit in it wrestle
with it but do not act on it so this is
the biggest thing Traders can do is do
not act on the fomo sit in it feel it
marinate in it if you will but just do
not act on it so going back to the story
that I was talking about where I was
getting fomo with all of the factors
that came into play the fact that I miss
the move the fact that I'm in a a 4-Hour
time frame and I have to wait so long
for these moves to happen and the fact
that I hadn't traded for most of March a
lot of emotions were coming up and one
of those was fomo and what I wanted to
do and what I was very aware of is I can
feel this sense of urgency to trade I
can feel myself wanting to take a
position even though the move has
already happened so it would be a late
entry but I was very aware of all these
emotions I knew exactly how I was
feeling and I knew it wasn't correct
thinking so if you can identify those
emotions as soon as possible that's only
going to set you up for Success so if
you can identify those emotions that's
going to be step one identify them feel
them sit in them but now let's come up
with some coping strategies okay do we
need to separate ourselves from the
market or from social media what's
creating this fomo or this hype that's
making us want to get in are we watching
candles green candles just continue
continue continue and it's making us
feel strange and we want to get in even
though it's a late entry let's close the
screen so these are just some things to
identify the emotions are first you need
to identify the emotions first the
second thing is putting some coping
strategies into place let's close the
screen let's separate ourselves from the
markets or the charts or social media
whichever is creating that fomo and then
come back with a clearer mind