hi guys I'm Tory trades welcome to my
channel we are going to talk about a
trait that I have realized I've
developed over time that over the past 9
years it's something that every Trader
needs to work on or develop or
understand in their own way and it is
sitting in this feeling and it's you
know sitting in draw down sitting with
fomo sitting with crazy profit and being
able to sit in each of these emotions
and deal with each of these but not
react to them is something that
separates profitable and non-profitable
Traders first of all just fomo in
general sitting in fomo is one of the
hardest things to do not acting on fomo
you can experience it it's not going to
be fun you're going to see the markets
making insane moves and you're going to
want to get in working on sitting in the
emotion but not acting on it is what's
going to separate you from being
profitable and non-profitable so I want
to tell you guys a story that I had this
year specifically and this is really
what helped me realize that I have
really worked on this trait I am able to
sit in fomo watch the charts make insane
moves and do nothing about it
specifically I hit my trading goal of
$200,000 this year and decided when I
hit that goal I'm going to be done
trading for the year I was able to hit
that goal in October and the elections
happened afterwards crypto made it to
all-time highs the markets made insane
movements and I was able to just sit and
watch and still not continue to trade I
stuck to my goal I was able to stay
disciplined and be done trading and I
think the hardest part is when when
you're a Trader and you see moves like
this you want to get in on them it's the
fear of missing out that's what fomo is
if you can truly believe that there's
going to be moves for you in the future
and you don't need to get on this
specific one that right there in itself
is going to separate you that's going to
get you to the next level so fomo
doesn't just happen on the charts it
also happens on social media so yes
crypto is making crazy moves and you're
watching it just completely Skyrocket
but there's also going to be times where
you're on social media you could see
somebody else making more money than you
making a crazy amount of money in One
Singular trade and that could tempt you
to making a stupid decision in the
markets that could tempt you to going
too heavy in a position not being as
particular about your entry or your exit
and if you can put some things in place
to keep you from doing that that's going
to help your trading in the future so
being able to sit in your emotions is
crucial as a Trader not only sitting
with fomo but also sitting in big
profits that was something that I
struggled with this year being able to
see yourself up a record amount and sit
in it and let the trade play out is an
incredibly difficult thing to do so
working on that more and more as you
level up as a Trader is going to help
you the next thing is sitting in profits
especially sitting in personal bests or
record trades and something that I
struggled with this year was closing out
of my trades early because I couldn't
sit in it I was so tempted to see that
dollar amount and just close the trade
out and the only thing that helped me
was holding a little bit longer each
time holding a little bit longer each
time and sitting in that profit and I
think if you guys can do the same if
you're up a record amount sit in it a
little bit longer let the trade play out
and you'll just simply be able to make
more profits by holding a little bit
longer and just continuing to to
practice and that's what I've done this
year as well so I took the time this
year to figure out what did I do this
year that was different how did I reach
this goal why was it easy for me and
when I reflected back I realized that it
was this one thing sitting in these
emotions sitting through fomo sitting in
profit sitting in draw down and I
realized this is truly what made me hit
my goal this year so all in all I
encourage you guys to go Inward and
really just self-reflect try to take
your time sit in the emotions don't fall
victim to social media or the traps of
fomo and take time to develop your
strategy work on these entries wait for
the entries let the trade play out
develop systems coping strategies to
help you from falling victim to social
media fomo and all in all it's going to
help you with patience in the long run
this is a long run game this is a long
game it's not instant gratification I
hope this video was helpful guys don't
forget to like And subscribe drop a
comment and turn that Bell on for
notifications so that you guys know
every time I post a new video see you
guys Happy Trading