This guy just made $10,000 in 10
minutes.
>> What they are doing is that these buyers
are trying to protect it. Done. We took
another 2,000 out of the market. We took
another 3,600.
Bam. $24,300
for the session. We are done in 20
minutes. [music] I trade million
accounts. It's my personal account. You
cannot do $25,000 session getting a
small risk on a 100,000 account. It's
impossible. What you see here is not
only because of the volume and the
platform because we need to be honest in
this. It's
>> the world's best scalper, one and only
Fabio Valentino.
>> If the markets today wants to give me
30,000, I take 30,000. If the market is
continuing to action, I can continue to
trade and build. But holding one trade
for all the movement is something that I
was doing before and I was less
consistent. For the first time in the
industry, I sit down and do a live
podcast [music] whilst the trader trades
live the New York session.
>> On Monday, we did $10,000. Yesterday, we
closed New York at 28,000 and today we
are sitting at 11,000. So, we will try
to close a six figures week.
>> I asked key questions about his process,
how he handles draw down, key trading
decisions in real time.
>> You cannot have 1 to 20 risk to reward
with 75%.
>> [music]
>> If you have call me because you are some
billionaire.
>> In this 2hour session you will see a
deep dive into an elite trading mind.
>> The number one podcast in the trading
space, the fastest growing, and that's
thanks [music] to every single one of
you.
Welcome everyone back to the Words of
Wisdom podcast. The number one trading
podcast in the world and the fastest
growing thanks to all of you and our
incredible guests. Talking which today
we're in Dubai and we're doing something
a bit different today. Today we're going
to have live trading which you know
already who that must be. This trader
was on Chart Fanatics and had an episode
that did over a million views in just
three weeks because he traded live the
New York session. Not only that, he has
another video uh that's already done 1.7
million doing the exact same thing,
trading live in front of you. And right
now, before coming to today's episode
and recording, he's already traded
London Session where he's made over
$10,000
just in London session alone. New York
session has just begun. It's the one and
only Fabio Valentini.
>> Thank you for hosting and this lovely
presentation. [laughter]
>> Thank you.
>> Today we are going to do a breakdown of
the New York session. Now considering
all the love that the community of chart
fanatics showed to me. I'm going to
share uh the London session that I did
yesterday and today. It was amazing
session. Uh really high rate, amazing
setup. And now we are ready to start.
Today it's day 15 of October. I traded
the London also. Today we are sitting at
10,000 and uh almost $11,000 profit. Uh
I have to share with you my rules uh to
trade the session. The draw down the
maximum draw down that I accept for the
day is 10,000. So considering we are
already in profit, the maximum that we
can do is lose this 10,000, go back to
break even and lose another 10,000
because I'm not willing to go above this
uh the previous week. Let me clarify for
you uh the the previous days of the
week. So Monday we did uh 28,000 no
$10,000. Yesterday we closed New York at
28,000 and today we are sitting at 10
11,000. So we will try to close a six
figures week.
>> Incredible. And uh the New York session
is getting ready. I can see already a
little bit of of absorption on the
bottom. We are recording the screen so
you don't have a shaky camera like I did
with Andrea in the first video. But they
loved it. They loved it.
>> So I'm going to to give a breakdown and
I will get closer to it so we can also
see how the session is unfolding. So
usually I wait for for European time the
first 30 minutes of New York opening to
to have a little bit of stability in the
session. But I can already see that the
sellers are getting absorbed brutally.
So I can expect this eye to be taken and
then to have a good session going up. I
will scale in with small contracts and
as we build profit even if we are
already 11,000 in profit we are going to
so the first the first high is purge for
the day what I expect is to have a long
session and I will explain you why we
are using
the profile distribution of the first
the first hours of the session as you
can see it's we did an amazing reaction
on the value area loop we were doing an
introduction Otherwise, this would have
been a long
>> Yeah.
>> And uh it's an amazing long. Now, we
expect a little bit of retracement and
we can trigger our first long position
here.
>> What you are seeing here, I change a
little bit the template and I will
explain you why. People that see me are
used to see big trades. Okay? It's the
same template just I make it hollow. So,
it's empty inside so they can see better
>> the the candles. This is the only change
that uh
>> What time frame are we on? cuz these
candles are closing rapidly.
>> I I made the 40 range now. So it's a
range chart because when you are in New
York opening if you do one minute candle
you can have huge candle and all the
data inside gets aggregated.
>> So I will show you how much is different
one minute or five minutes. Let's do
five minute. I show you the one that we
were using the other time.
>> You see how much is difficult to read.
It's all clutter. But if you use either
one minute or either I like to use range
during openings during opening you can
see really clearly what's happening
intraday gap it's I'm afraid of tweet
Trump again because Friday was
>> was pretty difficult and uh so we had an
intra in intra gap it's really rare to
see something like this and we are
trying to build our first position of
the day
>> the first position that I'm considering
as I was saying to you is going along
from the bottom of the range from here.
>> Mhm.
>> Going to target the value area high. So
we have a lot a lot of room of movement.
Now this gap is not really convenient
for us to trade because we are trading
against this huge pressure. I want to
see some absorption here. How can we see
absorption? As I explained to you big
trades
>> it means they are hitting a wall. That
is this area that I created
>> and then going to capitalize with an
asymmetrical risk-to-reward to go long.
This this is the the setup that I
explained in chart fanatic that is going
from the value area low in a momentum
day to the value area high and the setup
is trying to unfold. They are trying to
push down as as of now they are having
result. So I don't want to go against
the flow if they are managing to breach
this level. I don't want to be inside
but I can already start to build my
position H. What you see it's
interactive broker because it's directly
connected. I can start to build by stop.
What does it mean that if the market
gets heavily absorbed here I want to be
cover below this low. Okay. So I'm going
to build my position here. We are not
going super aggressive on the size and
we check if these sellers arriving at
follow through. As of now, the sellers
are really strong.
>> Mhm.
>> They breached the level. Okay. So, what
I'm doing now is cancelling the buy stop
and going to consider another area. So,
this one is not valid. We took a stop
loss. No. Why? Because we analyze
exactly the interaction between the
market participants. Now, this is the
distribution. Let's make it including
more data. As you can see here, there is
a red level. Okay, this one is the P. So
where the most volume got exchanged in
the value area low. So basically is
giving me the point of maximum interest
for the accumulation that created this
up movement. So this is the second area
that I can consider. If this area gets
broken, I don't want to be long for the
day. So it will be really with a big
probability a consolidation day. Let's
check what they are doing. We can check
also with the delta
what they can expect and we can start to
build our long position. One, two, three
contract going for four. We are going to
cover ourself below here. It's only
$2,000 risk. We can take other position
here. and we are going to try all the
recovery of this movement for a profit
of $7,000.
Now, I didn't load it full size because
I want to scale as we go up. I want to
be right with the market. So, I'm not to
load everything while the market is
collapsing, of course.
>> But what I can see clearly here is that
they are starting to get heavily
absorbed. So I have an area and if we
want to be more conservative we can
already cover our stop losses here. We
have half the risk on the position and
going to load also position
on the way high high. So this one is too
high. We can load other two one and two
and try to capitalize on the long
selling sellers super aggressive but
unfortunately not fortunately for us
they are being absor absorbed we are
risking 2,000 okay we are risking 2,000
to make a potential
$10,000 okay so soon guys we will go
risk- free on this position
This is the AAA setup.
>> Yeah.
>> Why AAA setup? Value area low. So we are
really low on the curve. The
market participants are setting up
because it's 30 minutes in the session.
So it's not uh sellers trying to aggress
buyers trying to protect already they
understood what they want to do and we
are building already the position for
the day. Now it's I don't want to take
risk because we are already in profit
11,000 for the day. In 1 minute the
position is risk-free. So we are risking
zero to make 10,000.
>> This is simply a trade that is done low
on the curve on absorption.
>> Mhm.
>> If this level gets broken, we can
consider another long position for for
the day. Let me clear everything that we
have here because it's really confusion
confusionary with big trades. The point
of risk that we have is the potential
close of the gap.
>> Yes.
>> Because the sellers can try to protect
again the gap.
>> Yeah. So, we can consider we are already
floating $5,000. We can consider to take
some profit
for the day. Let's see if we have a
reaction. If we see buyers getting crazy
aggressive on the upside, it's not worth
it to take a position. But we will trail
our stop loss. As soon as we see buyers
getting in the position,
let's check.
>> And just to clarify for everyone at
home, this is live capture. know that
this is personal account. This is not
>> live capital. So he risked actually
$2,000 of his own personal capital.
Currently floating $5,000 of his own
personal capital in the space of a few
minutes. Um which is incredible to see.
And you could see, you know, one thing
we didn't, you know, maybe do in the
intro is if needed, Fabio won't speak
and will focus, but he's done a really
amazing job of really just running
through exactly what's happening minute
after minute, handle by handle, movement
after movement, which I didn't expect
personally. I thought I would, you know,
we would give pauses for Fabio to focus.
So that's incredible uh you know level
of skill set to be able to consistently
you know break down exactly what's going
on as it's happening while managing
entering and executing. I took 5,000
out. Uh not still but stopping profit.
Okay. Because I don't want that we are
going to hold the gap and to give back
the market. We are floating 7,000 just
is not wise to like we had anyway we
position ourself here guys. Yeah. Zero
draw down like
>> but I've heard you talk about it before
right. It's not worth you risking 5,000
to make 5,000
>> right.
>> Totally not worth like consider that
even now we risk 2,000 to make eight. So
we are already riskto-reward four.
>> Mhm. If we get this takeprofit, it's a
five R for the day. Considering that
also in the New York in the London
session I took five R is 10 R for the
day. It's an amazing session. And let me
be honest with you, it's not that we
shoot 10 session with and we are
choosing the best one. We are doing this
live. Okay.
>> I I wish I was allowed to spend much
time with you.
>> So we we are just uh evaluating now the
the auction of the buyers. It's crazy
aggressive and even without big trades,
I can see how much they are protecting.
I want to be covered here. We are going
to take out 6,000 if it goes bad.
>> But as you can see, this is the first
level where the buyers are struggling.
>> Yeah.
>> And when we are having a reaction sell,
so I will be really tight with my stop
loss because every tick down that it
takes is like five 5 $500 that I give
back to the market. We can expect a
squeeze if we get this high and we will
go directly to take profit. So as soon
as they touch this level all these
sellers are trying to push down being
absorbed. So if we manage to reach 24987
I can consider already a take profit
because I can expect an expansion up.
Let's see how they do. Let's take a
break for a minute there guys cuz I want
to tell you about our incredible sponsor
Alpha Prime. The first of its kind in
the industry. Now, evaluation firms have
been in the industry for the last few
years and done absolutely phenomenal in
terms of its impact for traders. As you
can see here through Alpha Capital and
Futures, so many payouts to so many
traders across the world. But now, for
the first time, there is an incredible
route for traders to become
professionals and to trade live capital
[music] and that's through Alpha Prime.
So, let me quickly tell you how it
works. You can just buy a challenge on
Alpha Capital, Alpha Futures, doesn't
matter which one. So on Alpha Capital
you have phase one, phase 2, phase three
challenges. On Alpha Futures you have
standard and advanced plans. Whichever
one purchase a challenge, show
consistency, build your track record and
then you can be invited to Alpha Prime.
Alpha Prime you will get access to live
capital. You will get access to risk
management and resources at a
professional level. You will have a
salary as a trader and access to trade
on live trading floors starting here in
London. [music]
This is the first of its kind where a
evaluation firm is finding talented
traders and then backing [music] them
with live capital and creating a route
to professional trading. I am very proud
to be [music] sponsored by Alpha Prime.
The links for both will be in the
description below. Alpha Capital and
Alpha Futures. Use the code RZ for 20%
off all challenges. Link is in the
description below. Now, let's get back
to the episode. As I told you, I traced
the horizontal level as the first level
of dominion of the sellers. And this is
exactly what's happening. How I did it
because I saw that this is the first
time in all this movement where sellers
are actually having a result.
>> Mhm.
>> So, it's not about volume, it's not
about price, it's about who is winning
the battle. Okay.
>> I will take 6,700.
As I told you, you will see an
acceleration as soon as you reach this
level. And you can see what aggressive
buyers on the top. If the buyers are
aggressive on the top, it means that
they are willing to pay a higher price
to get an asset. So I can expect a
continuation and squeeze. We can see a
little bit of absorption here because
it's a round number. We are almost at
25,000 that it's a psychological level.
Yeah. I'm not willing to give this money
back to the market. So I'm going to
cover below the gap $8,000 in profit.
and we see if they can already we are
close to value area high. So here
>> done. Okay
[laughter] 10 minutes in the session
10,000 $11,000 of profit. I want to show
you a little bit the trading stats of
the week so you can understand how I I
manage the risk in this account.
>> So just to clarify, it's almost over
$1,000 a minute that just took place
there.
>> Yes. So this is my model NASDAQ model
account I'm going to get from Monday. So
we have all the week it's 13 till today
we are going to generate. So we are in
profit for the week 65 66,000 almost
this is the track record of the week and
I want to clarify something like the
maximum draw down that we add is on
profit. Okay, as you can see, we are
going to capitalize on the the position
and risking back our profit. Like if we
want today, we can shoot for a $50,000
session. Just we need to understand if
it's worth and I want to show this. This
is every single execution
>> on losing trades and on profitable
trades. What you can see is that all the
losing trades are contained in 2500.
All the best trades are like 6,000,
10,000. One trade was 12,000. This is
the only way to be profitable. Like
making sure that when you are wrong, you
are wrong fast.
>> Yeah.
>> So just to do a recap, we took the
bottom of the day, we expand higher
without a single draw down. Probably the
session is going to continue higher. For
me at the moment there is no trades. Uh
this was the triple A setup. Let's see
if we can have a breakdown and test
trade. Yeah.
>> So it if they break the value area high.
>> So as you can see in volume analysis
this one is constantly developing with
new information.
>> Now we have the up part that is so small
because the buy pressure is crazy. What
they are trying to do is they are trying
to recover the squeeze that Trump did
with the tweet. Okay.
>> So in this session what I'm going to use
is a momentum model. So if we can break
this high, we will see exactly the same
that we saw in all our session. So I
want to take a small risk here
with a buy stop. Why? Because my stop
loss will be really tight rates.
I can do four contract here and I have
an amazing level to to cover myself
behind that is this level of aggressive
sellers. So they are bu protecting the
level like crazy.
I can have a really small stop loss
here
[snorts] and I can capitalize on the
squeeze. Now the only risk of the
squeeze is the feeling level. I can be
filled at a level that is not so amazing
as someone can expect because the market
just does
>> what we did in all our funny. Okay. And
I need already to prepare my stop loss
because it will be so fast that it can
give me an absorption. Okay, we are
covered. We are only risking 1,500. We
are betting here on the squeeze, guys.
We are betting on the squeeze. We are
low sides. We are trying to make 3,000,
risking, 1560. And as soon as we go high
trail stop- loss and get back inside.
Why? Because this level is creating a
liquidation. There is a big probability
that this level will create a
liquidation. Now we are getting to the
protection level. Why the protection
level? You see the area. Yeah.
>> Buyers stepping in.
>> Sellers are getting aniliated on this
level. Absorbed. These are aggressive
buyers. What does it mean that if we
reach these aggressive buyers, these
sellers will need to close. If sellers
needs to close, we have a an expansion
higher. Okay. So this is the momentum
setup. Yeah. I'm betting on a long
session and I'm fast in covering myself
if I'm right in the position. Okay.
>> So now guys, if we manage to get high, I
need to be really fast at covering and
adding contract because I want to be in
the wave. Yeah.
>> Okay. Fast. Okay. We cover. Our stop
loss is only 1,200.
We are going to put it to zero really
fast. Okay,
huge auction higher.
Where can we cover ourself? Below the
aggressive sellers. Okay, now we want to
see a big wave wave up. If the movement
is starting, okay, I cover myself here.
I'm risking $20 to make 3,000. If the
the auction fail, yeah, I don't want to
be in because it means that the buyers
are not strong. What what happened here?
Sellers to back control. I can try
another time
here with a small stop loss
also here.
See if we get filled.
>> Now what I was trying to explain before
is how much chart can become cluttered
when it's new your session. Okay. See
how much is dirty. Yes.
>> In minutes is really difficult. I prefer
to watch one minute but it's really
again we are risking 2,000 we are not
risking back the profit not even the
profit of New York we are risking we are
really low on the risk side we want to
make 6,000 on this one
sellers trying to get aggressive getting
absorbed so what I can do
load other contracts on the potential
squeeze up
>> putting all my risk here. Still risking
2,000 but now the potential is to make 7
8 10,000.
>> Yes,
>> this is dynamic risk management.
>> But you can see the aggressiveness of
the management as well.
>> It's uh like this part there is no
indicator that can help you. This is
just daily practice on managing position
session by session. And it's really
difficult guys to explain this while I
do because the mental process is lower
than the execution. So I'm trying to do
the best. So in this case
>> we give back to the market a total of
2,500 on our profit because the auction
is low. You can see the auction is
really slow in this side. We can try
only the limit because you see that they
are pushing with aggression on the top.
This is the last trade for the day
because if the auction is failing, they
are getting back in the range. Yeah,
>> I don't want to be inside. Okay. So what
I will do here
is wait for these big buyers to get
supported.
Auction going back up covering myself
below the low one stop loss.
First position is filled.
We can also try to get some limit here.
four
and the last one.
So, we trail the risk here
and we are trying to shoot for
5,000 $7,000 also $8,000.
But we want to be fast in how much risk
we input in the market. I want to be
fast at putting risk to zero because
this is the most important part.
auction is really slow guys. This is
really slow session for the day and this
is probably because the liquidity got
dry after all these move up that we
monetize. So they are accumulating as
they go up.
Let's see if we can
>> if if we weren't in the studio right now
would you have walked away after the
10,000 or you would still be looking?
>> No, I would walk away because already
20,000 for the session I took a triple
A.
>> Mhm. just I want to make them
participate in all the auction but this
is not healthy for my accounts. It's
just I want to explain them as much as I
can showing all the setup but this is
not how I trade when I'm like I if I get
the 20,000 profit for the day my rules
say it's done because probably you will
have consolidation after a strong move.
We took the best move of the London and
of the New York we walk away.
>> Mhm.
This is how it's managed usually, but
you know, we are on the channel, people
want to see, so let let's do it.
>> I appreciate that. I appreciate that.
That's why I wanted to ask though to
just see what the uh what the reality
would have been.
>> Yeah.
>> But it's good to hear.
>> So this position is not what I like. I'm
going to take profit on this one. Why?
Because the auction failed.
>> I was going to say, yeah, what were your
thoughts about this?
>> So we are back. We are back in profit
at 9,000 for the session. I will try to
build on the way up here one
and two here. Cover myself here for only
1,600 risk.
I remove this one because it's the old
take profit. If this sellers get
absorbed is another momentum AAA setup.
So we can play again. Okay. Okay. We can
play
putting all our risk here.
Okay,
let's shoot for $5,000 risking $800.
It's an amazing trade this one.
We are covered below aggressive sellers
failure.
>> Yeah.
>> So, we are capitalizing on other trades
failure. This is the model.
I'm going to take profit as soon as the
market goes up because I want to close
at 2,000. So, I'm going to bring No,
this one is too low.
That's trade. Now, the auction is going
>> now. They are starting to auction
higher.
>> Yeah,
>> all these big trades are protecting us.
>> I expect another expansion up.
And what was your settings in terms of
the to show as as a bubble on the on the
chart? What was the minimum contract?
>> Always the same. It's 30 contracts.
>> If you are in London, I use 20. But I
record that for the community everything
like they have a full master class of
one day with me for free.
>> So now we are floating again 3,000. I
will take a little bit of profit if we
break the high
because now I start to see that sellers
try to protect the top. You see they are
developing a sell candle in do in the
cons the the situation of dominion of
buyers.
>> So probably we will go back here and if
we go back here I give back 3,000 to the
market is not really convenient for me.
But if we break this eye another squeeze
will happen.
So what they are doing is that these
buyers are trying to protect it. They're
done. We took another 2,000 out of the
market.
Oh, amazing. We took another 3,600.
Bum.
24,300
for the session. We are done in 20
minutes. But guys, now you know I like
always to be humble. But we took the
bottom.
>> Mhm.
>> Till the value area high when the buyers
took control. We took some stop loss and
they wanted to show how the stop loss
are small related to the profit that you
can make. and then we took all the
expansion higher. I don't think it's
smart to continue trading because after
a wave like this zero retracement the
market will just go
>> sideways and when go sideways it's
expensive for me to trade because every
trade that I open I pay commission and
on futures are not so small in
interactive brokers.
>> So just
let's do a recap of what happened.
>> Mhm. The other time on chart fanatic we
exactly went through all the models. So
value area high break test these trades.
Yeah. Value area low accumulation phase
model one model two momentum trades. So
we managed to take a new session all the
execution that I explained in the model.
And there is someone in the comments
that I saw. Fabio you are gatekeeping
something guys. I don't have another
screen. I don't have a phone. You think
I will risk $25,000 in one session just
to pretend that I use a model just this
is my personal model and I decided to
share for free on this channel and the
result of the views are amazing and I
think we will just guys try to squeeze
up again on the tweet of Trump because
we are almost reaching this level
>> and I want to show you the perspective
on the five minutes because all the
people are used to to trade on the
minute chart.
>> Yeah.
>> It doesn't change anything. Okay. What I
want to show you what happened. Huge
aggression on the value area low.
>> Yeah.
>> Full of sellers.
Huge aggression of buyers with result.
If you are not using order flow with
price action, you could have take this
trade here. How much is your
riskto-reward? One one. How much? We did
10 R.
>> Yeah.
>> It's really different. Okay. So the
reason because people say also in the
comments is better price action. It's
not a battle. I use price action.
>> But price action is the impact and the
result. Order flow is exactly what's
driving the price.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay. The other information that you can
get if we want to make a master class
that is worth $20,000 it's options. Zero
DT options nowadays is so important. I
didn't use option now but you can use
options to get a sentiment for the
pressure.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. Options today were completely
long. I only watched this at the
beginning of the new year session. So
just I decided to flow which platform
you can use. There are a lot of free
platform but there are also paid
platform on the option side. For me,
it's not worth to pay 300,400, $500 per
month just to know the option pressure.
But you can get I I can share with you
some links where they can just see if
the option are pushing high
>> or low the pressure a good for for
pressure. So what we did now is that you
can see here we are completing an
expansion day.
The only trade that we can take is the
mitigation and the test of the value
area high. Considering this huge
aggression for the day, I don't think we
will reach this level. I think we are
going to shoot for the Trump tweet high.
>> Yeah.
>> To squeeze another high
>> and then I don't know maybe Baron Trump
can try another shot for 200 million.
But
>> unfortunately, we don't have insider
position
>> and we it doesn't seem like you need it
to be honest.
But um just to clarify as well when
we're referencing this Trump tweet on
Friday the 10th, Trump made a tweet out
of nowhere in regards to tariffs on
China. Cryptocurrency absolutely melted.
NQ and everything really sold off
aggressively and then on the weekend he
tweeted oh actually no is old as well.
>> China president is so good.
>> Yeah, my dear friend. So
>> so volatility has been increased. Uh you
know Fabio was saying just before we
started how you know this week's been a
bit crazy in terms of trading for him.
really difficult to trade this one
because as you can see
>> you get sharp moves you get really hard
expansion really hard usually the market
condition like this is the tweet okay
>> the market condition that I'm used to
trade is this one like you build you
accumulate you expand I take the
breakout trade and the value area low
this one is not a breakout trade it's a
collapse of the universe okay and what
they did today is that they are just
targeting this high and even my
pre-trade model was that today we will
push and squeeze this high we will try
to reach at least this level also market
maker don't like this kind of
environment okay like this kind of tweet
is the reason market makers can lose the
profit of the month because liquidity
completely disappear because they don't
want to input risk here so the price
melt so be really careful ful with days
like this specifically if you are
leverage on crypto because you can get
slippage you can get not filled at the
level that you want if you are doing CFD
the risk is way higher because it's on
the broker when he want to close you but
uh be really careful out there this
market condition is not easy to trade
just what I'm trying to share is that
professional tools are out there if
hedge found an institution use orderflow
there is a reason you watching exactly
what is driving in price at
fundamentals. So it's not some kind of
furu guru stuff that is providing you
with a readym made model and also one
dear friend of mine told me look you are
going to do live session you are going
to show people that is possible to make
five figure sessions six figure weeks
but you are not clarifying the capital
that you're putting in the market the
total account so I want to be really
clear on this I trade million accounts
it's my personal account you cannot do
$25,000 session getting a small risk on
a 100,000 account. It's impossible. And
I want also to clarify that what you see
here is not only because of the volume
and the platform because we need to be
honest in this. It's years and years of
reading that brings you to this level.
Don't expect that you start to use
orderflow and you get results like this
because it's not a magic magic tool. is
not something that is alone sufficient
to make you profitable.
>> That level of experience and the reps
that you have to put in is what develops
to what you're showcasing today as well
as obviously capital size that you're
trading with. But you know if someone
puts in those reps, the whole purpose
really is to highlight what is possible
when you've done that leap level work
when you are able to decipher the
information that order flow does provide
you in conjunction with as you've
already marked out you know just
understanding significant highs or
liquidity you you use this in
conjunction together is what then
creates such a result. I think people
are blown away by the accuracy of course
the you know the confidence of execution
that you have but I love the fact that
you always highlight the years and years
of effort and time and sacrifice that
has to go in
>> to make it actually possible. One
question I do have in terms of I'm sure
people are asking maybe or thinking this
like you've marked out these potential
areas that price could go to.
>> Yes.
>> Why not just hold your trade? Why not I
know obviously you're a scalper but why
not hold your trade and get this
potential bigger target?
>> I did a lot of research on this. Okay.
So what I notice is that you can shoot
for high riskto-reward but if you shoot
for high riskto-reward you will be
completely destroyed in contraction day.
Okay I prefer look I can show you
because it's really important for people
to understand my complete model. Okay.
So on the account I want to take only
from Monday I took like 100 execution
like total of 100 execution. I want to
show you the average uh winning trade.
Okay. So the average winning trade is
$1,000 on one contract. Okay.
>> One contract. Now I load 10 15 20. The
average losing trade is 600. If I try to
shoot to get the maximum high, my W rate
will get lower. I already don't have a
huge W rate. I have 43 to 49%. Okay,
>> but my W rate is based on average and
maximum winning trades is $10,000 per
contract.
>> The max losing is 3,200.
If I want these numbers to go up and
these numbers will go down. It's a
balance. Okay. So what I prefer is is to
have consistent 10,000 7,000 10,000 days
instead of having small days like -5 - 6
- 7 + 60 okay because if you try to
shoot here and you will here today you
will have maybe 50,000 60,000 day but
yesterday in the London I would have
minus 5 and yesterday had plus 10 okay
so it's always to which kind of approach
You can be a sniper and shoot for the
high. But your skill is not sufficient
because if there is enough pressure, you
will never reach this level. Okay. Maybe
now we go down. Imagine floating 60,000
in one session and seeing break even.
>> Yeah.
>> Mhm.
>> It's it's a trading approach that I
understand. It's more relaxed. But I
don't like it because I like to read the
market in life as it develop and if it's
necessary cut my trades. If the markets
today wants to give me 30,000, they take
30,000. If the market is continuing to
action, I can continue to trade and
build. But holding one trade for all the
movement is something that I was doing
before and I was less consistent. I know
that it's counterintuitive,
>> but if you think about this, getting
from A to B and A to C, it's of course a
huge number of different in ticks. Okay,
this probability in ticks is contained
and distributed through days.
Look at a day like this. Okay, what I
will do? I will get value area alloy and
I will shoot for the close completely
zero. This one is a session that I made
28,000. Okay, completely zero. Look at
this week. What I can expect down we go
to cover here. Bam. Liquidated up. Mhm.
>> Oh, we are distributing down value area
high. I shoot down but I don't want to
close here. That is level mark. I want
to close here. Bam.
>> Like I understand what you say but this
model of keeping and holding it's only
working in days of volatility and you
know that there is statistic of the
market that 70% of the time the market
is stationary.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay. I want to make money also when
it's stationary. So, I'm willing to
sacrifice this extra 20,000 to have 70
80% of green days.
>> And it's also, you know, something to
take note of is, as you mentioned here,
you might get stopped out,
>> but you'd be right.
>> Yes.
>> Right. But then what's saying you're
going to get the execution?
>> Imagine how much you bite your hands if
you get affiliate auction liquidated
here and see something. It's really
frustrating because you were in profit
of maybe 20,000. Now you are minus 5 for
the day and also you are correct and
then when you enter here because it was
so fast that to get this movement
>> like you needed to be sure really that
the market will continue.
>> So what what this is the approach that
I'm having constantly this is the
account that I show on where I do I call
it hypers scalping because every new
information of the market for me is a
way to monetize it. Okay. So if we go
down here we can check we took the
absorption
holding holding holding trapped buyers I
would have closed here okay I will never
hold till here why because now and what
it's important for me is now the market
is bunching on a wall okay
>> and I don't want to risk that this wall
takes back 20,000 like let's put
everything in frame if we hold this
trade till up it was like 20,000 trade
Okay, I have my break even here and
someone says I'm already break even. I
don't care. And no, it's not like this
because you are willing to sacrifice
20,000 on the down. I treat every trade
not only from stop perspective but from
profit perspective. Okay. The only
things I'm willing to do now if if it
breaks, I load again $2,000 profit and I
squeeze another 10,000 for the market,
but I'm not giving back the 20,000 that
I make. This one is crazy.
>> You'd rather build your cushion, build
your profit and then risk your profit
only.
>> Risk your profit if there are the
condition till we don't go for.
>> So right now there's only two trades
you're saying, right? One if we break
above and then retest
>> or we retest the exact and also this
trade here there is one thing that is
holding me to take it. Okay.
>> Because we didn't close the structure.
This is a movement that the market
makers don't like.
>> Okay. because they are not willing to
capitalize on this and this movement
create this imbalance. The the nature of
the market is to rebalance and expand.
>> Okay. So this for example it's a model
of chart fanatic that I gave that is the
test of the value area maybe a little
bit of absorb sellers and then we have
another trade. This one is a potential
30,000 additional trade for the day.
Getting this trades means that you are
betting on the fact that all this will
not be rebalance
and that these aggressive buyers are
willing to break this level. It doesn't
seems to me a condition in the market
where they can break because look how
much they tried. It's 20 minutes that
they are trying as soon as we exit the
trade here they stopped. Okay. Why we
exit the trade and they didn't shoot
high? Because I see them struggling.
Okay. I I give an example to the student
on YouTube. It's like a boxing match.
Okay. Would you ever bet on a winner
after four round after is getting
completely destroyed? I will never do
this. Okay. Now the market is saying
look
>> in this condition.
>> The winner won the first two rounds.
>> Yeah.
>> Now the other one is punching back and
they are almost the same. Okay. I don't
want to place a bet. I want to place a
bet if you win another round. Why?
Because my probability gets higher. I
know that it's counterintuitive because
traders expect that the more activity
you make, the more you hold, the more
profit you made. I did extensive
statistical research on this and it's
not like this. And you can understand
this also with VWAP standard deviation.
Okay.
>> The probability that you will get the
maximum standard deviation is like 10%.
Yeah. So out of 10 session, one session
reached the extreme level.
>> Why you are willing to sacrifice the
profit of all the nine session build the
profit then when the market is ready to
give you it will show you for example
now the buyers are getting again
aggressive. Okay. What we can do is try
an expansion phase with our stop loss
below here risking maybe $2,000. Okay.
to make another 46,000 and closing
30,000.
>> Yeah,
>> this is a trade we can do. Okay. But not
when we are getting absorbed because
when we are getting absorbed like we are
betting on the losing side.
>> Yes.
>> And and they know that um usually
traders think in terms of set and
forget. Okay. They execute here and they
say my target is here. I go to eat
pizza. I cannot do this. Why? because I
have had too much pain to see
risk-to-reward 1 to 20 1 to 30 going
back to zero. Yeah. And when it's
personal account and when you are giving
back to the market 40 50,000 trust me
that you start to take partials. Yeah.
>> Or you start to to get it down.
>> Then of course it's amazing when you see
a trade getting the bottom of the day
getting to the top of the range but is
only 20% of the session. Okay. For me
it's not worth it to to trade like this
but it's totally a personal opinion. I
have one of my dear friend he trade only
gold.
It does lowly rate huge riskto-reward.
>> Okay. This is another model that I can
respect. It's not from my side because
you have days of the calendar red huge
green red red huge green. I don't like
it.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay. It's just personal opinion. It's
like
>> Exactly. Yeah. It's being able to handle
the reality of the decision you make.
Right. So, like even going back to what
we were saying earlier, this trade even
if it was to play out and and you know
fit the criteria in reality there, if we
weren't sat here, you wouldn't be on the
charts.
>> I I wouldn't be.
>> Do you when you finish, do you just
close it and then walk away?
>> I close it. I close it. I can get back
to the market for example for what he's
doing now. Now, I like it. Why pushing
higher? What happened to this seller?
>> Sellers is getting locked. Okay. So, now
we have a potential squeeze here. This
is the only trade that I can evaluate.
Let's do another one for the community.
Okay.
And going to cover really low. How much
are we risking? 800. Okay. Why? Because
if these aggressive sellers are holding,
we can get the squeeze at the top.
Let's try to close this 30,000. Okay. If
we are wrong,
it's not convenient for us to continue
trading. We can load one on the app
because if it explode, I'm immediately
in profit and that's free. Okay,
consider it's only $800 risk. Uh so we
can take another trade if this one goes
to stop. But I will not continue because
as you can see sellers are really good
at protecting this level.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay. So now we are betting on the fact
that this buyer protected and these
sellers will not continue the movement.
So we are you see how much time how many
times they push right absorb push absorb
aggressive buyers. What does it mean?
They put the lock here. They say, "No,
no, no, bro. You don't go here." Okay.
What are you trying to do? It's not the
time.
So now I start to like it. And they want
to be covered immediately. As soon as
I'm right,
we cover below this.
>> Yeah.
>> And it's done. Okay.
Risking. Look, not even if I do $2,80.
Okay. Where are we trying to shoot for
the extra 6,000?
the session.
This is not something to be tried at
home. It is not one of the best setup
and we had the fill auction. What does
it mean? Again, you see how much buyers
they absorbed.
>> Sellers are strong on this level. Now,
what is good for us? Because there is
something that is bad, something that is
good. If they take back control, they
get anniated. We go directly to
target in one candle. Okay? But this is
happening because we've already had this
expansion move, right? The move, the AAA
setup's already taken place. Yes.
>> So this is why we're then seeing price
stall at this level.
>> Yes. Exactly. Now like you had the
expansion now. It's like an elastic
band. You cannot only throw. You need
time to get it back to normal state.
Then you can throw again. Okay.
>> Imagine like a crossbow or a bow.
>> To shoot an arrow, you have before to do
it again. You cannot shoot two arrow in
one. So this is how the market really
moves. Okay. So they are now it seems
like a buy accumulation.
It's not the best one to be honest, but
I see that there is a wall here. Like
I'm I'm not taking a trade that is not
protected. I'm taking a trade that is
protected by a buy wall. Okay. On a
$25,000 day, what I'm risking 2,000, not
even 10%. It's okay. You can you can
build on the profit. But if we break
this level, we start to go back in the
range, you know that you made what you
needed to made. Okay. And for example,
now I will be really in anxiety if I see
this level not holding and knowing that
if you shoot down, I give back to the
market 25,000.
>> Yeah.
>> Like it's also risk-to-reward is not
only when you take a trade, it's also
when you manage a trade. This is
something that everyone forget. Not many
traders are right. They take good
trades, but they want to shoot for 1 to
40.
>> Mhm. If you close one to three, one to
four, maybe you have 75% win rate. But
they want to show one to shoot one to 40
and they have 90% losing days. But I'm
still profitable because one day in the
monte, okay, is it sustainable to do
with million where you see I going down
100,000 to make 10,000. Yeah, but I'm
profitable. Yes, but your brain, how
does it work? So what happened here?
Philuction.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay. So we don't want to be in this
trade again. Yep, there is only one
condition where we can be in this trade
again if we break this eye. Okay, we
take the test. But now the market I know
my chicken is going to go here again.
Why? Because all this movement is not
efficient. Auction market theory always
rebalance movement.
>> Okay. And this movement is not balanced.
It's a huge expansion without testing
anything. Yeah. So it's pretty risky.
Now, it's also not clean at all.
>> Well, in terms of range, I did want to
ask like what's that based off when when
you say range chart? What's it?
>> It's Oh, but I like this. It's almost
based It's based on
uh what's closest to the 5 minutes.
Okay. 40 range is really close to the 5
minutes. But you see, but I like this
one. Wait a second. It's because I want
to
cover behind this. You see we are we are
going to auction really good high
and they want to cover here. We are
going to have a risk
1,600
for the last move up. Okay, this is a
trade that is worth to do. Why? Because
they show me that they went below the
structure.
>> Yeah,
>> they completely failed. What does it
mean that there is something here
>> in terms of
passive orders? There is a huge
absorption. Okay.
Now, position management. Okay.
If they break this level, I can put all
my stop loss below this.
>> Yeah.
>> So, I'm still risking 2,000, but now my
profit potential is way higher. Okay.
>> Mhm.
>> So, this is the the concept of
managing your trades. You see still
1,400. I can even load one contract more
two contract more. Sorry.
>> Better not from here but better
executing here.
>> So you're showing right now you're
showing how you have to be near the
speed fast.
>> Yeah. And we saw how you normally are
you on like a PC.
>> Yes.
>> Yeah. So you saw how like the we were
struggling to drag it down.
>> Yeah. because you need to be fast and I
was clicking on the level but usually in
my setup I have four screen okay like
it's not easy to to trade with a
trackpad guys it's trust me
>> but in my trading room home trading room
>> I'm faster I can promise you
and also I lost a little bit of time to
explain
>> of course yeah
>> let's see how we are going
>> don't know where the market's going next
stop worrying about your trading just
get informed formed on exactly what's
happening in the markets and what to
expect. From forex to futures to stocks
to crypto, be on top of it all. That's
why tens of thousands of traders are
subscribed to Market Journal, a free
newsletter that allows traders to keep
up to date with the markets every single
week. Remember, an informed trader is a
profitable trader. It doesn't matter if
Trump tweets, AI stocks are pumping, or
if Bitcoin drops out of the sky. Market
Journal has you covered. Join for free
today using the link in the description
below. Let's take a break for a minute
there, guys, cuz I want to tell you
about our sponsor, TradeZella.
Tradezella is the number one trading
tool for all traders. It doesn't matter
whether you're a crypto trader, a
futures trader, or a forex trader,
whatever trader you are. All you do is
connect your trading platform directly
with Tradzella. It automates and makes
your trading journaling so easy. If you
want to be a profitable trader, you need
Trading Edge. And that is exactly what
Tradzella does. It allows you to
identify edge, maintain your edge, and
optimize [music]
your edge by automating your trade
journaling, in-depth analytics, back
testing, bar replay, and so much more.
Now, W gets you 20% off your yearly
subscription with Trade Zeller. So, use
W for 20% off your yearly subscription
or RZ [music] 10 for 10% off your
monthly subscription. The link is in the
description below. Now, let's get back
to this episode.
aggressive sellers again buyers
protecting the level but at the same
time buyers are getting absorbed so now
it's I'm not really confident on this
why
trapid buyers so much aggressive sellers
>> fortunately we are risking so less
>> this is what
>> keep you but you need to take a lot of
but I'm relaxed because I'm risking
a small portion of profit
>> and when you risk
this small portion and you build for the
day, you build for the day, you are
sitting on 22,000.
>> Mhm.
>> Like what is the worst that can happen?
You close to $20,000. Yeah. What's the
problem? When you start to be aggressive
at the start of the session where you
don't have profit, your brain plays
tricky games. There is a huge part about
the mindset that people don't
understand. But when you are in draw
down, you have less clarity. Okay? So
your role is immediately to build a
cushion for the day. Mhm.
>> and sit on it.
>> Yeah.
>> Like a king. Okay. You stay there. Worst
that can happen is you lose the profit
back.
>> Now let me commend this again on this
big sellers. This is completely dominion
of sellers. Okay. So this
this
expansion high that we were trying
failed. Two times it failed. Okay.
>> We still want to be long. They didn't
broke the structure. We trailed our stop
to make it slow, but they didn't broke
the structure. We are still sitting at
$20,000.
We can, you see, aggressive trades on
the bottom. We can still try
to get it
on the way up building and at the top of
the range. But why? It's not that we are
getting crazy now and we want to to
start building because they show
aggressive trades on the bottom. Mhm.
>> Completely absorbed again. 1,120.
Okay. The reason I fraction is because
I'm fast and I can understand really
fast how much am I risking.
>> Okay.
>> Mhm.
>> If you put immediately 10 contract, you
cannot build exactly in the level to
make the risk always 2,000. Maybe you
load everything on the top of the market
and you risk 4,000.
>> Yes.
>> Okay. by but but but by putting risk in
the markets this way you can still do
it. Now it's getting a little bit dirty.
This is not easy to read but I will make
it easy for you.
>> Protection level from buyers,
protection level from sellers.
>> Okay, we are covered below the
protection level for buyers in this
case.
>> We are position up in the range. This is
not where I should have put my position.
I was slow this time. This is what I
should have put as soon as you see
aggressive sellers because in this case
I could have already been break even.
>> True. Yeah.
>> Okay.
Let's try to shoot for an expansion
higher. You see again on the top of the
range what what happened? Buyers
>> aggressive absorbed.
>> Same at the bottom. Yeah.
>> Absorbed. Okay. So this is the tighter.
This is the fight. The smaller
compression range gives the best upside
potential. Interesting.
Now I I like to put horizontal level on
the last protection level. Before the
last protection level was this one.
>> Mhm.
>> When you understand it, it's not so hard
to get it. It's asymmetrical risk. They
load again aggressive again absorbed.
Okay. You can see every time they try to
go here, bum bum bum bum bum. Okay. What
we can do is get
a buy stop here because if we arrive
there, we put all our risk here. So,
still lower, still 2,000 risk, but more
upside potential. This is the game.
>> And also, if they touch this high, it
means that buyers won the battle.
>> Mhm.
>> And if they won the battle, I want to be
on the side of the winner,
>> of course. Yeah.
Let's see what they can do.
>> Failed. Yeah.
>> Failed
>> defend it.
>> See the risk of executing a lot of
trades is that you get caught in this
consolidation.
>> Yeah.
>> And you pay a lot of
>> And this is why you normally walk away,
right?
>> Why I walk away? Because I took the I
take only the best AAA. This one is not
a AAA, but it's a setup that can explain
to the the viewer how you momentum
trade.
>> Yeah. [snorts]
>> So when you walk away, you walk away
completely. You don't look again. Don't
look again and start to do something
else because otherwise if you see
something interesting you want to open
[laughter]
but I'm in profit let's let's risk
something else here
>> you see this is destroying the buyers
>> this means that the this is the
protection level okay they try to go
again here what's happening
sellers controlling done okay
70 thou 17,758
for the session and now again buyers.
Okay, you can continue to build up for
the day. You can use this 7,000 to make
another 25, another 30. You can do it,
but not from here.
>> Okay, it's not smart to do it from here.
If we need to evaluate a new trade, we
need to break
>> because otherwise
also this big bias is not really sitting
confidently. Okay,
we want to try a last one in this case
if they break. Okay, so we want to see
this one not holding.
Let me
buy stop here.
Buy stop here.
Buy stop here and the other one I can
load on the retracement. Now what the
market is showing me they have results.
Yeah.
>> So it means that the level that we used
to close our trades was perfect.
>> Mhm.
>> This level one was perfect. This
exactly, you remember we closed here.
Okay. This was exactly when the market
started to slow down.
>> Yeah.
>> Now we are betting on the reaccumulation
phase.
>> Mhm.
>> That it's
it's a really good trade. The problem is
that every time they go to test the
accumulation phase, you are liquidated.
Yeah, you can take a lot of small stop
loss, but five small small stop loss is
$10,000.
>> Exactly. Yeah.
>> Like what you
>> this absorption.
>> Okay.
>> I was going to say like what are your
thoughts? Like I know we're profitable
for the day, profitable for this session
in particular still, but after taking I
think that was three stop losses. Yes.
What are you thinking? What's happening?
totally okay because a risk in a
momentum trade that is valid as soon as
you have a mental process of a setup
that can pay you five four six times the
risk I'm okay like I'm not worried at
all like we we went to 24,000 to 17,000
I'm calm I know that for the day we were
24,000 okay we can still go to 10,000
for the day so I have still a little bit
to risk because I only risk the profit
of the session
>> so we are up 8,000 We are still
profitable for London. We can try to
build another trade and close at 30.
>> Yeah,
>> a 13,000 trade will be good. But the
market is not giving us and this is
important guys to understand the
condition. If the condition gets this
you cannot watch this and says I want to
make because the market is saying to you
we are in contraction. Yeah we can stay
like this four hours.
>> What are you going to take seven eight
stop loss?
>> Mhm. [snorts] So now they reach again
the this the protection level that is on
the bottom side. Okay, this one is good.
You can bet on an expansion higher
but on this one I will take a smaller
risk like I will not risk 3,000 or more
not even the time you see while I
explain the market already unfolded
here.
So what I want to do is loading here
protect protecting myself here because
what does it mean that if we reach here
this one won the battle. Yeah.
>> If this one won the battle this one
probably is ready for squeeze.
>> Okay. Okay.
Absorption here again. I like it.
This is a level where we can cover
ourself. Now riskto-reward wise
let's check
10 contract here. Okay 10 contract
we are risking 2,700
to make a potential 10. Okay it's not
bad. The problem is that again they are
not holding. So I need to cancel you see
how much you need to be
>> dynamic fast and dynamic and understand
how the market is behaving. Okay.
>> How easy or hard was it to be dynamic?
You know when you was developing this
skill set
>> it's all about real execution. Like
everyone thinks you need to study on
books. Like I'm not a big fan of theory.
I'm a big fan of practice. Start with a
10,000 account, try to build it to 20,
30, 40. In the process, while you build
the account, you understand so many
things
>> that you understand also why some trades
are not worth for me. Okay. So, I'm a
big fan of practice.
>> Yeah.
>> And for example, now they did an amazing
failed auction. The sellers,
we can jump in.
Sorry this sometimes I stop but it's
really hard to
>> that's what we're here for. Yeah.
>> This is what we clarified on the chart
for next episode that that was live
charting.
>> Yeah. Live trading is more difficult
guys because you need to be super fast
in your mental process. What I saw here
is the last point of protection from
from buyers. So if this one doesn't
hold, we are done for the day and we go
down.
>> Yeah. But if this one hold I'm risking
2,400 to make a potential 10 15 I can
bring the account to
30,000 for the day and it's not a lot of
movement that I need. Yeah.
>> Okay. And also if I'm fast this 2,400
can go to zero risk really fast.
>> Mhm.
[snorts] sellers taking control back
again on the level. Now I expect to see
these buyers
passive
showing the upper hand. Okay. So all
this area is the protection level that
we have.
>> Yeah.
Let's see how we are doing for the day.
Aggressive sellers again
done what we can expect now
acceleration. You see?
>> Yeah.
>> Now we are out of the range. Now all the
look aggressive sellance on the bottom
and you can expect now we can expect to
arrive back here. Okay. Now what
happened? This is important to
understand. We took
three trades and we took three trades
that were on the long side and four
consolidation trades. Okay, in these
four consolidation trades, we took stop-
loss really small. We are still $5,000
in profit. This is the power of
risk-to-reward. Okay, this is the power
of building profit for the day. Now in
this case
the setup
that you can evaluate the triple A is
this one. Okay. It's on the test on the
upper range. This one is an amazing
setup. You can also try to shoot at
least for this eye.
>> So this is a setup that can bring you to
15,000 to 40.
>> Mhm.
>> Continuing to engage here for me it's
not worth it because it can
>> but it wasn't worth for you anyway
personally. It's only because we're
shooting this video.
>> Wasn't worth for me if I was alone. But
for me, $10,000 is not changing my life.
And I'm really happy to show also how to
handle draw down. Okay. Is not switching
my mood, but is giving to the audience
an understanding of a symmetrical
riskto-reward and why it's not worth to
engage it. Okay. The next video that
will come out on my channel is one
session that I started and I took like
six, seven stop-loss, eight stop loss
maybe exactly like this. Okay.
>> So the first content on my channel will
be my work session. Why I'm doing this?
Because I want to teach them that's an
exchange. You are putting risk in the
market. The market is giving you back
something. To make a session of $15,000
in profit, you need to be stoic. You
need to be strong enough to have a
10,000 draw down and continue your life
like nothing happened.
>> This is what they need to understand
before the discipline that it takes and
to build this you have to go through a
journey that start with losses. Mhm.
>> This is the reason I wish everyone, they
will kill me, they will say that, but I
wish everyone to enjoy their bad days
and streak of stop-loss because you will
bless these days because they teach you
how to survive. You cannot be a boxer if
you don't know how to get hit and stay
still standing on your feet. It's easy
when the market for example if today was
first wave second wave third wave
$70,000 for but this creates in the mind
of the viewer of chart fanatic a a wrong
misconception about trading because they
expect that they can do this this
session was perfect because we were
precise we protected our profit we took
two AAA trains then we start to brag
around what can we do what can you
execute I want to explain momentum
This is what your brain does in real
training
when specifically when you want to merge
the educational part with the execution
part because you you feel that you need
to do. Okay,
>> this is the same pressure that people
get when they start trading to pay the
bills. No, but I need to make this
profit for the month otherwise I cannot
pay my bills. This is what destroy you.
It's pressure. And this is what in the
World Cup for example happened to me
like really
>> I I was trying to shoot for the first
place and I sacrifice that 6% profit
that if I will kept it would have gave
me the first place. I still close with a
500% in 12 months of live execution but
I could have got the first place. Why I
didn't took it? Because I want to show
to the world how much I can make. This
is pure ego.
>> Mhm.
You take execution that are not
following the models, you are still
profitable. Yeah, but the first one was
220%, I closed 220.
So you sacrifice the possibility and
this is something that people needs to
understand. Now on proper maybe it's a
little bit easier because it's not your
money, you don't care. Okay? But when
you have a personal account it's big
enough that is millionaire personal
accounts
you pay this error in cash and immediate
the trading is the only the only teacher
that removes error from you in form of
cash and immediate. So be really careful
about this. As you can see big movement
we if we rewatch the session after this
>> it's not worth to trade three because
usually you have
>> consolidation
>> you will see that probably prediction is
right okay probably they will skyrocket
up but it's the same as I was saying
before
>> while you while you try to take the
short how many times you get liquidated
okay this is the the lesson that I can
give to them Well, it goes back to as
well uh what we were saying or that
question I asked earlier is why don't
you hold? Why don't you hold? But
imagine
>> holding holding and seeing that only
this win is 7,000 less.
>> Yeah,
>> it's not worth for me. It's not worth
like and just cover yourself as soon as
it break you cover yourself
>> and you trade. But then it went back and
it removed you. Yes. But why I close my
trades here instead of waiting for stop-
loss here? because
I prefer to have a controlled risk that
big winner
>> instead of having one huge winner, but
if it goes bad, I give back all the
profit of the new session.
>> Plus, why would you do that anyway when
the concept and the framework of the
trade is based on the fact that they
failed here?
>> Yeah, they failed and therefore they
failed.
>> You could say give it breathing room,
but why? here here the trade that I was
trying to fade
>> it's called value area low fade okay so
it's a bet that you go from the downside
to the upside yeah
>> there is only one market condition where
this trade is not profitable is when the
aggressive buyers are stuck so they
cannot break okay so as you can see also
if we try again here we will have again
take another stop worth it okay probably
we redell balance the session and then
we go again up. Okay. And this is I want
to show you also something
that the stop loss that we took
the stop-loss that we took here
from
the starting of the session till now.
Wait one second. And they want to show
them the single trade. Look at these
rits. This was the session. Look how
much they are a lot but they are small.
They are controlled. Yeah. Okay. I don't
want that a loss can be like this
because otherwise it bring back all my
my profit and also
this week this is really important to
understand. This week my equity line of
the sell trade is almost in uh draw
down. is 1,700 minus the equity long.
It's $67,000 in profit. Okay, this is
important to understand because it means
that in this market scenario, the sale
is not profitable. And I know why
>> because when you have a huge expansion
down like TR trades, okay, the market
will try to build again till the level
of inflection down.
>> Yeah.
>> Because market maker want to transact
efficiently. Yeah.
>> And this is the reason you have building
of the session uh building sorry of the
week like this and then if you join the
direction against the squeeze you can
build a lot of profit for the session.
So as we can see
D now it's five. Usually they move in
the power hour.
>> Yeah. So usually you see now we will
stay in this range probably for another
one 1 hour 2 hour then they reaccumulate
down and in the power hour you go up.
>> Yeah I will show probably I will show
you I will send you the screen of the
power hour session
>> usually they do like this. This is
called P shape in volume analysis. It
means that all the volume is built on
the top part here. you [snorts] go back
to test to reaccumulate and you
rebalance the profile and then you
continue. This is a model that I gave to
chart fanatic and it's uh this is the
momentum squeeze that we took. The
second one is this absorption of the
sellers.
>> Yeah. and then skyrocket up. Definitely
because the other thing to note as well
about you know why don't you just hold
the trade is the fact that you were done
in 10 minutes
>> is when you are done in 10 minutes you
need to take and go home maybe it will
not be the most educational session but
you need to take and go home because it
means that the market expanded in the
first in the first hour of the session
>> 90% of the session that expand they
rebalance till the power hour this is
the structure of the New York if you
expand immediately
And Trump is not tweeting. You
rebalance.
>> Yeah.
>> Expanding power hour.
>> Okay. This is this is the reason 90% of
my execution of model B testing of the
value area after their expansion is from
7:30 European time till 9 because it's
the power hour movement.
This is what you can expect. For
example, now the market is giving you
because every indicator have a weak
point. Okay. The big trades have a weak
point when you are in consolidation
>> because they are just fighting but no
one is winning at the moment.
>> If we want to add another pro proxy we
can put the cumulative volume delta that
is the summary of all the delta exchange
in the session of the contract and this
give you the pressure. As you can see
also the cumulative volume delta is not
so defined in the starting of the
session was so clear. We are bullish
now. They are selling a little bit,
buying a little bit, selling a little.
Don't engage here. Don't engage. If they
break, we have another trade.
>> Mhm.
>> Probably not before power hour.
>> That's okay. That's okay. It was more
than enough just to start off straight
away with $10,000 win, which was a one
to five risk-to-reward, which was insane
>> given the fact you'd already made
$10,000 as well.
um you know in London session as well as
then after that $10,000 trade we then
took was it one or two I think it two
more trades
>> I think it was three more trades
>> and uh but was crazy the draw down like
because
>> when you took a trade if you can put
your stop loss to zero in the first
minute it means that you are joining the
battle on the momentum side removing the
stress in the first minute is something
that is crazy for this field
I I do also swing trading based on
fundamentals.
>> Everyone says how you can scalp. I want
to say to them how you can swing. For me
going to sleep with a stop loss in
machine that I'm doing that I wake up
with anxiety.
>> It's it's different approach just there
is not the right one. If you are a
sculper you are usually one person that
is patient
>> and this one person that is able to
control emotion
while you trade. Yeah.
>> If you get excited for 5,000, 10,000, oh
my god, I knew that I shouldn't have
open, now I open again. It's not for
you. Like, leave it there.
>> How have you always been, you know, more
stoic and calm? No, I started
with my first account that was scalping
the NASDAQ on CFD and I was always
trying to trail my stop loss but the
spread was me up, you know,
because the spread is always widening in
CFD broker. I don't know. And I was
getting so mad that I would execute
again if the stop loss was taken by
spread. this will destroy my statistics.
Like the win rate is way lower than 40%.
If you can get 40%, 50 60% in the best
month with one, two, three, like your
equity line is like this.
>> Mhm.
>> So it's uh I've not I've not always been
like this. I've been like this when I
start to detach myself from the output
of the session. Like I don't even watch
the performance at the end of the day. I
watch at the end of the week. Like for
me a six figures week it's amazing. This
one is 60,000 for the week from Monday.
It's amazing.
And I know that in 5 days around I win
four days and I lose one.
>> Yeah.
>> So when I start to see that the session
goes bad, the condition are not bad,
usually I walk away.
>> Yeah.
>> I don't let the market take seven, eight
stop loss. My rule was three losing
trades to stop is exactly what we did
here
>> in the starting of the session. I give
more room. I have four or five because
usually you have consolidation and then
expansion.
>> Mhm.
>> This is exactly what uh what I noticed
to be the best approach to survive in
this market and also study your market.
This is NASDAQ. Study your market. If
you trade ducks, the model is completely
different. You will trade in the
morning.
>> So to reply to your question, no, I've
not always been patient. I've been
really
an ADHD guy wanted to to execute there.
>> But you understand that you don't make
more money by being more active. You
make more money by selecting better your
trades.
>> This is the the best lesson that you can
get
in terms of your speed. Have you always
been able to operate at speed when it
came to execution and management or is
that something you had to develop and
refine as well? Let's say that you need
you need to be really good not only at
moving orders but in decisional process
like
I noticed that trading is really
connected to your life. If you are an
overinker sculping is not for you
because you need to take a decision fast
and you need to take full responsibility
for the decision that you are taking.
Absorb on value area low they are trying
again to auction high.
>> Yeah. So you need to take full
responsibility for what you are doing
and you cannot overthink.
>> Yeah.
>> I have one friend of mine, I try to
teach him for free. He spend one week
with me. He's a person that thinks, you
know, this kind of guy thinks over and
over and over again.
>> Yeah.
>> In the moment that he was thinking about
executing a trade, the trade was already
take profits. Like sculping it's not for
everyone. I want always to be clear on
this. It's
it requires certain trait of behavior of
the person that you cannot learn.
>> It's not something that you can learn.
You you need to be
to be prone to have this kind of uh of
trading approach and something that
unfortunately
>> you cannot learn. Not always you can
learn. You can be the best at uh
learning the fundamentals, the
technicals, but if you're the way you
are is totally opposite to this, you
will only try to fit yourself in a box
that is not for you. Maybe you are an
amazing swing trader if you are an
overthinker. Yeah,
>> maybe you are the best option trader
because you are you have a rational
mind, statistical mind, but it's it's
not for you this kind of approach.
>> Mh. And um you can of course work but
why working to filter in a model that is
running against you you know and if you
are fast in taking in taking decision in
in life if you are
changing idea fast and are really low
ego and willing to take a stop loss
because you are wrong and immediately
jump on the train.
>> Yeah.
>> You can be an amazing trader that follow
model like this.
>> Yeah.
And what was your process like of
learning order flow?
>> Learning order flow arrived only six
years after I was trading because I was
trying to get to understand why a
pattern works. I will give you an
example. If we have a daily high or a
daily low,
>> I noticed that when they spike down or
spike up, you have a movement. So now it
opens a lot of conspiracy theory. They
are hunting. they are they are ready to
take they want to liquidate.
>> So I started to study what happens in
intraarket structure. So you need to go
down you need to understand you need to
study interaction of the order and I
understood that simply what's happening
is that the aggression of the sellers is
not as strong as the passive orders and
you see absorption. You see absorption
you see absorption and you see
absorption. Okay, that is what is
happening here is not that they want to
take your stop- loss here just they are
trying to push down but passive orders
are holding.
>> Yeah,
>> by understanding this my whole
understanding of the market did a level
up because I was not guessing will it be
a stop run, will it be a failuction,
will it be this, will it be that now I
understand exactly what's happening. If
you for me it was I can compare this to
the switch of driving a car. Okay. If
you drive with price action you are
watching you are trying to drive
watching the weights or Google maps.
Okay. But you don't see the street. You
just know that you need to go from here
to here because the structure is like
this.
>> When you start to see car you can see
obstacles. You can see that you are
stationary because there is traffic. Why
we are not going? There is traffic.
There is orders. Okay. So this this was
a big level up for me is was an
understanding of the market that I never
had before and this is the reason I'm
sharing so many contacts for free
because I really want to give back to
the industry something that is not
conspiracy but something that is really
how the market really moves like there
is an exchange there is an aggregation
of the order you can this is actual
execution people pressing buy or sell is
not an indicator that is giving you a
MACD cross.
>> Yeah. So this is this is what changed my
life, what changed my perception and uh
I'm really enthusiastic to to share with
the world this approach that can help
everyone. You don't need to change your
trading model. Mhm.
>> You you can implement in all the
operational you can see here again
>> same thing
>> same thing buyers trying to gras they
did the liquidation of the eye now they
are going down now just they try to
press and you can see from the total
orders they are pushing up breaking no
breaking no why not enough aggression
there are passive orders getting this
liquidity that are creating a range but
it's normal if you think about this like
the elastic look how many orders they
loaded
>> yeah Now they are resting, they are
breathing, they are understanding what
they want to do next. And then you will
see either aggression and we go to
rebalance and we have aa for power hour
or they are just saying look we want to
reaccumulate here because we are pushing
we go up.
>> Yeah.
Now for you watching real time order
flow is giving you a better
understanding of what's happening behind
the curtain. No, definitely. I remember
it changed my perspective the last time
we sat down because it really opened my
eyes to how detailed of an understanding
you can have regardless of the even
trading it or not. Just being able to
understand why the market is reacting
here, what's happening. Cuz even here,
even where we've taken these stop
losses,
>> none of those stop losses meant, oh,
we're wrong.
>> It's understanding that, okay, here's an
opportunity
>> that can generate a good risk-to-reward
idea.
>> Exactly. backed by understanding what's
happening behind these candles and these
movements because there'll be people who
have none of this information just the
candlesticks.
>> Yeah. They seem
>> and they'll still be executing. Yeah.
>> They'll be going okay look below this
low stop loss or wherever it may be
>> and yet in this understanding we are
able to scale back and take a step back
and say okay three times now the auction
has failed to do anything. The buyers
and sellers have failed to take over or
any control. So we stop and wait and
watch and we still off the back of that
have an aaa area below. Uh timing might
be a factor that might not come into our
uh you know advantage but we now still
have that and we also have the you know
if the auction was to break the high
then maybe there's something but at
least we understand okay now the time is
done and this all comes after the fact
that we had a AAA sell.
>> Yeah and profitable. You know why it's
convenient? Because you know always also
when to stay calm
>> like when you see orders not having a
reaction it means that the liquidity
wall is getting so thick.
>> It's like if you are punching a wall on
the upside and on the downside. This is
what is happening. When you are here you
don't know but after 20 minutes that you
are here you know that you don't want to
engage. And this is the condition that
is cing creating the best squeeze.
>> Mhm.
>> Because this can be also a pre-market
condition and is giving you momentum
trades or AAA.
>> Yeah.
>> And what's the reality in terms of
obviously both of our sessions have gone
very very well
>> in terms of the market movements, the
predictions today in particular live
trading um you know with good size and
making a good P&L for the day.
>> You know what does it look like on a
like this week's been really good for
you.
>> Yes. But what does it look like on
average you know the average performance
over let's say this year
>> are you having losing days are you
having you know that sort of you know
>> you are having uh losing days 100%.
But what I'm really good is at cutting
the losing days as I was saying to you
like I have statistics on everything
like I people journal in the weekend.
No, people go to dance in the weekend.
What I do in the weekend that is very
boring. I go through my metrics and try
to understand what I can improve. Okay.
I noticed that the days that start with
three or four or five stop-loss end up
with a losing of 20,000 15,000. I start
to cut them at 8 9,000. Okay. So, of
course, I have losing days. It's really
difficult for me to have losing months.
The last losing months that I have I had
was March 2024. And if you go to see it
was
>> like
>> lack of volatility.
>> I'm a trend follower. It's killing me.
>> So, of course, I have losing months. Uh
I work with big capital. Yeah. So I
don't try to get huge percentage like
200 300%. Usually what I do you can have
a good frame by dividing the performance
of the world cup by five or six.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. So if in the world cup I did 500%
usually in my trading account this year
I did 100%. Gotcha.
>> I did 80% I did 70%. the still for a
private hedge fund because I'm working
with my personal capital of multiple
millions. an amazing performance of
course
>> but for a retail trader it's not enough
like it was crazy because when I talk
about performance they start to say 60
70% per year
>> is not worth it why because I trade with
1,000 it will be $600 it will not even
be to pay the bills scale capital like
they try to scale performance without
understanding that
>> the real focus point is how much capital
can you manage and also
It's really important to understand
because I received one question why you
don't open your own hedge fund or why
you don't go to work with this position
in an hedge fund. The reply is only one
capacity of the strategy. What does it
mean?
>> How many millions I can manage? Yeah.
>> Without getting too much slippage
>> or having a feeling point that is not so
good to the point that is worthless for
me to execute.
>> Takes away the edge. the capacity of the
strategy sculping the NASDAQ. Yes, I can
diversify with as it's around 25 to 40
millions.
>> For a hedge fun 25 to 40 millions, it's
peanuts. They work with billions. They
work with hundreds of millions. So, this
is a model that I love that can be
amazing for me and it's a model that is
purely relying on order flow and market
interaction. And the reason I'm sharing
this with you is because even if you
study, okay, you will not take my brain
out of me. The market understanding, we
are never going to have the same
execution point because the mental
process and the neural network that you
have in your brain is getting deeper in
understanding. But there is
discretionary. We are taking
discretionary decision. What does it
mean? We have a model but we put on
leverage our understanding of the model
of the market. That's the difference
between with between quant. if my
strategy was quant so I always have the
same execution pattern I I couldn't
share with the world because in this
case my edge will go to zero
>> of course
>> okay
>> and uh this is uh this is the reason
also now there is still a trick to
execute this model on multiple hundreds
of millions by understanding that NASDAQ
and S&P 500 have 95% correlation S&P 500
is a lot more liquid than NASDAQ. I can
split my execution and I can work with
more capital. Of course, this is
possible. Okay, but uh it's important to
understand the capacity of the strategy
specifically if you are a scalper and
where is your limit. My limit is
scalability. This is the reason I'm
studying with Andrea uh option models
because they can give you statistical
and mathematical consistent return with
um scaling with a lot more liquidity.
Okay. Like I know that if I want to
trade 1 million uh account with this
strategy, it will not be possible. So by
making 15,000 I cannot make 1.5 million
per day because
>> imagine we are loading already 10
contracts. Okay. To make 1.5 million per
day, we need to expose 100 times more.
So here I will need to execute 1,000
contract. 1,000 contract I will bring
the market here. So I'm already losing
my edge.
>> Yeah.
>> So this is this is something really
important to to understand.
>> What what was your sort of starting
capital like? My starting capital in
12 or 14
was made by crypto. Like I always say to
my audience that I make a big portion of
my wealth understanding market cycles
early with onchain analysis.
>> So I jump really early on the train of
crypto and I understood because this
model I also trade on crypto. You can
imagine with leverage what you can do
with crypto like I managed to take one
single bull run on leverage completely
on futures. You can imagine the return
this build the first capital that I had
and I can say that I never hold the
dollar. So I only use I have an account
for only daily expenses but mainly my
capital with this deep understanding
it's always either in trading model
either in long-term options either in
crypto my portfolio so even if you
understand with 5 10 15 20,000
if you manage risk properly and you have
two income freelancer income because I
did to get the starting capital I did a
lot of work yeah okay I was doing serv
server monitoring in the night database
from midnight in the night to 8:00 in
the morning and with 4 hours of sleep
during the day I was starting to trade.
So it was really stressful and with this
capital I understood how to allocate and
how to diversify. You have income from
trading, you have freelancer income and
you have your cash deposit that is
bringing constant because you understand
the halving cycles of crypto. So you
have three forces pushing in your
direction and you know that every dollar
that you put in today will be $10 in
five to 10 years. This is creating an
exponential curve and is what is giving
me today the possibility to trade with
multiple millions account personal and
uh it's giving me today
more than 50 60% of my income coming
from trading and other than this I run
business. So I have uh a SAS at the
moment where I'm putting all the effort
that is an orderflow platform not yet
started but I already know that it will
be good because it's built by the best
traders on the world. So we are
gathering all the best traders and
saying what do you think about this? I
want to give a shout out to Carmen
Rosato. I enter in the call with him and
I say look how will you make this
better? Okay. So when you create
something by people that actually make a
lot of money trading, it cannot be bad
because you will ask them what they
need. Okay?
>> Other than this, previously I was doing
education. Now I stopped doing education
and giving everything for free because
education it's a lot of effort and at
the moment it's way more profitable for
me only focusing on trading
>> and what I plan in the future is to
focus on hedge fund advisory. So to to
be a market strategist and provide
models for hedge fund because this is
what I love. I love to create models
either quantitative, either
discretionary, either statistic
statistical model and uh solving the
cubic cube uh the Rubic cube that is the
market is so is always something that
gives you a thrill and excitement
because you are fighting against PhD
hedge fund like so if you can understand
it's not only how much money you can
make but the ability of brain
stimulation that it gives to you
>> and it's something that Never stop. You
cannot use the same model for pers. I
always try to refine. Yeah. For example,
you see I make it all because I can see
better candles. So I can see the
interaction. It's constantly developing
also because the market is constantly
developing. So I know clearly that you
cannot put a static model on a dynamic
market.
>> Yes,
>> it's impossible.
Even if we took
>> still back in
>> even if we took a short or if we took
along with really large stop loss
>> liquid
>> still get liquidated. Yeah.
>> So there there are situation where you
don't want to engage. Now volume can
help you a lot because you see that you
are still in the range with volume. So
price sometimes goes on its own you know
spike but then you need to validate with
volume because it's the merge of volume
and price that is giving you an actual
edge.
in terms of when you plot on your volume
profile like what where are your start
and end points how do you justify or
determine that
>> this is a really smart question so what
I make I have two ways of plotting
>> either I do it in compression range if I
want to play the ping pong between the
area but the best way to do it
for momentum trades is from the
expansion movement okay so you can see
contraction contraction contraction
contraction expansion Yeah.
>> So what I do is I plot from point A
to point B till the actual price action.
What I was trying to explain to you is
that we have a P shape.
>> Yeah.
>> Because all the volume are concentrated
on the top. Okay.
>> Mhm.
>> This market environment cannot go on
forever. Okay. So usually what you do is
you go to the value area low. Okay. It
will be amazing if they also test here.
And then you have an expansion higher.
This is the trend following model the
AAA. Okay. So all the volume it's here.
They are reloading from here. This is
the level of the value area low.
>> And you always need to understand that
you cannot take every swing point. But
you need to get the first directional
move of the session.
>> Yeah.
>> If this was premarket, this is New York
session opening. Okay. The game plan is
done. And then also there is a really
good model that is called orb model. I
don't know if you ever heard range
breakout. Okay, this is a model that if
you put in a context is really strong
because the model is saying look that
this low is not getting touched 80% of
the time.
>> Yeah,
>> this is strong because it's saying to us
look that you are going to reaccumulate
from here and what you have this is the
last protection point of the sellers.
Look at the delta of the buyers.
Complete control. When we went down, who
was controlling price here? Sellers.
Okay, now that it's buyers, you see that
aggressive sellers on the bottom already
bouncing back. We didn't even reach, but
you see that sellers have a hard time
now going down. Okay. So, you can try to
take in this range a setup that shoot
for the 25,163.
Okay.
In this case why even if I was alone I
will stop because we reached 24,000 okay
we went to 15,000 how much is it is on
the trailing profit of the day 10,000
9,000 or down okay I don't engage why
because the market condition now it's
getting hard to trade yeah okay so in
case where you really have a triple
aggressive seller you can still trade
you are you are trading 200 in the worst
case you are still profitable not not
only for the London but also for the New
York. Okay.
>> But usually the statistics never lie and
you need to understand how to manage
your emotion otherwise as a sculper you
will see opportunity everywhere.
>> Mhm. Like if you if you don't understand
how to qualify and free them, you will
see opportunities everywhere here.
>> In terms of a statistical analysis, like
where did that sort of passion to study
that come from and how helpful has it
been for your trading?
>> When you understand that this number is
directly correlated with how much
statistical test you run. For example,
um when you want to take profit,
>> you need to understand the strike point
of the take profit. Okay, if the VWAP
high is here and I try to shoot for
here, I know that nine times out of 10
it will reject the VWAP. Okay,
>> I run extensive statistical test on this
and it came from the necessity to boost
them we rate because boosting from 30 to
40 to 45 like I have now percent we rate
it seems like a small number but 15% we
rate more with this risk-to-reward it's
a lot risk
>> it's a lot I have also a trading model
on another account one to one
risk-to-reward 75%. like the equity line
is like this because it's consistent
>> but I know exactly when not to trade the
the model that I was saying to you only
trades here.
>> Yeah.
>> So I switch you know when I cannot trade
this model I switch to the consolidation
model like here I would have made a lot
of money with that model.
>> All this test
>> you cannot base on personal perception.
You need to to have a backing of
numbers. Yeah. So what I usually do I
export all the data I put in Python.
Python have machine learning neural
network all the infrastructure to make
huge test. You can know everything about
your trading history and I I'm not in a
position to take decision based on this.
I go to Luca one guy that helped me on
this. Shout out to and he say look Fabio
it's not worth to take trades for
example after 7 Italian time European
time. Why?
>> So he goes down the data point. your W
rate is low like you have 20% W rate so
remove this perfect on Friday you always
lose money like uh in four weeks of the
month three Friday you lose remove
Friday I have one day of vacation per
day all these kind of test I know for
certain that a lot of people don't do
>> of course yeah
>> okay so it's giving you an edge for
example
>> before I had a model on crude oil the
model was amazing but on Wednesday was
giving back all the profit that he made
because Wednesday the volatility on
crude oil you can check on this gets
crazy and this was a compression model
we removed Wednesday the model was
profit factor 2.1
>> it was completely completely consistent
what in what you do so people
underestimate the power of data
>> so journaling tracking the data uh
always understanding what's your metrics
either you do directly in the platform
either you do in the journal like you
can use the one of whom are you? You can
use everything. Okay. But if you don't
have data, you don't have a way to
improve. If you don't have a way to
improve, it's impossible.
>> Would you say that also what's super
important is to not only dissect the
data. So I just had uh someone on the
podcast actually who was a systematic
trader.
>> Okay.
>> Right. So he will take the data. So you
know from the CFD space you hear back
test. Yes. Everyone always thinks a bar
replay, right? You just go back in time,
press play, and then you know try and do
the whole risk reward as if it's live.
>> Well, he was saying how in systematic
trading back testing is essentially
taking all of the data. You have to do a
bit of coding. So you can use AI to do
the coding, etc.
>> And you there's he uses a program called
a polygon he said.
>> And essentially it will then spit out
based on the parameters he's asked for.
So let's say if he said price when it's
over VWAP or when it's already extended
he does micro cap stocks.
>> Yes.
>> Um small cap sorry.
>> So he'll be like okay price has done
100% gap and it's uh faded and the
volume's reducing stuff like this. And
then he'll put the input that into
polygon. It will give him the
statistics.
>> Amazing.
>> You know on 9 years worth of data, four
years worth of data. Yes.
>> And then he now has rules around his
trading. So the trading is if a or you
know if ABC execute manage and so on. So
all the decisions are based off
systematic which was interesting though
because he goes it has obviously its
pros but then it had you know by
sticking systematic he had a you know a
good few years of a of a rough time and
he had to
>> overfeitting a little bit.
>> Yeah. And then he had to introduce some
discretion and some of the intuition.
This is important because also Jim
Simmons was saying that completely
systematic edge have a lot of edge
decay. What does it mean that they the
system breaks so fast?
>> My strong point on this is that I do
analysis, I trade. I know that the model
is adapt to every market condition. So
if I'm not trend following, I don't
trade. Okay. I put the power of machine
learning on my data that is
discretionary. I have the best of both
worlds. Yeah. So this is the reason I I
had also a portfolio of system then I
start notice every month now the system
four system broke out of 20 replace them
replace them replace them I saw the
profit factor I compare with mine and
say it's not worth to trade quant for me
of course if you are sittel the market
making it's worth of course. [laughter]
So how many different portfolios or sort
of trading accounts and and systems do
you have? I have a lot because I
diversify them by edge. For example,
this one is hyper scalping. Okay. If I
want to do intraday trading, I use
another portfolio because I need to
track independent data otherwise I
cannot do all the research. Option model
it's on another broker. It's Charles
Schwab also. Andrea Charles Schwab, we
have separate account for everything we
need to do. Crypto I don't want to
publish any crypto exchange or brokerage
but I do on another field holding ledger
like
>> I separate like if it's a different
business model no
>> like I don't want the data from deep
charts to merge with the data of workass
edge
>> of course
>> because I don't have clear margin I
don't have clear execution like people
that trade everything in one account for
me it's it's unefficient okay
>> so I I have separate account. I have the
option account. I have the futures order
flow crypto scalping. I have the
long-term investment. I have the stock
picking account. I have like I love to
create models. Okay. I have the NASDAQ
scalping. I have the NASDAQ intraday and
I diversify capital.
>> Okay. Uh this is 15,000 only on this
model.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay. The option model is making 8,000.
The crypto scalping with the runup is
making another 9,000. This is
compounding. Mhm.
>> The only thing that I I don't accept is
to put a model that is not beating the
sharp ratio or compare with the sharp
ratio of the other because if you put a
distribution and if you see that you
have six models with an amazing sharp
ratio and profit factor and you say
let's put another model just to
diversify but the sharp ratio is here
it's not worth for me. So I have like a
gaus distribution of the edge with all
the edge that I put in the market
>> and I optimize and always monitor them.
If a model is not profitable anymore I
remove and all the other one recover the
loss that the model did. It's it's an
amazing ecosystem
you know but still the most profitable
one is NASDAQ. There is nothing
comparable to order flow scalping for me
also on crypto is extremely profitable
but nothing algorithmic of option comes
close to this.
>> Okay. So when it comes to the crypto is
that uh when you say that's profitable
is that the long-term investing or is
that even the do you do like the futures
trading?
>> Imagine like imagine like this
I use the futures order for scalping
crypto as income.
>> Mhm. I use this income to funnel in my
long-term account.
>> The long-term account does only
arbitrage.
>> Yeah.
>> And investment. Okay. Arbitrage is
getting profit for small inefficiency.
Okay. It's quant
>> and is making not a huge amount of
money. It's making 20 to 30% but market
neutral. And then on top of that I have
a complete understanding of presidential
cycles, albein cycles, intermarket
correlation to know exactly when to
allocate capital. Like if I expect that
ripple will
>> uh overperform Bitcoin in the short term
like what I did I put 40% of the
portfolio in Ripple. It went to $1.2 to
3.5. I liquidated put it back in
Bitcoin. You know this is the the stuff
that I do. I'm always active on this and
it's purely based on data. I analyze uh
onchain data.
On top of that, all the profit that I
made with crypto sculping, orderflow
goes back in these accounts. So, they
grow long term. The pro the daily profit
that I withdraw monthly is funneling
here. So, I have one ecosystem, crypto
ecosystem.
>> Then I have the orderflow ecosystem,
NASDAQ intraday model, NASDAQ scalping
model and options. Okay. Because options
can be also intraday. They can be zero
DT.
>> Yeah.
>> And now we are building all kind of
model with Andrea that they are crazy
model. There are models that can yield
80%. Okay. Per year. It's huge. Of
course, the problem is still liquidity.
You can do with 5 10 million. You cannot
do with 100. Then you have the long-term
investing. So like stock picking. So
what I do in stock I'm giving a lot of
edge guys. Uh so on stock picking what I
do I build um on my own rules that can
predict which stock is going to
overperform the market. Now everyone
will say no it's impossible. So it's
possible. Okay. What I do is that I
exploit one inefficiency of the market.
What is this inefficiency? Congressmen
of US
>> they have information. This information
is not getting punished because they are
allowed to do insider trading. So if
they are allowed to do insider trading,
>> I'm allowed to use their trades as
information because it's completely
legal. It's public available
information. Not public you need data
sources, but you can work your way
through on this. I put my earnings
model. So now what I'm doing, I'm
getting the trades of the most powerful
people on the planet, but I'm timing
better than them using earnings model on
intraday gap.
>> It's going crazy amazing. like the the
track record uh on the brokerage it's
now we have also to say that S&P 500 and
stocks are expanding but still I run
extensive test is profitable also in um
rough times where the stock market goes
down because you go on the defensive you
go on like it's I love to do it this is
the the most funny models that I have
because you need also to understand why
they are buying so maybe you see the
politician that buys I will not make
name the politician that buys is three
millions with private account or one
pharmaceutical company. After two months
they approve the stage four of the
company. So you see like 200 300%.
>> This is something that from my side is
not ethical that they can do this
because they have a role in approval of
this stuff.
But not using this kind of information
is unethical for my side. Why? because
these are public information. So if you
are a trader, your role is to get always
the most informed player of the market.
If I ignore this data, I will stay
behind all the people that use this
data.
>> Yeah,
>> this is my stock model. It's a little
bit complicated. There are four model
running at the same time,
>> but it's it's profitable.
>> How do you manage all these things then?
How do you track and manage all these
different portfolio? like the stock
model is so easy because I go through it
on Sundays. Okay. So I prepare and do
everything on this on one day of the
week. It takes one hour, two hours
because already the AI is doing a huge
work on this aggregating data. I have my
own platform that I built through the
years that is making all these analysis.
uh the option model Andrea and the Rico
that is one of my mentor built structure
that you can do with 10 uh 10 minutes
per day. Yeah.
>> Only in the evening only in um I was
saying something that I cannot say only
in certain time of the day only certain
time of the day and they have a huge
profit factor and uh is not getting your
time is not getting too much of your
time. Yeah. Okay. So the models that
take the most of my time is NASDAQ
scalping, but it's also the most
profitable one. So also in time
allocation, you need to understand.
Okay.
>> And in the weekend when I'm bored on
Saturday, I do crypto order flow because
we need to work like we need to
>> we reach the level.
>> Yeah, we were watching in the
background. I say should we do like a
recap of what's happened here? So what
happened here is that from the level of
absorption that we were watching they
contracted back to the level that we
were waiting that is the triple a setup
based on absorption from here it's a
little bit early but in 2 hours you can
expect that from here they recumulate
and go up okay
>> and we will check how it goes
>> but it's you see already they are really
struggling I don't know if it's visible
but they are really struggling to go
down
>> it's the first time where they reach one
level
>> and why They are struggling because this
level is packed with aggressive buyers.
>> Yes.
>> Okay. Now they will start the they will
touch the closing of the structure and
this is where you can expect a lot of
aggressive sellers interacting.
>> Yeah.
>> And buyers trying to protect. Okay. So
here you want to see
>> buyers stepping in to protect. If you
don't see it done for the day and it's
not done. You see for example here I
will never execute. They are controlling
aggressive aggressive aggressive
aggressive. This is like the momentum by
that we took. [snorts]
>> Buyers are trying from here to stop the
movement. Now if you get a complete
absorption of the movement, you can try
like you were saying the expansion up.
Got
you you can uh you can try this trade.
But the problem is that you have a
really big stop loss. So maybe you can
cover here. I will I will not execute
it. I will only put the marker.
>> Yeah. to show like if you put 10
contract here.
Okay. At the break of this high.
Okay. So at the break of this high this
trap buyers Mhm.
>> you can execute. You have
10 contract for a
2,500 is too much. We need to lower the
size. We need to go on eight
eight contracts.
So now you're risking exactly 2,000.
Okay. If you break this level, you have
this play. You can cover also below here
by putting lower size. But already you
cannot execute. You see control of the
sellers again buyers. So the triple A
setup didn't present themselves today.
Anyway,
>> getting back to that question from way
earlier. If you held your trade
>> like imagine
>> a pain
>> imagine we arrive here.
>> So we closed here and then build another
position.
Now all the profit that we took it's
almost zero.
>> Yeah. So we go back to the question like
is it worth it if you have a really high
rate? But honestly I do a lot of talent
scouting like if I see someone that is
profitable I always took the time to
jump in a call with him and understand
his edge because maybe in its capital
maybe in its direction
but I've never seen I've never seen an
edge that is adding at the same time a
lot of we rate and a lot of riskreward.
One needs to be sacrificed. Yeah. And I
mean not in one month but I mean on 12
months. Okay.
>> So you cannot have 1 to 20 risk to
reward with 75% if you have call me
because you are soon billionaire. You
are soon billionaire.
>> But you need to to choose what you want.
Okay. From my side I prefer a balance.
>> Mhm.
>> Good win rate good riskto-reward.
In this case we would have close
probably also in loss because with this
then it cut all the profit of the
previous one.
>> Exactly. you are uh like we were we were
attacking now the profit of London
session
>> it's really bad it's better to
>> take profit
>> and again just to really reiterate and
get that point home that's why I asked
the question to really see the reality
Fabio if we weren't here in the studio
trying to make this video and to
showcase live trading you would have
been done after that first trade
>> right or the first setup trade that
first movement
>> the the directional one that was 1 to8.
Yeah,
>> the momentum one we closed 25,000 for
the day is done. But I'm really happy
that we took this trade
>> because the audience can now understand
and frame which kind of condition is not
yielding a profit for the strategy.
>> So contraction
>> that's the reason we only trade here and
here. Exactly.
>> Okay. Yeah.
>> So, it's uh I think with the previous
one, this episode and the ones that are
going in my channel, they have a master
class that outside will cost at least
$10,000 that is totally free.
>> Mhm.
>> You can study, you can try with press
because this model, the good part is
that they work also on price action.
Like if you know what is an expansion
phase and contraction, you can for
example wait for the recovery of the top
and get the expansion higher. You are
not for, this is what I want to enforce,
you are not forced to use volume. I use
volume because it helps me to
understand. But for example, for forex,
it's useless because volume is so
fragmented in 1,000 OTC sources. If you
trade Euro dollar, British pound, it's
better intermarket analysis. Yeah,
>> you watch Euro dollar, you understand
the pressure of British pound, you
understand the dollar and you have a
context of accumulation phase,
distribution phase, you see maybe they
spike a hello, they failed, what does it
mean? There is an absorption you can
understand by price this stuff. Okay,
but volume on indices and on
commodities,
>> it's amazing.
And one thing I was going to ask
actually in terms of handling all these
different portfolios, you're trading
obviously weekdays, NASDAQ, hypers
scalping, your Saturday sometimes when
you're bored trading crypto, you got the
portfolios, etc.
>> What's the reality for you in terms of
your, you know, outside of when we see
you in the studio, outside of your
trading windows, like how are you
operating? Do you have to set up your
whole life to facilitate peak
performance? This is something that I
was hoping that you would ask guys.
There is no coconut uh with straw on the
beach. Uh I I moved to Palm View at the
moment. I have one of the best view.
I've never been to the beach. We have a
private beach. I've never been to the
beach. Why? Because this kind of
lifestyle is sacrificing. I'm not only
saying, "Okay, you have money. You
cannot." No, because now I go home. I
need to prepare. I have lives. saying to
prepare the long-term setup. It's a it's
a lifestyle. It's like a bodybuilder.
Okay? They build their life around their
work. I built my life around my work. I
have something that I cannot sacrifice.
I cannot go out drinking, drifting with
Ferrari and the day later I wake up at
10 because I have stuff to do in the
morning. And the only way to manage this
life is being completely
with obsessive compulsive disorder
disorder on organizing stuff. Everything
needs to be a clock. Okay? Because if
you stop
>> organizing this way, confusion will
overcome you because you are managing
multiple models, multiple company, you
are at the same time trying to have a
little bit of private life because your
family wants to see you. Something like
this. So, it's um it's draining and this
is the reason I want to go on long-term
low commitment model options because my
capital is getting really high at the
moment. For a retail, it's it's really
high and I I know that I can already
retire like I'm 30 years old. I can
retire the next 5 to 10 with an amazing
life without staying all the afternoon
in the chart. It's what I love, but it's
draining doing this every day. It's
really stressful, specifically scalping.
And uh I know that I will never stop at
least to to watch because I love the
market. I love the market.
>> But um like it's not the life that
people expect. Okay? They expect you
make your first one, two, three million,
you walk away and you only enjoy life.
If you do this, inflation will up
all the money that you have made and
your life will be like this only for one
or two years and then you will go back
to the rat race.
>> Yeah. And uh it's a lifestyle. It's a
lifestyle that I love. It's not heavy
for me. Working is something that
empowers me and make me feel productive
and it's not heavy for me at all. It
would have been to break even now.
>> Exactly. Yeah.
>> So we we would have lost all the profit
uh for the day. So this is an amazing
lesson on how to manage also your
position. This is an amazing lesson.
It was incredible honestly to see the
speed and I think you did a phenomenal
job of explaining what you were doing as
you were doing it because I remember the
you know uh when we had discussed on the
the last child fanatics we said that
this isn't live trading because
>> you know live trading I need to be
logged in. So I was actually expecting
me to kind of narrate or whilst you're
trading and then when there was an
opportunity to pause then talk about it
but you managed to to do both. If we
didn't had to explain everything that I
was doing here with this position, I
would have loaded another 10.
>> So, we could have made 40,000 on the way
up. But doing this in is that you load
two contract at every breakout. It's
impossible to do this. Manage the stop
loss at the same time explaining what
you do. But there are more aggressive
way of management that on this movement
could have made a $40,000 day and also
on the momentum. But it's just
impossible to trade, explain, watch the
camera like it's it's not doable. But I
hope that they understood my model and
they understood
>> how how it is that I work every day.
>> Definitely. And the one interesting
thing actually just to frame as well
before coming here today when Fabio we
were planning to just do a normal
podcast and Fabio mentioned why don't we
do this? Why don't we trade this
session? I know and we love it as well.
>> But he did say like look at the end of
the day I'll trade live capital. I'll
trade my fun personal account and I will
win or lose. I don't we'll just do it.
You know, even if I lose on the day,
we'll still put it out.
>> Uh if I win on the day, we'll put it
out. And I was happy as well, even
though we, you know, for the recording
still continued to trade and we took
some losses there.
>> I'm happy that we kept that in there.
I'm happy that we did that. And that's
why I asked you that question like, how
do you feel after taking those losses?
Because in my head, I'm like, oh no,
we've taken losses. We need to win. But
that's me.
>> Oh, right. I don't know. It's it's like
in my head I came here saying to Andrea,
I hope that we will have a draw down
session. Why? Because
you can teach 10 times more stuff if you
have a rough session. This is the reason
on my channel is coming the worst
session of the month. Okay? If
everything was good, you don't have to
explain. But getting a reason why we
stop executing trades when this move
happened. Okay? and seeing that when
this move happened exactly was the top
of the day is letting them understand
that you know when is the moment to to
stop okay you are not like we are still
in profit 15,000 if we risk on this way
down after the break the short from here
that I was sure was coming here okay
>> on this one I will zoom
>> from this movement aggressive sellers
stop we could we could make this
movement risk 5,000 of the 15,000 close
at 30 40,000 but still I will do
something for ego
I will not do something because it's my
model.
>> So what I show you is the raw reality of
trading. I took profit and I took
stop-loss. This is the real Fabio. This
is the real trading. There is no sugar
coating. There is no let's do five
session and load the best one. No,
>> we we don't we don't do this stuff and I
think they h ah anyway we have a London
session of yesterday that was amazing
that we will share with chart fanatic
and was something like this but done in
London
>> without needing to explain because I can
comment later so managing super fast and
I made like 10,000 risking 1,500
>> incredible
>> so was was really an amazing one
>> absolutely incredible do you know in
terms of uh the reality Now, do you ever
have times where you break your rules or
go until or revenge trade or go outside
of your system?
>> It's really difficult because I know the
price the price of breaking the rules
like uh in my setup in uh
>> Mhm.
>> in uh in my trading station at home.
There is um there is one quote that is
either you respect the rules, either you
pay the price. And I have a screenshot
of the statistical model on Python of
how much I lose when I break the rules.
Okay? So it's always there with me. And
when you see me, we are live. We can
risk 15,000 close the day 100,000 six
figures in one day every no because I
know that if today I give back this
15,000, tomorrow if I lose 10,000 in
session, I will I will be in loss. I
will not have the the amazing week. Like
in the week we are 60,000 in profit in
three days. We still have two days to
go. It qualify to be a six figures week.
Why I need to break the rules for ego to
show it's not worth it. At home I don't
do it. There is only one time that I did
was last year because I had a really
difficult situation at home. Uh I
received a really bad news and I was not
with mental clarity to to manage. I took
full responsibility for what I did. I
get back on track and in one week I
recover everything.
>> But uh this loss is screenshot and it's
on my desk uh to remind me what happens
when I go go far from the rules. Because
if you have an edge but you don't
respect it, what's the reason of doing
all this work to build? Because building
an edge is the stuff. It's not trading
guys. Building an edge or building the
experience to have an edge is the real
work. Yes. So why not respecting rules
if you have this then you can also put
some rule to yourself. Okay. So for
example what we want to put in the
platform is to not be able to trade when
you get a trailing draw down for the
day. Like if you're profitable 40,000
you get minus 5 or 10 the platform block
you need to call the support and say
unlock my account because I want to
trade. This is something that is a
mechanical stop to the that you
can do. Okay.
But when you are professional, you don't
need stuff like this. You just need to
have an a conversation with yourself and
say, "Look,
for ego, I'm burning a $60,000 profit
week for for what? To to be able to be
right on the movement. Who cares?"
>> Mhm.
>> Like people on YouTube,
I understood something that is really
funny. Like one guy texted me and says
if you really want to give back to the
community you will sell a course. Say
look if you sell a course you are a
course seller. If you only trade you
only trade you don't care about the what
are people what a person need to do like
and giving everything for free study you
don't need to pay anything. So I
understood that
>> you will never be able to make everyone
happy in life. Okay. You will always
have haters. You will always have. So
the only thing you can do is stick to
your plan. If they like the plan, they
see the the reality of what trading is,
of course, they will be in the oh but I
trade stop run liquidation one to 100
you are not able to trade take the
critics and go on but don't trade for
eco because is what is burning your
account or don't trade to demonstrate
someone else that you are worth it
because this is what really destroy oh
they are also breaking the law they are
>> this is what I like here is that the
order flow is keeping you out of the
setup like a price action cont maybe
would have put the limit.
>> Yeah.
>> And inside here you see
>> higher high higher low. We're trying to
enter
>> super aggressive buyers absorbed. No
orderful trader will consider this. You
can consider the short to the value area
low and also this one would have been an
amazing trade.
>> Mhm.
>> Okay. So it's possible if we trade all
the session with capital to close 50 60
>> just not worth it because the risk is
that here you get another consolidation
like this and you are done. So even when
you you set your life up to operate and
be efficient, right? You make those
sacrifices. Let's say there's a day
where you've had a you know you're ill,
right? Or you've had a a bad night's
sleep or maybe something's happened.
>> I don't trade. It's not a problem.
>> Yeah. like I just walk away I don't
trade because also on this I have
metrics like when you trade and you are
not in a sharp remember that my edge is
discretional okay so if you are not
sharp you are tired you didn't sleep
good at night
>> you are putting your capital at risk
yeah
>> like the lack of focus can burn $20,000
$30,000 like when you work with a big
account you are paying big money for
errors
>> so just uh it's not I walk away. Look at
it's the the law of large number is
giving me an edge over 100. Like this
week was 120 execution. Okay. Over the
year I make 5,000 execution.
>> If I lose three or four trades, nothing
has changed. The performance will be
there. Maybe I'm lucky and I lose the
bad the bad day. and I so you know it's
just uh you have to consider that
>> allocate time allocation wise if you are
sick it's always better to not be at the
market always better to not be at the
market because the edge it's you
>> if you were a quant you make your system
run
>> so it's not a it's not a problem and
what do you do then actually for
downtime you know a lot of people
>> you know they they'll do the drinking
they'll do the partying they'll do you
know things like go on till the late
night. I love I love to create stuff
like for example recently I'm spending
30 minutes every evening evening
researching information and data and
aggregating them with alternative data
sources to understand if I can have an
edge informationational edge okay
creating this I I know I'm a nerd on
this but I I love to do it like I really
love to I really enjoy if they say look
today you cannot earn money with this
okay you only will live out of business
and other stuff I will still be here
every because I like to for me it's like
chess. People play chess not to be paid
but because it's stimulating their
brain.
>> Yeah.
>> For me financial markets is the big
chess board on the planet. You don't
have one opponent, you have the word
against you but it's it's so funny and
stimulating for me. And uh of course in
my free time I like to go with other
traders and friend that they are
stressed to spa to ba Russian ba and
stuff like this. But um I always have a
way to keep myself occupied and I'm not
a party guy. Like I don't like to
>> to go to do shopping, to go to do
partying. It's not for me. I've never
done this before I had money and I never
done this now that I have money. It's
just not fun for me. Okay. So
>> that's what I do. I prefer to spend some
time with friends and uh something chill
in the free time. But my free time is
really low to be honest places. There is
not a lot of free time. But also with
people see when people see that the
perception that they have of financially
free is really different from the truth
because be financially independent and
rich without working like it's really
hard if you start from zero like if your
father is not leaving you real estate
worth 50 million or 100 million. It's
really difficult. You always need al
also if you delegate your business a
little bit of interaction daily calls
weekly check it's necessary to run the
business. So getting a a different
perspective of what trading is a
professional one and how much sacrifice
you need to make to make this really
your profession. And I think it's
something that the industry really needs
at the moment because we we saw I I
don't like to make names and I will stay
on my own here because I already
received enough threat threatening. But
a lot of people
open white label accounts.
>> They forge track records and they make
money with everything except from
trading. Okay? They make money with the
surrounding of trading but not from the
market. Okay? The real skill is able to
making money by understanding and
predicting what the market will do next
and adapting. And finding a real traders
that is also willing to do this publicly
or willing to share with you in real
time is something that I've never found
when I was trying to learn the
profession. Okay. If you if you want to
study for example medicine, you go to a
real doctor and you have a university.
But if you want to be a real traders out
there, you you find a lot of fake gurus.
M. So it's you also don't have expect
you don't know which expectation to set.
If people continue to sell get rich with
$1,000, people will believe this is
possible.
>> Yeah.
>> So the problem is not the expectation of
the people, but it's also the
communication of the industry.
>> That's very true. And
>> in terms of your personal journey, you
mentioned earlier having a mentor.
>> Um like what did that look like for you
in terms of trading education? Did you
do a lot of self-eing? Was there mentors
that helped you? Like what did that look
like for you and how did you pick your
mentors?
>> I took a mentor in the moment that I was
already making a lot of money and I was
I wanted to scale with edge with one
person that was managing a family office
of a lot of money. I cannot say the
amount but was okay. So I took a mentor
because I want to
>> be able to diversify from the model that
I have and get models that run without
me. So I took a mentor on different
market of op on options but on order
flow I never had a mentor because what I
did is spending weeks watching price and
understanding in my brain what I can
expect after I see every move. Okay,
it's pattern recognition. The difference
is just that people do with this with
candles. I do this with deeper
information inside candles. But I think
if you put if you put someone and you
say look watch this for one month
>> don't execute sooner or later they will
we start to see that certain pattern of
order for an edge now you have a model
>> start to execute on a demo plot this in
a statistical distribution now you are a
trader
>> yeah okay
>> you can't avoid the work right that most
people try
>> that is the reason I don't sell a course
because I can give you the best
knowledge I I I want I can give you the
best but if you don't put the effort
it's like people signing up for gym
never going expecting to lose weight by
not going like you cannot pay for
something and get transfer we are not in
matrix where you put the and then you
get knowledge okay you need to to do the
the lift
>> and I need to say that 99% of people
they want something ready they want the
YouTube strategy 99% we rate with moving
coverage. Okay. And this is the comments
that I usually get on my channel and
they say why you need to over complicate
this because financial markets are
complicated because it's
multiple information they are exchanging
in darkpole. You have order flow. You
have options. If you want to make this a
50 200 that cross moving average model,
good luck on the good luck.
>> I love it. We're coming to the end now.
It's been such an incredible episode, a
very unique episode of Words of Wisdom
for sure. Um, just to finish off, I'd
love you for you to talk to the audience
like just give them your best advice in
terms of scaling their journey as a
trader, you know, no matter where
they're at, whether they're a beginner,
maybe you can give different advices
based on where they're at, but but
beginner to intermediate to advanced.
Uh, like what would your message to the
trading audience and community out there
be? Okay. So
to the one that are starting and to the
one that are scaling,
don't put capital at risk before you are
able to measure your edge. Measure your
edge. Either it is algorithmical, either
it is with a trading journal. Get your
statistics ready. Be able to understand
your draw down, your profit factor,
because these metrics are the one that
you will want to check when you are in
draw down. And if you don't have
something that is backing what you are
doing, you will start to say, "I'm just
gambling." Trading can get like gambling
if you don't have an edge. So start in a
way that is protecting yourself before
risking real money. Do all the work
necessary before that you put real
capital at risk. So in the moment that
you put real capital at risk, you will
not lose money for ego but you will lose
money only for the retracement of the
market for your model but you will be
profitable in long term. The difficult
part guys is not trading. The difficult
part is the patience and the work that
you need to put to become a profitable
trader with edge building. From this
moment it's all on the upside and check
your expectation. You cannot get rich
with a small account. You cannot try to
flip your account. Real trading is based
on risk management. Don't check the
return. Check the draw down and base the
model that you use based on the draw
down, not on the return. Because if you
are not doing this, probably you will
never check the return. You will only
check the draw down and you will have a
huge risk of ruin.
>> I love that Fabio. Thank you again for
being the one to suggest this first of
all, but doing this again for us and
trading live today with your own
personal capital. you know, you don't
have to do this. You don't get any
benefit other than the benefit you're
giving to the community and the
feedback, no doubt. And uh, you know, on
behalf of everyone who's watched this
episode, all of your episodes, and the
last Chartan episode, we want to say a
massive thank you for showcasing this
and opening a a new door to a level of
transparency that wasn't in the industry
before, I would say. And I think most
would agree. Everyone at home, drop a
comment with your biggest takeaway from
this unique episode. It's absolutely
crazy. It blows my mind every single
time. I actually have to do like deep
thinking afterwards like what just
happened. But links for Fabio will be in
the description below. Check out
obviously Deep Charts as well, the
Ordero platform that as Fabio said has
put in so much time on their end, but
also gotten feedback from some of the
best traders in the world. So, it's
going to be an absolutely world-class
platform as well. And that's just me
saying that. So, sorry if it gets a bit
awkward in me doing that in front of
you. But, um, but yeah, hit subscribe,
hit like. Other episodes are on screen
and until next time, take care.