I pray for many things. I prayed for
this $5 mansion. I prayed for a family
that I love and a day trading strategy
that wins trades. All these things are
similar in that they require constant
attention, but when I put the work in
and follow the two steps of the
strategy, I'm rewarded. So today, I'm
going to teach you the one day trading
strategy I'll use for the entire year
with live trade examples. Now, I never
promise future trading results or $5
million mansions, but if this helps you
at all, please smash that like button,
subscribe to the channel, and let's dive
in.
I live trade this strategy every day and
I even back tested it 1,000 times to a
win rate of 79.45%.
My community trades the exact same
strategy manually and using my trading
robot, and here is some of their results
from the past week including some prop
firm passes. And this really all comes
down to two steps. Step one,
displacement orbs, and step two, session
analysis, which is how I avoid dumb
losses. And every open range breakout
trader should already know this. But
let's start with step one. I'm trading
the New York session only looking at the
first 15-minute candle of the New York
Stock Exchange open. That candle goes
down, it goes up, and then it's done.
Then all I'm doing is marking out that
candle high, marking out that candle
low, and this is the trading range for
my trading session. To get the time
right, come to the bottom right here.
Make sure you're on New York time. Then
I'm changing time frames to the
five-minute time frame, and I'm looking
for an impulsive move out the top or the
bottom of the range with some big
candles that create some actual
displacement in the market. You could
see we're getting that push up right
here, and I want to see a candle
closure. You could see the candle closes
right here. If a candle just wicks out
and doesn't close, it doesn't count. And
if the move doesn't have these big
strong candles like this, it doesn't
count because it's not going to create
the displacement we need. Now, in that
aggressive push up, I want to see the
creation of a level of demand or even a
fair value gap because those are my
entry models. I'll show you the fair
value gap after. And this makes a
displacement orb. So in order to have a
valid demand, we've got one, two, three,
four green candles in a row. You want to
have three or four big green candles in
a row. You want to see recent structure
get broken. See, this price took out
this high. Ideally, have a couple of
these fair value gaps, and I draw the
demand zone on the red candle here
before the big push up just like an
order block. At this point, I'm simply
waiting for price to come back to that
level of demand and give me some sort of
a reaction. Right here, we have two
wicks. It's respecting demand. That's a
good sign. But I really like it when
price prints an engulfing candle
pattern. So you could see this candle
right here is engulfed by this candle
right here. It has the bigger body.
We're not looking at the wicks. And so
when that candle closes with the
engulfing, that's where I'm going to
enter my trading position. Generally,
I'm putting my stop loss below the level
of demand, even if it's a big demand.
And then I've got to figure out my
target. You know, 1.5, 1.6. Try to get a
good risk-reward ratio. Now, just a note
before I play out the trade. You see
that bullish engulfing candle pattern
right there. This is rare. It doesn't
always happen. A lot of the time, I'm
just entering when I see the demand zone
holding. So if you're doing some back
testing, don't get frustrating if you
don't see this get printed every single
time. Now, let's play out the trading
position. You can see we got a good
reaction off of that level of demand.
Wicket into it one more time and then
price started to push up. As I expand
the trade right there, you could see we
keep getting green candles and do smash
that take profit efficiently. Now,
before I get into the second entry
model, comment anything below for your
chance to win one of five free slots to
my VIP room. Last week, I gave out six.
Now, let's get into that second example
and then I'll teach you how I avoid dumb
losses using session analysis along with
a live trade. So we're still in step one
here, but I'm going to show you the
second entry model, and I'm going to
introduce you to an indicator. So come
click on indicators right here. I want
you to type opening range, and you're
going to select breakouts with targets.
Then come up here to settings. Tick this
off. Make sure this is at UTC-5,
9:30 to 9:45, and you'll see it's going
to mark out the range for you. So this
is our range for the day, and I'm
already on the five-minute time frame.
And then what do we want? We want that
big impulsive move. We want that candle
closure. And on this one, we have a
level of demand right here, but we also
have a fair value gap right here. So we
had that nice displacement right there,
and now I'm waiting for price to come
back to my level. It comes back to the
level. It looks like it's respecting
that fair value gap, right? So we're
just taking a look at that. And then
what do we get? The bullish engulfing
pattern gets printed right there. So at
this point, my level held. We're not
coming down to demand. I could get into
a long position right here. On a trade
like this, I'll have my stop loss around
the midline. You could put it below the
fair value gap. I'll have it around the
midline here. And on this one, I'm going
to target around 2%, maybe 2.2%,
something like this because the market
structure has been very, very strong. So
I'm expecting that push up. Let's go
ahead and play that trade out. See what
happens. Respected the fair value gap.
Smashed the take profit. Went even
higher than I expected. Very solid. But
in order to get a win rate anywhere
close to 79%,
this is where step two session analysis
is so important. Let me teach it to you
now. Now, the market moves in very
predictable ways depending on the time
of day. The Asian session ranges. The
London session pushes. And the New York
session reverses. And I'm always looking
for this exact same pattern every single
day to make sure that I'm placing my
trades in the right direction. Let's
break down why this happens. The Asian
session simply doesn't have a lot of
volume because there's no real market
makers trading within the Asian range.
But then we come into the London session
and the big players are starting to make
moves which creates our London session
push down. This is generally a swing in
one direction or the other. And then the
final session of the day, the New York
session where I do most of my trading.
This is where I see the best trading
opportunities. A ton of volume comes
into the markets and that's where we
frequently see this reversal. So if the
London session is bearish, I'm looking
for the New York session to be bullish.
Now, this doesn't happen every single
day, but it does give us an edge
especially as orb traders. Now, before I
take us into the chart examples, let me
explain why this really happens. It's
all about liquidity. You see right here
the Asian session is ranging creating
liquidity above and below this level. So
I expect price to be pulled above and
below this level as price attempts to
seek out and sweep this liquidity in the
markets. Now, in this case, you could
see the London session starts, sweeps
the Asian session high, and uses the
momentum for the London session push. It
then sweeps out the low and uses that
momentum for the New York reversal. And
I'm often using these levels for targets
as well. They're very simple targets. So
if we sweep the high, I could target
this level right here. And then if we
come and sweep the low, I could target
this level right here and start scaling
out of my positions. Now, I'm going to
make this even easier. Let's jump to the
charts. Now, I'm on the charts. I'm
doing this on the 15-minute time frame.
Let me show you with real examples. You
could see we have our Asian session
right here. That's our Asian session
range. Then price takes liquidity. We
get the London session push. Then we
sweep the Asia highs right here, and we
get the New York session reversal with a
fair value gap right there and an easy
trade right here. All right, let's move
to the next day, okay? Let's take a
look. What does the next day look like?
We have our Asian session range. Price
comes below in the London session,
right? We get that London session push
right there sweeping liquidity. Then we
get the New York session reversal. It
doesn't come to the top of the Asian
range because hey, that was a pretty big
move. It's not going to make a huge move
like that every single day. And I'm not
even cherry-picking. Let's just move to
the next day. What does it look like?
Let's take a look. We've got a bigger
Asian session range this time. We had a
pretty big move, but we do still get the
London session push coming into the New
York session. Sweep liquidity below this
level, and then we get the New York
session reversal. And the New York
session reversal does take liquidity out
at the top. So at this level right here,
we have again another obvious level of
entry. And do that with the orb, and
we're absolutely cooking, right? But
sometimes you don't get the reversal.
Let's take a look at this example right
here. Asian session range. Liquidity
gets taken out at the top in the London
session. We get the London session push,
and it also sweeps the liquidity out the
bottom of that Asian range. And in those
cases where London takes out the top and
the bottom, I frequently see
continuation. So instead of the New York
session reversal here, we got a little
bit of a pullback, and we had
continuation. Now, how do I combine step
one and step two? I'll show you in a
live orb trade example right now. We're
at the end here. Let's go through a live
trade. We have the Asian session range
right here. We get the London session
push. I'm on the 5-minute time frame
right now, and then I'm looking for the
New York session reversal. So, based on
this pattern, I'm looking for buys right
now. So, let's zoom in a little bit
right here and see what's going on.
Well, what do we have? We have the top
of the range and the bottom of the
range, right? Now, we're looking kind of
at that step one, the early part of the
lesson. And so, what are we looking for
from this range? Well, we're looking for
something like that. We're looking for
an impulsive move like this one,
creating a level of demand, right? The
red candle before the big push up, and
then I'm waiting for price to come back
to that level, right? What am I doing?
I'm waiting for price to come back to
that level. I've got to get myself into
a trade. Now, we didn't really get the
bullish engulfing right there, but our
level is clearly being respected, and
you're almost never going to have every
single one of these confluences line up.
So, as price breaks out of the demand,
that's something I'll use as well to get
into a trading position. I'll put my
stop loss below the demand right here,
and then I'll let my trade play out,
targeting the previous level that price
just reached. Will we be able to get
there? I hope so, and there it is,
smashing the take profit right there. We
could play this out a little bit further
to see how we would have done. We would
have done even better. So, let's zoom
back out here. Let's put this on the
15-minute time frame. We had the Asian
session range. We had the London session
push, sweeping the liquidity below the
bottom of the range, and then we had the
New York session reversal right there as
price continued to push up. Now, it
didn't come all the way to the top of
the range again. That was a big
distance, but it's very possible price
will still seek out the liquidity above
that Asian range as it frequently does.
Now, again, you're not always going to
get the perfect supply and demand or
fair value gap setup. There's tons of
ways to enter ORB trades, as I've shown
in all my ORB videos on my channel, so
make sure to watch those. Consider
joining my VIP trading room or picking
up a copy of my Trade with Pat Robot
that trades this exact strategy
automatically. Leave a comment, smash
the like button. I'll be back next week.
Much love.