okay today I'm going to do my version of
a raw reality video obviously this is a
little bit higher production but it's
not my normal like dark techie setup we
got the charts on the screen we got the
black background all the cool stuff um
this is just in my living room yeah I
like to do it a little higher production
than most people do their raw realities
I could have done my iPhone but it is
what it is I like the I like the higher
quality but I want to talk about the my
version of the raw reality of trading
and maybe some things that influencer or
Educators don't talk about in the
trading space or maybe just some things
that you didn't realize and you only
will realize when you've been doing it
for so long I think maybe what a lot of
influencers and Educators don't talk
about or teach is that this just truly
takes time like regardless of the
strategy that they're going to teach you
in these 21 days in these 7 Days in
these three months you got to get the
chart time in there is no getting around
that there is no getting around the fact
that you have to just have experience
with the charts you got to put the chart
time in and I'm talking like not a month
not a few weeks if if I had to say my
raw reality version I'd say it's got to
be like between one and three years to
where you are comfortable confident in a
system that you have mastered like I
think three years is fair I know that's
not a fun you know thing to hear that
you may not be successful or profitable
or consistent or confident in the
strategy that you're trading until 3
years that just kind of hurts to hear
but it's it's like my raw reality of it
I didn't find consistency until year
three or year before and my reasoning
behind that was it could be very
different than yours mine was the fact
that I just wasn't even consistent with
trading at all I don't I don't think I
actually believed in it I didn't trade
every day I wasn't looking at the charts
every day I'd take weeks off at a time
there would be you know months where I'm
just looking at the charts maybe one to
two times a month not even trading just
looking at the charts and then I'm
distracted and doing something else so
it's it's very enticing to see the
results that a lot of Traders have um
after they have been trading for so long
it the results that I have see easy but
it took me 9 years to get to this point
now it's not that I had to struggle for
9 years I had consistency and
profitability you know after year three
or year four but to be able to go into
the markets put 20 contracts in Platinum
come out with $30,000 a week later that
took 9 years that took confidence that
took Capital that took experience like
those whole nine years it it took that
long for me to be able to do something
like I am now whereas it may look so
much easier to you you're like she just
hopped in hopped out 30k I could do that
no I don't think you could the amount of
times that Platinum pulled back and I
was in draw down had to you know stomach
through those the possibility of
solidifying a loss I don't know if many
of you guys could do that that's and
that's I say that with love that it took
me nine years to be able to stomach
pullbacks like that and draw down like
that whereas a lot of you guys would
probably be you know cut the loss right
there or maybe try to go in and out and
in and out and trying to just chase the
price instead of just truly letting it
do its thing and letting go my motto
with trading is don't know don't care so
I'm now obvious obviously there is a
little bit of care in there but it's
it's the fact that my strategy does all
the work for me so I truly have to just
don't know don't care and let the
strategy do its thing so I would say my
point on the the time that actually
takes to become consistent and
profitable and to maybe a point of just
success in trading I'm going to say
honestly 3 to four years like we'll say
three maybe because now there's prop
firms where you can build Capital
there's um a lot more knowledge and
education in the space you have more
access to to mentors and education so
and communities so I would say we we're
talking 3 years 3 years until you can
realistically see profitability and
consistency okay and the next point that
I want to make in this raw reality video
is starting with small Capital it is so
freaking hard it is so hard now this the
thing that the things that I'm about to
say may feel and sound very harsh but
like I just keep going back to this is
my raw reality if you are coming into
trading thinking that you're going to
turn $100 into 5,000 10,000 100,000 I
don't believe that's going to work I
don't I'm sorry if you don't come into
trading if you are an adult who is you
know ready to take this seriously and
you're trying to truly become successful
at trading and you don't have at least
like $3 to $5,000 worth of savings that
you can be comfortable with losing and
investing I don't think trading is for
you that's that's a harsh thing to hear
but I think realistically you've got to
have like $3 to $5,000 of capital to get
started and that's after you have you
know educated yourself in trading after
you've simulated after you've got a
strategy down now let's go in with this
$3 to $5,000 worth of capital and
actually give this a go and even still
so these statistics are still not in
your favor even if you do invest $3 to
$5,000 the odds of you making it are
still pretty slim so it's it's such a
tough thing to hear that I should be
able to make you know I should be able
to put in a 100 bucks and get to 5,000
or get to a th000 even or get to 10,000
and I just don't think that's realistic
I don't think that's going to happen the
the odds are not in your favor and
especially with a smaller account it
takes 10 times more effort to build that
Capital so I would say raw reality of
becoming successful in trading and
actually building Capital you're looking
at like $3 to $5,000 minimum to start
and you got to be comfortable with that
all going away okay but touching back on
the the harsh truth of if you don't have
5,000 or 3 to $55,000 saved up you maybe
already got some work to do outside of
trading like if you can't develop a
system or a budget to where you can set
aside money every week every month that
goes into a savings account that you're
going to use for who knows what to
further your education to put in
Investments to learn how to trade I
think you're messing up you're not in
the right category of Finance if you
can't even save $3 to $5,000 just to
have as an emergency fund as an adult I
don't think you're in the right space so
that is my my harsh kind of raw reality
for that question that I always get in
trading can you start with $100 you can
but the odds of you being successful and
building that Capital are going to be
very slim okay and another point that I
have for my raw reality is trading comes
down to the trader and I think that we
all May know this collectively but we
don't actually you know give it its we
don't give it credit we know that
there's plenty of strategies out there
there's plenty people can trade with
moon phases indicators people can trade
with trend lines people can trade with
Fibonacci ICT SMC I think those are one
of the same Elliot waves pyramids there
are so many different ways to trade so
why is everyone either successful or
unsuccessful in their own way all
trading these different strategies and
it comes down to the person if you don't
have discipline if you are not
consistent with One Singular strategy if
you can't master whichever one you
decide to go with I think it's all on
the person I've learned how to trade in
my family and I was taught by my uncle
he taught many of us in the family he
taught my sister he taught his sons his
daughter cousins family friends I mean
he's taught as many people that ask
they're like listen I want to learn what
you do show me and not many of us made
it to be honest I think I may be the
only one and is it it's got to be
because of me because he taught us all
the same thing I think I was just
consistent I was I was determined I was
like I'm this has to work I had like
such a such tunnel vision when it came
to trading I know what I want and I
think that comes with a lot of things um
in life I'm a Leo so you know I just
when I have a goal it doesn't matter I'm
getting it whatever it is I'm getting it
and it's it's a cool trait to have it's
a way cool trait to have but also it's
detrimental to a lot of other things you
forget to do other things and it's just
but I think it comes down to the person
you got to have you got to be that
person you got to have that grit you got
to have that perseverance that tenacity
that it's consistency it's just it's all
within the person if if you aren't in
tune with yourself and your visions and
your goals you're not going to make it
in trading you guys could all trade the
same strategy and you will be able to
see based on the person who makes it and
who doesn't so understanding that this
is very internal there's so many
different strategies out there it's
obvious that it comes down to the person
the trader to actually make this work
and make this successful okay so we're
just going to go ahead and call this
video the harsh raw reality of trading
since a lot of these topics are just not
fun to talk about and it hurts my
stomach a a little bit to say and I know
you guys don't want to hear it but maybe
if I can set the raw expectation it will
give you a better Fighting Chance and
not kind of rely on what social media
has portrayed trading to be like so
another harsh raw reality is you
probably shouldn't quit your day job
like definitely don't actually even if
you are making it in trading and you're
doing pretty well I need you to have
multiple sources of income whether that
is maybe you just decide to do a side
gig maybe instead of your you know 9 to5
that you drive to you you're doing
something on the side instead but never
just have trading as your main source of
income you could imagine now all of this
makes sense when I say it to you you'll
be like oh duh yeah when you start
putting so much pressure and so much
weight on each individual trade your
psychology is bound to mess it up like
regardless of how great your strategy is
and how good you are at applying it and
um your entries and your exits
psychology is going to come into play
and you going to start seeing things I
kid you not it's like a mirage you're
going to start seeing things in the
charts that you probably didn't if there
wasn't so much pressure on each
individual trade to make it so
understanding that you've got to have
have this relief of you know multiple
sources of income I have multiple
sources of income and I will always have
multiple sources of income never will I
put on my eggs in one basket never
that's YouTube That's course sales
that's you know bringing income from
just social media streams that's trading
as many streams of income as I can have
okay but I don't I don't hide my streams
of income I don't say that trading is my
only source and I'm rich because of
trading no I am doing well as an
entrepreneur because I have multiple
streams of income here we've got social
media that's YouTube Instagram Tik Tok
What have you all of these streams from
just views I've got trading I've got
education I've got a pre-recorded course
I do coaching I do Partnerships
collaborations I have multiple streams
of income and that's very evident across
all of my social media platforms come at
me if you will I give the real raw
reality of trading I am very transparent
and I understand that you can't win when
it comes to social media I could show
you broker statements I can show you how
much I do make from Trading outside of
anything else and I still will give push
back I it's fake it's not real she's
making more money from anything else yes
I am making money from multiple streams
of income but bringing that all back to
you need to have multiple streams of
income take the pressure off of each of
your trades and truly just use trading
as a tool it's it's an incredible thing
to have how cool that I've got these
multiple streams of income I did amazing
I did excellent at trading this year
just q1 I made 50k I went ahead and
withdrew that and furnished my entire
apartment like I'm talking nice furnish
as you can see here so that was the
coolest tool to have with trading luck
I've got other streams of income that
are making sure bills are paid each
month I'm investing in this long-term
this it's just having those multiple
streams of income takes the pressure off
how cool to be able to make 50k in
trading in just one quarter that's
freaking wild and going back to saying
it took me 9 years to get there so
having the the right expectation of how
long this is actually going to take it
is going to take you a long time it's
going to take you a few years understand
that let it sit a few years you're not
going to be successful next month you're
not going to be successful in 3 months 6
months and if you do it very well could
just be by accident you could have
gotten lucky and if it's truly you know
because you are good at this and because
you're structured and disciplined and
consistent continue then show me you can
do it for the next few years but
understanding that it's going to take a
few years please understand that it's
going to take a few years and then the
small amount of capital if you are a
functioning regular adult I don't know
any other way to say this and you
haven't developed a budget or a system
to be able to have a savings account or
something on the side to invest in this
probably isn't for you anywhere between
$3 to $5,000 I think truly is what it's
going to take to to get to this level
that I'm at or other Traders or just
being able to to grow capital in general
the third thing is understanding that
this is the successes that you have in
trading is the trader and not the
strategy there's so many different
strategies out there it makes sense that
okay everyone's trading you know we'll
say pyramids 10 of these guys are
trading the same pyramid strategy but
for some reason only three of them are
profitable and consistent it's the
trader cuz they're all trading the same
strategy it very well could have been
their psychology may be a little bit off
maybe one of them interpreted a little
bit differently or they they didn't
trust the system or the strategy it all
comes down to the trader not the
strategy and then the last thing is
don't quit your day job continue to have
multiple streams of income to be honest
look for more streams of income keep
that day job start trading now let's
look for another side gig you want to
have multiple streams of income to truly
allow trading to act as a tool and to be
successful in it that is my harsh raw
reality of trading I know you're
probably not going to feel great or
motivated or pumped after this but at
least I can feel good and have my
conscience clear that I have I've set
the expectation the full raw reality
realist expectation of trading okay I
hope this video sheds some light on your
expectations coming into trading if you
liked it there's going to be plenty more
on my page don't forget to subscribe to
my channel hit the like button drop a
comment if you agree or disagree with
everything that I'm saying and don't
forget to share this as well share this
with your friends and be like listen
this is what it's really like