Last year I made $100,000 in trading
profits. This year I'm coming up on
$200,000 worth of trading profits. I
have broker statements. I've got live
loginins. Everything that I'm doing is
real trades, real trading. I've done
interviews where I have submitted 24
months of broker statements. I have
achieved the life that every trader
dreams of. Not the fancy cars, not the
fancy mansions, not the insane
lifestyle. I'm living a realistic,
incredible life. And it's all thanks to
one person. My uncle. My uncle. My
uncle. My uncle.
My uncle. I have always given credit
where credit is due. I would never in
any world, and this has been one thing
that people ask me all the time, "What
got you into trading? Did you ever see
yourself getting into trading?" The
answer is no. I would have never even
considered this, would have never even
fathomed being a trader if it wasn't for
my uncle. Many have speculated if my
strategy is real, if my trading is real,
if my success, my results are real, even
if my uncle is real.
People probably thought the whole uncle
story was
made up. I didn't even have an uncle.
Well, today we're going to find out.
No one knew I existed before I even let
the world know. Many of you guys think I
am an industry plant that the market
makers themselves picked me, handpicked
Tory Trades, plopped me into social
media, and I am an industry plant. I'm
here to sell you guys, scam you guys.
Some of you guys even claiming that this
is some elaborate story made up to
benefit my brand and my image to give me
validity in what I'm doing or to allow
me to climb the ladder of success in
social media or on the internet by using
this crazy madeup story. It is finally
time to reveal the man, the myth, the
legend himself, Uncle Mike, in this
podcast.
So, I started from nothing to all the
information you taught me. And I think
that's why I've made it.
Nine out of 10 don't make it. I'm
talking to a brand new person.
Okay.
I said, "Have you ever read that or
heard that?" First question I ask is,
"What makes you think you're going to
make it?
Why do you think you're going to be the
one or two that make it?"
This is someone that has impacted more
than just my trading, but my life in
general. He has helped me see the world
differently. He has helped me understand
what it is to be an entrepreneur, to
always have multiple streams of income,
to look at the markets in a very
different way. It's my uncle. In this
podcast, we're going to discuss how we
all got into trading.
I was 37 years old when I started. Now
that I've been teaching people for seven
years, so keep this in mind. I'd already
been trading 20 something years.
The psychology behind successful
traders.
I simply need to know, my brain needs to
know those two questions. How do I
determine when to get in? And then my
mind's on to when do I get out?
And Uncle Mike himself reveals some
secret tips to how to consistently be
profitable. Hey,
I know what I'm doing. Listen to me. Let
me teach you how to do this.
Here's your three secrets.
This is one of the biggest videos I have
ever released on social media. Point
blank, period. I hope you guys enjoy
this podcast.
All right, so Lauren and I finally got
my uncle on a podcast today. We had to
we had to drag him in here, but I think
this is against his will. This is um
this is going to be a really interesting
conversation. And it's just kind of
getting you guys an idea for who who
Uncle Mike is. Who is the trading
template? Uh who is Lauren? Who am I?
So, we're going to get really just
really into it, into the nitty-gritty.
So, I guess we we had some questions for
you, Uncle Mike. Um but we can we can
start it, you know, however you'd like.
We can talk about your journey,
how I got here trading,
how you got here. Yeah.
Uh like everyone else, by the way, I'm
going to show you this right here. If
you can see this. Okay. The reason you
want to trade, everyone who's watching
this, why why do you think people would
even be interested in watching this?
They want to make money.
Okay.
Just do they want to make money to be
rich or do they just want to be
comfortable?
I'd say comfortable
safe
is for the most part. Yeah.
Okay. And and and people are getting
older, right? You two are still very
young. Just think you two added together
I think's less than me or close
something like that. Okay. So today it's
$2,900. I've already locked in. Is that
good?
That's excellent.
And I've got a trade right now. I'll
push it in a minute. It's another
$1,200.
Nice.
So that's over $4,000.
Yesterday was $7,500.
Is that good?
Wow. Yeah.
The day before was $4,000.
The day before was $4,400.
All right.
So that's four days.
So what is that? Does that mean I'm a
genius? No. It's just because I take I
took the time to figure out how to
engage trading correctly. Okay, so let
me close this trade real quick.
When you do that, you need to close out
your trades. I'm going to save my
$4,000.
Old days, it used to say order filled.
You remember
that's my iPhone now.
Okay, that one's done.
Order filled. And and this is how you
want to get to you want to get so that
you're trading on your mobile phone. I'm
off somewhere in some office building. I
was tied up to get here and I'm making
my trades. Is that awesome or what?
Being anywhere on the globe generate
your income. So, and that's regular. So,
the questions I have is my journey. I
was an alarm technician. Everyone would
know that. And uh I was a regular worker
person generating my income. But
everyone always hears about trying to
make a little extra money. At certain
times your mind goes off into the future
when you get older and you know
whatever. So I came across trading.
That's when Lauren was born.
Okay.
So that was 28 years ago.
And I started right then. I happened to
see a commercial and it was someone in
front of a computer. Now if you can
picture 28 years ago computers were like
wow. Okay.
Yeah. um we didn't even have a computer
in our family. So I as soon as I seen
that I thought because being out in the
field working being a technician and
then when I seen someone made it look
like it was easy you know oh I can be in
front of a computer and make my money
instantly I told my wife I'm going to go
for that. I'm going to learn how to do
that. And that's how I started. Right
then I started and I'd like to tell you
it was happiness but it was miserable.
Oh my god.
because I everything that we do. So I
say now it's it's learning how to undo
you. You are the problem.
Yeah.
It's not trading. It's not as it
anything like that. It's the way we
naturally think. And the way we
naturally think keeps us safe, does
things for us. But in trading, it's 100%
wrong. Which you two would know that.
Yeah. We know.
So anyway, I started on my journey. Back
then it was read a couple books.
Okay.
Which is useless.
Okay. I bought, you know, that idea, oh,
it's a $100 book. I've got some $100
books that I bought and trading. No
good.
Wow.
All right. Uh, there wasn't, to my
advantage, there wasn't the internet.
So nowadays, the rate of people not
making it trading is amazing.
Probably the highest it's ever been.
It's just unbelievable because how are
we all programmed? You want to learn
something, you go on internet, YouTube,
Instagram, wherever, and there you go.
Before you know it,
you've started. You You've got a hundred
videos under your belt. Okay? Because
it's natural. Remember, it's undo you.
You think, "Oh, I want to learn how to
trade. I want to learn how to trade."
That's even what my site says kind of,
right?
Learn how to trade. That's exactly
wrong.
All right.
Okay. It's learn how to think
differently. There's the problem. Undo
you. So you go in there and change it.
So anyway, I counted a huge blessing. I
had enough money when I started. Not
tons, but I had enough money, enough
determination.
I was just, it was a blessing for me to
be able to weather that learning curve.
Both of you have been there. And you
two, I say have it much easier than
other people.
Yeah.
Right. Yeah.
Because you had me.
Exactly.
That that was that is probably why
you're in. Matter of fact, if it wasn't
that, I would have to bet against you,
too.
I think so, too. That's just the way it
is.
You had me a controlled environment, a
controlled content. I knew exactly what
to give you
right at the right moment.
Totally different. Yeah.
Okay. Maybe you can see that, maybe you
don't.
But anyway, so you guys are there
because of that.
People nowadays go on the internet, they
start watching everything. Before you
know it, you've heard 20, 30, 50
different varieties,
things like that
and uh
your mind goes into a state of
confusion,
analysis, paralysis.
You just you're just done. Okay.
So that's that's kind of my journey. I
got started. I did it. I went through
all that for three years.
Okay.
Okay. So, picture that's a long time.
That is.
During that three years, I quit a couple
times.
Oh, yeah.
Now, you both know that I don't like
cussing, right? I don't cuss. I'm
telling you, it was so frustrating.
Couple times I went to my car and
cussed.
Man, I'm telling you, that's how painful
it is. When you have a you're up, you're
up, you're up $1,000, all of a sudden in
30 minutes you're down five.
I'm telling you, will you
So, thank the Lord I was I say I was
able to weather through that.
Now, I think I've made I don't know 20
or 30,000 trades. Is that a lot of
trades?
That's a lot of trades.
Real money trades.
Yeah.
You just get to pick up stuff. So, my
process, I was talking to someone
yesterday about someone who was
interested in me helping them, and I
said, "The trades I've made this week,
and I told them, you know, 4,000 a day,
seven yesterday, almost four and four,
four days in a row. That's pretty
awesome." But if I were to show you
those trades and how I did it, what's
cool is I could show you the trade I
made 25 years ago,
exactly the same. the coolest thing.
That's the coolest thing.
That's it. So, so anyway, that's my
journey.
Okay,
that's how I got here.
So, three, so three years in
three years, it took me three years
because keep in mind, I was the kind of
personality. Let me little background. I
owned my own business.
Yeah,
that kind of person is more of a
self-direction type person. Okay.
I I thought I was successful there.
Naturally, I thought I'd be successful
here. Major lie. Okay. And then though
when I was starting I was the teacher,
the exam giver, you know, the truth or
whatever you call all that the three
parts, you know, I'm doing it myself.
That's why I didn't make it. If I would
have had a mentor,
Yeah.
someone who as soon as I was deviating
from the course,
bring you right back. Okay.
Yeah.
It's crucial. That's what you guys had.
I didn't have that. So that's why it
took me three years.
Yeah.
Next thing is I was 37 years old when I
started.
Okay.
Now that I've been teaching people for
seven years. So keep this in mind.
You're you're a little unique from me.
You're starting a little bit earlier,
but I'd already been trading 20some
years.
No one knew I existed before I even let
the world know. Yeah. That's kind of
interesting, isn't it? Yeah.
Most people are they made a trade and it
worked out. Hey,
I know what I'm doing. Listen to me. Let
me
I would even go for um when I first
decided to start teaching helping
people,
I never go on the web, which you guys
know that. All right. Yeah.
So, I said, "Well, I Okay, if I'm going
to go help people, and I'm knowing that
YouTube's coming around and whatever." I
to the first one I started, I went on to
the computer and uh I searched trading
and stuff like that. I did it for a
whole week.
Okay.
All week. All day. That's right. Who's
doing this? Who's teaching people?
And at the end of that week, I was just
like,
it was so
skanky,
like a flea market.
And I I really kind of got a little down
like I was telling my wife, I'm not
sure. I just don't know that I can do
it.
Yeah.
And I really had to pull it together.
Okay, I'm not like that. I know the
value I can bring. So, I got into it and
I'm glad I've done it. Yeah,
I've helped a lot of people now. Okay.
But anyway,
because there's not many people like you
is the thing.
It's not I'm just different or whatever.
So, anyway, I'm not saying people out
there aren't good. There's lots of good.
You're good. There's lots of good
people.
Yeah.
It's just that uh there's lots of bad.
You got to weed through. You got to have
the discernment. You got to be able to
tell who's good and who's bad. I you
know and and in part of this you guys
like the new social media stuff.
Yeah, we do. We like it.
I know. That's that's good. You know,
I'm kind of still old school, right? I'm
uncomfortable being in front of a camera
or whatever. It's just just not my deal.
No big deal. But anyway, when I talk to
people, one of the first things I tell
them, which you kind of say this, I've
heard, is I say there's there's
statements of truth that someone can
make.
It's truthful, but depending on where
you're at, the hearer of that would
determine if you can abide by that
statement of truth. Do you know what I'm
talking about?
Like time.
Could you think of something what I'm
So, for example, this is it.
Relationships. Everybody's got
relationships.
This guy, I'm going to pick on a guy.
This guy's got problems. He's a drunk
issues, whatever. And the daughter's
going to go date him, and everyone know
he's got a problem.
And if you said, "Hey, okay, you can
date Mr. Problem, but it's going to be a
rough road."
Yeah.
Okay.
And but she loves him and all of that,
and he's going to get better, you know,
and everything.
and they get married and then lo and
behold within a year you know what
happens divorce right.
So
would you say back then that it would a
truthful statement someone that's
already got all those kind of problems
would be more difficult
to make a relationship work. I mean it's
not that they can't get better. People
get better all the time. But it's just
proven that. Okay.
Oh yeah. Starting out with more issues.
You're starting out with more issues.
It's going to be more difficult. That
statement is truth. Yeah.
Did that person were they able to accept
it? See what I'm saying?
So, for example,
I would tell someone new who wants to
get into trading, learning how to trade,
and why they get in is because the
money.
All right? So, I tell people, picture
this the alphabet, the A through Z. We
want to teach someone how to read,
write, and do all that stuff. Where do
we start?
Yeah. Alphabet.
A. Yeah.
And we work our way down to it.
Wrong answer. The brokerage account
everyone always asks. Oh yeah. Right
away, what brokerage account should I
have? How much money should I have? I
say listen in the alphabet
the trading question the brokerage
account is letter Z.
Oh yeah.
If I can get people just to okay, let me
surrender, slow down and go. This is
what you need to hear first.
Okay.
And then this is what you need second.
If I can get the people, the ones who do
that, everyone says I'll do it. The ones
who do it usually do wonderfully. I've
got several people trading full-time
now. Wow,
that's amazing.
Isn't that crazy? And then I've got also
several people that know, I got to have
a brokerage account. I've And I'm going
for it. I've had people who have bought
my course and and watched a few videos.
Wow, that seems easy. next week. Fired
it up. Lost a tons and have called me up
crying.
I mean crying.
Wow.
And I'm thinking, "Oh boy, what's going
on, dude? You just bought the course two
weeks ago." Well, I thought I got it.
No.
Let me see. You know what I'm talking
about.
Yeah. Yeah.
So, this trading is phenomenal.
And there's so many things I could talk
fast and and since we're on a short
loop, maybe I should talk fast, right?
because I typically talk short. I mean
it's slow. But anyway, what other
questions you got for me? Sorry.
I think a lot of people want to know. I
mean, when it comes to people just
getting into trading, it's it's a long
process. If you can understand that the
I mean, it doesn't have to be long. I
guess to be honest, it doesn't have to
be.
It took you a while.
It did.
Why?
I think it was the information you gave
me. I didn't pay for.
First mistake
that I didn't pay for it. Every family
member,
oh my god,
and friends that I have over the years,
I've said, "Well, I can do this. I can
give it to you for free."
Yeah.
I've done that.
And guess what?
They don't take zero.
I'm telling you, zero.
I think that was my number one reason.
You were going to be a zero until
something happened to you.
Yeah. Exactly.
And whatever. And you came alive.
Yeah.
But every person I've given it to for
free
is just
they're not trading.
It just doesn't They just don't even do
it. Oh, I would love that. Even people
who have called me, people I don't know,
you know, like uh vets and stuff like
that, military and I've had a problem, a
man, hey, I can give you this course for
free. This would be wonderful. Thank you
very much. Here you go. You're signed
up, dude. Go get them. I can go look
from in the back end, they've never even
opened it up.
Wow.
Once I started putting So, everyone who
wants to make money, raise your hand.
Everyone's raising their hand. Okay. And
uh who would like to generate an extra
couple hundred dollars a day? Everybody.
All right. And whatever else. And now
who's willing to pay a little money?
Yeah. That's where the hands go down.
Okay. That's just how it works. So part
of the reason I charge and I keep
charging people is because it weeds out
the wannabes.
Yeah. Oh yeah.
It just works. You put money into it.
I'm committing. It's just it's like a
magic turn on switch. That's why if
you're not paying for information almost
like this information here, there's
people who will be watching this and
guess what? They're watching it for what
purpose?
They're thinking they're going to get
something out of it that they're missing
like some secret.
That's what they think they're getting.
Some secret sauce. Okay.
Or entertainment.
Or entertainment. That is it.
And some I heard someone say it's
edutainment now.
Edutainment. Part of their brain says
I'm getting educated. Wow, that's a good
term. Really? I'm being entertained.
Yeah.
Okay. That's why YouTube, Instagram,
everything else is so popular. All
right. Do I have all my colors? All the
colors set on. Okay. That's popular.
It's just the way it works. Uh so when I
say a statement of truth, I'm cycling
back to what I was going to say. A
statement of truth. If someone asked me
what's the worst thing they can do
nowadays, what would you say?
I know the answer.
I You know the answer. The answer is go
on to YouTube, Instagram, Tik Tok or
whatever else.
Yeah.
I'm just telling you, you cannot learn.
And but the problem is is because when
you go to build a house or a structure,
what do you got to do first?
Blueprints.
Blueprints. Come up with the design. Get
the blueprints. We've got the land. The
land's cleared. We're ready to start
building. What goes in first?
Foundation.
The foundation. Correct. You want to
skimp on the foundation.
That's probably the most important.
It is. You want to put real thin
concrete, bad wood, or whatever, the
foundation's built on some bad stuff.
You want to skimp on the foundation?
Absolutely not.
Of course not. That's like a a dumb
question. Well, when you say this is the
way the brain works. Oh, I want to learn
how to trade. I want to get into trading
to generate income a different way. I
want to own my own source of income.
Okay. Well, what do we do default? We go
to online. Correct?
Keep in mind, you've just told the
brain, "Hey, I'm going into learning
mode." And what does the brain know to
do?
Lay the foundation first.
Okay. Okay.
It's like imprinting animals. Okay.
They're born first thing. That's mama.
Yeah.
Okay. You go online, learn to trade.
First thing you start hearing, seeing,
your mind is stashing it automatically
into the foundation. Yeah. You don't
even know it. Isn't that crazy?
Yeah.
I go and I finally think I've filled
that up. You don't know that you have
and you filled it up incorrectly. And
then all of a sudden, I flip, you know,
you do this right on your phone. you go
to the next little thing and here's your
three secrets you need or whatever or
this or the 10 whatever
you're stashing in the next thing.
You're building this file system in your
mind automatically.
Yeah.
And then finally you think well I can
talk a few bits of lingo to my whomever
and now I'm going to go trade and it's
miserable.
Do you know what the stats are people
making at trading? I think it used to be
what 80. Now it's like 90 95%.
Crazy. That's
such a bummer.
So why is that? Why? First of all, I'm
not sure that's really true. That's what
we've it's heard. Someone published it
and said that. Yeah,
it's not that case with my students. I
don't know about yours, but it's not.
But anyway, overall, I would say that.
But um
so
so you see what happens. They come to it
because they want to diversify their
income, which is smart. Yeah.
How they go about it. So that state back
to that statement of truth. First thing
I say is do not go watch videos.
Yeah.
Random videos. You're done.
Matter of fact, when I talk to people
and I talked to someone yesterday, I
said listen and however they found me,
now this is where that kind of gets
weird
nowadays. They're not finding me unless
they go to a video.
Okay?
So there is a problem in what I'm
saying. Okay? There's got to be
something.
When when I had my alarm business years
ago, you guys maybe you know this. There
used to be a yellow page. Yeah.
You remember that big old book? And I'd
have an ad in there because I could
figure out electronics. Well, now the
yellow page is the internet.
Yeah.
The problem is there's a gazillion
things.
Yeah.
You don't know which one to look at. So,
uh, this guy found me via the internet
somehow.
And I said, uh, have you watched how
long you been doing it? three, four,
five years or whatever. Have you watched
lots of videos? Oh, yeah. Tons.
Hundreds.
Oh, boy.
I said, so the little bit I could help
him, he bought my course today, by the
way.
Okay.
Anyway, I said, listen, I'm going to
give you a statement of truth. Do not,
if you want to make it, whether we
whether I help you or not, worst thing
you can do is go watch another random
video.
Yes.
And I said, but I tell you what, it's so
addictive. It's so pooling.
Yeah.
I'll bet against you. I have to I have
to bet that you will go watch more
videos. Now, in this case, he
bought my program, so I'll be working
with him. But overall, what would you
think of that statement? Is that too too
harsh, too crazy? Don't go watch YouTube
videos.
I think it's fair. That was the first
thing that you told me and Payton was
everything that I'm about to teach you
is all you need to know.
That was the that was the most truth
that I've ever heard. And thank gosh
that I didn't go watch any videos. I
never got in. I know. very lucky cuz
that's not the case for many people now.
Okay.
But I think that's maybe because I
wasn't like I was given the information
for free. I wasn't quite obsessed enough
with it to just try to fill my head.
People want to just fill their head.
When they get obsessed with it, they're
just they want every angle, every
answer.
So I think luckily I just I took
everything you said, everything. And
that was all I knew. So I started from
nothing to every all the information you
taught me. And I think that's why I've
made it or am making it or am
consistent.
Yes. Yes. I I think so. What about you?
It's tough. No, I was just going to say
it's tough, too, because I think that
when people, like you said, they get
obsessed with it. It's like they want to
see the success. They want to like have
hope. So, that's also why they go on
social media because they're like, "Oh,
this guy's doing it. Like, I have hope
that I can one day do it kind of thing,
you know?"
And and that would be in that context.
Yeah. Are there other people that do it?
Yes.
That does give you hope. Okay. So,
here's another statistic. So, back to
the statistics. Nine out of 10 don't
make it.
I'm talking to a brand new person.
Okay.
I said, "Have you ever read that or
heard that?" And they say, "Yeah, you
know, eight out of 10 or whatever."
First question I ask is, "Well, what
makes you think you're going to make
it?"
Yeah, that's a great question.
You think you're going to be the one or
two that make it and not the eight that
don't?
I'd say probably because I'm talking to
the right person. Oh, I'm talking to
someone.
That's the one.
If they thought that. Yeah. But, uh, I
usually ask that. So, why do you think
you know why you're making it now?
Because you were able to get the
information and you've now modified it
some obviously. Okay. You're still
working on it, right?
Okay. So, that's something I ask them.
All right. What else? What other
questions you got? Keep in mind, I was
brought here under the grace.
Okay. Everybody wants to know kind of
what's the trading like nowadays. So you
can trade from your phone, you know,
what are you trading? What time frame?
Okay.
Some of the nitty-gritty stuff.
Good. Just those those things,
those unimportant,
they really are. I know they are.
They are unimportant. All right. So,
here's what I tell people.
I I uh that's why I probably don't do
these things. Matter of fact, if you go
to my YouTube channel and you watch and
you used to be my editor for years,
okay? Matter of fact, I think that's
also why you made it.
Oh my gosh, I watched hours.
You watched hours and hours and had to
clean it up and rewind it to clean it up
and then do it again. You have heard
what I've said more than anybody.
More than anyone. Okay. Yeah.
So that's why repetition is your friend.
It's not important. All right. It's not
the deal. It's not the strategy. It's
not this indicator. It's none of that
out here.
Now, of course, you have to engage with
that. I had a guy yesterday I said,
"Well, are you talking price action or
is it this or is that I'm using a a
Fibonacci?"
I know whatever. Trust me, I know.
I said, "Okay." I said, "Well, they all
can be something." All right, but the
the thing is it's in here. Remember,
picture this. All right. I'm taking data
in. I'm looking at the screen, TV or my
computer. I'm looking at the data.
What's happening, okay? Or I'm watching
screen. I'm now listening to somebody
friend or what I'm hearing or whatever
in a Discord room or whatever I'm
hearing. I'm taking two points of data
in. Correct. Mhm.
It comes in, it goes to this file system
that's in your brain
and then it clicks and it sends a little
protein electrical current down. By
okay,
data comes in. Click sell. Is that
right?
Yeah.
That's exactly what happens.
Interesting. It came in. It goes in.
what I'm thinking, I'm hearing, seeing,
hearing goes up against my already
established file system,
my total life file system, and a segment
of that is what I've learned about
trading, and it fires out the output.
Buy or sell. That's it.
Where's the problem?
The problem is in the file system in
here. Okay? It's what you're taking the
I could have five people right here
looking at the same information.
Oh yeah. They're gonna come up with
They all see it's a red bar. Unless
you're color blind. It's a red bar,
right? Yes. And how do they come up with
a different push
your file system? You got to rewrite
your file system.
And so when you do that, like building a
house, it's crucial.
That's why if you what I was going to
say earlier, people that go to my
website occas my my YouTube and I guess
my website
uh you're nicer to people. I'm I'm not
as nice. Okay.
I don't say how I do it at all.
Yeah.
You kind of say how you do it and that's
fine.
I am so particular.
We're going to do this. This is what you
have to know first.
Yeah. And until we get this laid out,
the foundation, I'll say you'll never
make it.
Yeah.
You might make it for a day.
That's what I'm not interested in. I'm
interested in you helping it. Think of
this. I started when I was 37. I'm 65
now. Is that crazy?
Almost. I'm almost done. Okay. Thank the
Lord. I get to get out of here. Okay.
But for all these years, I've not had
anybody tell me what I've got to do.
I wake up, I go.
Last month, you guys know I was in South
America and uh right on my phone.
So, one of your questions will be what
are you trading now? I used to trade
stocks.
Back when I started, it used to be 20
and 18. 20 really and 116th.
20 and 532.
Was that weird? I had to get out my tape
measure cuz I was a carpenter and knew
that and I had to calculate what that
was 20 and a quarter.
It was all represented in that fraction
stuff. Okay.
Okay.
And uh and then sometime I don't
remember but they came out with decibb.
Now it's 20.10 or 20.25.
So much easier. Yeah. Okay.
Back then you there was no online stuff.
Mhm.
I used to call
okay
all day. One day, this would be an
interesting story. Show you how powerful
the mind is. Whether it's a lie or the
truth, if you believe it, it's truth to
you.
Yeah.
I had a trade one time. Uh, Aunt Lynn
and I were going out of town. We're
driving and um there was nothing online.
Yeah.
I'd call Okay. And I'd call and the guy
I knew him, hey, so and so, maybe it was
Cisco, and he'd pop out the price. Okay,
thanks a lot.
Okay,
10 minutes later, hey, it was nuts call.
They probably It was just so crazy
because you couldn't get the
information.
Anyway, I'm losing money that day. We're
driving from here to North Carolina.
Time I get there, I'm down $12,000. That
was a miserable day. I wasn't telling my
wife, you know, so I said, "All right,
thanks. All right, I want to close that
trade. I I just couldn't take it. It was
overwhelming."
He goes, "Well, what trade you talking
about?"
I said, "Well, I need to close my
thousand shares of Cisco." Goes, "Well,
let me check here. You don't have a
trade." I said, "What?
What?
What happened? What do you mean?" "Well,
let me look here." Well, you had a trade
uh yesterday, Cisco, but you had a close
at market,
and that means when the market 4:00
automatically closing. I forgot
I had done that.
Wow.
All day long.
I'm losing 2,000, 4,000, 8,000, 10,
12,000. I said, "All right, cut that
thing out.
You don't even have it."
I'm telling you, it was an amazing
experience because I believed it all day
long.
So whether it's truth or a lie, if you
believe it,
it's there. You go.
Wait, I have a question. How did you
see the price? I mean, you would call
you call and ask.
You didn't back then if you weren't in
front of your computer because you had
to be in your computer. They didn't have
Wi-Fi and stuff. Okay. It was we didn't
have these kind of phones. It was flip
phone.
Yeah.
So there was no screen.
So you just kind of knew I got in at 20
and at 1/8
it's now here or here and you'd be
calculating in your bra.
So did you develop the trading template
after you could see the charts?
Uh I developed and and keep in mind this
will help people template.
Yeah.
I was a carpenter before I became an
electronics. I used to hang doors.
someone would come, a carpenter would
hang doors and you'd have to measure out
and cut where the hinges go.
Well, when you got a bunch of doors to
do, instead of measuring,
and I did that, of course, but then I
said, I'm going to get a piece of
plywood. I'm going to cut what I called
a jig.
And so now I could take a a door. It's
called a slab, put it on its edge, put
this piece of wood on there, tack it,
and then scribe it. And now I could use
my router tool,
give me the next door. Mhm.
Put it on there.
Done. Like that.
I took the time to build this jig, this
template. So, when I say my template,
it's really my process, my
understanding, my routine,
okay? My knowledge of how I'm putting
the pieces together. Once I realize this
works to give me the positive results,
boom, it just that's what I'm doing.
That's why today I do exactly what I did
25 years ago.
And how I got there was I was I've made
thousands of real live trades, some
winners, some losers. And I was able to
start pairing it down, parsing it back.
Why do I have these losers? What do they
look like? What are the characteristics?
These winners, what happens? What are
the characteristics? And I started
mapping that. And when I came up like,
"Oh, whoa. Is that it?"
I went made trades on that
understanding,
started going green, dude. I locked it.
Wow. Okay. Same thing. And you would
know because you you teach it and tell
people about it and they say, "Ah, that
don't work." You know, that's that's too
simple. It's too easy.
Okay. It's and so the process are there
other processes or other things people
could use to trade? I'm gonna say sure.
Yeah.
Okay.
Doesn't matter,
right?
It's this. It's what I see, what I hear
into my file system, my training brain,
and then all of a sudden it fires it
out.
Yeah.
Is that cool?
And I So now I don't have to think about
it. And you're probably getting like
that. It's I mean, you're not there yet,
but you're getting there. Okay. You're
getting there. All right. By the way,
does the world know that you just had a
$40,000 trade deal?
I did. I announced it to the world. The
day she did it, she told everybody. I
told her
your biggest trade.
Yeah.
Is that awesome?
That was the coolest.
Just think there was a point where you
thought, "Does this really work? Can I
make 50 bucks? Can I make a $100?" And
you just knocked out a $40,000 trade.
Way cool.
That's cool. Congratulations.
Thank you.
Yeah, you're gonna get there. One day.
Absolutely. I don't know.
You guys are going to be better than me
because
I I and I this is my benefit. I got to
help you get started and supporting you
and getting you there
because you just don't want to. You
know, who likes talking about income? I
can't stand it. I don't like thinking
about it. But we're humans and and
finances are part of our lives. Okay?
And uh as you get older, all right? And
everyone who's watching this, when you
hit the age 45,
it's it's illegal to discriminate, but
I'm telling you, you're 45, you're 50,
the world, the workplace world
Oh,
it's silently pushing you out.
Yeah,
everyone knows that.
Yeah.
Okay. We just can't say it, but everyone
knows it.
Dude, since I started learning how to
trade, my income has gone up every year.
Is that crazy? Yeah.
Now, what's that's not even the crazy
part.
Being in front of my computer was
awesome. Trading is awesome. But you
know this now and you know it. I tell
people the coolest thing about trading
is doing it from my phone.
I know
if if they say, "What brokers do you
use?" And I use Trade Station. Okay. And
uh and I could care less really. The
reason I use Trade Station is that's who
was around back then. I've been there 26
years. That's a long time. Yeah. Right.
Oh, yeah.
One reason I feel very safe.
Now, are they really safe with my money?
I don't know that. Remember I said
earlier, but I think it's safe.
It's truth to you.
That's correct. I would never go to an
offshore account. None of that stuff.
Never.
So, I feel safe with my money.
Okay. Been there 26 years, never had an
inkling of a problem.
Yeah.
Their platform, they try to do cool
stuff, which I wish they would never do
that. Okay. And I I kick him and fight
him about that. But anyway, it works. I
can
But once it came to doing it on the
phone,
game changer.
That was Wow. Oh, yeah.
I'm telling you,
you I could be like you do. I'm walking
around, you know, everybody looks at
their phone, their thumb. You would
think I'm texting somebody or
responding. I'm making a trade.
Oh, yeah.
You get to that stage, man.
It's so cool.
It's fabulous. So, I could care less
about the brokerage account, whatever,
but if they took the mobile app,
that'd be a drag. If I had to go back
and sit in front of my computer, no
good.
Yeah.
All right. What else? What's another
question? Oh, here's the age. If you're
younger than 35, they need to talk to
you two guys about getting trained
because listen, 10 year olds think like
10 year olds, right? kind of
they're interested in the same stuff.
18 year olds are kind of interested in
that.
Yeah.
40 year olds are a little different.
Okay.
I think people shouldn't come to trade
or unless there's an exception.
Okay.
You two guys I've forced to be an
exception.
Yeah.
But typically until you're 35 and really
if I said the age is Moses age, you know
who Moses is?
I've heard him. Moses. Moses came out
when he was 40, I think, or something
like that. At 40. At 40 years old. Think
of this.
When I first started training, you we
were getting this thing going. I was
going to start teaching people, and you
were one of those,
a punk,
18, 20. Okay. I said, "Man, if I could
get people right out of high school and
show them this, it'd be fabulous."
Right away, I found out, oh, what a
wrong thinking. They've had 18 years of
being indoctrinated about you got to get
a job. Yeah. Be responsible.
Great lie number one. Great lie number
two is hey, if you want to really act
like you're smart, go to higher
education because these 12 years did
nothing for you. Okay. And go two, four,
six, and it's really 10 years now and
pay for it. Go into debt. But maybe
you'll get to cut in line.
Yeah. and get a job. And that's that's
what I was up against. So I realized,
oh, I made a mistake. So now
people buy into that, they do it. But
when they get to be 40,
now they kind of are more comfortable in
theirelves and you know what all that
mature and they get to look back and it
for some reason you kind of look
differently going forward. Hey, what's
the next 20? And I get to look back at
the last 20. What has what I've been
buying into the job thing in this case
done for me?
Nothing, right?
Been laid off a time or two or I know
people have been laid off. I have no
retirement. I have no whatever. They
wake up and say, "What else can I do?"
Yeah.
Trading is that.
I mean, I can prove it hands down.
Oh, yeah.
What if I said, "Okay, you can go into
trading, but guess whatever? You gotta
quit whatever else you're doing and go
100%.
Would that be crazy? No one could do it.
I couldn't have done it. Okay? Or you
want to go into another business, big
bucks, big risk, the whole nine yards.
Trading, you do it in your bedroom in
your panties. Okay? It's just crazy. No
risk at all.
Rewrite your thinking.
Practice it. Prove it to yourself. Hey.
Yeah,
I kind of got this.
Okay, let me get it. Come up with a
couple thousand dollars.
Yeah.
And let me try it. Wow.
It's amazing. Yeah. Isn't it?
Yeah.
So, all right. What other questions?
I mean, we could go back. We can go back
to what do you trade?
Oh, yeah. Okay. Okay. So, I traded
stocks forever and I got it down to
probably six or seven stocks. the same
ones I traded for 10 or 15 years
and everyone asked what are those
exactly but it didn't matter
it does doesn't matter the point was I
found a place to go fishing and the fish
bought bit they bit is that it fish bit
they were biting
they're biting biting
okay and I went back the next time there
that's where I'm going fishing
all right so my ones I worked on worked
out Great. When I started teaching
people
and then they started doing it, they
realized, oh, there's a thing called PDT
rule, pattern day trader. In the stock
world, you have to have $25,000.
Basically, not many people don't have
that, right?
So, I instantly realized, uh, okay,
guess what? Let me show you this. I've
always known this, but I'm going to do
it. I'm gonna go open up in a totally
different financial area called futures.
It could have been options. Nowadays,
there's cryptocurrency, bond market, all
kinds of different things to trade. I
went and opened up a futures account. It
was done in a day or two and I started
trading the same way. Same thing I know
how to trade. And all of a sudden, I I
think I put 10,000 in my account. I
could have put a thousand. Yeah.
But I had it. So I put 10 in there.
Started trading, winning trades. And so
now I eliminated that problem.
Yeah.
If you're going to get into trading,
futures is where you want to go.
Okay. Number one benefit, you can start
with a little bit of money. Yeah. Okay.
And then other benefits, which I
didn't really think about too much, but
it trades, which you know, 20 hours of
the day.
If you're a worker B all day long, you
can't trade. Good. Futures are trading
at night.
Yep.
Little bit of money. Easy. Whatever.
Again, where is that trading come in on
the alphabet?
It's a
Z.
It's not a I know. Z, right?
The brokerage is brokerage Z.
When I have people come to me who's
already been trading and they have a
brokerage account,
I say, "If you could do it, cancel it."
Yeah. Okay.
Okay.
Listen, you're 16-year-old. I bring the
car. It's in the driveway and here's the
keys. But now you don't know how to
drive yet. Let me teach you how to
drive. Do you think they're really gonna
be focused on how to learn? Let me get
in that.
They are just eyeballing the car the
whole time. Okay. You can't help it.
Yeah.
I say take that out. You're not learning
how to trade for today to make a couple
bucks today. You want to become totally
financially independent.
Okay. And you can, it really does work.
But you've got to go through a undo you.
Yeah.
Rewrite the thinking.
Does that make sense?
Yeah, it does.
People who would do it will be uh
they're happy. Mhm.
So, I trade futures now.
Yeah.
And then I narrowed it down real quick.
I've got two of them that I trade.
Okay.
I don't even trade what you trade.
I know.
Isn't that crazy?
Yeah. Yeah.
And some people say, "Well, is that it?"
I say, "Listen, I know them." Like you
talk about that. Uh, you get to know
your instrument. It's like dating. Find
out what's your quirks, what's your
problems, where you're going to have a
where you're going to go off. Okay. I
need to I have these two. I can tell you
what they're doing. My I can literally
pop open my phone and within seconds my
brain is firing off the signal.
Is that neat?
Yeah.
I I trade the same two things for the
last seven years. Occasionally I'll do a
little something else. Just why? I don't
know why,
but that's what I do. 99%
same two.
Yeah.
Over and over and over.
Okay.
How boring. I love it.
But you know what? I'm not into I don't
care. I want to not I don't want to have
to think about it.
Yeah.
You guys have iPhones. This is cool.
What do you spend your time on?
There's a thing on here called screen
time. Oh, yeah.
You ever seen it?
I came across it six months ago. I said,
"What's this?" You know, I don't even
know what this thing does. All I do is
talk, text, and trade.
Yep.
Other than that, that's it. Okay.
little email screen time. Anyway, I can
go show it to somebody. 100% of my
trades are on my phone for seven years.
My screen time averages 10 hours a week.
Wow, that's impressive.
Nowhere else. You look at my YouTube,
zero.
Okay, really? I mean, unless I go look
for something very quick, I need
something. Uh, anything else? I don't
have Instagram. I don't have I have if I
have them it's because you guys set them
up for me. Let everybody know that.
Okay. I don't participate
but uh I trade.
So if someone's watching YouTube, what
does that mean? It means that Do you go
watch a bunch of other people on how to
trade?
No, not at all.
Correct. That's your first clue. If
you're watching, if you're hunting
looking, that means you don't know what
you're doing.
Okay. Yeah. So, if you're one of those
persons listening to this, hopefully to
glean something, typically we tend to
say, if I said, "Do you want to be
mentored? Someone to walk you through
the steps of how to do it. We're going
to go through a treacherous mountain.
It's 10,000 ft. It's scary.
You want to go on your own?"
Absolutely not.
You want to get a guide book and try to
go on your own or do you want the guy
who's been up and down the mountain?
Oh, yeah.
Okay. Well, here's the drawback to that.
Gota pay.
Isn't that crazy?
Most people by default.
[Music]
I think I'll try this.
Waste time. Break their legs. Broken
that. Fell off the cliff. Right.
Disaster.
It's disaster.
But you know what?
I'll go flap some money down on some new
whatever.
Oh yeah. New phones, new Yeah. when I
have people say one guy says, "Oh,
listen. I'd love to do this. I want to
do it."
And uh but you know, $2,000. I charge
$2,000. I don't know what you charge,
but $2,000. That's kind of steep. I'm
not sure. I said, "Okay, actually, I
have a $1,000 plan, too." It was the
$1,000 when I was talking to him. I
said, "Okay, yeah, yeah, makes sense.
$1,000 is a lot of money." It's not.
It shouldn't be, right?
Not. If I gave you $1,000 and you right
now at your ages, would that be
revolutionary to you?
Would it change things big time?
No,
it really wouldn't.
It could disappear in a day.
This just just does not. So, picture
when I'm talking to someone who's 40
years old, they've been working, let's
say, 20 years. Okay? They make their
income.
$1,000 we already agreed is not a big
deal.
You've been working.
Have Have you been able to save this
nothingness that we just talked about?
$1,000. It's nothing, right?
Have you been able to save that for 20
years? You should have $20,000 saved
into your savings account. You know how
many people have that?
Not at all.
It's sad, isn't it? What happens? The
money went through their hands. They
earned it. They earned 50 to 100, 150,
but they have nothing left.
It's because they're thinking. Okay. So
anyway, it's not a lot, but traveling up
that they'd rather try to do it on their
own. That's why people are watching this
here to maybe pick up something. And I
say, "So be it." I did that route.
That was my personality. I I was I'm,
you know, whatever. Okay. I'm a business
owner. I can make decisions. I had a
successful business. So I was thinking
okay with that.
Okay.
All right.
But so I thought I would do it here and
and I was one of those people. I was not
used to paying people for things.
Okay.
So I would have been that.
So I tried it on my own. And that's why
I say thank the Lord really that I made
it because I tried it and it was
frustrating if I could have been wise.
So I tell people this. You want to get
into trading? First of all, you need to
get into trading.
Okay? If your source of income is
working a job,
you're disposable.
It's why.
Yeah.
You see what I'm saying? It's just no
good. You're better than that. The only
reason you even have your job is because
you're able to do something. That's your
evidence right there. I could do this on
my own. I can think a little bit better.
Okay.
So, anyway, I I go to do that. get into
that trading and now
if you try to when you come on YouTube
or wherever I say here's your first
thing to to decide do I want to try to
do this on my own
selfadminister
the information process it come up with
it practice it think I'm doing it right
or
do I want to get a mentor that's the
only first question you need to make
you ether getting a mentor. So, go watch
some YouTube videos if you want to. Your
goal is not to learn how to trade. Don't
tell me about a strategy. I don't want
to know about your strategy, your 10
points, your three, this, all this is
all you need to know. I don't want to
know that.
I simply want to know
am I going this on my own
or am I getting a mentor?
Okay,
that's that's first thing. Yeah,
the wise people, the ones who understand
things a little better,
will go with a mentor.
Yeah,
they got to spend a little bit of money.
Okay. But they also would know, do I
want to spend 2,000 bucks, get trained
on how to do it, or do
I want to lie to myself and not think
I'm gonna spend more than that because I
am. I'm gonna spend way more in time and
everything else.
Yeah. and and just blow it. You see what
I'm saying? Let me get there now.
Yeah.
So,
what did the Sorry, wait real quick. Go
back to what you had a guy that didn't
have the thousand or said.
Okay, but that's a lot of money to me.
And that's sad when I hear that. And he
was around 40. I said, I understand. I
understand. I got a question for you.
You got a a smartphone? He goes, "Yeah."
"What kind of?" It was an iPhone. I
said, "How many of those you had?" Said,
"Oh, I've had four or five of them.
because he was 40. You know how they go
out. I said, "What if you lost your
iPhone today? What would you do?" And
first I asked, "How much is it?" He
goes, "Oh, I think they're 1,100 bucks
currently. If you lost your iPhone or
broke today, what would you do?"
What do you think he said?
He's got to buy a new one.
So his his um priorities
priorities are not on trading. It's on
thinking about buying this training,
getting me just to be financially
independent. That's a lot. That thousand
dollars I lost my phone.
Crazy.
That's why people are messed up. Okay.
So, my my thinking, my desire is there's
a scripture says, "Let each of you use
whatever gift you have received to serve
one another. This has been a gift.
I get to serve you guys. I get to serve
other people. You're getting to become
servants
to serve other people. So, if I can help
them in this particular area, they want
to talk biblical stuff, I'm into that.
That's what I'd really like to talk
about. But this is we're this is a
financial thing at this moment. That's a
thread in our life, right? So, we're
talking about finances. What's the most
efficient way to be in control best you
can to be independent?
All the benefits
and have ample income. I'm driving my TR
I'm driving my wife's car the other day.
It's a 2016, you know, it's a nice car.
Thing didn't start.
I go get it checked out, whatever. Uh I
take it to the dealership. Starter's
bad. Two grand for a starter.
Amen. Go ahead and do it. Okay. I go
pick it up. Done. Few days later, I'm
driving my truck. I need to do take it
in to do something. O engine oil light
came on. I get there. Hey, by the way, t
$2,000. Go ahead and do it. That would
be $4,000
smacked against me just like that.
Most people are popping that onto a
credit card and what a drag.
I'm telling you, it's wonderful.
And And you're there now. Mhm.
You're getting there. That That is No,
dude. Done.
I've made $4,000 a day for the last
several days, right?
Yeah.
I can That's the way you want to be. So,
what I was willing to go through it why,
whoever, I don't know why. I got
prompted, led to go into this route and
I prompted you to go into it and now
you're trying and I'm trying to help
other people get into trading.
It takes work. You got to undo you.
Oh yeah.
Let us reformat the way you think. I've
got two questions as a trader. What are
they? What do I want to know as a
trader? I'm going to go trade today.
You, you're traders. What do you want to
know as a trader?
When to buy, when to sell.
That's it. There is nothing else I need
to know. I don't need to know anything
else. When I go to check out, say, "Hey,
like today, I'll take my $4,000."
Uh, they simply ask, "Mike, did you know
that the presidential elections coming
on? Did you know what the geopolitical
scenes going on? Did you know this
happened to war over here? Did you know
that rates?" And this
they simply say, "Where did you get in?"
Yeah.
Where did you get out?
Let's make sure. Here you go. Here's
your money. Mhm.
I simply need to know, my brain needs to
know those two questions. How do I
determine when to get in and then my
mind's on to when do I get out?
Yeah.
Master that
my trade today looked like it looked 25
years. It's fascinating.
It really is.
So, and you know that. So, all right.
What else? What's another question?
What you got? Okay. Well, since you
haven't said what instruments you trade
specifically,
futures.
Okay, futures.
Correct. I trade the one called YM.
Okay.
Which is weird.
Yeah. I don't know where they got the Y
from the Dow.
Mama.
I don't know. And NQ.
NASDAQ. That one. I get
no quality. I don't know what it is. NQ
and YM.
Okay.
You could trade the ES.
Uh the RTU. where they come up with that
one.
Platinum.
That's that's that's those are not
necessarily indexes, right?
But a a unit.
Okay. But indexes.
Um so so now in going so they're what's
the first thing people are coming to
YouTube? I say if they're going to go to
YouTube, what's their goal?
They should find a mentor, not a
strategy.
They should be thinking their first
thing to decide, am I wanting to do this
on my own
or do I want a mentor to get me there?
Mhm.
If you're going to go on your own,
then of course you'll go watch a
gazillion things to try to
piece it all together.
Remember the odds. Nine out of 10
do that. They don't make it. Okay. So,
if they go for a mentor,
then now the mentor's job is to, hey,
show me because I don't know.
Show me how I sit.
Remember how I used to teach how to sit?
change from the long chair to the short
chair.
Yes. Okay. So,
down to that, how I sit, how I'm
thinking, what I'm doing, what's going
in my brain first. So, now I'm building
this like a m a muscle memory thing.
Okay? Automatic thinking. When I come
in, I go into trade, I'm looking the
data through my eyes. What I hear, I
typically, by the way, shut my ears off.
Yeah. Okay.
I don't want to hear anything. It's what
I see. And now it goes into this file
system I've got. And it's just
automatic.
That's just cool.
It really is. It really is. And people
don't believe you can do it from your
phone now. They think it's too complic I
say uh it's actually the way to go.
Yeah.
Okay. Oh, yeah.
I with some caveats. Trading on your
phone has a whole new dimension. You're
out. You're mobile. You're in your car.
you're doing stuff. Okay, think about
it. And even when my thing says 10 hours
a week, if I logged in to my brokerage
account right now and I put my phone
down or it happens to be on my leg or
whatever, it's still registering.
Yeah.
So, I'm really not even 10 hours a week.
Okay. If it knew that, maybe it's half
that.
Okay.
My goal is five, by the way.
So, I'm there at 10 easily. But uh so
the problem I tell people when you're
learning no phone,
okay,
when you're learning, it's shut the
world off. Yeah. Kids, leave me alone a
minute. Wife, I got it. Shut the phone
off.
Focus.
Yeah.
Okay. We're trying to rewrite your
thinking patterns. You've got to focus.
Do you think people focus nowadays?
Absolutely not.
They can't help it.
you know, I'm not an Instagrammer, so or
anything like that. Well, when I first
got my Instagram and I went on to it,
okay, I said, "Well, I got an Instagram
account that you guys made me." And I
said, "Oh, look here. Whatever." I'm not
kidding. I don't know how, but there
were the best, beautifullest, nakedest
women in the world.
I see.
And I'm thinking, I'm brand new. That's
bad news. I shut that off. I went back
another time. So I see what happens.
They for some reason that must be like a
default thing. I think they know my age.
I'm a man. Whatever. That's normal,
right?
If you're of the world, it's normal. So
they're just pumping that stuff in
there. I can't handle that at all. It's
that's bad news. So I don't do any of
that phone. Now though, in my trading,
I've narrowed it down to a couple
thoughts.
When you're in your when you're learning
though, uh-uh, be in front of the
screen, be focused, have a little
notepad, be able to replay that thing
because you can't help it. When even you
or me when I'm teaching somebody
something, you can't help it. Even
during this, if we could see in your
brain, there's certain times I said
something and you went off to say, "Oh,
I got a question about that or I
wanted."
Well, you missed the next five words I
said. Those were the five that you
needed.
You want to rewind it. So, when you're
learning, be in front of the computer.
No distractions if you can. Try to learn
to focus. I had one of my students
recently within two months. He was in
y'all's age group and he bought the
course and we got on the phone and
talked his bike, your lessons are too
long. He said, "Dude, I I'm telling you,
if it's longer than three minutes, I I
just can't do it."
Oh my gosh.
I said, "Say that again. Three minutes."
He goes, "I'm not kidding. I'm I'm
either off onto a text, I'm off to doing
something else. I got my whatever. It's
just real quick. Your lessons are 30
minutes. They're too long."
I said, 'I don't know what to tell you,
dude. I feel for you. I said, ' Okay, I
tell you what. How about you stop at
three minutes and quit and come back and
you can do another three. Is that crazy?
Yeah.
But I know that's how it is. And you two
are falling into it. So, I'm telling you
on public
broadcast, be careful. The world is
wanting you not to think, not how to
have critical thinking and not be able
to carry on.
Yeah.
Okay. for 30 minutes, 40 minutes. I bet
half the people.
I'll send you money if you want to prove
it. How many people have dropped off
already?
Oh, I mean that's a great question.
I mean, you probably know the stats. How
many people? They're already
Yeah, they've already tried to scrub to
the end. Where where's the sauce?
They've talked too much. Okay, bad news.
If you want to be financially
independent and your alternative is
what? Keep your job. Go through all of
that. It is risky. You're getting older.
Go go go go go look at anybody else's
statistics. People who retire are poor.
They have no money, no savings, nothing.
Okay. Or do your job if you really love
it, but learn how to fold this right in.
Yeah.
And it can be awesome.
Your income can go up. And then this is
my primary income. Of all the things I
have for income, this is it. Is that
crazy? There's nothing else I do that
I've popped in 20 grand.
Oh, yeah.
This week on my phone.
Is that crazy?
Yeah.
Wow.
So, I trade the YM. Make sure I answer
that question. The NQ. If they go away
tomorrow, I could care less. If my trade
station goes away tomorrow, who cares?
I would cry if they took the mobile app
away.
Yes. Yeah.
Okay. So, when you're learning, don't do
it on a phone. be in front of a
computer. Pay attention. Take this thing
seriously.
If I can get them to go serious,
quick. Focus. Give up some of your
Netflix binging. Okay.
Yeah.
Let's go learn something here.
Uh you can get there pretty quick. Yeah.
It don't take years.
Yeah.
All right.
Okay. I know that's a tricky one because
I I know if it took me years, but that's
because we talked about I I didn't take
it that seriously. You weren't even
ready.
Yeah. Yeah. I had to find my own way
back to it.
And and the reason I had you and your
sister come into my videos, Lauren
wasn't o old enough at the time. Okay.
But uh the reason I had you guys do it
because you knew nothing. Yeah.
I could get true honest responses.
Yeah, that's true.
That's what I was looking for.
Okay.
People love it. They love it. Uh, matter
of fact, I had someone the other day who
who've seen you because you're so
popular out there and uh but they were
in my course said Tori was so young.
I know. I know. I was a little older
than they think probably. I think I was
maybe 22, 23.
Something like that. Yeah.
But yeah, I think it can be I think with
the right amount of focus and discipline
and like if you can really just strip
away the distractions, I think you can
make it a lot quicker. Oh, yeah. It's a
simple strategy, but it's for some
people takes longer to strip that
distraction away. I think that was my
case, too.
So, if they're willing to do that to
undo, you rewrite to how you think. I'm
not kidding. I have a total different
thinking process when I go into trading.
For example, if I said, you guys might
not know this, the video guy over here,
he might know this. Okay. What's a good
What's a good rate of return?
That's a great question. I don't know
if you guys if you want to respond to
that, Fono, what uh what's a good
interest rate rate of return in the
world on your money? If you're at your
bank and you say, "Hey,
it's probably not as much as I think.
It's four or five percent." Really?
Okay. That's that's like Whoa.
Okay.
Okay. Overall, the stock market, if you
invest in that, maybe they say 10. I
don't know where they come up with that,
but they sell people on 5%.
Okay.
That's what everyone thinks. Okay? You
go to any banking, any institution, all
that stuff, it's four or five percent.
That's just what it is.
They keep you poor.
The whole thinking is poor. Okay.
That kind of I had to rewrite all of
that.
Oh, yeah.
I I generate 100%
with your trade the other day.
100% gain in a month.
Oh, yeah. It's a totally different way
of thinking.
It's crazy.
Okay. Yeah.
So, that's why I'll tell you this. When
you go to post, which you might have
done it already. I posted one of my
trades, which was a good trade. I've had
many, but I posted one. They don't
believe you.
Oh, I know.
They get, "Oh, I can't get there." So, I
realize I I I'm I'm helping people more
when I say, "How would you like to make
250 to 500 bucks?" It's within their
scope of belief.
Yeah.
If I would have told you you're going to
make 40,000 bucks one day,
you
tricky tricky. Yeah.
In this video, get one of those things.
Thought.
Yeah. Okay.
You can't believe it. It's not there.
Now you can do it.
You're looking forward to it the next
time. You already know how to do it. And
now you're thinking bigger. And why not?
It's so awesome. Why? What's changed?
Did the two buttons change? No. Did the
instruments change? Did the clocks
change? Did the weather change? Did Did
anything else change?
It was only thinking.
Isn't that interesting?
Change here. Change here changes
everything.
So, we can help people.
Oh, yeah.
It's awesome. It's fantastic.
What else?
Time frame.
How much time frame?
What time frame do you
Oh, do I trade in?
Yeah.
Okay.
another non
important
that's correct but they're standard
questions or normal questions. Okay. But
it's it's uh the only reason there's
time frames. The only reason there's a
chart is for us to kind of break it up a
little bit to think we got something.
Okay.
Have we been talking for five minute
sections here? Yes. Have we been talking
for a 10 minute section? Yes. Have we
been talking for 30 minutes? It's all
the same.
Yeah. It's just how we want to slice it
at the moment. Yeah. Right.
So, time frame is nothing.
Yeah.
What's a better question?
That's normal question. Uh here's a
there's a whole list of the the wrong
questions. But keep in mind,
I was asking the same wrong questions.
Okay. Because I came from the same
uh grouping of thinkers that were
programmed by the world on how to think.
Yeah.
What's my win loss ratio?
Oh gosh. What's your win percentage?
What's your win percentage?
There are multiple.
What? All that stuff.
Trust me, I know
those are the same normal questions
because
now we're on the other side. It's like,
okay, but not taking that like you're
dumb because I asked those questions.
Yeah. That's all I knew to ask.
Right. Right.
I would go to the bank and all I would
know to ask is, hey, what's the money
market producing now?
Four, five percent.
Okay. That's all I knew. That was my
limitation. Mhm.
Now it would be where can I make 100%.
100% on my money. If I invest 10,000,
I'm looking to generate 10 this month.
If I generate a hundred, put in a 100,
I'm looking
that was un unth thought of. Okay.
So, um my time frame is they're all the
same time.
But to help different views,
but to help it's a different view. Mhm.
Why those views even come about is keep
in mind it's me. It's the person who's
doing the trading is the variable. It's
not my process, my understanding. It's
not the instrument I'm using. It's not
the platform. It's not the time frame.
It's none of that. Right?
The variable
is your thinking. We have to change your
thinking.
There's a scripture that says, "Be
transformed." You're of the world, but
don't be of the in the world, but not of
the world. You've got to change your
mind if you want to get somewhere
different. Okay.
I'm a trader. I'm trading this life for
the afterlife. Ain't that interesting?
Yeah.
I'm always thinking about the big
long-term picture.
What I do here determines that. Okay. my
financials,
what they are, determines what I'm
thinking about. Now, you go do a job,
for example, if you go do and there's a
lot of people have a job, okay? Lots of
people. Were they ever able to say,
"Today, I think I'll go do my job and
and do four times the amount of income.
I'll receive four times the amount of
income." It's not even possible.
So, they wouldn't even tease themselves
to think that way. Mhm.
It's not realistic. They know it can't
happen. That's the first test. You're in
the wrong thing.
When I go into trading, my mind is wide
open.
Yeah.
I didn't know I was going to generate
$4,000 on my phone today.
Right.
Okay. I didn't know 7500 yesterday.
My mind is open.
Yeah.
Isn't that crazy?
You didn't know the other day you were
going to pop in a $40,000 day? No, I did
not.
You see what I'm saying? But you know
now with your thinking
position, new thinking paradigm, that's
possible.
If I engage it correctly, let the market
do its thing,
get in position to let it do its thing.
Wow.
Yeah.
Is that crazy?
So time frames, all that. So it comes
back to the person, how they think. And
so now what it kind of breaks down to is
are you a person that's super fearful?
When I
talk to the people who call me,
I try to go into some questions. Uh for
example, are you a person that's super
fearful?
Do you live on the negative side of life
kind of or more on the positive side of
life?
Okay. And and everybody's different.
Yeah. Um, I I I put people into three
categories
and and not in a bad way. It's just that
they're either they're uh winner
category,
they're wisher category, or they're
whiner
whiner. I remember that.
Wer. Yep.
And they're all good people, good souls.
It's just the way they've put together
in life. The winner is someone who
thinks I can. I want to. I know it's
going to be I don't know what I'm doing,
but I'm willing to try.
Okay. I I've got that in me that I can
get knocked down and try it again. I
want this. I'm I have faith that I can
figure it out. And they do it.
The wisher is, "Wow, that sounds
awesome. That sounds cool. That's
wonderful. Yeah. I wish I could do that,
but they can't ever move kind of.
Okay.
And then the whiners are the ones that
nah nah I I can't do it. I don't know
how to do that. That's too risky. That
don't work anyways. Whatever. Well,
people just find themselves
and and you and me are bouncing between
those.
So, for example, when I see someone
who's a handsome guy and he's got big
muscles, instantly I go, "Hey, I'm going
to work out and be Mr. Muscles."
But when I get home tonight, I go right
back down to Wisher because I'm going to
pop those chips in my face and watch
some TV and do nothing.
I I don't have it. I'm not going to push
to go get muscles that I could care less
about. Yeah.
See what I'm saying? I'm not a whiner
there, but in that space, I'm a wisher.
I admit it.
In finances, that's what we're talking
about here. Which one are you? Which one
are the people who's watching us? Are
you a wisher
and you're and that's where you're
living? Are you a whiner
looking to complain and all that stuff?
Or are you a winner? Does that make
sense?
Oh, yeah.
I think this here's how far I go with
it. Personally, I think the YouTube
people I know you probably don't want me
saying this. You cut it out of you. If
this got cut, you know, I think that
there's so much YouTube content
creators, so much stuff. It's free.
It's designed that way. Did you guys
come up with the 30 second little trash
things and get rid of it and go to the
next one? Tik Tok trash, Insta trash,
whatever. You didn't. Somebody else did.
Somebody put that on our minds, didn't
they? And where are we living? In that
302 world. Yeah.
That goes nowhere.
Okay. I can't think past 30 seconds. I'm
having a blowout. Hey, what's my Did I
miss any messages?
You see what I'm saying? It's crazy.
If people want to be in the winner
category in finances, I'm talking about,
okay, you got to take action.
That means if you're on YouTube, if
you're not The only time you should be
watching a video if you have students,
they should only be watching you,
learning from you, hearing from you.
Don't get confused by hearing 12 other
people.
It's it's terrible. Yeah.
They'll stay confused. The Bible says a
double-minded man is unstable in all of
his ways.
Do I go with the moving average thing,
support and resistance trash, or do I
use that? You know, is it that VWAP
Whatever. Do I get level two?
You know what I mean? Do I need my super
scanner?
I know.
Do I join a group because I'm really
lonely?
[Laughter]
Okay, that's uh that's that's the 90%
qualification. Write a book.
Let me tell you who's in the 90%
category.
And that's why we tell them today.
Yeah.
Do you ever go watch YouTubetubes, all
that stuff? Not really. I don't.
There would be no reason to.
Now, I'm not saying I'm talking about in
referring to trading.
Yeah. No.
Okay.
Occasionally I'll watch something. I
mean occasionally. Remember,
you can tell on my phone. There's zero.
There's zero on any of that stuff. Okay.
I do my business. I make my trades
almost like I'm not making trades. I was
making my trades for a second. Matter of
fact, here's another test. Something
that I tell people. If you're looking at
the screen,
you're intending to push the button.
Okay. If you're not
If you're not intending to push the
button, you should not be looking at the
screen.
Okay.
That's scary.
Yeah.
Whoa. That's how I live by not looking
at the screen because I know I know how
to think now. Yeah. Okay. When I go to
look at the screen, it's because I'm
intending to do something.
Yeah.
You don't sit there and just watch that
thing.
Whatever.
Scary, happy, scary, happy. Okay.
Whatever. That's that's you're in the
90% camp.
All right. What else?
I mean, the basic things that I always
get asked is I have to I have to come up
with the answers. I had to say this is
my win percentage. This is my win to
loss ratio. This is my I don't trade
with R multiples. This is my percentage
of risk. So, I had to go through that.
You were willing to take a different
route to me.
Yeah.
I'm more for
I don't know why, but I'm more Let's get
right to it.
Yeah.
Let's Let's spend a couple hours and let
me show you what to do.
So, I'm probably not as friendly. Not
that I'm not as friendly. I'm not as uh
whatever. I'm just more a matterof fact
utility kind of person. Yeah. You guys
probably find me boring. You know what
I'm saying? Kind of. You know what I
mean? But we're gonna we're gonna go
somewhere. I'm gonna get us there. Yeah.
You know what I mean? We need to do
something. I'm getting it fixed.
I'm just That's my brain. Purposedriven,
utility driven. Uh the reason I have the
phone is because it's a tool.
Yeah.
The only reason I trade the only reason
I trade I really don't want to trade,
right?
That's kind of interesting, isn't it?
Yeah. But I still need income.
Okay. I think I need income.
Remember that.
Okay. Everything's changing.
Thankfully, I've generated good. I don't
know what's going on here. They're
always listening to us.
I know.
So, anyway, I trade because I like new
fresh income. I need new fresh income.
My goal happens to be $1,000.
Okay. If I could pop in a thousand
dollars a day doing my little trading
thing, I can live and be happy.
Yeah,
that's just awesome.
So, that's why I trade. I don't like
thinking about it. So, I took the time,
get it down, and now I really don't have
to think about it. I just do it.
Okay, you're a little more
accommodating.
you guys want to ask me 400 questions
and uh and and at the end I'll you know
tell you you really didn't want to ask
me those questions. Here's what you want
to ask me so I can get you there.
I'm more like let's just get there.
Yeah.
So
just different I appreciate the
entertainment
aspect. Yeah.
And and and listen
and you're you're so you got such a good
personality and you do too. You guys are
different than me. We're God made us all
differently, right? You guys need to be
in publicly and uh uh whatever it's
called. Uh you guys like movie stars,
okay? I mean, you got those qualities
about you. Got good looks, you're nice,
you're young, you're friendly, you're
honest, you're that kind of person. I'm
just a boring old utility. You want to
know how to trade, I'll get you there.
Yeah.
You want to get that fixed? Let's do it.
Yeah,
just different.
So,
and people resonate with different they
do different
mentors. Different ones, different ones.
So, it's wonderful though, isn't it?
It's the course.
You like to say that you can say that
you're getting close to saying it.
I can see it because I see it.
You get to see the people who are
watching this are uh
you know, I know how they're thinking.
They're trying to see are they really
honest
because on the web you got to have that
honesty filter because man it's crazy.
Okay. I actually think this um people
who are going to claim to want to help
people in this space anyway
should have you know I say this I don't
believe this but I like the notion of
it.
Okay. a test. Okay.
Okay.
Uh that Okay. Not I made one good trade
and I can trade. I think you need to
trade x amount of years.
I don't care if you made a ton of money
or not. Go through it for x amount of
years before you even get to do it.
Yeah,
that would be something. Uh validation.
But let's say you someone does that. I
waited 20 years. I could show them all
my tax return. The tax return is the
truth. Yeah. It's nothing else. Okay.
The problem with that is unless they
come to your house and go into your file
cabinet and pull out the thing
themselves, if you produce it on a
camera,
they're not going to
that's a lie.
Because it could be a lie.
Yeah.
You know what I mean? There are movies
and there's movies you think that really
happened. That was made up.
That's So everyone knows thing can be
made up. So they really can't tell
here. Okay. So I say when you go to
learn, always learn at first. You're
wanting to believe me. I know that.
That's why you bought my program. They
want to believe me, but you just cannot.
But you can start applying it. And when
you see it happen from you pushing the
buttons and the money starting to come
in, you will believe it then.
Yeah.
Okay. You'll prove it to yourself.
That's the only time you prove it to
yourself.
Yeah.
Then you'll do it.
Yeah. Oh, yeah.
So, the questions are, are you a
scaredy-cat? Remember I asked you that a
minute ago? You guys think I ask a
question, then I go off on a little
tangent. I do that for a purpose.
There's a different type of teaching
style. I go off a moment, but I always
spiral back to come back to it. Okay.
So,
students, you should ask your students,
what kind of person are you? Are you
scared? Are or do you just Is that how
you think? Is this really scary to you?
Is it risky to you? How about this? Are
you a person that gets angry?
How about you? I'm gonna ask you to on
public TV right now. Do you get angry?
No, not really. Rarely.
You're driving down the road and someone
cuts you off. What do you do?
I don't even honk.
You know, you know, some people kind of
give them their pinky.
Okay. Right. or they cuss or whatever go
off. Right.
There's people have anger issues.
If you're an anger person,
I'm telling you,
you're not gonna like that. Tough.
Trading is going to just get you angry.
Yeah.
Okay. Because
are you a blamer?
Do you kind of look to blame others for
things that aren't working out or
whatever? You want to blame God? You
want to blame your spouse? You want to
blame your kids? Blame your crummy
parents. Everybody blames your parents.
That's fair. That's fair. You want to
blame, you want to blame, you a blamer,
come to trading, they will teach you how
to blame.
Who are you going to blame? The market.
Yeah, that's and it will. You want to
blame
all the internet people, they, you know,
whatever.
Your mentor, the market, whatever,
whatever. Okay.
It's you, how you think these little
line item things
are the points of resistance to you
being successful.
Think about it. I'm pushing two buttons.
A blue one and a red one. Is yours blue
and red?
Um, green and red.
How did you get yours green?
Um, I think there's settings on Trading.
Oh,
you changed it.
And I'm using a new platform, which I
probably won't get you over on Trading
View instead of Trade Station.
Okay, good. Trading View is a a great
little charting thing. I mean, for using
it. Um, I tell people to go practice
there.
Yeah, it's a good spot to practice.
Great place. So, um All right. So, but
the two buttons is it? Yeah.
Is it called buy and sell?
Yeah,
probably.
Or long and short.
Long and short. Did your say long or
short?
It probably says buy and sell. You know
better not.
Buy and sell. So, it's the same two
buttons.
How do we get to it? How do I get to
pushing which button? The correct button
at the right time. What I'm seeing, what
I'm hearing goes up against my file
system
and it just sends out the signal. Mhm.
You and I and other you can teach people
how to do that. And of course there's a
million people that say they can teach
how to do it.
Yeah.
And maybe they can. There's there's a
couple people that if I had to trade Oh,
let me ask you this. Do you trade
shortterm or longer term? That's part of
that question you asked earlier. Right.
There's Do you know what a scalper is?
Real quick.
Real quick. Okay. You know what a swing
trader is?
Oh yeah. You talk about that, right?
Swing trader, what's the difference?
There is no difference. It's how much
time you put in between the two. See,
there's us humans. Let's call a scalper,
day trader, uh, whatever, short-term
trader, a swing trader, or an investor.
They all are pushing the buy button and
sell button, but they like to put a
badge on.
Yeah.
It's stupid.
Okay. Means nothing.
Let the market tell you, "Hey, we're
going to give you money now if you do
this now."
Okay. Ding.
Here's my ideal. What's your ideal
student?
Um like their personality
kind of just whatever. If you said real
quick, here's my ideal student.
It is an entrepreneur. Um somebody
because they are already in the mindset
of I need to have multiple streams of
income. So the pressure is not heavy on
one source.
Okay.
So I'd say entrepreneur is probably if I
had to make it that broad, entrepreneur
is the best trader.
Okay. Any ideas?
Somebody who is I think I know
totally somebody who has not been
trained totally new.
Okay.
I was going to say I could be way going
off a liar. Is it are women better
traders?
I think I think so.
Okay. All three of that
a woman
who's got some entrepreneurial who's
never known anything about trading.
All right.
Okay.
Because each of those bring potential
problems.
First of all, this is a fluidy kind of
type of
grooving with it. Whatever you call it,
right? That way. musicians, people who
are musicians. You two both are great
musicians, singers and all that.
Uh it's got a rhythm to it.
You just you just naturally do it. Me,
unfortunately, I
I just can't do it. I would be much
better if I could.
Uh not knowing anything about it is my
best student
because I can simply say, "You see this?
You see that? Do this
easy. You see this? You see that? Do
this.
See this? See that? Do this. And I'll
repeat that. And they will before you
know it, they see this. They see that.
They do this. And they're off and going.
Someone comes to me who's already
learned about it. They've already opened
their file up. They've dumped all the
poison in.
They can't help it. Even if you say,
"Yeah, I want to learn what you're
saying, Mike." They now have to, and the
mind does not want to admit, "You dummy.
You spent six years of all this stupid
stuff. You're going to have to go back
and tell your friends and your family
that you were nuts. You were off base
the whole time."
Yeah,
that's hard. Kind of like that. A newbie
is best.
Oh, yeah.
But here's a drawback. Everything has a
pros and con to it. The newbie, I show
them how to trade and they go start
doing it. Thank you, Mike. That was
awesome. Thank you very much. You're a
great guy. And they go off. The person
who's already been trying for several
years
and I show them how to do it. When they
get it, they can't stop.
Wow. Thank you. This is wonderful. They
just stay on it because it's taken them
so long to get there.
The newbie just thinks like you go to a
restaurant, you expect a good meal.
Thank you very much. It was great.
You're out of there. But you've had bad
meals. Now you go to have a great meal.
Who's the chef?
Right.
Bring them out here.
That's right. So,
so those are the things of the people.
So, back to another thing I talked about
and come back to. I personally think
YouTube if there's any value all your
subscribers you got a bunch of
subscribers which is wonderful people
like you myself I say you want to hear
what I've got to say I really want to
deal with the serious ones I'm charging
you something
I'm not charging you something to make
money you make plenty of money I'm
charging you because it's a gateway to
yourself
wake up do you really want to do this.
We're going to class. We're going to
school. We're rewriting who we are.
We're undoing you. Okay. So, is it worth
50 bucks? If it's not, go find all the
other ones. Yeah.
You want to know where the nine out of
10 people who don't make it live out
there?
Yep.
Okay.
One of these days, you're going to get
bold and say, "All right."
Yeah. I'm gonna put them Yeah. Oh, yeah.
when I get tired of answering all the
questions and
it's it's it's it's it sounds kind of on
the one hand the whiners will complain
and the wishers will be disappointed but
the winners understand
yes I'm committed now I want to do this
now I want to break free from the the
job bondage type of thing
who wants a boss who wants to be told as
an adult when you're able to take a
potty break.
Yeah, it's crazy
when you can go on vacation and when you
can't and how many days you get and what
a game that's just you're an adult.
I know. It's crazy.
Why not? And this mechanism, whoever
came up with it, it's just wonderful.
Yeah.
And now that you can do it on your
phone, it's like I feel like I'm on
another plan.
Yeah. It's the coolest crazy.
It really is.
Every time I pull into a fast food place
and I'm whatever and I'm getting I'm not
kidding. I do it every time. I'm think
if I could just get that person to
listen.
Yeah.
For a few minutes.
They could do what I'm doing.
Yeah. There's no That's the coolest part
is you could have a broken leg. You
could be
anything years old. You could be 18
years old. Probably not. But
for the most part, you could be anyone.
Anyone. Anyone. There's exceptions all
the way through it.
Yeah. But it's way cool.
All right. So, here's what I'm going to
tell you. I'm just going to say it all.
You cut out what you don't want.
Okay. Fair.
Okay.
Uh,
your people, tell them to own up. You in
or you're not in. Okay. If people Here's
another Remember the qualifications I
was talking about. Which group are you
in? Remember what the three are?
Winners, wishers, whiners. They're in
one of them. And And you can be in it
depending on what space we're talking
about. Okay.
uh religious matters with me. I'm a
winner into that. I don't need anybody
to prompt me to say believe in God,
trust in God, follow in that way. Dude,
I'm in 100%. My finances, I'm totally
about it. And I see the results of that
life living that way. Working out,
things like that, I'm a wisher. Am I a
whiner about anything?
Not too much. I just fortunately don't
hang out there too much. But you know
what I'm talking about. Okay.
Yeah.
So now with this in your space, if you
can get everybody to own up to get
serious.
Yeah.
Oh, decision making. Are you scared?
If you're coming to trading and you're
scared about things, if this trading is
like here's another major problem I
have. So far, it's still usually men
that contact me. I don't know about you,
but it's men that contact me. First
problem that person has, he sees it,
he's interested in it. First problem, I
call it the spousal effect.
Oh,
he's got to go get his wife to get on
board. I got to go get permission
because my wife, this is like risky,
scary gambling and everything. And I
feel for there's a lot of guys that are
shut down. And I'm thinking, dude,
you're willing to go take some chances,
take some risk to better your family, to
go for it. You You might not make it.
You might fail, but you're willing to go
for it.
But because your wife's too scared or
whatever, shutting you down and so many
people are robbed. They're robbing
themselves. In your case, if you can get
people to own up in or not, if you want
free content,
go to all the the garbage pit.
Yeah.
I went to the garbage place recently.
Have you ever been to a garbage dump?
An official dump.
I haven't.
Have you been?
Yeah. In Middle.
It's pretty amaz I don't know if the
Middle one the one you went to. Talking
about a real dump.
Oh, okay. Okay.
Phenomenal. Crazy. I took a little video
because I had to go dump some stuff. I'm
talking mountains.
Okay, I see. I see.
Oh, there's a pile of mountains of
electronics and
refrigerated. Okay, just mountain of it.
And then there's a mountain of this.
It's just crazy. So much trash out
there. That's what I think of the
public, YouTube, all that free stuff.
Because people are going because it's
free. I'm edutaining
myself and I've been doing this for a
while and I still don't make any more
money.
Come on, let's get with it.
Yeah.
Why don't we make a plan to get you
generating just a couple hundred bucks a
day really quick?
Yeah.
And then you can grow from there.
Wouldn't that make sense?
Wouldn't it be wonderful for people?
You didn't want Are you proud that you
took nine years to get where you did?
No.
No. Okay. It's because you were young. I
started you young. You're a test.
I'm a test.
Test two baby. Okay.
Now, because that I had to have that for
that that honesty reason why. But you
got there. Okay. But now you can get
people there quicker.
Yeah.
Really quick.
And why not? So, don't watch any YouTube
stuff. Get rid of all the free time. I
mean the the free
free content
those free contenty apps things people
on their phone. I don't even have them
on my phone. Okay. I don't even want to
be induced to do it.
And uh I focus. And guess what? Because
I paid that price and it wasn't a price
really. I decided to go that route.
I don't work.
Yeah.
For for since you two have been born. I
I've never seen that.
Isn't that crazy?
Yeah,
that's how it can be. Why did I go to
college? I don't even know how to think
about that college stuff. Right.
Right.
I'm opposed to it, matter of fact.
But I learned how the world works and
particularly with finances. And here's
something that somebody created. Learn
how to do this.
And wow,
it's crazy. It's like, wow. Are you sure
we're on the same place?
I know, right? I know
it's wonderful.
All your little followers could get
there.
You gota It's up to you to kind of
push them a little bit.
I mean, it's kind of tough.
It is. It's hard.
But hey, listen. Would you rather have
uh a thousand people that you've got
trading full-time and wow or 250,000
that just come and watch them freestyle?
Yeah.
Give me my coke and whatever and leave.
And
I'm not saying they're bad people. I I I
could have been into that or whatever.
We all fall into it. So try not to take
I hope anybody who's watching is not
like I'm putting down anybody because
I'm really not. But I will kind of tease
you a little bit to try to prompt you
out of a position that you're in.
Yeah.
You don't want to be a free content uh
consumer
consumer. Okay. Get serious. It's your
life. Next year you'll be a year older.
When I started trading
at 37 and now I'm 65.
Isn't that crazy? Sounds old as the
hills, don't it? Can you see my hair?
I'm getting
great. Are you getting some?
Yeah. Oh, yeah.
So, uh,
it's just wonderful. So, we're talking
finances, how to think. It's about
changing what you do.
Everyone who's got a normal thinking
mind can qualify.
Uh there are things you will have to
rewrite in your thinking. If I'm a
scaredy-cat, well, good. If I come up to
you right now, I was thinking about
this. If I get close to you and I
do this right in front of your face, I
bet you will flinch. Yeah.
You want to come over here and let me do
it?
You see what I'm saying?
And you will flinch because that's the
way it is. But after I do it a couple
times,
yeah,
you will
and occasionally I'm gonna pop you, but
once in a while you're gonna get one in
the eye, but overall you can withstand
that, right?
You learn to be in an uncomfortable
environment and become comfortable just
like everything else. Just like
everything else,
that's how it was trading. It's
phenomenal.
I remember, have you ever had a loss?
Oh, yeah. losing trade.
Oh yeah. Oh yeah.
How about like when you were down a 100
bucks? Like a and then you someday you
grew and it was 500.
Yeah.
Have you ever been down big?
What?
Um I was down almost 30,000.
Okay. $30,000. That's hard to believe,
isn't it?
And you're still living, breathing,
going on. Still here. Okay. You learn
how to manage that. But now it's no big
deal. You learn to become comfortable
where you used to not be comfortable.
Yeah. You learn what input used to cause
you to react this way is now you've
taken control of that and you're
thinking this way.
It's really
simple
if you're willing to undo you and
rewrite it. Well, thank you guys for
inviting me to come over.
Yeah.
Forcing you
forcing me to do this.
Forcing me to do it. I hope it helps. I
hope it helps you too because uh what I
like uh both is that you guys have good
spirits,
people who who uh train people. They
don't have good spirits, it's not good.
So, you guys do. So, and I'm here to
help. I'm here to help add that extra
little something that
I would have that you guys wouldn't have
yet.
Exactly. Yeah. Yeah.
I mean, I could give so many cool
examples,
even examples you don't even know about.
Yeah,
man. I've I've learned how to untangle
the mind in a fascinating way. So, uh,
it's pretty cool.
We need like a weekly.
Yeah.
Oh, untangling of the mind. That's what
it is.
What is it? Unwrite. Rewrite yourself.
Rewrite your mind.
Yeah.
All right. Look out for it. Maybe it's a
weekly thing. It's going to be behind a
payw wall.
Yeah. Believe it.
We want serious people only
and and that is it. Okay? Because it
just is the way it is. Prove it wrong.
If you if you want to go prove this
wrong, then go spend some time and try
to prove this wrong. Okay? But the the
stats everyone knows in any discipline
of any field.
Go do it for free. Give free content.
You just kind of listen. I've got two
pens. I've got a pin that's a $20 pin
that you paid for and I got a pen that
is uh free. Okay. Two writing pins and
um
the writing pen really is smooth. That
baby, you know, we've had a good pen
that rides. I love that.
I love a good pen.
Okay. The pen I bought it's okay. All
right. But it's nice, but it's just not
as smooth whatever that's in that. And
you forgot the two pins somewhere.
Which pen are you going to go get?
The one you spent your money on for
sure.
Why? The other one you just said better.
There's just an attachment.
It writes better. You like it.
You see what I'm saying?
Yeah.
You will go get the one you paid money
for. Everything's like that.
Yeah. I remember uh one of our kids when
we had the car. Hey, you know, do this,
do that, whatever. Okay. Never. We
bought them their car. They bought their
car. They bought their car. Okay.
And uh guess where it started being
parked not under the oak tree and all
the stuff. It got parked in the garage.
Yep.
And it just it just changed because now
there was a financial component to it's
mine. I paid for it. I've invested into
it.
It just works differently.
Yeah.
That's why I charge people.
To get them prepared.
Okay. Awesome.
That was so awesome.
That's a wrap.
All right, guys. Well, thanks for
watching.
How do they find us?
Tradingmplate.com.
Tory trades
trades with Lauren.
Awesome.
All right. Thanks for hanging out, guys.
Dude, way cool that I got to share Uncle
Mike with somebody. Like, he probably
just blew so many people's minds.
I don't know. Okay.
It was uh it was helpful if I were to
say what would I try to communicate as I
thought about this was to get them
prepared on which way to go.
Yeah.
Not that I'm entertaining because there
was nothing entertaining here. I didn't
tell them how to trade. They don't know
how to make any more money today. We got
to start when you're going to build
something. You've got to start first.
We're going to build a house. We don't
need to talk about shingles, insulation
d electrical taxes.
We got to start here. My foundation.
Everything hinges on that.
Which So which way are you going to go?
Mentor or try it on your own? Mentor,
then lock in. Yep. I only stay with you.
Drill them. Question them. Whatever you
got to do, get it there. That's it.
Yeah. And then you can get there.