hi everyone and welcome back to my forex
channel so in this video i will show you
my go-to strategy using two moving
averages
so this strategy can be used on any time
frame you like and it works the best on
any jpy currency pass since japanese yen
currencies tend to trend quite a bit and
this
strategy also works in a super simple
way which is a following the trend so
either
the upside or the downside i just want
to let you know that this
strategy will not work for you let's say
on
your gbb or usd swiss franc because
these currencies
are just totally different as every
currency parent has the different
mindset i will show you a few examples
so you will see that this
actually works and it will work on the
future trades
as well alright guys so the first step
is to add two moving averages of periods
and 50. i have mine already on but for
you just go in indicators type in
ma or moving average does not really
matter double click because you will
need two of them
and just change the settings i think it
comes in tonight so just change to 50
and
25 and if you have any questions or
issues you can address them in my
comment section down below or just feel
free to contact me on my instagram so
let's have a quick
view of our price action so i am
currently on ncd jpy
one hour chart i have identify my
horizontal areas of sensitivity because
it's been respected couple of times and
i do see that it's been
a downtrend form inside of our zones but
then the sellers failed to push the
price towards the downside because the
buyers came into the market by forming a
channel and it's super clear that we are
having a squeezed pattern because of our
channel and our resistance zone
showing that there's no much space for
the market to move plus our moving
averages is also indicating us that the
more than likely the bulls are coming
into the market and they will push the
market towards the upside so what we are
actually waiting for is for the retest
on a lower trend line
of our channel and we are waiting for
that break through
our resistance zone so let's just take a
look
as you can see it's smartly fluctuating
it did respect it over here but now
we're just waiting for the break and
confirmation and as you can see
we have another retest on our lower
channel line and the moving averages as
well
let's just continue and as you can see
we have a break and as you can see
we tested moving average appear 25 plus
lower uptrend breakthrough resistance
with a clear confirmation from the balls
as we having a bullish engulfing candle
and we would be entering along
over there so we are entering on the
bullish engulfing candle the stop
loss must be below of our both moving
averages and
we would be profiting around 59.3 pips
so far and by looking at this trade we
would be looking by taking this into the
portions because by
looking at the past we have some sort of
horizontal area of sensitivity so you
know based on
a past price action this is where would
be portioning and we still will be
profiting just in case of course if the
market will decide to turn around you'll
still be reaching around
31 33 pips in the profit so you know
once you
having your tp1 taking you will probably
have to move your
stop loss to an entry and keep going for
the maximum you can reach
so now let's just take a look on the
next example as well and it's really
really close as the key principle for
this strategy is to follow the trend so
here we have
a clear flag pattern so when the market
is in consolidation
or in this flat pattern we are not
actually looking for any
entries we are actually looking for that
price action to tell us that we have a
confirmation to enter a trade so in this
scenario we have
a bullish english candle over here and
we will be entering because it's in
between of our moving averages so we
will be profiting around 40 pips of
course our stop loss must be below of
our moving averages so now take a look
over here the same chart following the
trend and as i said generally speaking
japanese yen currency is tend to trend a
lot that's what they do since the
beginning
of the invention of the forex so here we
go we have another great example of
a buy entry we have the market is some
sort of consolidation yes we had a nice
bullish engulfing candle but we wouldn't
be entering a trade because it was
outside of moving
averages so the best entry opportunity
is when the candlesticks is
above of moving averages or they are in
between so one of the good qualities of
the forex trader is to basically be a
patient so basically we are waiting for
a better opportunity for this trade and
as we can see
we have a push and exhaustion with a
lovely bullish engulfing candle and this
is
where we would be entering and we will
be profiting around 81.8 pips stop loss
is below of moving averages and
more than likely we will be taking
profit in the portion so you know once
the tp1 is reached we are moving
our stop loss to an entry so this is
what we will be doing we will just be
carrying on doing this
it's very simple very easy to use all
you need is to find a right
trend of 25 and 50 moving averages on
for an entry purposes and stop-loss
levels but also don't forget to identify
your support resistance
zones depending on the market condition
and if you join the video smash the like
button and comment down below and i will
talk to you later bye
[Music]
you