okay guys we are back with another 5
minute trading session this is a live
account this is real money this is me
getting back into day trading getting
back into the five minute time frame and
we are down
$200 200 bucks okay 187 now 175 but wow
I forget how freaking exciting this is
so much happens in just a few minutes so
I made a previous video where I was in
one trade before this one price had
gotten to my stop loss and I needed to
reverse now just these are things that
I'm I'm going to walk through just
getting back into the 5-minute time
frame some things that I need to put
into place helping me master this time
frame make better decisions and walk you
guys through the strategy and what an
open trade looks like an open Live trade
I don't know how else to show you guys
that this is real besides we've got
trade station here I'll pull it up you
guys can see this is an open account
we've got this position open right here
I'll let you guys see the last four of
the account number so that you guys can
cross reference on all of my videos you
know that is my one account you guys can
even weed through and make sure that
account balances are making sense that
trades are making sense this is the same
account that I've been showing you guys
so this is a real live trade open on my
trading view account I have trade
station connected or synced to trading
view so that I can place all my trades
here instead of having to do it in the
brokerage account but right now we've
got an open position I am in a long
position in Copper on a 5 minute time
frame and let me walk through some some
things that I I want to put into place
moving forward this is fun I'm in a
position I'm so grateful that I'm in a
position to where I can experiment with
a live trade I'm in an open trade right
now just having fun in the five minute
time frame I'm so grateful that I am in
a position to do that I don't recommend
it but I can do it so watch me we're in
the 5-minute time frame I reversed a
position to go long right here when the
downward trend line was crossed so you
guys know I'm a trend line Trader
especially a trend line break Trader so
when a when we get a break of a trend
line I'm either thinking long positions
or short positions if we get a break of
an upward trend line I'm thinking short
positions if we get a break of a
downward trend line I'm thinking long
positions and you guys if you've been
following along my journey if you've
been following along my YouTube videos
you can probably piece together my
strategy I've got action lines and
safety lines safety lines are
essentially what keeps my risk mitigated
it is where my stop- loss goes on the
other side of that's where I'm willing
to let the price come to that's the loss
I'm willing to take when I'm in a
position is my safety line sometimes my
safety line is in profit sometimes it's
in loss and then the action line is the
original line that gets crossed that's
telling me to get in to take action so
right now we're down 100 bucks and some
things that I want to talk about that I
would like like to implement in this you
know going back to the F minute time
frame is now that I have time and I can
make decisions a lot quicker I'm not
looking at 4 hours worth of price
movement on One Singular candle I can
put some things into place to help me
make better decisions especially since
I'm making decisions quick so if we are
thinking of getting into a trade because
a line is broken I'm sure you guys
experienced a lot of fake outs in the 5
minute time frame where price looks like
it's Crossing it's poking through and
then turns around in the other direction
what things can we put into place to
help us make better decisions and avoid
some of those fake Fouts and the first
thing is we can wait for the candle to
close so we can wait for that full 5
minutes to make sure that the candle
breaks on the other side of the line so
we've got a downward trend line price
broke through I immediately reversed my
position I mean it happens to be working
out a little bit better right now but I
was in draw down about 200 bucks just a
few minutes ago now we're only down 112
but I want a little bit more confidence
in my trade or a little bit more
confirmation that price is truly
breaking and what better way to do that
by waiting for the candle to close so if
I had waited for the candle to close
instead of just immediately reversing my
position from short to long I probably
would be feeling a little bit more
comfortable right now and I wouldn't
have entered that trade I wouldn't have
reversed I'd still be in that same
original trade I would have been up and
probably back to only you know up a few
dollars right now by waiting for the
candle to close it just gives me a
little bit more confirmation a little
bit more confidence that price truly is
changing direction so this is something
that I maybe would have done a little
bit differently so instead I'm down 150
bucks I would have felt better if I had
waited for this candle to close to feel
more confident about switching taking
that long position so right now I am
still in a long position I'm wanting the
price to continue up now what's keeping
me in this trade why am I still in this
trade but I'm down 150 bucks it is this
line right here keeping me safe my
safety line until price breaks this
upward line which it touched once it
touched twice it very well could touch
it again or it could break it and then
it have to solidify this loss but this
is the only reason I'm still in this
trade is because price is still
respected this upward trend line my
safety line let's kind of watch it
together let's see all right I'm down
137 50 are we going to get any more
movement of course it decides to do
nothing right now as we're just sitting
here looking at it what would I want to
do with my lines right now if I want a
little bit more confirmation what I'm
going to do is I'm going to take this
line and rotate it to this new high
where copper came up to
4.5 37 is and then fell down so now if
I'm considering taking a position or
maybe you're not in any positions right
now I'm in a long position I'm going to
give it until it breaks this upward
trend line but let's say that you're not
in a position right now you would have
your lines exactly where mine are and
you would simply just wait for the price
to break one of these two right now it's
smack dab in the middle it's in the
middle of this downward line and this
upward line now you just sit on your
hands and you wait for a good position
and wait for one of these to get broken
we don't know if you know the downward
line or the upward line is going to get
broken so we're simply going to wait and
some things that I may be recommend is
wait for the candle to close once it
does break once one of these candles
breaks this downward line or this upward
line let's wait for the candle to close
it's only 5 minutes I'm sure you've got
5 minutes to wait to just have a little
bit more confidence about this position
that you're in so let's wait for 5
minutes let's wait for that candle to
close CL and if it still has broken that
line let's take that position let's get
in and now we have an action line which
is the one that got crossed and then the
opposing line is our safety line that's
the one that's going to keep us in seems
easy right but now we're on the 5 minute
time frame so we're going to be making a
lot more trades we're going to be making
a lot more decisions very quickly price
moves and Es and flows so much in the 5-
minute time frame so just be prepared
for that to be honest I'm excited I
haven't had this much adrenaline in a
trade in a really long time so now I'm
down 150 it was down 170 a second ago
now it's 150 I was up up you know 70
bucks earlier in this trade so this is a
lot of fun but making sure that you also
mitigating your risk do not go over 1 to
5% of your Capital especially if you
guys are new Traders making sure that
you have a good strategy maybe it's not
my strategy but making sure that you
have full confidence in the strategy
that you use and you are mitigating your
risk you're abiding by your rules
outside of just psychology which is a
whole another ball game so making sure
that outside of psychology youve got
your strategy down right now I got my
strategy down like the back of my hand I
could trade this strategy on any time
frame a one minute a one hour a monthly
a weekly right now we're trading the 5
minute the strategy I've got down the
psychology is always different is always
new I'm always finding out new things
about myself as I'm trading right now I
shouldn't have this much adrenaline in a
trade but I do and maybe it's because I
also had an injury drink not too long
ago but it's way fun to be in this five
minute time frame so let's kind of watch
this let's see what it does I'll maybe
leave this up on the screen recording
and I'll pause my audio and then we'll
kind of watch this play out in fast time
and then I can go back through and
explain what I did or how this trade
went all right guys so you got to see
what price does within just a few
minutes here we are down 300 bucks but
that's okay that's all right if you guys
are trading comfortably also understand
that copper has much smaller versions so
I'm trading a mini version of copper
it's a little bit more expensive a
little bit more pricey but I'm able to
you know stomach a loss like this or
handle a loss like this or just even a
position like this but if you guys are
new to Futures Trading and you've got
much smaller Capital much smaller
position sizes or much smaller starting
balances we've got something called the
micros which is going to be one tenth of
what I'm Trading so you may only be down
28 bucks instead of 20 287 or and then
you have the ability to trade multiple
micros so maybe you you want to scale in
and out a little bit whereas I'm trading
Just One Mini I can't go any lower than
that that's just one singular mini but
when you have the ability to trade the
micros you can trade three micros five
micros maybe even Just One Singular
micros just to kind of dip your toes in
just to get a feel for what it's like to
trade the Futures Market but understand
that you guys have the ability to to
mitigate your risk and to come in much
lower in position size than I'm in so
experiment with the micros see what it's
like understand you know how much a
micro costs how much the risk is
involved in your account size making
sure that we're trading between you know
1 and 3% of our Capital size and right
now I want to show you guys why I'm
getting ready to solidify this loss and
why I may be considering short positions
and getting right back into it so we're
at a 5 minute time frame we're making a
lot of decisions real quick so right now
I am down 262 I'm going to reverse this
position so I was in a long position
now I'm thinking of going short so we're
going to take our Mouse to this open
position and we've got this fancy little
literal reverse button okay you didn't
get to hear the sound but usually you
get it you get a little ding okay now we
are in a short position so I was long It
reversed me to go short now what am I
thinking here I solidified a loss and I
consider that I call those fees so when
I am taking losses in the market I
consider it a fee like everything else
that you pay in life when you do
literally everything I've got door Dash
coming I had to pay a fee to get that
door Dash over here so I look at losses
in the market as fees it is as per usual
you'll pay fees and everything in life
and that's trading is not exempt so I
consider this loss of fee but now what
am I thinking moving forward now I'm
simply going to reverse everything so I
had an action line I had a safety line
I'm going to reverse those the old
safety Line is now the new action line
the old action Line is now the new
safety line since we are in a different
position here so now what is keeping me
safe is this downward red line as long
as price can stay below this red line
I'm happy I'm comfortable I'm going to
be making money if price breaks this
downward red line then I have to pay yet
another fee and essentially I continue
to do this until I finally find the
trend the one that goes and the name of
the game here is yes you pay a fee when
price doesn't work out you pay a fee
when price doesn't work out you pay a
fee when price doesn't work out but when
you finally catch the trend you catch
the runner you make up for all of those
fees plus more and that's kind of the
name of the game here when we are trend
line Traders when we're in consolidation
when price is moving sideways we get
tossed back and forth we pay a fee we
pay a fee as long as we are in the
correct position size and we're not
overleveraging these fees are small the
$200 was small for my account size and
it should be $20 maybe for your account
size or $2 for your account size so just
making sure that the position size
you're in makes sense for the risk of
your capital of your position or of your
starting balance and now understanding
that okay yes we pay these little fees
but when we are able to catch that
Runner catch that long move it makes up
for all of those fees plus more so the
name of the game is not only to make
sure that you are set up for the right
entries but it is also to make make sure
you have the right exits so if you saw
some of my videos before you understand
that I am struggling with having these
higher position size I'm coming in a lot
heavier than I'm used to I'm trying to
grow my account a lot more and I'm
struggling with psychology and holding
those winners longer It's tricky to see
these big numbers that I'm not you know
as used to and it makes you want to take
profit sooner but making sure that we
are truly letting these trades play out
that's where we capitalize and we can be
consistently profitable with this
strategy if we can let those runners run
if we can let those winners run we do
that by simply not looking at the dollar
amount to be honest if you could
actually remove the dollar amount that's
going to be better for your psychology
maybe we want to look at ticks maybe we
want to look at Pips maybe we want to
look at percentages but don't look at
the dollar amount if we can remove the
dollar amount from the psychology we're
able to trade more purely based on the
strategy so if I can continue to watch
this trade play out and continue to
Trend down I am trading as per the
strategy if I close because I am up
amount or I just want to Simply make
that last loss back it doesn't allow for
us to to catch those big runners or to
to make this consistent if you're just
simply trying to make up the last loss
you're going to find yourself being back
at break even or overtrading or Revenge
trading when we just simply need to
follow the strategy we need to stay in
for the entirety of it and and let this
thing ride so right now we're up 12 ho
dollars this may continue down maybe it
doesn't but the name of the game here is
to try to stay in for the entirety of
the trend so I'll check back in with you
guys on the this trade we can maybe I'll
continue to screen record and I'll do
another little pause I hope that you
guys got the idea of you know this
strategy how I find my profitability and
how I find my consistency is because I
am able to stay in for these Runners all
right there we go we're up 62 we're up
70 this is so fun I love watching this
okay but the five minute time frame is
different different than the 4-Hour time
frame now talking about the perks of the
five-minute Trader is we can close this
trade yes the adrenaline is there it's
fun it's cool it's emotional but the
coolest part is I get to close this
trade and then not have to think about
it anymore so with that being said we
are going to close this trade and not
have to think about it anymore here we
go we were up
$37 boom We collected a $37 profit we're
done we are done trading until I open
the screen again tomorrow and place
another trade I can sleep sound tonight
thank you guys for watching don't forget
to hit that like button subscribe to my
channel and hit the bell for
notifications and I will see you guys in
the next video thanks guys