What is that thing that separates a professional
trader from a beginner trader
and they make money on the same strategy
but we lose money on the same strategy,
if you search on the internet
you will see multiple trading strategies
and many good traders have
shared that strategy but when
you try to use the same strategy you
lose it, you are not
able to make money in it but the person you are following has already
made money on that strategy,
what is that thing that actually
separates you, you are using the same thing, the
thing is not working, he is using the same thing, the
money is being made, the answer to this
question is understanding the probability
theory, that is, they
know how probability theory works in the market
and their mindset is a
probability mindset, so in this entire
video we are going to cover all those topics
and we will understand
what probability theory is, probability theory
How does probability theory work in trading?
How to
develop a mindset that's called a probability mindset.
And finally, there's a
bonus point for you. I'll also share a cut strategy with you,
so you'll get
to see a live example. And if
you work with understanding, then definitely you will be
able to make some money. So, let's
not waste much time, let's jump straight to the video.
[Music]
Now, you've understood that there's
one thing that separates
beginners from professionals. By using the same
strategy, they're making money, while
we're not. But what is that?
Now, before understanding that, let's understand
what probability theory is. Because that thing
is directly linked to probability theory.
If you search a little, go back a little,
you might have been taught it in 11th grade,
but you never paid attention
to that thing. Probability theory means
how many possibilities there are for a particular thing to happen,
what are the percentage chances that
thing will happen, and if we start trading.
Talking about probability, apart from
how much confidence you have in that particular
setup, that probability is only 50%. That is,
when you plan a trade,
understand this thing very deeply. Because if
you understand it, all your trading
psychology problems like Phumo and
Greed will go away. And as far as
I am fully confident, you already know that
in trading, strategy,
technicalities and all these things are only at 20%. The
rest 70% is just the mind set. How you think when you are entering a
trade,
so listen to this thing very carefully. If you
want to execute any trade, then only
its probability is at 50%. Suppose you have
any strategy, now whichever trader you
follow, you follow mine or
someone else's.
If you
follow all the traders in the world and apply their strategy
on the chart, then its probability is only
at 50%. That is, according to 50%.  That
thing will work and at 50, according to the theory,
that thing will not work and that is why a trader
plans the risk in advance that if that
thing does not work then I have a risk of so much
and I will be out of that particular trade.
Now now the probability theory
says that the probability of that particular trade was
50, that is,
at 50, it will work, at 50, it will not work, no matter what
setup in the world, you can bring your inner circle trader
sir or any other trader sir, bring
me, bring anyone, the probability of everyone's setup
is just 50, it is a harsh
reality. On hearing this, you might also be thinking
that no, no, those traders of mine
bring accuracy at 80, they
bring accuracy at 90, [ __ ], if you do 1000 or
2000 trades, the average will come out,
I am not saying this, listen to me, listen to the
rest and the next level head
managers.  If you listen to it, the same thing will come out,
50, and
you may have confidence in the maximum probability of 60, but the
probability is just 50. I hope you will
understand this statement very well. Once we understand this thing, okay, the
probability of this trade working is 50. Now,
probability theory says that
whatever happened in the market today will happen again tomorrow.
Listen again, whatever happened in the market today will happen again tomorrow.
For example, today you created a strategy, let's take the 830
strategy. According to the 830 strategy,
today I made a video and
showed you that look how well
this strategy has worked. Now,
when you take that strategy and put it on the chart, it
worked today. It may not work tomorrow, but it will
work again the day after tomorrow, that is, the way the
movement happened in the market today will happen again tomorrow.
Now, after hearing this, you must be thinking
that if this is so, then how easy it is to make money.
Whenever that thing is working, we make money.  You have to
invest and then two times four times four times eight times 16 times 16 times 32 times
32 times 64 and
you know how compounding works, the calculation will be done
and you will be a millionaire and
billionaire one day but this is not the reality, you know
what is the catch in this, whatever
strategy, whatever it is, it works,
probability theory says that whatever
happened today will happen again tomorrow, but no one knows when it will happen,
no one knows, this is a very deep statement,
but you have to understand this thing and trust
me no one knows now what, when we ever
plan a trade, no trader
knows whether this thing will work
100% or not because if I
know this thing, no thing is going to work 100%,
think for a moment, why would I not invest all my money, use a
little logically,
if I come to know that my
next trade will work at 110, why will I not put a
full amount of mine and just get it
doubled in the next trade only, then it  This means
they also know that I, my analysis,
my confidence. The "That
Now" theory says that what happened today will happen again tomorrow.
Sounds very simple,
right? Fine. All
strategies work on this basis. Otherwise, think about it.
If what happened today doesn't happen tomorrow, then it
means that no strategy in the world
ever works. No matter how many traders, no matter how many
strategies you've seen, they
work because the
market behaved the same way today. If it didn't behave the same way yesterday, that's okay. It did the same thing again the day before,
and
you made money. The basis of all strategies rests on this. According to
probability theory,
what happened today will happen tomorrow. The catch is,
no one knows when it will happen. Now,
no one knows when it will happen,
but we do know that it will definitely happen.
Keeping that in mind, we always
work with one strategy or one method.
Because when we work in one way and
stick to one strategy, only then will
probability work in our favor.  I
hope you understood this point very well. Now, to
illustrate it better, let me explain.
Market cycles are
a
circle. Something happened here today, it will come around and be back at the same place tomorrow. The
thing in the circle
seems very simple, that it started from here.
When the circle is complete, we will
do the same thing again. But in reality, the
market is not a circle. The market is amoeba-
shaped. Amoeba is such that no one knows
what shape it will take. Nothing is known.
Anything can happen at any time. It is possible that
today you took a trade, that thing worked yesterday, that
thing worked yesterday, you took a trade the day before yesterday, you took a
stop-loss hit. And this happened in your first month,
you entered your second month, took a
trade today, hit your
stop-loss yesterday, took a trade the day before yesterday, hit a big
target. I hope you understand because
understanding this also requires some IQ. If you are
not able to understand, it is okay. Once
you trade, you will understand after spending six months or a year in the market,
then you will understand. Then
look back.  But do watch the video and understand
this thing. This is how probability
theory works. That is why we always
work on a strategy and if we
work on a strategy then there are
chances of making profit. Everyone says that we have to
work on a strategy, we have to work, we have to work,
but no one
can ever explain specifically why we have to do this. This is the reason why we have to do it. Now let's
come to the second topic which is how it works in trading.
Now for that you will have to imagine a little,
increase your imagination power
and assume that you have a setup that
whenever a rejection candle, which we also call a hammer candle, will form near the support,
I will take the trade. It was formed near the support,
I took the trade thinking that the market will go
up from here. The market went up a little and went down and
hit the stop loss.
No problem, a stop loss has been placed. It will feel a little bad
that the first trade went bad for the day.
Now it is not looking a little good. I
took the second trade with courage and
took the trade for the second time. The same rejection candle came
back near the support, took the trade, it did not work,
then the stop loss was placed.  It will feel worse the third
time the market
formed a rejection candle back at support. The third time a trade was
taken, the market went up a bit.
Stop loss was set again. The mind gets confused. When taking a trade, it gets
activated. When taking a trade, it gets
activated because our brain
records our actions. Everything
we do, that is our
brain works. Whatever we do, whatever happens to us,
it all gets recorded in the brain and
based on the feedback of that, we react further. I
hope you got this point. So now
what is the feedback in your mind? You
took one trade like this, took two trades like this,
took three trades like this, which means that
every time in the market, a rejection candle is lit like this
and the market is going down. The
fourth time the market came to the same zone, a
rejection candle was formed, you said I will
not take the trade, the market goes down, I will
short.
You got an entry back in the market, you did
not take a long trade, you said let it rise a little, we will
short it. When the
market came up a little, you shorted the place
where you thought the market was falling for the first time.  Yes, I went
short a little, the market
came down, from there it rocketed and went to the target of 1:5 10.
I really have to tell you
that this has not happened to you
because it has happened to me a lot, it has happened to me a lot. The
first trade was an AS1
hit, the second trade was an AS1 hit, the third was an
AS1 hit. We took a frustrated strategy,
now we are planning based on the market feedback. We
took the fourth trade, the
AS1 hit in the fourth as well. Now this fourth trade
itself causes a big loss.
How is the feedback in your mind that the market will go down, the
market is going up. Now you are losing money,
but somewhere you are
getting into revenge mode, how can I be wrong every time?
Now you are not worried about money here,
you have to fight the market here. Because
here we are talking about right and wrong, how can you be wrong at all the
times? Because humans do not like rejection. If
someone makes a bad comment to me,
I do not like it,
you will also like it, because we do not want to accept
negative feedback and  We do
n't have to be wrong whenever we
want to say something and the other person
counters it. We don't like that he is saying
wrong. I am right, everybody wants to be right, that's right, but it
cannot happen in the market. It can happen that you
take four trades today and put stop
loss on all four of them and you have to do it like this, okay,
fine, accept it, market got that, let's
close this,
but we don't do that and then averaging and
that averaging some times blows away the entire capital.
Now think about the opposite scenario,
if at the same place for the fourth time also we
stick to our strategy that boss, my
strategy is that a rejection candle will be formed near the support,
I have to go long, and if I had gone
long, then what would have been the end outcome? The
three stop losses that I have placed
continue slowly back to back, those three
stop losses all covered up in a single trade,
and this has happened with me. There was a
loss of Rs. 35000 something on the third trade.
Took the trade, hit the stop loss and reached a loss of 45000.
Took another trade. A single trade was
given a target of 1:4, maybe that trade and
that single trade was 300 something or
something and in the last, in a slight red, I
closed the day at 11000. Do you know
what the biggest lesson is? I had also shared it
first, shared it completely and then showed it that
no, look, it has been covered in a single trade,
I am closing it. Do you know
what lesson I learnt? One trade proved to be too heavy for me. Because I
was not following one strategy, I will succeed. Probability will
never come in my hands, it will never
come and this is the secret of
all traders, I follow any one, that is why
they work on the strategy,
they know it or not. Yes, this is the ultimate
thing, only when I do this will it happen
and I told you this because this is what is
called probability
mindset, what is mindset, I have a
set, a process set, yes my
mind thinks like this, it works like this.
And when professionals are trading, they have that
probability set in their mind
that this is the only clue of trading,
so when the conclusion is the same, I know everything,
some people learn from someone outside or
you know, they join a class
or learn from here or from anywhere, and
some people, while making losses in the market,
they just figure out that this is the
conclusion at the end when they give a little deep thought on
themselves and this is called having
a probability mindset, and until you develop a
probability mindset,
trust me, there is no option to make in
trading, no
option, no, bring any strategy, you will make
money in one month, you will make money in two months, you will
make money in one year, in 11 months it is all
gone, in 13 months sorry, it is all gone, it has happened to
me many times, it took
me time to learn and figure out
things because there was no one to guide me at
that time, and every person's starting
point is different.  It happens and that was with
me but now you have this golden video with
you covering three important things
what is probability theory how does probability
theory work in trading those
three trades and one trade opposite taking
example and what is probability mindset
now let's talk about the bonus you have a
strategy I will tell you about a cut strategy
okay now what is that cut
strategy it's basically its full form is it's called
CET cut strategy y
confusion candle you turn I will repeat one more
time confusion candle you turn now on this
strategy if you want a detailed video
because it will take me time to explain as of now
I am giving you a quick sneak
peek of this strategy okay
in this strategy we open a candlestick on a five minutes time frame not five
minutes
three not one not 15 not one hour nothing just
five minutes on a 5 minute time
frame we have to look at two confusion candles of the same range
two confusion  Candles, now
what is a confusion candle? I will
put a video of a candle sec below,
understand it, but you will see wicks on both sides,
many people also call it a spinning top, but that
is confusion, okay, its conclusion is this,
two confusion candles should be of the same range,
when candles of the same range are formed, mark
its high, mark its low,
if the low breaks then we will go short by
keeping a stop loss above and if the high
breaks then we will go long by
keeping a stop loss below, it is a simple strategy, now
if you follow only this and by
following this only, first of all do a back
test and see, there are two types of
things, back testing and powered testing,
first of all do a back test and see
what percentage results you are getting,
I will not tell you in this, I have just shown you some good studies,
now you tell yourself
what percentage results you are getting, the
second thing is you will do forward testing, that is, do not
invest any money, don't believe me, I always say don't believe
me, first use it, then believe, that is,
first forward  In testing,
apply it to the chart and mark it and see
how many of your trades are going right out of 50 trades
and then if it is working for you then you don't do anything else you know
the strategy
you have probability mindset you know
how probability theory works in trading
how probability theory is applied in trading everything and with that said that was it I hope
you liked it all the
best