here is to the 10% of traders that
actually make
it now this is why 90% of Traders fail
hi guys I'm Tory trades and if you are
just now tuning into to my channel I am
a nine-year trend line Trader and I'm
here to share my knowledge and
experience that I've had in the markets
for these past nine years topic today is
why 90% of Traders fail now I'm not
going to give you a buzzfeed list of
don't do this don't do that don't do
this I'm going to give you one main key
thing to work on and this is going to
change your trading I guarantee you this
is not a get-rich quick this is not a if
you follow this one thing you'll make a
million dollars in trading no this is
one attribute that you can hone in on
and tune into that you will see dramatic
results in your trading it is patience
patience patience
there are so many different aspects
where patience comes into play in your
trading and how it helps so let's start
it with just patience in your
expectations how long are you expecting
to become profitable in trading how long
are you expecting it's going to take
until you make x amount how long do you
think it's going to take for you to make
it as a successful Trader if we can
apply patience to that our expectations
are already putting us in the right
place so let's realistically understand
I preach this that it is going to take
time it's going to take years years so
understand that there's not going to be
a formula that you can just plug in and
be successful in three months it's going
to take time and it's going to take
years of experience in order to get to
that real level that serious level of a
profitable Trader those life changing
numbers it's going to take years so
let's change that expectation let's put
patience on our expectation for how long
it's going to take us to be
successful that's a great start now
let's apply this patience to our trades
if we have a strategy in place we know
what an A+ setup is or we know what
results in an entry what gets you into a
trade but let's have patience when we
are placing our trades and taking our
entries let's you know make sure that if
we're trading a certain session there is
a possibility that we are in front of
the charts for 1 hour two hours 3 hours
and we don't even get a setup and maybe
understanding that that's okay because
waiting for the right setup is going to
get us closer to profitability and
closer to success than taking five or
six you know mediocre setups and I think
that gives you a lot of confidence in
your strategy when you know what an A+
setup is and you can sit on your hands
and truly wait until you get one it is
all about
patience God if we could apply patience
to every aspect in our life we would
just be so much better off now let's
talk about some more Concepts here let's
understand that there is patience in the
learning process as well you've got to
find a strategy that works for you you
got to find one that resonates with you
that you can apply and you can you know
hit hard for a year two years that you
feel comfortable with and that you are
confident enough in the strategy that
you can give it that much time and I
know that's a little bit of a scary
thing you know if you've got a strategy
that you're you're not quite sure how
you know profitable it could be or how
well you can apply it or even how much
data there is behind the strategy you're
using
I could understand how that might give
you the heebie jeebies you might get a
little bit skeptical or nervous or
scared out of pursuing it and committing
to it long term so you definitely want a
strategy that you you can see the
results for and you believe in I guess
is really the easiest way to say it that
you believe in this strategy you can
truly give it your All You Don't Mind
Investing a year two years into it
because you know the results of it and I
think that's where it was easier for me
I had my uncle teach me a strategy that
I saw actual results it wasn't some Guru
or some Mentor online that is not
tangible that I couldn't touch or that
was just not real to me versus my uncle
I could look over his shoulder and be
like that's his actual account that's
his actual trading account his lifestyle
represents his success in trading it's
very different when you truly believe in
something man we could go real deep into
that one maybe we'll save that for
another video but just having belief in
your strategy so that you can commit Li
MIT time to it and that requires
patience you got to put the one to two
years into just learning the strategy
and mastering it so having patience with
yourself and with the strategy to
understand that okay this is going to
take a while to get there but I've got
the confidence and I believe in this
strategy next is going to be patience
and building Capital that sounds like
pulling teeth ain't nobody want to talk
about slow and steady wins the race
nobody wants to talk about it because
it's not fun and it sucks but that is
that's the name of the game here now
there are other ways to do this you
could simply you know if you're working
part-time and you're trading on the side
as well maybe let's start a fund where
we're going to put x amount into this
trading fund and maybe we're building
you know startup Capital that way maybe
it's not through trading maybe we are
we're Sim trading while we're working a
9 to-5 and then we've got a savings
account that we're just putting money
into while we're still learning how to
trade making sure that we're still
working those muscles exercising those
trading muscles getting the chart time
in plac in the Sim trades plac in the
paper trades getting as much data as you
can to truly prove to yourself that okay
I can execute and I can be consistent
and these numbers here are showing me
I've got hard data hard numbers that are
showing me I can be consistent meanwhile
I've you know built up this buffer this
savings account that I can now invest
into actually trading live money now
there's the alternative to that is
simply just trading incredibly small
position sizes and building your Capital
that way but still it requires the
practice the chart time before you even
start trading live money so just
applying patience to the the capital
building you can take two different you
know two different routes you can build
Capital with your 9 to5 and savings
accounts and budgeting or you can build
your Capital with your trading account
and making sure that we've got
incredibly low position sizes so that we
are just kind of racking up you know
dollars at a time versus getting into
that trade and then losing the capital
and then having to pull money over here
and put it back in there's two different
routes you can take but making sure that
you've got patience with either one
patience with your savings account that
you're going to invest in trading or
patience with the small Capital that
you're going to continue to build in
your trading okay and then outside of
patience with building your capital or
patience with you know building a
savings account let's say that we have
mastered the strategy we've shown the
results we've proven to ourselves that
we can be successful in trading or at
least be consistent in trading but now
how do we really capitalize how do we
really go to the next level and that is
patience withholding your profits longer
oh that is such a hard thing thing to do
being able to hold that trade and have
patience in that specific trade is
really going to show the next level of
like maturity as a Trader if you can let
the trade play out it's in its entirety
that right there in itself is you
leveling up letting the trade play out
don't look at the dollar amounts don't
get fomo don't close a trade too early
don't spend too much time on the charts
like truly letting a trade play out for
its entirety maybe that's letting the
trade actually hit the takeprofit or
letting the trade actually hit the stop
loss l or whether that's you know if
you're trading trend lines waiting for
that trend line to get crossed or that
safety line to get crossed for the trade
to play out you gave it its due
diligence to show you the trend was the
price was following along the trend or
not but just having that patience to
hold the trade for its entirety maybe
you guys have seen some videos where I
talked about it in the past of kind of
what it's like to build a relationship
with an instrument and you know get to
know it and really get the feel for its
personality and that requires patience
that requires time so you've got to I
guess kind of understanding that the
patience and time is almost one and the
same but time will pass no matter what
you do but the patience is you having
the understanding to let the time pass
that was some knowledge right
there so it's just more of an action
that requires effort or intention time's
always going to pass but like us
understanding the expectation for for
letting it pass so knowing that okay if
I want to get comfortable with trading
oil I have to be patient I've got to get
chart time in I got to watch to see what
it does every day if I want to have
patience in my entries I've got to
actually see scenarios where I'm
presented with an opportunity to get
into a trade but I pass up on it because
it's not A+ it's not the trade I was
waiting for so I'm going to sit on my
hands and wait for the next one and then
patience in exiting your trade too soon
that will come with experience you know
you got to exit your trade too soon a
few times to understand that oh if I had
stayed in I would have you know been
able to capitalize on more profits here
or if I had stayed in I would have at
least felt more confident about my
system or my strategy versus is you know
clipping out of those trades too early
so understanding that each one of these
things are going to require
modifications self-awareness
understanding that okay do I am I a
person that needs to feel the fire a few
times I need to put my hand on the flame
just to understand that oh okay this
this is how I should not do it and then
now let's come up with a process or a
plan on how I should this is what a
trade looks like when I get in too early
or too late so now I need to be more
patient with my entries or this is what
happens when I close out of my trade too
early and I take my profits too early
these are the benefits that I reap by
simply staying in the trade for its
entirety understanding that this
strategy is going to take me a year or
two to master so that your expectations
are not so you're not trying to strategy
hop when this you know strategy or
you're not seeing results from it
immediately so knowing that okay I have
faith in the strategy now I just need to
get the chart time in get the experience
in versus someone who did not have
patience with a strategy would probably
try it for three months then move on to
the next one then try it for for three
months and then move on to the next one
so patience just has such a huge role in
trading and if we can really truly
master that it comes with self-awareness
but it also comes with just identifying
it when you get presented with the
opportunity to get into a trade and it's
not the trade that you need or you want
or that you've practiced pass up on it
so all in all we just have to practice
patience with our trading practice
patience practice practice practice
practice holding longer practice waiting
for entries practice your mindset
knowing knowing that this is going to
take a while having the right
expectations so this is this is all the
biggest reason why 90% of Traders fail
is because they don't have patience if
you can come in with patience you're
already setting yourself up for Success
you're already kind of separating
yourself from that 90% let's move into
that 10% how are they thinking are they
patient okay I'm going to be patient I'm
going to embody everything that patience
is so whatever you can do to get you
closer to that 10% of the successful
Traders we got to do it thank you guys
for tuning in today if you enjoyed the
video hit the like button drop a comment
share the video and hit the bell for
notifications so that you guys know
every time I come out with a new video