so in today's video I'm going to show
you the most accurate one minute
sculping trading strategy that I
actually never shared on this channel
before it's super simple to follow and
it's built around only one and the most
popular trading indicator so without
further Ado let's begin so step one is
to open trading view or whatever trading
platform you are using and let's add the
indicators first so to do that just go
to the indicators stab and type in
moving average and it's going to be this
one right over here but make sure to
click on it three times as we will need
three of them so in order to make the
strategy work as it designed to we will
have to adjust the settings for each
moving average so follow me along so to
access the settings click on this gear
icon over here and inside the input
section just change the value from
default to the value of 20 and click
okay the next moving average needs to be
set at the 40 and the last one will be
set at a value of 80 you can always
change the color for each moving average
to green blue red pink Etc so the color
is your personal reference but I like to
keep it bright just to see better so the
reason I shareed this strategy today is
that this strategy can be used on any
given time frame as long as you trade
with a trend and you are not limited to
one type of trading style so you can
swing trade day trade and yes you can
even scalp and this trading strategy can
be a great addition to your current
trading plan because it's incredibly
easy to follow and understand its use so
as we move along the step two is to
identify the current market Direction
and to find the trend you simply need to
observe where the price action is moving
and then determine whether it is above
or below the moving averages so when the
price is above the three moving averages
it's an indication of an uptrend and
this uptrend is categorized by a pattern
of higher highs and higher lows however
if the price consistently Falls below
the three moving averages it usually
indicates a downtrend and in such cases
you will often observe how the price
forms a pattern similar to a descending
steps forming lower highs and lower lows
but let's say if the market is flat you
will notice how the price action isn't
making any new highs or lows but rather
staying stagnant and in this phase the
price moves just horizontally often
referred to as a sideways market and
when you're using this type of trading
strategy I recommend avoiding this type
of Market when looking for trading
opportunities because we are seeking for
a trending Market instead so before we
move along with the video if you have
been searching for a free trading ideas
or if you're interested in following my
trades and seeing this kind of success I
have had recently then joining my group
is the best thing you can do and for
those who really want to dive deep and
trade like a pro then my ultimate price
action course is the way to go it's
basically all my best Knowledge from The
Last 5 Years condensed into something
that can really accelerate the way you
learn trading and of course you will
find all the links in my description box
down below so let's now discuss the
rules for executing buy and sell trades
so for sell trade within a downtrend the
approach is very straightforward so
first of all you have to ensure that the
price remains below the lowest moving
average indicating a strong downtrend
and then you have to wait for a complete
candle to close below this moving
average confirming that the market is
committed to this downtrend so once you
see this occur the next step is to wait
for the price to pull back now this
pullback is a slight upward movement but
it doesn't surpass the moving averages
acting as a temporary pause rather than
a reversal so to determine the exact
point of entry after that pullback you
basically have two options now the first
option you can switch to a lower time
frame for a more detailed view or you
can remain in your current time frame
for your broader Outlook so because I'm
currently on the 1 minute time frame I
will stick to it but let let's say if
you are on a 5-minute chart you can
simply switch to the 1 minute time frame
and use it as an entry now this is very
important to keep in mind but the key is
to ensure that the entire Candlestick
has closed completely below all the
moving averages so remember that the
price action doesn't necessarily have to
go back and touch the moving averages
what's actually crucial is to confirm
that there was a pullback in the price
and then a continuation of the current
Trend so step three in our Trading
strategy focuses on setting the stop
loss effectively now when you place your
stop loss it should be positioned just
above this highest moving average line
and this placement is strategic because
it actually allows you for some Market
fluctuation while still protecting you
from your significant losses however
there is always however but it's very
important to remember that the size of
your stop- loss will vary based on the
time frame you are trading in so for
scalpers a tide stop loss which is
around 5 to 10 Pips is very common to
use but on the other hand day Traders
they typically set a wider stop loss
ranging from 30 to 50 Pips just to
accommodate the larger price movements
expected over the course of a day now
for taking a profits you actually have
two very effective options to choose
from so for example if you set your
stop- loss at 10 Pips on your trade you
could set your take profit at 20 Pips
establishing a 1 to2 risk reward ratio
on the other hand you can actually use
key support and resistance levels to
determine your take profit Target so
let's say if you are in a sell position
you can look for the next significant
support level and then set your
takeprofit target just slightly above it
and this strategy is based on the
tendency of prices to pause or reverse
at these levels now to enter a bu
position in an uptrend you will
essentially reverse the strategy used
for a cell position in the downtrend so
the first thing you need to do is to
begin by confirming that the price is
consistently staying above all the
moving averages which basically signals
a strong uptrend and suggests that the
market is leaning towards upward
momentum the next crucial step is to
wait for entire candle to close above
this moving average and this is a clear
sign that the buyers are in control and
the market is solidifying its upward
path so following this your attention
now should shift to observing a pullback
in the price now this pullback is a
slight downward movement and should not
cross below all the moving averages so
it's more like a brief dip or a pause in
an upward Trend and after this pullback
the critical moment comes when the price
starts moving upwards again so that
resumption of the uptrend at this point
indicates a strong entry opportunity for
a Buy trade and when it comes to setting
your stop- loss and take profit levels
consider placing the stop loss just
below the lowest moving average or you
can even place it based on predetermined
your risk risk reward strategy okay so
based on what we have discussed so far
let me just walk you through a trade
that I took yesterday so this is gbpusd
on a 1 minute time frame so the reason I
entered this trade is because gbpusd was
in a strong uptrend on the 50-minute
chart as well as on a 5minute chart just
basically making higher highs so what I
did next is I basically narrowed to the
one minute time frame and the bullish
bias can also be seen over here we have
a nice uptrend the resistance was broken
and now it stands as a support now I
will slightly zoom in so you will be
able to see it better but this is the
pullback that I was talking about but as
you can see the Candlestick never closed
all the moving averages it was basically
rejected by this support level over here
and as you can see the Candlestick
eventually closed as a bullish engulfing
confirming that the buyers are taking
control again and I entered the trade on
a closure so this time I aimed for 1 to2
restor ratio but as a cherry on top I
also Mark this 50-minute resistance Zone
as a potential profit Target Zone as you
can probably tell the result is very
obvious I did reach my takeprofit target
as you can see it literally bounced of
that resistance zone of course guys
before you start bombarding me in the
comments I took way more than one trade
but to show and break them all down for
you it would probably take me like an
hour but I just want to show you that
this trading strategy is simple
effective and when everything lines up
it's just so incredibly satisfying to
watch those profit targets being hit so
if you enjoy this video make sure to let
me know in the comments down below and
you might want to check out this
previous video over here where I share
my personal experience how the Forex
tester has been a game changer for me