hi everyone and welcome back to my 4x
channel so in this session i will share
one more scalping strategy using one
minute time frame and only two
indicators
in this one minute scoping strategy we
will focus on a fast trade to capitalize
quick profits and this strategy is just
simply amazing because you know it's
simple and easy to follow and anybody
can adapt
to whether they are experienced forex
traders or maybe you have a lex
experience but you're looking for
strategies to basically renew your forex
journey i will definitely show you how
to set up everything in regards to your
charts and tools that we will use to
help us
out and it will be a lot of information
about this strategy so you can make
notes if you really need to and as you
know me any questions in regards to this
video
or you just want to say hi just reach
out to me on my social media and i will
leave all the information in the
description down below so before you
will jump into applying this strategy
and placing the trades
make sure you are on one minute time
frame all right because
there have been some times for me that i
went
to apply this strategy and i seen oh
them i'm not in the right time frame
so just make sure you on one minute time
frame for this
specific scalping strategy and for this
strategy we will use two different
indicators for our confirmations to
enter at rate so we will be using
exponential moving average of 200 and we
will use a stochastic so as you can see
mine was already on but for you all you
have to do
is just go on indicators and type in ema
or
exponential moving average it doesn't
matter and it will be the first one so
just add it on
so default settings for ema is comes
into nine but all you have to do is just
to press on this button
and change into 200. so once you're done
with your exponential moving average
indicator you also have to add a
stochastic all you have to do is just go
on indicators and type in
sto it will be the first one
and default settings comes into 14
3 3 but you have to change to number 5
instead of 14. the reason why we are
changing the settings from the defaults
to the ones that we have already is
because this is going to group and
overbought and oversold
zones of the stochastics which means
more trading opportunities to take so
once you applied all the indicators
correctly the actual strategy is like
two plus two the first step is of course
is to identify a trend
because as you know the trend that you
are in is going to determine what types
of trades
you will be looking for the best and
easiest way to do it is to basically use
our 200 exponential moving average
indicator and the rule for it is very
very simple
so if the candles is above of 200 moving
averages
it means we are in a buyer's market in
an uptrend vice versa if the candle
sticks below
200 exponential moving averages it means
we are in a seller's market and we will
be looking only for
a sell trades so as you can see in this
example we are in an uptrend because the
candlesticks is above of our 200
exponential moving average and let's say
if the candlesticks is below of our 200
exponential moving averages means we
are in a downtrend and we will be
looking only for
a sell trades and i'm always telling
this golden rule to my subscribers that
always go with a trend because the trend
is our friend
now as we just finished talked about the
exponential moving averages
let me just tell you how the stochastics
indicator will help
us so the stochastics is basically for
telling us
where to enter those trades and the key
principle of the indicator is that
whenever you have a crossover on the top
of the area
it's the overbought market and we will
be looking for a
sell trades on the other hand if we have
a crossovers
on a lower area we will be looking for a
buy
trades because it's oversold zone so
this is super important for you to
understand how this tool works in a
forex trading so your second step
is to look for a stochastics crossover
and this is super important but in
addition into crossovers you want to
look for
a momentum so when you see a crossovers
happening
in the stochastics you don't want to
only look for the blue and orange lines
you know going up or down so let's say
over here we have a crossover based on
blue line crossing at orange one but
then they both starting heading towards
the upside
so that upside movement and crossover
is the momentum that we are looking for
to enter a trade and let's see this is
example for a
sale trade so as you can see the
stochastic moving averages crossed on
the top of the zone
indicating an overbought market but we
are waiting for that crossover of moving
averages to start heading towards the
downside and that movement is what we
are looking for to enter a cell
trade so once you listen to the
christina's teaching lesson let's go and
i will show you how effective this
strategy works so here we have a euro
usd
on one minute time frame and we are in a
wireless market because the candlesticks
is above of 200 exponential moving
averages and
we will be looking for a buy trades only
based on crossovers in the lower
zone of the stochastics indicator so i
marked it with a yellow line so it will
be easier for you to not
look anywhere else but ingest in that
cross over so as you can see
we have a stochastic crossover and the
momentum towards the upside so this is
where we enter a buy trade and we also
see a green light from the buyers as
well
by showing a bullish engulfing candle so
of course our entry point will be
the bullish engulfing candle closed and
we would be entering on
a long so as you see we are entering a
trade only bullish engulfing candle
in regards to your stop-loss the
stop-loss zone
should be in the recent area of your
broken support
and resistance so as you can see even by
applying two different indicators
and following the correct steps we would
be profiting in a round of 19 pips
of course you would be possibly keep the
trade until
over here because this is the zone where
you will have to close your trade and
look for new opportunities look into
your stochastic fourier crossover for a
confirmation to enter your trade so take
a look for a cell example as well
on your usd one minute time frame as you
can see a crossover of stochastic
occurred on the top zone
indicating an overbought market and our
candlesticks is below of 200 exponential
moving averages so what it means we are
looking for
a sell trade so as well i marked the
zone with the crossover
where it happened with the yellow line
as well we have a bearish engulfing
candle it means
we are going down because we have a
confirmation from the seller market so
as you see i
marked the zone with a sarcastic
crossover happening and
we have a bearish engulfing candle we
are going down
don't forget to put your stop loss zone
in a recent horizontal area of
sensitivity so it's either support or
resistance and as you can see we will be
profiting 59
pips in total and as you see guys if you
wait for those opportunity moments to
enter the trade and you follow the
criteria of the strategy
this strategy can pay off very very well
so if you enjoyed this video smash the
like button and comment down below and
once again thank you for watching me and
until next time
[Music]
bye