I'm going to use this $30,000 trade I
could have came in with 10 contracts it
got to this area of resistance I closed
my trade trade management here we go the
markets were just so foreign to me I
never thought I'd be able to do
something like
this I've made over $130,000 this year
in just nine trades using one simple
strategy which is trend lines I
understand trend lines has such a
negative connotation in the industry but
I'm here to show you exactly how it's
worked for me before I go any further
here are my verified statements from my
broker okay here is January statement
here is February
statement here is my March
statement you'll see I did a $50,000
withdrawal here is April
statement had $50,000 month here is
May's
statement no trades here is June's
statement no trades here is July's
statement
$40,000 trade and here is August
statement all right let's get into it
okay this is a $30,000 trade that I made
in Platinum using this three touch Point
Break Playbook now I'm going to put this
in replayed mode so you can see exactly
what I saw when I entered this trade as
I'm watching Platinum I am continuing to
track the touch points to this downward
trend line I've got point a point B
Point C we've got three touch points
here on this downward trend line price
broke through I have alerts on my trend
lines so that as soon as price breaks
out out of whatever Trend it's following
along I'm notified so I got an alert on
my phone when the price of platinum
broke this downward trend line so that
is my initial entry to get into the
trade I can go ahead and check off this
very first box of my three touch Point
Break Playbook simply by saying okay did
the trend line have three touch points
yes it did all right the next checkbox
on my playbook was the lowrisk setup
price was close enough to this opposing
trend line that this could have been a
low-risk setup I could have came in with
10 contracts taking on about $6 to
$7,000 worth of risk this year I am
working on scaling up taking higher risk
positions I'm trying to grow this year
so I came in with 20 contracts instead
of my normal 10 contracts so I cannot
check off the lowrisk setup because I
came in heavier in position size if I
had came in lighter which I do have the
option to I simply could have traded
this setup as per usual came in with 10
contracts and checked off this lowrisk
setup box I'm not going to on this
specific trade because I came in with 20
contracts now the next checkbox is is
there over a week's worth of data on
this trend line and what that means is
does it have three touch points but
there could be a scenario where we've
got three touch points on a trend line
but it's all within the same two or
three days that's not a whole lot of
data backing up this line whereas this
trend line that we're looking at has
over a week's worth of data we've got
the first touch Point here which is that
high we've got the second touch point
this pullback and then price gravitated
and created a third touch Point here as
well so this has over a week's worth of
data I can go ahead and check this third
check box off okay now how long am I
staying in this trade for what does the
trade management look like my risk goes
on the other side of the opposing trend
line if the price price breaks this
upward trend line that it's currently
following along which also has three
touch points 1 2 3 I'm willing to take a
loss if the price cannot respect this
upward trend line and breaks out of it
that's when my trade and my loss is
solidified now let's go through the next
few bars and see how this played
out right here it just created a fourth
touch point of this upward trend line
and then it just created a fifth touch
point on this upward trend line it is
crazy to see price truly respect these
trend lines to the literal T but now
neither one of these touch points was an
indication to close it was simply
getting close enough to my line to where
I would have had to consider if it broke
closing that trade but it never did it
ended up respecting this upward trend
line 28 many times I ended up closing my
trade after the break of this 946 level
here now let's go to the exit CR
criteria which one of these two check
boxes gave me an indication to close my
trade I've got two options here the
first option is I can continue to track
this with yet another trend line coming
in steeper point a point B here on this
last pullback and then simply wait for
the price to break this trend line to
where now my risk is no longer trailing
along this line it is trailing in profit
along this steeper trend line or the
second exit criteria is is price getting
closer to a level an area of support and
resistance a key level an area where the
price of platinum is likely to hit and
and then turn around I can go ahead and
check that one off price got to this
level here this key level of 9461 so I
closed my trade at
94885 so just very shortly after it
ended up breaking this horizontal level
or this area of resistance and that is
as simple as it is I entered because we
had a break of a downward trend line
with three touch points price ended up
respecting the opposing trend line which
also had three touch points and then I
continued to stay in that trade as it
moved in my favor price moved steeper
and steeper away from me we're up
$30,000 it got to this area of
resistance I closed my trade I had two
options to close I could have closed
because of the break of the steeper
upward trend line or I could have closed
simply because we hit this area of
resistance I chose the resistance this
was a $30,000 profit I went long 20
contracts I was able to take on higher
risk trading 20 contracts versus my 10
contracts I risked $14,000 for this
trade my realized R multiple is 2.4 and
I held this trade for about a week and
the craziest part about this is it is
simply just trend lines so I'm not
taking the break of every single trend
line there is criteria that needs to be
met before I'm taking my entry is there
enough data behind the trend line how
many touch points does it have how close
is the price in conjunction to the
opposing trend line is it respecting the
opposing trend line how much risk am I
coming in with and then this is the
trade management this is this is truly
it we had the break price respected the
opposing trend line price got to an area
of resistance I'm out I'm going to give
you guys another example here we go
we've got another $30,000 trade based on
our three touch Point Break Playbook
first things first did the price break
out of a three touch Point trend line
the answer is yes we're checking that
box off here we go here's our downward
trend line touch point one touch Point 2
touch Point 3 price broke that's our
entry criteria now let's go to the next
box is this a lowrisk setup price is
significantly far away from this
opposing trend line the opposing trend
line is the upward trend line you have
two options here you can create a lower
risk setup by reducing your position
size so you can come in with only 10
contracts if your normal contract size
is 20 or if you are trading the micros
you can come in with Just One Singular
micro you have a lot of options here for
the next entry criteria how close is the
price when it broke to the opposing
trend line it's a little bit farther
away so I can either do one of two
things I can reduce my position size or
I can go in heavier knowing that this is
not low risk this is higher risk so I
have entered my trade 20 contracts at
88872 I cannot check off the lowrisk
setup because I ended up coming in
heavier in possession size now you have
the option to check off that box and
make it a lower risk setup by reducing
your position size now let's look over
the next option is this over a week's
worth of data we're looking at February
2nd 3rd fourth fifth sixth 7eventh eight
yes okay and also remember I came in
with 20 contracts accepting this higher
risk trade because this year I am
working on leveling up I working on
taking on that higher risk I am trying
to increase my position size increase my
Capital work on this exposure therapy to
these bigger trades so I'm in a position
to where I can come in with a higher
risk next check box is there over a
week's worth of data on this trend line
the answer is yes we've got over a
week's worth of data on this downward
trend line with the three touch points
boom we're checking off that next box
now trade management here we go we are
in the trade 888 price is working out
we've got some sideways movement here
it's in our favor we get one giant red
bar here's the kicker I did not have to
close this trade even though this was a
scary Red Bar and I'm in draw down it
still respected the opposing trend line
I'm in this trade I'm still in it even
though it got so close to it and even
touched it maybe I'm sweating a little
bit maybe I'm like okay I might have to
consider closing this trade I might have
to take this loss soon it didn't price
respected this upward trend line I
didn't even know price was going to come
down and create another touch point on
this trend line at the time of Entry I
only had these previous two touch points
here but price ended up creating a third
touch point on this upward trend line I
love to see that now what made me close
this trade what is my exit criteria
let's go over price ended up getting to
this area of resistance this 91852 I
closed now what price did I close 91862
oh my gosh spot on price got to this
level I said I'm done I'm out okay going
through our Playbook we have got three
touch points on our downward trend line
check that box off I created a higher
risk trade by coming in heavier in
position size so I can't check that one
off over a weeks worth of data on the
downward trend line yes exit criteria
price got to an area of resistance I CL
closed my trade checkbox hit this is
$330,000 in just a week using trend
lines you guys this is a simple strategy
people truly like to complicate things
over complicate it no I do not take
every break of every trend line there is
criteria that needs to be met but this
is what it looks like when all of this
criteria is met this is the
possibilities it can do this is two
trades where I made $330,000 holding a
trade just a little over a week using
these trend line breaks I understand
that trend lines has a bad rep in the
industry get a little bit picky here
about your trades about the breaks but
it it truly trading can be simple it can
be simple yes it's not easy it's going
to take some time to understand what the
criteria is what the Playbook is getting
to know your instrument mastering your
time frame working on holding profits
longer there's going to be many other
things that come into play that don't
make it very easy but the strategy is
simple it truly blows my mind even to
this day that I was able to make my way
in a space that seems so complex so
intimidating by simply just drawing
lines on a chart it's it's something
that I'm so incredibly proud of I mean
Going Back 9 years ago trading and the
markets were just so foreign to me I
never thought I'd be able to do
something like this it's truly
fascinating that I can trade a trend
line strategy and make over
$130,000 in just nine trades this year I
hope this helped I hope this can
encourage you that trading doesn't have
to be over complicated to opt for a more
simple strategy that it can work just
make sure that you've got the right
criteria in place you're able to
replicate it and you're able to do it
over and over again again all right guys
don't forget to hit that subscribe
button we are going to be using the same
playbook for many more trades in the
future I will see you guys in the next
video