there is a plethora of information on
the internet when it comes to trading
and that was similar to what my uncle
was talking about in the podcast was is
truly like the ultimate basics of
trading is get my dad a Lambo if you
could make an extra $1 to $2,000 a month
I
think if you guys follow me on social
media you know that I preach that my
strategy is Elementary I think I say
it's just the perfect way to say it I
view myself and I have utter confidence
in myself and in my strategy and in my
system is truly like the ultimate basics
of trading it is trend lines and today I
want to kind of walk you guys through
how I found success in the elementary
strategy of trading or the elementary
side of a system essentially and why
it's important though so the first thing
is I want to go over what what the
ultimate problem is and I'll go ahead
and just have you guys drop it in the
chat what are you guys' biggest
struggles I can almost guarantee I
already know the first top three but as
Traders you guys are here looking for
specifically trading advice risk
management absolutely we got psychology
where to start okay that's the one I was
looking for where to start where do you
start there is so much there is a
plethora of information on the internet
when it comes to trading where do you
start how do you know what system how do
you know what strategy how do you know
what instrument how do you know what
time frame how do you know what Mentor
how do you know what course how do you
know what videos to watch there is a
black hole of information on the
internet so obviously it makes sense
since there is so much information how
can you narrow it down how can you find
the easiest way to get into this so
everything that you guys are going to
learn tonight in the webinar which make
sure you guys have notes I'm going to go
through a few bullet points that I want
you guys to kind of sear into your brain
if you got to type it into your notes on
your phone or write it down on a sticky
note it's going to be very helpful
especially for those that answered you
know where to start the next question
that I had is how many of you guys saw
the podcast that I did with my uncle
which was in the trading space broke the
internet some people thought that I
didn't have an actual Uncle he didn't
exist and this was the whole facade I
was putting on if you did not be sure to
go to YouTube it's the most recent video
that I've got his face is plastered all
over the thumbnail you can't miss it
it's the Uncle Mike I kept this a secret
YouTube video but just put that on your
watch list we got to stay tuned for now
because we've only got an hour with you
guys tonight but in that podcast for
most of you guys that saw it what do you
guys think the main theme was and the
coolest part while you guys were typing
that into the chat I didn't really get
to dictate where the conversation was
going when I sit down and have a
conversation with my uncle it could go
in either direction this could be a life
lesson this could be almost like church
I mean depending on how religious he's
feeling that day or how in touch with
the Lord he's feeling it could be like a
almost a a coming to Jesus even outside
of actual religion like what are you
doing with your life are you motivated
or it could be a trading discussion and
I was hoping obviously we could really
get heavy nitty-gritty in the the
trading and I wanted to know I wanted
everyone to know his time frame his
instrument his psychology his strategy
and instead he just talked about what
was heavy on his heart or what he
thought was most important for traitor
and what it was it was essentially one
was getting off social media which is
ironic because you guys has found this
webinar because of social media so
there's pros and cons obviously to
social media but he was just making sure
that you you know the balance with
social media when you're looking for a
strategy or looking to get into trading
naturally you you kind of want to
submerse or immerse yourself in the
industry you want to figure out
everything that's out there and that's
where the problem is because there's too
much information where if you can just
kind of hone in on one strategy one
system which it doesn't even have to be
mine mine happens to be oh I'm blessed
to have found my strategy mine happens
to be the easiest one to make me x
amount of money I'll get into a little
bit of the goals and how close I am to
my goal later on in the webinar tonight
but very exciting news but it's the it's
truly just the easiest system now
there's plenty of other systems there's
ICT there's SMC there is trading based
on fundamentals on Purely just news
making a decision based on economic news
or political news so there's a lot of
ways that you can be successful and
consistent in Prof itable in trading but
I don't think the strategy is the issue
here I think it is the committing to one
so if you let's say that some of you
guys are fundamental Traders and you
trade based on news you do your research
you do hours of research on whatever
news is happening and then you make your
decision and then you let's say you know
four weeks you've tried it and then
you're not able to find the success so
you move on to the next strategy and
then you do the same repeatedly over and
over again and I think that is the
epitome of Traders getting into this
industry is strategy hopping if if you
can truly just hone in on one strategy
you guys are much better off and that
was similar to what my uncle was talking
about in the podcast was just find one
Mentor one system even one instrument he
said he traded two I believe which was
ym and the inq but for the most part I
believe he just trades one and has
traded one so it's this is kind of the
theme of tonight one system one strategy
One Mentor one instrument one time frame
just keeping it as as simple as we
possibly can so I'm going back to the
the problem of trading so essentially it
is it's overwhelming there's an excess
of information we understand that and
what I want to highlight is the easiest
strategy the most Elementary which is
taking it way back to the basics and I
know you guys have heard this term
before which is the trend is your friend
I'm sure when everyone gets into trading
that is like one of the most common
phrases that you learn or that you come
across in trading the trend is your
friend we are bringing it way way back
to that that's simple of a strategy now
I do want to know if you guys know the
statistic of traders that actually make
it it's the 90% there was actually a
Trader one of the Educators or
influencers in the space Trader Nick who
posted something today and I had already
had this kind of this part of the
webinar planned but it was the 909090
90% of Traders lose 90% of their capital
in 90 days how true that is I don't know
but it sounds pretty accurate and I
believe that's fairly close to true so
now my next question for you guys is
most of you guys are here tonight you're
trying to find that that profitability
that consistency or that secret sauce
from this webinar but now I I am curious
what makes you guys think that you going
to be in the 10% this is and it's not me
trying to challenge anyone or say that
anyone's lesser than I am just curious
to know what do you guys think puts you
or is going to put you in the 10%
because I want to I want you guys to get
hyped you got to have something you got
to have at least at least some
confidence that you are going to be in
that 10% because if you don't even have
that you might not make it so I can see
a lot of awesome answers I see
determination I see we're not given up I
see the willingness the dedication
self-awareness consistency I mean okay
all of these are the attributes to a
successful Trader so as long as you guys
know and believe that you're going to be
in that 10% we're already a little bit
ahead of the curve we're already a
little bit up there you got to have the
confidence at bare minimum okay and then
now if you guys are like okay I can be
in that 10% what does it look like what
does the actual success of that look
like now I have been able to Showcase
that in the most genuine realistic way
that I possibly could I think that's
what kind of Drew all of you guys to me
or to my social media that I'm not one
of the the gurus that flexes the Lambos
and the Richer Millies and the crazy
Mansions or the private jets I've never
even been on a private jet am able to
find profitability and consistency in
trading and one the best and biggest and
to be honest the number one dream result
from Trading is the time freedom and
luckily I had a mentor my uncle who did
not Flex any of those things either so
when I got into trading my dream result
was never Lambos and Richard Millie I
say Richard Millie just the the nice
watches and the private jets it was
never that that was never the end goal I
didn't really know that was possible
with trading because I only got to see
the success of my uncle which was he
never worked a job he was home all the
time he took our family on trips I was
like okay so if I learn what he does I
can reap the same benefits I can reap
the same rewards I get to stay home I
get to take my family on trips and
that's exactly what I want and that's
always been the goal so I want you guys
to kind of paint this picture in your
head as well so I want you guys to think
while I'm going through this next topic
think about the ultimate dream result
for you so now it very well could be a
Lambo it could be all I want to do is
get my dad a Lambo I want to get my dad
a boat so that's totally fair but now
the first thing I want to ask you guys
is the the realistic results what do you
guys just at bare minimum want to get
out of trading now the next question I'm
going to ask is when I say realistic
results I don't want you guys to to take
a step down or to to make your dreams
smaller so with that being said what is
your ultimate level 10 I've made it
dream result results so my dream results
I've still got goals that I haven't hit
yet in trading I want to make a million
dollars in trading profits within one
trading year that's one of my goals I
want to get my dad a boat I want to take
my family on trips regularly absolutely
creating generational wealth if I could
create generational wealth to where my
kids kids are comfortable I've I've made
it that's how I know I've absolutely
made it now that's absolutely positive
or possible so I want you guys to think
of the realistic results first think of
the the time Freedom think of the
getting out of debt thinking the
quitting the 9 to-5 my biggest goal when
I'm teaching when I'm encouraging people
to get into trading it's never really to
create one stream of income with trading
I want to encourage and this maybe is
just me as a person I want to encourage
you guys to yes leave the 9o5 that will
always be the goal but not only not just
cut off that stream of income but move
into the entrepreneurial side of Finance
or of the the workforce is being your
own boss now don't having someone to
answer to creating your own your own
hours your own rules I think and that's
something that I just I preach and I
think it's incredibly important is just
never having one source of income and
this is a question for you guys and I I
actually sat whenever I was creating
these notes for the webinar I was like
okay let me see if I can think of One
Singular Trader whether they're an
educator or an influencer or just a
successful Trader in general how many of
them actually have one stream of income
and if you guys know drop it in the chat
but there is none I don't know any that
have one stream of income that is just
purely trading yeah there may be 1% it
could be less than that if there is a
personal Trader that you know or just
someone in your life I know trading is
hard to come by so you probably don't
actually know in person very many
Traders luckily the internet has brought
us all together where we can find each
other but let's say that there is a
Trader that does not sell courses I can
almost guarantee they have another
business whether that is real estate
whether that is e-commerce whether that
is running an actual business if you
guys watch the podcast that I did with
my uncle he had an alarm business that
was his very first thing his alarm
business became successful which allowed
him to have more money to invest in
trading then from there he had
e-commerce he had real estate and I want
to follow in those same footsteps now
with me my streams of income are a
little bit different than my uncles's
because I'm living in a a different
generation to where I can make money on
the internet now too I can make money
being an influencer being an educator
real estate long-term Investments even
kind of getting connected with a
financial adviser to know okay where do
I need to put you know if I've got a
mutual fun if I've got a life insurance
policy I need you guys to just think
multiple sources of income across the
board Point Blank period even if you
guys decide to take my accelerator or
take my course or take any of my
education all I hope is that you guys do
get that part out of it we've got to
have multiple streams of income and I'm
always going to push for that so if you
guys are trying to purely just leave
your 9 to-5 and have trading as your
main source of income I'm just going to
advise against it that's my personal
preference I think always multiple
streams of income Point Blank period
okay but then moving on to the the next
part this is the fun part where I was
talking about the 111 keeping it simple
so this is the three-step solution to
your problem I'm kidding this was the
easiest most catchy way that I could
come up with the Simplicity to my
strategy and it was the the kind of the
one1 rule so the first one is one
strategy One Singular strategy the next
one is one mentor and then one hour a
day so I believe those three things I
kid you not if you decide to go as far
away from trend lines as possible I
still think you're going to find
profitability with the 111 with the one
strategy the One Mentor in the one hour
a day whether you decide to trade supply
and demand support and resistance if I
knew anything about ICT I would use
examples but I don't know anything about
it but regardless if you use any
strategy I truly think the 111 rule is
going to get you guys from struggling
maybe stagnant maybe just not seeing
success or just not able to get that leg
up that's that's it right there now the
importance of the simple strategy though
this part I want to talk about and I'm
going to go a little bit more into it
later on in the webinar when I'm talking
about science experiments and kind of
the variables but I'll I'll give you
just a little tidbit or brief overview
is that the least amount of variables
the better if you've got too many you
don't know what's working what's not so
we'll get more into that a little bit
later but then the one Mentor is also
important because if you've got if
you're listening to one person on the
internet saying to do this and then
you've got this guy saying to do this
and this guy saying to do this now which
one do you choose which person do you
listen to and obviously that just makes
sense you're going to get confused
that's just not going to work so truly
just listening to and letting One
Singular Mentor kind of steer you in the
right direction when you're veering off
the path a little bit just having that
same Mentor bring you right back okay
this is what you should be doing so the
importance of Just One Mentor is huge
and I know that's hard because there's
so many people selling everything in
your face all over the Internet they're
like listen to me I'm right that
person's not right I'm right ICT is a
fraud I'm right or this guy he's a
scammer he's not right listen to me I
truly think if you guys can just find
one person now it's going to be tricky
to find one but you've got to have a
little bit of discernment you got to be
able to do your research and truly find
someone that their Style resonates with
you so it's going to be tricky too I
understand that part but once you do
stick to one and then the last thing is
1 hour a day you guys already know that
applies in whatever you're trying to do
whether you're working out trying to
start a business the one hour day thing
that creates the habits so those were
the the one one ones but now the next
question I have for you guys and this
has always been this is like a probably
a lifelong debate in the trading
industry what do you guys think is most
important is it psychology or is it
strategy that's like the does the
chicken come first or does the egg come
first is there an actual answer who
knows um well I'm going to let you guys
know there isn't a right answer I I
think I think you got to have both but
obviously if you've got good psychology
it will help any strategy whereas if
you've got a good strategy but not good
psychology that just doesn't benefit but
the good psychology will help cross the
board so the benefit of having good
psychology is going to be a little bit
I'd say it tips the scale just a little
bit but still I don't think there's any
right answer you got to have both but
fascinating to hear that you guys think
psychology is it now I will say that
when I am talking about psychology it is
emotions it is confidence it is
maintaining discipline and there was
something that I had listened to I don't
know if you guys have heard of Alex
heroi have you guys heard of Alex Heros
he's an excellent business strategist he
helps entrepreneurs like I'm talking 10x
100x one thing that I heard on one of
his podcasts one of his webinars was
preparation equals confidence so if you
guys are let's say you're getting maybe
you're not even live maybe you haven't
gone live yet you're just paper trading
you're Sim trading and you are you have
the this crippling anxiety you're not
prepared so you're not ready you're not
confident and I think making sure the
the preparation is there the foundation
then you know that's where the
confidence comes into play then you guys
won't be so nervous to to go live to
place that trade so making sure that the
preparation is there and he's a little
bit more harsh than I am but essentially
he was like if you're nervous you
haven't done enough work work harder try
again I believe yes there sometimes
there's nerves naturally you can kind of
turn them into excitement instead of
nervousness you can kind of trick
yourself but for the most part if there
is this crippling anxiety or nervousness
it's because there's not enough
preparation so you need to continue to
prep continue to prepare continue to get
the Reps in I think that's one of the
biggest Parts about psychology that's
how you you build your psychology is you
you prepare mentally there are even
outside of the trading space it's it's
always the same concept there's many
Concepts that just apply to Simply being
an entrepreneur running a business that
correlate with success in trading so if
you guys are into self-help if you guys
are into leveling up doing webinars
going to conventions I can guarantee you
those will help in your trading okay and
then the next part is strategy so now we
can kind of talk about this science
experiment that I was talking about so
when we're trying to find a strategy
which is hard because there's probably
thousands of different ways to trade
probably thousands that's what I'm going
to guess and figuring out which one
resonates with you I understand that you
some of you guys here in the webinar
tonight might not resonate or might not
be able to to make trend lines work for
them and I'm going to guarantee that for
the most part it's going to be the
traders that have too much experience
that they're like there's no possible
way that something as basic as trend
lines can make me or generate me money
in the markets and that's usually it's
like the hardest thing to take it back
to the basics after you've immersed
yourself in trading in different
strategies for years I'm not saying
there's no hope because there is but
it's usually the ones that know too much
that have the hardest time making trend
lines work but regardless even if you
decide not to go with trend lines trying
to find something simple enough for you
to to understand and I'm talking like
you can't be intimidated by it you have
to believe you can do it and trend lines
just checks all of the boxes when I was
first introduced to looking at a chart
the chart itself I was like okay it's a
little bit intimidating there's we got a
graph we got you know the X and the Y
AIS we've got some movement here we've
got some bars some candlesticks then my
uncle threw some lines on it he threw
some trend lines on the screen I was
still able to follow I wasn't
intimidated so you got to find something
that resonates with you you got to have
full confidence that you can understand
it to its fullest and what easier way to
do than trend lines now why would you
want to why would you want to trade a
simp system I think the reason why most
people gravitate towards me anyways is
because I'm able to do the least amount
of effort the least amount of research
the least amount of all of it to get my
success I had tunnel vision I never lost
sight where I'm like you know what maybe
I need to try something else maybe my
uncle what he taught me isn't going to
work for me maybe he's not being
truthful and there were I'm not going to
lie there were moments where I had some
intrusive thoughts but I never acted on
them I never was like you know what
let's try something else and that's the
coolest part keeping it simple if you
can find a system I mean that's why you
guys try to find webinars that's why you
guys do courses is because you don't
want to do the trial and era yourself so
if I can get you guys from point A to
point B in the fastest and requires the
least amount of research and the least
amount of time that's what I'm here for
and that's exactly what my uncle did for
me I mean you guys are this is going to
blow some of you guys' minds but when my
uncle taught me he kept it as simple as
possible I never learned about Fibonacci
I had to learn that word while getting
into social media and I'm pretty sure I
mispronounced it for most of my year on
social media I didn't even know how to
place a stop loss when my uncle taught
me that's one of the craziest things
that I think people won't understand I
never used take profits didn't know what
they were I didn't even really know what
the Forex Market was he made sure that
everything he taught me was just I'm
talking Bare Bones like the Bare Bones
so when I'm when he was done teaching me
I was able to place a trade generate
money generate income just open close a
trade and just do this consistently he
wasn't like okay I need you to go I'm
showing you how to do these trend lines
but now I need you to go research the
earnings reports for X Y and Z and I
need you to do some research on the
correlation between these Forex pairs
like when I tell you guys it was Bare
Bones it was here is a chart this is the
price and this is the time in between
each bar okay I can read a chart easy we
didn't even get I didn't even know what
a Candlestick was he had if some of you
guys I know a lot of you guys are
newbies but for the experience Traders
you guys know that there's different
types of charts you can look at you can
look at a line chart you can look at a
bar chart you can look at a Candlestick
chart there's a few other options as
well but we just looked at the bar chart
kept it as simple as possible he even
had all of the colors stay the same we
didn't have red bars and green bars so
I'm telling you he just dumbed it down
for me and that's what I want to do for
you guys dumb it down so yes if you guys
um decide to to learn with me you you're
not going to be incredibly educated on
what moves the market what moves the
dollar it's simply just I want to get
you guys from point A to point B and
this kind of leads back into the I was
wondering how many of you guys work the
9o fs well now I'm curious how many of
you guys are already entrepreneurs I
feel like this is this strategy is for
the entrepreneur this is truly what I
feel like now obviously it's going to be
for the newbies and for the nineo fs I
think making the segue to entrepreneur
is going to be your best bet but when I
tell you that this strategy is for the
entrepreneurs it truly is one because it
does not require 100% of your attention
you can still focus on your business you
can focus on that side gig I know some
of you guys some someone said I own a
juice bar but it requires a lot of your
your time a lot of your attention you
have to focus on that so how could you
possibly make trading work when it
requires hours upon hours every day of
research of figuring out the strategy
comprehending it making sure it makes
sense to you and that's the coolest part
about the strategy is that it's it's
simple so the entrepreneur your basic
everyday entrepreneur who has a business
to run who's maybe got a family a 9 to5
maybe you're going to school that has
too much of their attention already
taken up this is too perfect we're not
going to go too into the nitty-gritty
when when you're done with the strategy
or you're done learning you truly will
be able to trade there's no more
prerequisites there's no additional
assignments it's just simply you
repeating what we've just learned if I
was to tell you that the strategy that
you're going to learn is the easiest
takes the least amount of time least
amount of effort and it's going to get
you from point A to point B I can
guarantee you guys are going to choose
that path instead of the path of okay
this is going to be a really complex
strategy there's a lot to it I've got to
learn order blocks and the correlation
between buyers and sellers and I've got
to do my my research on the news coming
up each day and I've got to make sure
that I'm in front of the charts an hour
before and an hour after market Clos
maybe that strategy could make you more
it's going to require a lot more time
and a lot more learning but I can
guarantee you guys if I was to show you
an easier path and it can make you x
amount make you at least we'll say like
a solid now it's all going to be
dependent on Capital size obviously but
let's say an average amount if you could
make an extra $1 to $2,000 a month I
think that's absolutely a great place to
start and then the more that you build
your Capital the more that you can make
it every month you'll get to a point
where I'm going to be talking about my
how close I am to my goal and I'm almost
at my 200k mark for the year which is
double what I did last year and the year
before that so it's just the more you do
it the bigger that you increase your
position size it's the same strategy
what I'm doing now is the same thing I
was doing when my uncle taught me it is
just simply getting the confidence to
increase your position size building
that Capital that actual capital and
that mental Capital as well there was a
phase where in my kind of this movement
onto social media where I was very very
self-conscious at first and I was like
maybe my strategy isn't maybe it's not
that great and I was able to to see find
my own success and trting but I'm seeing
some of these guys make millions and I'm
like I'm not I'm not anywhere near close
that I'm not making millions I'm just
making a few thousand dollar extra a
month and had to bring It full circle
and be like okay you know what maybe
some of these guys aren't even actually
maybe some are not actually profitable
or actually making the results that
they're saying they're making or if they
are maybe they've just got so much more
Capital so there was a disconnect and
when I was able to kind of Bring It full
circle and be like okay the strategy
that I'm trading it may not be Einstein
it may not be this crazy complex
strategy that's going to make me the
most it possibly can but it makes me
enough and it's not overwhelming and
it's truly it's tangible it's digestible
and it gets me where I need to go and I
truly think that is trend lines and
Trend reversals and the bounce and the
break there's a lot of different ways to
trade for the newbies they may not know
some of those terms but there's a lot of
different ways to trade trend lines
specifically but man when you can just
bring it down to the base it's so
important and I do want to talk about
the the science experiment kind of part
of it and this will go to the next one
is just implementation which I'll get
into the implementation part next but
the science experiment so let's say that
you guys are trying to figure out I'm
going to give you guys an example of
what I did back in elementary school I
don't can't remember if I did too many
science experiments but I do remember
one and it was trying to figure out what
food would make this plant grow the most
and I had three of the same exact plants
but now if you were to truly figure out
what food could make this these plants
grow the most or the highest or the
biggest you want to make sure that
you're keeping as many variables making
sure that there's least amount of
variables let's say that you've got the
same plant you've got the same soil
you've got the same amount of light
you've got the same amount of liquid
that you're giving each one but now the
only thing that's different is the type
the type of food that you're giving each
one then you can see very clearly and
easily okay so I fed this plant soda it
died turns out didn't work this one I
gave milk this one I gave water this one
I gave orange juice maybe we're doing
three or four but when you keep those
very a small you can see very easily
what worked and what didn't imagine as a
Trader trying to figure out what works
and what doesn't when you've got three
different types of lighting you've got
three different types of soil you've got
indicators moving averages you've got
the news fundamentals you've got this
guy saying this how could you possibly
find success or find what works when
you've got too many variables and I
think that's the that's truly the
epitome of trading just retail trading
specifically is just trying to find
consistent when you got too many
variables you got way too many variables
so keeping it simple and that's where if
you've got something as simple as trend
lines then you can even experiment with
the trend lines so let's say that you're
trading trend line bounces and maybe it
doesn't work for you so now you're going
to try trend line breaks and then maybe
you find a little bit more success and
then now we can start maybe
experimenting with time frames same
strategy same trend line breaks but now
I'm going to try the 4our now I'm going
to try the 1 hour so truly keeping the
amount of variables as small as possible
is going to be it goes back to that 111
that one Mentor one strategy in one hour
a day you can see results if you just
just keep it smaller test do a little
bit of trial and err see what works for
you even the the strategy that my uncle
taught me I do things that just a hair
different than what my uncle does and
that's because I had a had very small
amount of variables and I was able to
experiment and say okay you know what so
when my uncle taught me we traded the
bounce of trend lines I stopped I
haven't traded the bounce of a trend
line in maybe two years maybe even more
than that and it was simply just from
experimenting doing a little trial on
air and seeing within that same strategy
what worked for me and what didn't and
some of you guys are going to exper ment
yourselves I mean some of you guys will
be able to incorporate maybe a moving
average into the trend line strategy and
you can see if it works because it's
only one variable you're just adding one
new thing does it work or does it not if
it does okay cool now we're going to
continue this we're going to continue
the moving average with the trend line
break and now we can try different time
frames so I know some of the terminology
for the newbies it it might be going
over your head but for the most part I'm
just trying to emphasize the Simplicity
and this is the theme of tonight's
webinar is the the elementary version of
trading and I am your Elementary School
teacher tonight and I'm here to teach
the Simplicity of a strategy and that it
can be done it can be easy I know that
sounds that sounds wild that trading can
be easy I don't want to say that it's it
it doesn't require the Reps because it
does just like that that one hour a day
that's a big part of it you can't just
simply try this for 3 weeks and then
just say all right I'm ready to go like
you've got to continue the one hour a
day that can't stop you got to continue
to build that habit so the one hour a
day helps and it it creates that habit
it gets the Reps in and it makes it so
much easier when you do decide to do
trial and error or experiment or add
something a little bit different here or
something a little bit different here so
I know I talked about strategy way too
much but now now let's go over the
implementation part so this is simply
when you're learning a trend line
strategy it can be implemented to and I
don't know if some of you guys know this
but trend lines obviously if we are
let's say we're looking at a chart and I
could tell you that it's any chart as
long as you you see movement and you can
draw a trend line on a chart this
strategy can be implemented so the
coolest part this could be the stock
market I know someone was talking about
I was looking in the chat someone said
something about Tesla or Amazon you guys
can absolutely draw trend lines on a
Tesla chart or an Amazon chart and then
okay so someone's talking about Bitcoin
and gold the coolest part is you can
draw a trend line in the crypto charts
you can draw a trend line on gold if you
drew one on gold it'd probably be
insanely steep because gold is
continuing to create actually you know
what it has pulled back a little bit but
for the most part it was creating higher
highs was blowing my mind but you can
implement this to any any Market that's
the coolest part and then it gets better
not only is it any Market you can draw a
trend line on any time frame you can
draw a trend line on a 5 minute time
frame you can draw a trend line on a 1
hour time frame a 4 hour time frame a
daily I mean if we've got any long-term
investors out there they're trading on
the weekly you can draw a trend line on
any one of these time frames so that's
the coolest part that goes back to this
is implementation but now it's still
simple it's still easy we're still doing
that one1 this is still a simple
strategy we've got One Singular Mentor
if it's me if it's not continue to
listen to that one Mentor that you
already listened to or that you've been
researching but it's just in that one 1
hour a day and that's going to be the
entire theme of tonight is just that
that one1 but the implementation part is
cool because it's it makes so much sense
so we've got a we got a simple strategy
and then how cool that it can just
simply be copy and pasted to a different
Market a different time frame a
different instrument and now the the one
hour a day though this is where gives
you a little bit more of an edge so
let's say that you've got the strategy
down you got the psychology down you've
listened to One Mentor and you've got
one strategy the 1 hour day gives you
that edge because now you are developing
a relationship with the instrument if
you are watching Bitcoin or crude oil or
platinum for 1 hour a day you are
developing a relationship you're kind of
getting a feel for its its movement its
volatility when does it make moves
what's an average move what's a sporadic
move what's a big move what's average is
it around you know 6:00 p.m. to midnight
that it just kind of Putters out you
develop that relationship by just simply
watching that instrument for 1 hour a
day and that is just even more of an
edge so just sticking with the 111 and
oh my gosh and I almost forgot about
talking about my goals which leads into
this as well my goal this year was to
hit 200k in trading profits and I am now
$88,000 away from hitting my yearly
profit goal and it's only October 15th
so that is the coolest part if I make
that $8,000 tonight I am now done
trading for the year and I don't think
it gets any cooler than that now I will
let you know that it is weighing heavy
on my psychology and this last trade is
driving me insane I'm almost too
hesitant I'm being too careful there
were moves in crude oil that I missed
that I'm looking at the charts I'm
watching crude oil the price is breaking
one of my trend lines I'm even talking
to my sister about it I'm like I'm
getting ready to get into a trade she's
like oo let me guess let me look and see
which one it is so she pulls up her
charts and she's like o is it crude oil
because it's breaking I was like yep I'm
getting into crude oil and I never did
didn't do it or like Platinum there were
moves in Platinum to the upside that I
missed so my psychology is a little bit
off because I'm getting so close to this
goal which is double my goal last year
so it's it's taking a little bit of a
toll me this is just me being a
vulnerable with you guys telling you the
psychology that I'm struggling with and
these these last $8,000 to make it to
the 200k and I think the craziest part
the kicker here is that it only took me
less than 15 trades so that 200k almost
we're almost at 200 is less than 15
trades whereas last year my goal was
simply I just wanted to make $100,000
and I believe it took me somewhere
around 75 trades if some of you guys
follow me on social media you know that
last year I was struggling with the
4-Hour time frame this year I've got it
down now I am a beautiful representation
of what a higher time frame what the the
benefits of a higher time frame looks
like and and truly just embracing it to
the maximum least amount of Trades least
amount of chart time I'm engaged Less in
the markets so now I can focus on a
hundred other things I want to have so
many streams of income I want to think
like my uncle does and some just
personal goals that I have this year is
I have been researching getting into
real estate all year am I going to get
an investment property am I going to get
my own property am I going to do a
duplex am I going to do a multif family
home and I want to be able to also have
my own business in the trading industry
so now I want to work towards now I
don't know what that is this is me also
being very open with you guys it could
be a program it could be a platform it
could be a an app I am looking to to
kind of make my mark in the trading
industry so I need more time and I need
more Focus to do that outside of my
trading outside of my social media
outside of my education I am I'm trying
to really just immerse myself as the the
boss entrepreneur that I am becoming and
I am actually trying to bring my
students into the same mindset as well
just multiple streams of income just
being the the best version of an
entrepreneur that you can possibly be
thanks for hanging out everybody see you