hey everybody Tory trades here did you
notice the setup it feels therapeutic
should I get my notebook out today we're
going to talk about the emotional aspect
of trading and specifically going over
isolation I'm essentially just going to
be talking about some strategies that we
can put into place to combat this and
share some of my experiences that I've
had and maybe just some that you are
also going through so we understand that
trading is a very solitary thing we are
making decisions day in and day out by
ourselves this is not a a group effort
this is not a team effort this is truly
just you in the charts and when you
think about isolation it's not just
physical like yes physically you are
isolated you are either in a room with a
computer you are alone holding your
phone just you in the screens but it's
also psychological you are alone making
these decisions by yourself so let's
explore why this happens and how it
impacts our mental health so we'll start
with me sharing my experience and I
remember when I first started trading
there was so much excitement so much
excitement I wanted to spend every
waking hour on the charts trading taking
as many opportunities as I could I was
obsessed I just wanted to practice the
strategy as much as I could when it's
something new you just want to
completely throw yourself into it well
after time went by and you did do that
and I did do that you find yourself
losing sleep maybe sitting in front of
the computer for too many hours maybe
not eating maybe skipping snacks
skipping meals you find yourself kind of
losing yourself I remember there were
times where the excitement phase was
still most of the year the first year
was exciting I didn't feel like it was
deteriorating my mental health I didn't
feel like it was hurting my physical
health either but it was the second year
when I found myself losing sleep I would
be glued to the screens if I was in a
trade yes I'd have my alerts set I'd
take the laptop to bed with me and I
would just lay there and stare at it for
hours and hours and hours no sleep I'd
be setting so many alerts that if I did
doze off I'd get an alert it' wake me
back up and I'd continue to watch I was
obsessive and there was absolutely many
times where it started to leave an
impact on my personal life I just wasn't
sleeping the next day like I was still
continuing to work and do other things
along with trading I wasn't myself you
know when you're in that like first 3
years of trading the losses take a toll
on you your confidence gets crushed so
it's like outside of isolation yes it's
me in my bed with the charts for hours
with my screen but then also so the
confidence goes down so this is like a
darker side of trading that I guess not
many people talk about it's a dark thing
when you start taking loss after loss
this is real money once you've made it
to live trading and you're taking actual
losses you start to put your value and
your selfworth in your trading and I did
that many times when I wasn't making
money I felt worthless as a person
that's such a harsh thing to say but
that's truly how I gave myself worse I
Associated it with my trading with my
success or my my losses but let's figure
out okay what are some way ways or what
are some strategies that we can put into
place to help us when something like
this happens and we can start with just
simply structuring our day how much time
are we going to spend in front of the
charts if we actually plan that out we
wouldn't tell ourselves to spend 12
hours out of the day in front of the
charts no we would give ourselves an a
lotted time to spend in front of the
market so now let's give ourselves an a
lotted amount of time let's maybe start
with just 4 hours at a time if you're
spending 12 hours 6 hours 8 hours in
front of the charts let's just cut that
to four four is still a significant
amount you can get plent plenty of chart
time with 4 hours in front of the charts
but now let's stick to that when that
timer goes off and you've hit 4 hours we
got to disconnect so now outside of just
you know structuring your day isolation
it gets very lonely so let's figure out
how we can still connect with other
Traders whether that's forms communities
social media let's find ways to connect
with other Traders we just want to
participate in a community where we can
talk about our losses talk about our
trades so maybe we're not actually on
the charts but we at least have a
community to engage with so it just
doesn't feel as lonely or best case
scenario you have friends in real life
that you can actually connect with and
you can meet up with them and you can
talk about your trades for the day and
that's going to be harder to do finding
traders that are actually in person I'm
here in Nashville and we'll be looking
to create some sort of workshops here
where where we can actually connect and
find that Community but I know where
you're at there might not be as many
Traders it seems huge you know when
we're on social media but in the real
world here trading is so small there's
not actually many Traders out there and
then lastly don't forget just taking
breaks Hobbies I mean I I preached this
all the time it's so much easier said
than done but you know reading running
exercising taking your dog out I mean
there's just so many things Hot Yoga
that's one of my favorites cycling one
of my favorites reading also one of my
favorites social media creating this
right here is a hobby of mine I'm not
spending time on the charts I'm talking
about the charts but I'm not actively in
front of my screen or in a trade right
now either so just finding separation is
going to be huge that's the last thing
that I have for helping combat this
isolation
this deterioration of mental health
these are some strategies that we can
put into place