let's face it trading can be tough
especially when it feels like the market
is working against you but what if I
told you there is a simple tool you can
use to turn the odds in your favor in
this video I will show you how I
overcame my own trading struggles using
moving averages so stick around to learn
how you can use them too to improve your
own trading results the biggest
challenge I faced as a Trader is that I
found myself constantly struggling to
find the trends and make profitable
trades I would easily get caught up in
the Motions of the market and I often
found myself entering or exiting trades
too soon or too late and I remember
feeling helpless as I watched my trading
account balance ring day after day
especially when I was trying so hard for
months to profit but no matter what I
did I just couldn't seem to get it right
as if the market was mocking me daring
me to try harder and on top of feeling
helpless I felt like a complete failure
like I wasted so much time and money on
something that wasn't meant for me but
then as fade would have it I stumble
upon an article about moving averages I
had heard of them before but I never
really understood how they work so I
started doing my homework and trying
them on my demo account and to my
surprise things started to click the
market wasn't so unpredictable anymore
and I was able to identify Trends and
make trades with more confidence than I
ever before and as I continue to explore
the moving average strategy I discovered
that in order to use moving averages
effectively I had to determine the
appropriate time frame to analyze I
learned that typically the longer the
time frame the stronger the trend but
delayed signals and therefore I found
that it's crucial to combine multiple
time frames to get a clearer picture of
the Market's movements when it comes to
technical analysis I always perform
top-down analysis starting from the
monthly down to the four hour time frame
let me show you an example of a trade I
took on March 6th which was a buy
position on the eurocad currency pair on
the monthly chart I noticed that the
price was in an uptrend which was
confirmed by the 20 period moving
average being broken and the price was
around 220 Pips away from being retested
as it has happened before if we take a
look back over here so I then looked at
the weekly time frame and noticed that
even here the moving averages are
trending below confirming the bullish
bias and the price has made a new high
because it has clearly closed above the
previous high so on The Daily I had very
similar scenario the 20 and 50 moving
averages are below however we also have
a daily resistance because of multiple
rejections in the past signaling me that
even if the price goes up it more than
likely will react to this level but I
was thinking that even before the price
does that we have at least a 60 pip Zone
that we could profit from so I moved on
to the four hour time frame and here's
where all the fun begins and the reason
I'm using four hour chart is to
determine the best entry point so based
on this analysis I discovered that the
20 and 50 period averages were acting as
a dynamic support and as someone who
likes to play safe are usually wait for
the four hour candlesticks to close
before making a trade but please
remember that you cannot only base your
trading decisions on the closure of a
Candlestick and price action and
fundamental analysis is also a part of
this big puzzle and as I mentioned
before about bullish engulfing candles
to closing above one of the moving
averages it's usually a successful trade
so I can show you a few examples so
let's say you would enter it on this
bullish engulfing Candlestick bouncing
off the 20 period moving average and of
course based on your risk management and
Target levels you could potentially
profited 40 Pips 80 Pips or even around
110 or maybe you will be entering on
this huge bullish engulfing Candlestick
that just crossed above the 50 moving
average and I usually go for 80 Pips but
again that depends on your risk
management and your risk tolerance or if
you let the trade run you could
potentially profit it around 180 Pips so
so this was just a couple examples on
how you could potentially profit it
based on a bullish engulfing candles to
closure now that I had the clear
direction for the market and a plan for
my entry it was time to focus on risk
management which is absolutely critical
for any trading strategy so in this case
of the Euro cat trade my stop loss was
strategically placed below the 20 moving
average so the trade played out as
analyzed and as you can probably see
here the 20 period moving average has
again showed its benefits by reacting as
its support and the eurocat pair
eventually healed my last profit Target
which was 160 Pips but you know
sometimes trading is not all about
rainbows and sunshines and as a Traders
we will inevitably experience losses but
it's how we deal with them that truly
defines us I have certainly had my fair
share of losses and I know just how
difficult it can be to pick yourself
back up after a significant loss one
particular trade that comes to mind is a
trade I took on ndd JPY pair back in
February the weekly and the daily time
frames was trending down and I thought I
had identified a great entry point I had
my moving averages lined up covering my
stop loss So I entered the trade with a
lot of confidence however as soon as I
entered the trade things started to go
wrong the market didn't behave as I
expected to and I was down a significant
amount of money and eventually the trade
hit my stop loss looking back I realized
that I made a common mistake that many
Traders make not following my trading
plan I knew that my trading Plan called
for me to wait for some sort of bearish
candles to closure before entering the
trade but I let my emotions to get the
best out of me and I entered the trade
prematurely to avoid making the same
mistake in the future I recommend myself
and you guys to stick to your plan in no
matter what and I always say that back
testing is crucial step in developing
and refining a successful trading
strategy because by doing so you can
identify any weaknesses and make
adjustments to improve its performance
in the future when I first started using
moving averages as part of my trading
strategy I knew that back testing was
the key to validating its Effectiveness
that's why I turned to Trader Edge a
powerful platform that allows me to
backtest my strategies with ease and
trust me Trader age is not just any
ordinary platform it's specifically
designed to make back testing more
efficient with features like built-in
profit and loss calendar and trade
journal to track and analyze your
performance with Trader veg I was able
to easily store and save all of my back
testing data which was incredibly useful
in refining mind moving average strategy
so if you're serious about trading and
want to give yourself the best chance of
success in the long run then back
testing is an essential step I highly
recommend trying out Traders platform
for yourself and you can even sign up
for a 7 day free trial using the link in
my description box down below if you
enjoyed this video don't stop here
Explore More trading strategies and
techniques in my playlist watch this
video next to discover new ways of
improving your Trading