what's poppin snake gang welcome back to
another video i lost my voice a little
bit i was sick for a little while and i
i've been recovered but for some reason
my voice just never came back so voice
is a little [\h__\h] up right now but
regardless we're still gonna do what we
got to do we're on our way currently to
pick up the urus if you guys watch the
rolls royce video you know that i
swapped the rolls royce for the urus
when the pole's race was done
so now i'm going back to pick up the
urus see how it you know how it came out
and to be real damn you gonna get over
or what the thing is
i don't even know what it looks like
because he didn't show me he said that
it came out so good that he's not gonna
show me until i get there so it's gonna
be surprised for me like i know the
color i know what they did to the rims
things like that but i i don't know
because i didn't
show me what it looks like i don't know
how good it came out but he's very
confident that it came out very good
they did it very fast if you guys
watched the last video the rolls royce
took a little bit longer than it should
have but the urus they did i swear to
god like a week and a half so very fast
very fast for that we're gonna go pick
it up right now see how it came out and
i'm gonna actually go over how i was
able to buy this yours buy my second
lamborghini thanks to crypto right and i
mean you guys know i make money from all
these different things but i'm confident
to give myself a second lamborghini
because i have so much more income
coming now trading crypto as well and um
we'll talk about that as well so stay
tuned for that part that's what most you
guys are waiting for so don't fast
forward to that part though you got to
watch the years too because i hate when
people just it shows me on youtube the
analytics that you guys be dropping off
and then popping back up when it comes
to the strategies but you got to watch
the full video come on 24 hours in a day
just watch the full video it's a good
video so with that being said we're
gonna go to get the airs right now and
i'll see you guys when we get there
all right we're here we just pulled up
to royalty tent like i said i don't know
what it looks like so we're about to see
right now as you can see the garage is
shut i guess uh we're just knocking
let's see what they say let's see
knock knock okay let's just let's just
crawl under
they got the music so loud they can't
even hear me hello what's up i'm outside
the garage all right cool all right all
right now my heart's racing all right
here we go all right
ready
oh [\h__\h] he's almost just gotta knock the
[\h__\h] out all right so looking at the car
it's like flawless
it looks nicer than like when i pictured
it i didn't i didn't picture this this
looks
wow holy [\h__\h] they even did the grill
purple the rims are purple
everything else is blacked out so
it looks so good all right bro it looks
great here you go
ready for that i'm going bro at this
point
now it looks good it looks really good
crazy good very detailed awesome
so now for the driveway cars i call
these the driveway cars because these
are the cars i'm gonna drive every day
this is like the daily type of cars kids
things like that we now have obviously
the rolls-royce ghost
and the euris i'm happy with the
driveway cars i really have it's like a
dream come true to actually have both of
these and wow
sorry for the mess i don't know if you
could actually see the mess you know we
got the louie bags right there the gucci
christmas has just been crazy um crazy
expensive i should say because it's
costing me a fortune the main reason you
guys are here is to pretty much find out
how crypto bought me my new lamborghini
yours okay and it's very simple it boils
down to a couple different things and
you know if you're not in my crypto
group where i'm sending out all my
crypto trades every single day
definitely join that the link will be
down below everybody's making this money
with me and you know if you guys want to
see results and all that good stuff go
to my instagram at mamba fx trading go
to my highlights and look at the crypto
gains you'll see testimonials you'll see
all my games and all the money i've made
and uh just proof all that good stuff
it's all there so just go to mamafx
trading on instagram and you will see
all of the proof with that being said
it's not that necessarily crypto bought
me a lambo right not the not that you
know i didn't have enough money before
to buy a lambo i could have bought in a
second lambo if i really wanted to
here's what crypto did for me okay and
this is why it's very important you guys
pay attention is because you know you
have to have more than one income stream
okay and i'm gonna tell you why right
now if i didn't have crypto making me as
much as it has if i haven't made seven
figures from crypto i would not have
been comfortable buying another supercar
okay i have a huracan rolls royce i had
the i gave it away you guys saw that
video there's just been a lot of cars
right there's been a lot of cars for me
to own three super cars at once you know
i had to have something that was going
to make me money consistently so that
way i could say hey this income stream
will pay for all my cars and these
income streams i'll save or pay taxes
whatever the case may be so you know i
make money trading forex now crypto for
like a year now i have a lot of other
income streams that i have listed before
you can go actually check out that video
if you have it it's on my channel but
the point i'm trying to bring you guys
is don't go and spend 50 of what you
make on a car or on something that's
materialistic i was never gonna buy a
third supercar if i wasn't making enough
to where only maybe five percent of what
i make is going towards the monthly
payment on those cars and that's kind of
how it is now it's actually less than
five percent so if i'm not making you
know enough to buy those cars cash five
times i'm not going to actually purchase
those cars and i really think you guys
should do the same okay so let's say
you're making 10k a month at your job
now don't go and spend 6k on a car
monthly or 4k on a car monthly okay same
thing with housing okay your house
always makes up like 80 of what you make
if you're you know working a regular job
but for those of you who want to be an
entrepreneur and making money you know
doing things online stuff like that i
would stick to a ten percent ten percent
of what you make should go towards a
house five percent towards cars that
puts you at 15 percent leaving 85
percent for whatever else which could be
groceries you gotta factor in their food
gas all that good stuff i really
recommend that you guys save 65 to 70 of
the money you make and out of that 70
you make um save you should definitely
be reinvesting half of it that's how i
play it the other half goes toward
saving slash taxes 35 is gonna go
towards reinvesting okay whether it's
forex crypto stocks housing i mean uh
real estate whatever the case may be
reinvesting it and then the other 35
i'm going with pay your taxes obviously
and save the rest towards a rainy day or
whatever the case may be that's how i
play it and it's working for me i'm very
comfortable where i'm at a lot of money
saved a lot of money reinvested i mean a
lot of money reinvested just sitting
places that it's growing constantly you
never want your money to just sit in a
bank account okay so i guess the message
in this video really would be is do not
spend all your hard earned money on a
car that looks cool but instead spend 75
percent of your money reinvesting saving
and then you can take that 25 percent
get the necessities that if you can't
afford a car out of that 25 or whatever
the case may be then you don't need a
car in that moment okay things change if
you need a car to get around and it's
another you buy yourself a nice little
honda or something very cheap that you
can find on offer up or you know things
like that for now you have to understand
that to get big rich whatever you want
to be you have to you know take the
route it's going to be slow it's not
going to be something that happens
overnight and you have to understand
that so if you have to drive a beat up
car for you know a year or two while
you're learning the craft of forex or
crypto or whatever the case may be you
have to actually be able to be
comfortable driving a car like that but
understand that one day you will have a
lamborghini you will have a rolls royce
you really got to manifest that energy
and you really have to put your all in
to get to that point but to you know
make a million dollars and then spend it
on a car and a house just like that is
not very smart i recommend you take that
million you do the 25 that's 250k
towards whatever you need for the year
the other 750k you're reinvesting it to
make even more money until you can
actually get a lamborghini with five
percent of what you make sounds crazy
but trust me this is why millionaires
stay millionaires the wealthy always get
wealthier because they do things like
this they don't just rush into that
lambo or rush into these things okay i
have a lambo rolls royce all these
different cars and i also have a house
over my head that i'm gonna be in for as
long as i need to be and my kids are
safe we're healthy everything's fine and
only five percent of what i make is
going towards those cars out there so
realistically i'm living great because i
followed a rule i followed a set plan
and i stuck with it and that's what i
recommend you guys do with that being
said i hope you guys enjoy the video
again this is how crypto allowed me to
get another car another supercar
mentally okay mentally is what i'm
trying to tell you guys is i can now buy
these cars mentally and i can actually
say hey five percent is still gonna be
five percent it's not gonna be ten
percent if i go get another supercar
it's gonna stay under five percent
because now crypto's making me so much
money if you guys are interested in
joining any of the things i offer it's
down below the crypto group my forex app
which is 100 free making people
thousands of dollars every day for free
other than that i don't have anything
else to offer follow me on instagram if
you guys want more content and i will
see you guys in my next video
peace out guys and i'll see you guys
later bye don't tell me how i'm feeling
when you really don't know still be my
little shotty at all on my show yeah
bust a couple shots if you [\h__\h] with my
brother
[Music]
me