have you ever found yourself caught up
in the Whirlwind of trading complexities
wondering why those charts and
indicators you obsessively analyzing
Dyson bring the results you want well
today I'm going to give you a refreshing
perspective on trading that will sweep
away the Clutter and bring you a winning
strategy and I also have a little
trading hack just for you but you will
have to stick around for that one you
know in the fast-paced training
environment the simple approach is often
forgotten because many Traders are eager
for quick gains and merge themselves in
the complex charts numerous indicators
and it's all too easy to get lost in the
details and forget what it truly matters
however let me tell you that the key to
trading success often lies in the
Simplicity you know it's all about going
back to the basics that you have learned
cutting through the noise of the market
and focusing on what truly matters so my
trading strategy mainly relies on two
things the 20 and 50 period moving
averages they help me to understand
market trends and pinpoint the best
times to enter and exit rates but there
is another important tool that I use in
conjunction with the moving averages and
that's the parabolic sorry it serves as
a great great complement to the moment
averages helping me to spot potential
reversals in the market Trend so let's
dive a little deeper into how I use
these tools and how to set them up on
your chart so first things first open
trademiew.com select your preferred
currency pair and click on the
indicators button at the top of the
screen and a search box will appear
inside that box type in moving average
and click on it you will now see a line
appear on your chart so click on the
settings or the little gear icon over
here to adjust the length to 20 and now
repeat the same process to add another
moving average line but this time
setting the length to 15. next we add
the parabolic sorry to our charts so
repeat the same process as you did for
the moving averages but this time type
the parabolic sorry into the serger box
and as per usual a simple strategy comes
with a simple setup guide so for a long
trade position here's what we're gonna
be doing so before I jump into any trade
I always make sure to check fxtree.com
because this is all about being aware of
any upcoming news events that could
seriously impact the trade and its
outcome so you should definitely make
sure you do this too to avoid any nasty
surprises now let's dive into the
nitty-gritty part which are the rules of
the strategy first things first add both
the moving averages and parabolics are
to your chart but for the sake of
clarity we are going to initially turn
off the parabolic style while we assess
the overall trend using only the mobile
averages on the higher time frames such
as monthly weekly and daily charts
remember that you want to be trading
with the trend so all these higher time
frames should align in the same
direction so for example if you're
looking to enter a long trade the price
should be above the moving averages on
all these time frames and vice versa 4
itself next with the parabolics are
still turned off Mark your support and
resistance zones and tag any trend lines
or chart patterns you identify this is
very vital to understand the why behind
your trade and make appropriate
decisions once you have done this turn
the parabolic star back on the four hour
chart is where we are mainly going to be
trading but the one hour chart can give
us a heads up on the moving average
cross a bit earlier than a four hour
chart so to successfully open a long
position ensure that the moving averages
are positioned below the candlesticks
and the parabolic star dots are also
below because this signifies a bullish
bias last but not least set your stop
loss based on what your price action
analysis is telling you or below the
previous low to give the choice some
room to move in case all people back so
the ideal entry should be based on any
strong bullish candles to closure and
it's even better if this happens right
after the parabolic side dots flips from
above to below the price so I highly
suggest opening a 50-minute chart as the
indicator will react quicker and while
we are on the topic of strategy I think
it's the perfect time to introduce the
dynamic duo which is disciplined and
consistency you may be thinking is there
a secret technique that professional
Traders are hiding well there is not
they're not so secret weapon is just
consistency in implementing a
disciplined trading plan and I would say
that your primary goal should be
sticking to the trading rules you have
set because it might be so tempting to
try a new strategy or bend the rules
when things are not going your way but
the fact is is that the trader who stays
loyal and faithful to the trading plan
takes home the profits So based on the
rules I just explained let's take a look
at my VIP trade I took on CAD JPY so
starting on a monthly chart I noticed
CAD overpowering the Japanese Yen
breaking through multiple monthly pivot
Points and even Crossing 104 triple zero
a key psychological level clear daily
signaling you bullish Trend now it's
time to get a clear picture of support
and resistance zones with the parabolic
Stars still turned off I marked these
zones along with any noticeable trend
lines or chart patterns so on the weekly
chart the price has broken out from the
double bottom neckline and it's trending
above both moving averages moving to the
daily chart a new high has been formed
and I marked this previous High Zone
over here since the price has been
rejected before so let's zoom in further
to the four hour chart and as you can
see the price shows strong bullish
Behavior by bringing the symmetrical
triangle pattern to the upside and this
is where we activate and bring the
parabolic star into play and as the dots
remain below the price they add another
layer of confirmation to our bullish
Outlook so this is the sort of
Confluence I always love to see when
planning to enter a long trade alright
so let's get to the exciting part which
is executing entries however it's not
all about just rushing in because we
also need to ensure that our trades are
protected in this case and in fact in
all of my trading moves I always ensure
that my stop loss covers the four hour
moving averages of 20 and 15. now do you
remember the trading hack I tease you
with at the start well it's time to
reveal it so sometimes well 90 of the
time when I trade I like to count how
many bullish engulf enclosures happened
above the 20 and 50 moving averages on
the one hour chart it probably sounds a
little bit odd doesn't it but hey
trading isn't always about the rigid
strategies and serious calculations and
Counting those bullish engulfing
candlesticks has proven to be a very
successful way of doing it you see
sometimes a Sprinkle of fun and
experimentation can shake things up in
the best possible way so why not to give
it a try so the way to calculate those
bullish engulf enclosures is like doing
a little back test before you entering
the trade to make sure to get that
additional confirmation for your bullish
bias so what you need to do is to open
your long position set your take profit
and stop loss levels based on your risk
management and price action and then
basically count every single bullish
envelope enclosure above the above
moving averages and see how many times
it hit your profit Target and that's it
so by using this simple yet highly
effective strategy the result for CAD
gpy pair becomes very obvious because a
route correct analysis you know the
trend alignment and identification of
key levels on the chart along with the
parabolic star does I was able to secure
another win for myself and my trading
Community because as you can see a trade
successfully hit my take profit retarget
resulting in a remarkable gain of 160
Pips so after 5 years of trading I can
honestly say that Simplicity is the key
to success however even when the winning
strategy Traders May stumble if they
like essential know-how to effectively
enter and exit the trades but you don't
need to struggle any longer because by
clicking this video over here you will
learn the four powerful strategies to
help you to achieve the success you have
been striving for