all right guys I have made it to 100K in
trading profits 102 to be exact wow this
is this is kind of wild this is pretty
neat this is something that I haven't
done before I'm I'm continuing to hit
personal bests personal records bigger
trades it's a little bit overwhelming
it's exciting but like kind of crazy you
guys got to follow me along this entire
Journey last year was was so tough you
guys got to see the entire freaking year
of trading and how not only was I just
trying to make profit as a Trader which
is freaking ridiculously hard you guys
should know that but I also was trying
to make a transition from being a day
trader to swing Trader you could see
every single month the every single
trade you could see the struggles you
could see from January you saw that I
placed 12 trades that's not a swing
Trader no that was a day trader right
there so essentially you guys got to see
the struggles that I went through just
trying to be profitable and then not
only that trying to go from day trading
to swing trading well this year I feel
like I got it down is that kind of do I
have a big head does it look too big
because I feel like I got a big head
right now now like I feel like I just
mastered the 4-Hour time frame it's easy
it's kind of easy to be honest I almost
have 100% win rate with the exception of
one loss which I'm going to be totally
honest with you guys believe me or not
was an accidental trade I got into a
platinum position two days before
contract was going to expire I had to
close it and then reopen but still I I
had almost 100% win rate this year I've
got only six trades let's see do I have
only six trades 1 2 3 4 5 six but not
many Traders can say espec especially
ones that are trying to get into that
4-Hour time frame or trying to make that
transition from day trader to swing
Trader which go figure I'm actually
going to go back to the 5 minute just
I'm experimenting with it stay tuned
that'll be a fun thing to go through but
right now we're just going through my
swing trading stats and we're six trades
in we're at
$12,800 this is really exciting I feel
like man it's it's very like rewarding
to put in so much work for an entire
year to Just Master that time frame and
then to come at it this year and have it
mastered like how
and not only that but you guys should
understand by now how freaking difficult
it is to make money as a Trader you got
to have your psychology down you've got
to have so much confidence in your
strategy you got to be consistent like
there are so many things that play a
role in a profitable Trader and I embody
that it's really exciting and another
cool thing is that I'm actually doing
this there's some people on the internet
there's some influencers there's some
Educators there's some gurus that don't
actually make money trading now I'm not
throwing any shade on anyone I have
everything to back it up I've got broker
statements I've live logins I've got yes
you can see my trade Zella I understand
that these can be modified they can be
changed or manipulated but my broker
statements can't my live broker logins
can't like this is all real so this is
it gives me like this this peace of mind
to to show you guys my journey to walk
you guys through all my trades to be an
educator to be an influencer I have the
credibility I have this confidence like
it's just it's there she is her I am her
let's kind of walk through each one of
these trades my average hold time has
been about a week for each trade the
most recent trade I was in this 24,000
trade was only 3 days and I'm going to
tell you exactly why it was only 3 days
one I closed early two I wanted to get
to 100K so that I can make this video
until you guys I'm at 100K yay there's a
video previously talking about how I
closed a trade early simply because I
wanted to make this video and here we
are making the video love this for me
cut hi guys Tori here interrupting Tori
in my own video I wanted to talk to you
guys about Apex and if you are looking
for somewhere to invest your money and
you don't quite have the capital to
trade it Apex allows anywhere between 25
to $300 K worth of funding if you pass
their evaluation you can become a funded
Trader don't forget to enter code Tory
for the best possible promotion okay but
we did make it to 100K we're six trades
in first trade of the year was on
January 29th it took me 29 days to just
place my first trade of the year I was
having PTSD from my last January which
was rough I was just nervous reserved
cautious I wanted to pick the perfect
setup I was so nervous that like what if
I come into this year and it's it's not
profitable and I'm taking everyone along
this journey and they watch me fail like
there was a lot of a lot of stuff going
into January but then finally on the
29th I said all right we're doing it
we're placing a trade I got into a
platinum position I made 10,000 bucks
clipped out early because there was
already so much psychology every single
one of these trades I clipped out early
we're going to walk through this we're
going to talk through it but first trade
of the year we wanted to just make some
profit collect that profit okay 10,000
bucks in the bag we're good to go moving
on to the next month I didn't place my
next trade until February 20th yet
almost another month goes by that I
didn't place a trade but but this one we
made
$229,000 that was my record trade Point
Blank period to date was February 20th $
29,000 I wanted to hold for a little bit
longer to hit that 30k Mark just to be
like it sounds like a fun number it's
you know it's even 30 but that $29,000 I
wanted it to be that round number we're
going to call it round because the zero
is round I know that anyways I got 29
I'm happy with it I was good I was happy
but I still clipped out early I just
simply wanted I I was up a record amount
I wanted to take that trade I wanted to
take that profit but you guys can see
the the psychology involved here I just
I closed out of yet another trade early
I wasn't able to let it play out for its
entirety then the next trade was March
1st I made 10,000 in crude oil so this
was a different instrument this is one
I'm really used to I've got a lot of
experience more so than Platinum with
crude oil I felt good about this one
this was the easy 10K but yet another
time I CED out early every single one of
these I did a lot of psychology involved
here when you make your record trade the
statistic of Traders losing all of it
and just they're too confident they're
going in way too heavy the amount of ego
it gives you I was very aware of that so
I just came into the next trade cautious
I wanted to just take some more profit
let's keep adding to the bag here now
the next trade same month March 26 this
was my y goofed trade negative $2,000
sure I'll take it we've got what 10,000
29,000 10,000 I'll take a Nega $2,000
all day but this was an accidental trade
and let me tell you why which I made a
video about it before if you haven't
seen it I'll link it somewhere here you
guys guys can see the video but I got
into a platinum position on the contract
that was getting ready to expire in 2
days first of all we're we're we're 26
days later from the last trade so
there's just so much time in between
each trade one I'm just I'm feeling like
I should be trading more which is not
true I'm a swing Trader but I'm still
kind of struggling with that psychology
so it was 26 days later for the next
trade I rushed into this one I also was
experimenting the eclipse was coming up
and I wanted to make a really funny
YouTube video about trade with a moon
phase indicator and letting the moon
tell me when to get into a trade so I
was really excited it was a full moon
and it was telling me to buy I was like
yes let's do it here we go 20 contracts
were long Platinum full moon eclipse all
of it content and then I just I goofed
and I didn't even look at the right
contract to get into so the contract was
getting ready to expire I had to close
the position with a $2,000 loss to be
honest it was $ 2,800 and then reopen on
the correct contract so on the 3D I was
able to re-enter I'm not sure if this is
the close or the open we'll find out a
little bit later you guys can go back in
the video and see but then here we go
look at this 30,000 I did it I hit the
30 Mark so this was even though not much
only a few hundred more than my last
record trade but still yet another
record trade on April 3rd I made
$3,121 wow that was exciting also
clipped out of that one early it's just
there's something about you know going
heavier in position size than you're
used to I'm working on scaling up this
year and being up a record amount
there's just a lot of stuff that comes
into play so I clipped out early and
then here we go yet again on the 29th of
April I closed a $24,000 trade this one
I went over I can also link this video
we got lots of videos I talk about it
all so I'll link it somewhere you guys
can see that specific video where I talk
through that entire trade entry exit and
everything but this one I closed out at
24,000 and the reason I closed that one
out early is because I could make this
video and I could say that I'm up
$100,000 for the year that's a lot of
information I know but to be honest we
only talked about six traes it's not
that crazy we didn't have to go through
very much we talked about every single
trade this entire year so far we're
starting Q2 now only six trades in
that's amazing so let's kind of go
through some of the stats my trade
expectancy is 177,000 cool my profit
Factor 3724 cool none of this Matters To
be honest I I don't put any of this into
context when I'm placing my trades I
know a lot of you guys do and I love I
love that for you I love how analytical
you guys are when I learned how to trade
my uncle taught me nothing about RR
taught me nothing about win percentage
about profit factors he told me when to
get in when to get out that's what we
went over and that's what I do but I
love showing you guys these stats it's
fun I like analytics and whatnot it's
it's fun to kind of look it up and be
like oh cool this is my average win to
loss 7.45 win percentage 8333 and then
my net profit and loss you guys already
saw I've said it about 500 times $12,800
40 really exciting so stay along for
this journey I'm trying to make it to
200k this year if you guys are not
following along this journey be sure to
hit the Subscribe button don't forget to
hit the like button and drop a comment I
will see you guys in the next video
thanks for hanging out