I went back through and watched one of
my old videos it was probably like three
or four years ago where a light bulb had
went off or a a switch was flipped it
was when I finally realized that I need
to start taking these small winds
instead of trying to hang on for these
big runs and it was the coolest part
about this video is on my YouTube was
pretty old I'll have to go back and see
if I can drop the link for you guys to
see it but it was realizing that these
big runners or these big moves don't
happen very often that makes total sense
of course not the price doesn't move in
One Direction indefinitely in the
markets but you do get these little
movements in between continuously like
you're always getting movement there is
always movement in the market you guys
Apex is running a crazy promotion right
now this isn't something that happens
very often so go ahead and utilize it
now enter code Tory to use the best
possible promotion so if you can
capitalize on the smaller movements in
between which happen much more often
than these big Runners you're going to
be more consistent you're going to be
more profitable in the long run and that
was something that I realized on camera
as filming as as I was filming talking
through like my trading and where I'm at
and my ideas for how to you know get to
that profitability and it it clicked it
clicked right there immediately it was
like oh my gosh if I could just take
these small wins I mean $200 a few $200
moves is incredible that adds up that
that absolutely adds up and in the long
run all you need is that consistency if
you could just continue to grab those
$200 trades you're on the right path
instead I was trying to hang on for the
big moves CU I wanted you know I wanted
that $1,000 that $5,000 move oh my gosh
and you know what I did instead I kept
giving up profit every time giving up
profit I'd hold too long everything that
I had made gave it back plus some
whereas when I said you know what I'm
going to be happy with these little
moves these little moves in between
these little trends that you can catch
you know and I was in the five minute
time frame back then too I was like
let's just capitalize on these smaller
wins let's take the smaller wins you're
going to succeed in the smaller wins
more than you in these long runs hands
down it's just the the likelihood and
the probability of you collecting the
small winds and capitalizing on those
small wins and generating consistency
over time is much higher than you just
catching a lucky Runner so just some
tips that I I found whenever I was
trying to make it from inconsistent
unprofitable to profitable was you know
what light bulb went off let's just take
some small wins and be totally happy
about it and stoked about it because in
the long run when you look back at the
month and you're like oh my gosh look at
the win rate look at all these little
winners I've got so if this is something
that you find yourself doing as a Trader
holding on and giving those profits back
let's try the small wins let's get
excited about the small wins let's take
a step back and look at the end of our
month the end of our week the end of our
day even and see you know what we just
capitalize on some small wins and we are
on the right path to being profitable