that's the Futures Market that's the
symbol for Google I can guarantee you
guys know what apple and Tesla and
Netflix and Google is now we want to get
in on this downward Trend how do we make
money when the markets go
[Music]
down I have got an incredibly simple
strategy that you can start implementing
as a beginner today after this video it
is three steps you can apply this to any
Market in any time frame I made 200k
this year simply by trading trend lines
I've seen my uncle make millions of doll
simply by trading trend lines and I've
got plenty of students whove been able
to be profitable and consistent with
trend lines as well here are the three
steps the first step is simply
identifying the trend Second Step
waiting for the price to break out of
the trend third step enter the reversal
okay now what does that look like how do
we identify a trend I'm going to make
this as simple as possible we're going
to start by just opening our web browser
going to Google you're going to open
Google and type in trading view trading
view is the platform where we can mark
up our charts and identify Trends all
right once you've made it into trading
view we're going to pull up a chart this
is the coolest part you you can pick any
chart you would like any chart and any
time frame I'm going to open Platinum
it's one of my favorite instruments to
trade and I've noticed in my 9 years of
trading that it respects trend lines 2 a
t the symbol for platinum is pl1
exclamation point now if you are a super
newbie and have no idea what pl1
exclamation point means or what Futures
are I can guarantee you guys know what
apple and Tesla and Netflix and Google
is you can go to the stock market type
in a a l that's the symbol for Apple
launch chart you can type in g o o g
that's the symbol for Google launch
chart you can type in TSLA that's the
symbol for Tesla launch chart all right
we're getting into Platinum pl1
exclamation point that's the Futures
Market that's things like Commodities
energies Metals indices all right launch
chart this is a chart for platinum
Futures in the 4-Hour time frame the
coolest part about this strategy is you
can pick any time frame you'd like now
what do the different time frames mean
it simply means the time the price has
moved between each Candle on the screen
so if we zoom in and look at each candle
here that means this is 4 hours worth of
price movement next candle 4 hours worth
of price movement so on and so forth now
if we go to the 1H hour time frame each
one of these candles is only an hour's
worth of price movement and if you go to
the 5 minute time frame each one of
these candles is 5 minutes worth of
price movement you can pick any time
frame you'd like if you're trading the
5-minute time frame you might not be in
your trades for very long you might be
in them for an hour 2 hours whereas if
you're trading the 4-Hour time frame you
might be in your trades for a week or
two weeks so there's different types of
Traders long-term investors swing
Traders day Traders and scalpers it is
simply just the way you look at the pie
so regardless of what time frame you
pick we can apply this strategy to
anyone I'm going to trade in the 4our
time frame now I'm going to use the
replay tool here to show you guys some
examples in the past of how this
strategy worked out you guys are going
to be applying this to real-time data
and if you guys make it to the end of
the video I'll give you guys a little
sneak peek at how this strategy has made
me 200k this year so first things first
step one identify the trend how do we do
that we're going to utilize the tool
boox on the left hand side of trading
view we're going to go to the trend line
tools hit the arrow to the left and
we're going to use the ray tool this is
how we draw all of our trend lines on
trading view when we're drawing our
trend lines we are simply trying to look
for the lowest point we see on the
screen and then trying to capture as
many touch points as we can without
price intersecting here we've drawn an
upward trend line with one two three
touch points excellent good job now
that's step one step two wait this is
the hardest part of the strategy sitting
on your hands and waiting for the price
to break the trend so now we
wait oh here we go step three get in on
the trend reversal this signifies an
entry the price of platinum is no longer
trending up we just got a break of the
upward trend line now we want to get in
on this downward Trend price was
trending up price broke the upward trend
line now we're anticipating the price is
going to continue trending down now
trending in the opposite direction so
this is called a trend reversal this is
what we're trying to get in on now we
need to identify a downward trend line
so instead of looking for the lowest
point we see on the screen we're going
to look for the highest point we see on
the screen same scenario we're going to
try to capture as many touch points as
we can without price intersecting point
a point
B all right now we get into the trade so
we are placing a sell order first I know
for some beginners that may be a little
bit confusing how do we make money when
the markets go down when we're trading
with a brokerage they allow you to
borrow shares and sell them before you
actually own them so we are anticipating
that the price is going to go down so we
are selling the shares to later then
when price drops buy them back and
that's a profit now we rinse and repeat
we are going to stay in this trade until
price breaks out of it a trend and then
we get yet another Trend reversal here's
a tip when drawing your trend lines the
more touch points you can get the better
how long do we stay in this trade rinse
and repeat same process as the first one
draw the trend line find as many touch
points as you can without price
intersecting and now in this scenario
instead of waiting to enter we are going
to wait to
close there we go price broke no more
waiting now let's go back to Step One
identify the trend when drawing upward
trend lines we're looking for the lowest
point we see on the screen trying to
capture as many touch points as we can
without the price
intersecting now rinse and repeat this
was the most Broad and simple overview
of my strategy but this is something
that you can start implementing today
full disclaimer it doesn't work out like
this every single time every single
trade there's going to be scenarios
where you get into a trend reversal and
the price fakes you out goes against you
doesn't actually Trend in the New
Direction this was an example when price
works in your favor stay tuned on my
channel so that I can show you guys what
to do in situations when the price
doesn't work out as easy and
congratulations you just watch the most
basic strategy for trend line Trading
that you can start implementing today
with that being said I did promise a
sneak peek into my trading results so
let me show you guys some real broker
statements validating that my results
are real using this strategy I use the
broker trade station this is my
portfolio for trade station all righty
guys here are my statements for the year
of 2024 pause at any time to make sure
that you can verify look at the account
balances totals profit and loss here we
go speed round January through December
2024 January February March April May I
took June off July August September
October November I didn't trade December
maybe I'll trade but probably not and
that is my broker savings for 2024 using
this simple strategy thank you guys for
watching this video don't forget to drop
a comment if you have any questions or
enjoy the content of this video for
future trend line trading tips and
tricks continue to follow along my
channel hit the Subscribe button don't
forget to hit the like and I'll see you
guys in the next video