so we're about to head to Utah right
[Music]
now what I end up making so far this
month's trading I love that
girl your girl ain't got boobs like
[Music]
this all right [\h__\h]
my boy new le single look at the camera
Isaiah how you say your last namea yeah
your addressing my address so you know
he uh freshly single so any any gay
dudes out there looking to find love gay
dudes in the San Fernando Valley
[Music]
all right all right
[\h__\h] slips too [\h__\h] much God I hate
this [\h__\h] the car is too cold and the
tires hav it warmed up and you try to
take off it just slips so I can't get
that
full we just [\h__\h] lost to a Tesla
Model
3 see
it oh 100 holy [\h__\h] any cops up here
we're going to jail today baby H I
didn't mean to get to 100 though that's
crazy that boy stood no chance though
his little Tesla can't see him hold the
thing
[Music]
I love that
girl hey we all got that one gym
girlfriend we ain't never talked to I'm
going to talk to her though one day
[Music]
soon your girl ain't got boobs like this
type [\h__\h] gym session done you know what
it is you know what to
do about to head to Utah and learn the
snowboard I guess last time I
snowboarded I was uh I was with my aunt
she wanted to go down this big hill and
I ate [\h__\h] like eight times on the way
down had bruises all over my body I
wased up so see how it goes but I ain't
snowboarded in a long
time dropped the top oh [\h__\h] realiz how
[\h__\h] bright it was out today but
another beautiful day in life in
[Music]
general
great gym session
done no matter what you want to do in
life no matter what it is chase your
dreams go do it go get it cuz at the end
of the day success or whatever you're
looking to accomplish in life is not
going to come to you out of nowhere it's
not going to fall in your hands you got
to go get it I used to be 230 lb
considered obese [\h__\h] this was 6 months
ago and I decided you know what
I got to make a change I got to work out
I got to lift I got to start eating
right cuz it got to a point where you
know I couldn't even play with my kids I
could even play with my children without
getting dizzy being lightheaded I was so
out of shape and the doctors told me
that if I don't get in shape start
working out I have to get on medication
I wasn't going to live to be even 50
years old the way I was eating I was
eating fast food every day no exercise
no working out it was bad but if you
just work hard at anything in life it
doesn't have to be working out it's just
an an allery if you just work hard give
it your all try your best wake up every
day with ambition and passion for
something you will be great in this
world but you got to go get it be
ambitious Chase your goals take that
leap take that first step towards
greatness and at the end of the day the
rest is going to follow all right so we
about to head to Utah right now bags is
getting packed up bring my
computer the road to Utah learn the
snowboard pick up some
[\h__\h] [\h__\h] is
good this is rough
damn I don't even know if this is going
to fit all of our [\h__\h] anyways they got
them little uh Uber XL shits the only
thing that I hate about getting Ubers
and lifts is that you got to trust
someone else with your life
and yeah some of these guys be driving
like [\h__\h] all right this I am no plane
train I get eaten by a bear or I fly
around I'm snowboarding this could be
the end hey keep an eye on him for me
man can't walk straight can't swim we're
going to see about the snowboarding wish
me luck
I like your car of
course that's my
car I
wish goodbye to California for a little
bit it's a much needed break get out of
here for a little bit enjoy the nature
of Utah so Uber they only let you keep
30% 35 35% out of the 100 that I spend
you only get to keep like $35 yeah for
real Dam that's horrible it's like
almost 2 hours of work cuz you got to
get back now too send you some extra bro
oh thank you sir of course of course and
your name is Paul Mark all right bro I
just sent you 500 oh it's big sir no no
it's okay bro oh thank you so much I
have a gooseb for your hard work bro
thank you so much I have three kider
that's why you know yeah I I need to
work hard of course bro hell yeah I got
uh I got five kids five kids yeah I got
five wow I have couple baby masas but
yeah yeah it's hard thank you so much of
course bro of course keep grinding it
for
him have a good
one now cuz they be checking my bag I
got like 800k worth of jewelry they be
going through that [\h__\h] why you got all
this for what are you doing I'm living
my life I'm being
myself one fo
forward grab me by the nuts he said left
leg forward right leg back he went
straight up gripped my [\h__\h] moved it
around he said you got a gun on you I
said that's just my dick moved it to the
side watch The View this [\h__\h] look cute
though hey she didn't really like me she
might have took one of the watches
[Music]
out that long I'm looking for you St
wife
tonight couple single mothers need some
support
hi we're getting cardio entering
[Music]
now
damn you go crazy
it's cold as [\h__\h] out here though damn
this [\h__\h] three
[Music]
stories so I guess this is where will be
the next couple
days let me give it b a quick little
test that's a good
view few watches I brought
yeah want this
[Music]
sunrise sunset it's all beautiful out
here but I want to show you guys really
quick what I end up making so far this
month trading to show you guys how I can
afford you know taking trips like this
28k 15K 10K and then a $1,900 loss
that's about $51,000 just this month
from Trading so you know that's the goal
in life Financial Freedom of course you
guys want to have the freedom to do what
you want when you want and one of the
ways you can achieve that is by trading
you can do that through a lot of
different ways but for me trading is
been the greatest for me the most
efficient way to make money however I
want to show you guys what I saw in
those trades the strategy that I use and
how you guys can make money as well so
let's go inside and talk about it okay
so I know a lot of you guys want to know
how I was able to make $50,000 in the
span of 8 Days the strategy that I use
and the exact technique technique that I
Ed as well as the guidelines to take
trades like this every single day now
it's not I'm not going to say it's a
super easy strategy but it is a very
simple one and if you stick to the
guidelines that I'm going to be giving
you you will be successful with the
strategy but you got to listen up
closely and you got to stick to the
guidelines it's very important that you
stick to exactly what I tell you to do
so as you guys can see here's my last 8
days and let's get to the strategy so
first things first you got to use a
solid broker that actually is
trustworthy that actually works the only
way you going to do that is going to
sway markets man go down below in the
description click my link you will be
backed by me 100% as long as you use my
link and then you'll have the best
broker in the market you guys can see
man super easy to use you got your
charts you can mark them up however you
want you just buy or sell whenever you
want it's really simple click buy you're
in you close here everything's done here
so it's like trading View and metatrader
put together super solid platform
actually never seen something as good as
this been using it for like 6 months now
only broker I recommend man so click the
link down below to get started with that
now as you guys can see today we took a
trade huge huge win now I want to use
today's trade as an example for the
strategy itself and how we use it listen
closely cuz I said it's going to be very
important you guys listen to every
single step that I give you when trading
the strategy cuz if you don't listen or
you miss one step the strategy will be
ruined okay so first things first we
only trade during New York open okay
6:30 a.m. Pacific Standard time/ 9:30
a.m. eastern standard time it never
changes it must be at 6:30 or past
nothing below you're not trading at 627
625 6:30 6: a.m. no 6:30 a.m. Pacific
Standard time is when you can enter a
trade or up to an hour after that always
keep that in mind you will also only be
looking at the 5 minute chart and you're
only going to be trading us30 or NASDAQ
during everything I just said 6:30 a.m.
on the 5 minute chart us30 or NASDAQ
okay now that we've got that under
control remember that and keep that on
you for life keep that right here
okay second thing we need breakouts very
simple very simple pattern all a
breakout is you got your trend line
breaks okay put this in replay mode to
show you
guys so you have trend line breaks which
would look like this trend line we drew
a trend line all we did was just simply
draw it with our line tool place it here
we have a trend higher high higher low
higher high higher low higher high
creating a trend line okay it's
respecting that trend line or we have
support/resistance breaks this would be
previous resistance right that would now
turn into support so this is more like
support here resistance here resistance
support okay it's doing both now if we
break this support to the downside we're
also breaking that trend line which
would give us double confirmation which
is even better you're not going to get
this every day but when you do you can
feel very good about the Trad you're
about to get into because you've broken
two different patterns at once but we
just need one of them right so we've
talked about the basics 6:30 a.m. comes
okay right here would actually be 635 so
it's time to trade now we can actually
get into this trade now 635 5 6:30ish
came in now we just want to see a break
whether we see a break of this support
here or a trend line break either way we
need to see a break we can also have
traded this off these highs so if price
breaks Above This High we would take a
buy position this is a resistance line
now we're going to play this candle and
see what it does as you guys can see
price starts to break out of that trend
line realistically we could have taken
our sell position up here but I wanted
to be safe and I wanted to get double
the confirmation so I waited for the
support/ previous resistance to break as
well we broke below both lines took our
sell position and price plummeted okay
and it really is as simple as that but
the biggest thing in the strategy is
6:30 a.m. on the 5 minute only us30 in
NASDAQ that is the biggest thing and we
look for our breakouts now let's say for
instance price breaks out a little bit
and takes you out now if this happens
right and price does break out and take
you out fakes you out is really the word
then check this out for instance I'm
going to put this in replay mode and
we're going to just draw imaginary lines
okay we took our cell position we feel
good about it but then price does this
boom stop loss now we're back here we
can take a re-entry on a break of this
support again now if we break again boom
we take our sell position once more so
now second sell position comes in and we
pray for that but again if it happens
again where we lose we probably chill we
had two two breakouts ended up faking us
out the markets aren't doing so well I'm
going to hop out of this trade now
here's part three of the strategy we
always go for one to fives always it
will always be a 1 to five okay so this
trade was a 1 to five this trade was a 1
to five meaning we could have tooken a
couple losses re-entered for a third
time hit our takeprofit five our Target
five whatever the PIP count is it's
usually 1,500 Pips guess what you're
still up for the day you're still up
very good for the day even though you
took three losses already and that's why
it's important that you hold these
trades and you always go for a one to
five now what a 1 to five means your
risk is worth one of your take profits
which is five or your your actual win
which is five times your loss okay
meaning if you lose five trades in a row
that one winner will break you even for
the day so that means you can lose five
trades and only have to win once to
break even that's a good feeling and
that's how you should be feeling as a
Trader again with this strategy as long
as you do everything I said right right
here is about 6:30 waiting for either a
trend line break a support break or a
resistance break right we have a trend
here we just want to see a breakout we
get a breakout to the upside as price
starts to move up cuz we do not take our
buys on close candles we take them as
the candle's going through so we would
realistically come in as this candle
starts to come up here boom we take our
buy position this ends up being a loss
that's okay we got stopped out we see we
have a trend now to the downside take
our re-entry on this break here at this
point we would put stops to break
even because we're already up more than
a 1 to two so here we either take a
little profit off the table move our
stops to break even and let some of
those runners go
and in this instance boom we came back
again so we have one win or we have one
loss and one break even maybe a little
bit of a win so overall we are down for
the day that's okay and that's why the
strategy is so unique because we already
took two losses today or we took a loss
and a half today we're not feeling so
good about it but then guess what when
the next day came which would have been
today we went we caught 1,500 Pips so
yeah we might have lost a net 180 Pips
yesterday but today we're at500 Pips on
one win that's how good the strategy is
is that you can have huge wins and baby
losses on repeat and as long as you hold
out for those one to fs and your risk to
reward is good put stops to break even
when you're about halfway maybe about
750 Pips you're going to be solid you're
going to make money with the strategy
but every day you must do the exact same
thing don't let anything change the
biggest issue in life when it comes to
trading the biggest issue that a lot of
new Traders have they can't hold trades
they don't want to hold their trades
they don't want to you know be okay with
oh let me put stops to break even they
want to get out too early they want to
go for one to twos one to no it's one to
fives every single time and if you stick
to it you stick to your game plan you're
going to be successful you're going to
make money this is a winning strategy
But first you got to perfect this you
got to get that psychology down I've
been using the strategy for a very long
time I call these trades out live every
single day in front of thousands of
people and I will literally show you
those results right here like I mean
literally every single day I live trade
in front of thousands of people and if
we go to member profits you're going to
see exactly what I'm talking about every
day right every single day we we have
profits look at that us3 sale from today
like I said it's really like that it's
really like that we also trade gold and
GJ as well so we just trade pairs all
day we trade pairs every single morning
New York session and we get people
passing their certificates we got people
getting paid out by their funding I mean
this is ridiculous how much money people
are making we've counted up over $5
million worth of profits just in here
alone just insane just insane if you are
not in there you are missing out but you
do not need it because I just gave you
the winning strategy itself learn it for
yourself perfect it get good at it and
you will make money in this industry use
the proper broker use the right strategy
stick to the guidelines I gave you I
gave every guideline you will need but
stick to it and be strict and religious
with it you will thank me later yeah
let's get back to the Vlog
[Music]
you put my name on your
bik idea