hello everyone and welcome back to my 4x
channel i hope you're doing great and in
today's session i will show you how
simple but profitable strategy can bring
you over 160 pips in a trading session
to be part of the forex trading it is
essential to have a strategy to trade
along with your trading plan and correct
risk management of course without it you
are just adrift and you probably don't
see the results
and i have to say that maintaining your
discipline is a key for the granted
success
of course on the other hand there are
several reasons why the trading strategy
does not meet expectations of a trader
so every trader needs to clarify this
before choosing the strategy wisely but
before we continue
if you're new to my channel don't forget
to subscribe press that bell icon to not
miss any of my videos and if you would
like to join my training community
with over 450 traders i will leave the
link down below to check us
out in this video i will share my own
training strategy that i use to send out
the signals out in my premium group the
strategy itself is super easy to follow
adapt and implement based on these
simple steps as there is no rocket
science here just a combination of the
best deal of moving averages
macd and technical and fundamental
analysis and of course a lot of people
ask me so which is the best analysis
method when you're preparing for the
training session and my answer that is
both
good technical analysis will tell you
when to enter the trade but a good
fundamental analysis will tell you why
you're entering this trade and if you
would like to learn how i
analyze the market before trading
session i will leave a pop-up on the
right side of your screen
so you go and check it out so first
things first i like to analyze my chosen
currency pair
for this scenario i have usd cad that's
the currency pair i analyzed for my
trading group which
actually reached more than 190 pips over
the trading session and the reason for
that is when you're doing analysis you
are drawing and identifying the
horizontal areas of the support
resistance you know the trend lines any
type of chat pattern formations
on at least four different time frames
of course depending on your trading
style and i like to try to keep
the charts clean as much as possible
because at the end of the analysis then
i'm adding all the required tools to
help us out with additional
confirmations for this strategy so let's
quickly do a brief analysis on usd cad
currency pair and as we can see the
weekly time frame on usd cad
is strongly showing us that we are in a
clear downtrend and during the downtrend
we can see that the price
makes lower lows and the lower highs
because of it the price nicely bounces
off the trend multiple times and
confirming a total bare pressure
of course as we can see the weekly
resistance was broken with a strong
bearish move and of course the mid zone
was also retested few times
indicating consolidation between the
bulls and the bears and as we can see
the weekly support is starting to be
broken because of this bearish engulfing
candle so before the price potentially
hits the monthly support we have some
room
left to make some pips on a daily
timeframe we can confirm what we saw in
a weekly so we have a lower lowest
bearish momentum towards the downside
and the usd is getting so much weaker
while the cat is gaining the power of
course i have spot the head and
shoulders pattern so
the head and shoulders we can see we
have a neckline and the two shoulders
before
the actual price continues to go towards
the downside so of course if you have
spot any type of chart pattern
information which can actually help you
with your throat just do it as it will
be easier in the future
so four hourly chart is currently in a
squeeze pattern scenario but because of
a daily weekly and monthly downtrend the
market will probably continue to go down
obviously take a look at this huge
bearish engulfing candle breaking weekly
trend
and this would be also a great enter
opportunity but i was waiting for the
news to came out and they came out
very well for the us so i was just
waiting for a better entry opportunity
and here it comes the importance of the
base of this powerful forex strategy we
will need to add the moving averages of
period 25
and 50 plus monk d on a different
settings that i used
and it's working absolutely wonderful
the procedure is very simple
all you have to do is go on indicators
and basically type m
a which is the moving average and double
click and once you have them on this
basically press on this setting bar and
change the length to 25 and another 50
and just press
ok and the same for the macd you just
basically type
macd and we will have to change the
settings as well the fast length
will be 15 instead of the 12 and the
slow
will be 30 instead of 26. all these
settings was based on overall strategy
results
and average winning and loss trade plus
the risk and reward ratio again
please remember to adjust your own risk
management based on your account
what you actually can afford so you
don't go too crazy or greedy just please
be disciplined with your trading plan
and correct risk management and the rule
for this strategy is to have a moving
average crossover
may 25 crossing below may 50 showing the
cellular pressure and following the macd
crossover and
we're waiting for the candle closure to
enter and i always
well most of the time i use wanted to
restore ratio and we are ready to go so
as i said while the news came out i
usually send the signals around two
o'clock
because this is where i know what to do
with the trade so as we can see now the
moving average crossover of course
happened over here where we have this
blue
darker blue line now trending below of
the lightest one but as i said
i was waiting for the news of course we
can see that the price is still trending
towards the downside
this is where i actually entered the
trade so let's just quickly add a short
tool for
this trade as i said i'm using one to
two wrist reward ratio
in regards to my trades and as the
market moves we all know that it moves
into continuation patterns so you know
we have you push
an exhaustion to the previous area of
sensitivity and then the trade continues
to go towards the downside so let's
actually play a replay tool on and see
how the trade went and as we can see
based on a full analysis the macd
crossover the moving average crossover
we are continuing to go towards the
downside as we can see the price is
nicely moving off the moving averages
totally showing the bearish pressure so
we are continuing to make the profits
and as we can see
we totally hitting the market with a
nice nice profits and this is how the
trade actually went of course it was a
tiny consolidation well at least it
wasn't hitting the stop loss but as we
can see
we actually didn't had any crossover but
the mangady was showing a crossover
again
which is showing total bearish pressure
so we continued to go towards the
downside and as i said
the trade was nicely reaching 160 pips
in the total profit so again guys this
is the strategy that i use
myself to send the trades on my premium
group if you'd like to try this out let
me know in the comments below how you
did it there's no rocket science as i
said but all you have to do is to have a
basic knowledge
do fundamental and technical analysis
correct trading plan
and risk management and i'm pretty sure
you have a granted success
[Music]