imagine market experience 40 42 years
stock
broker chamber New York Stock Exchange
and he trades for hisis
as
retk and how you have to actually make
in trading now I hope
Peterman is one of the most famous
Traders on the floor of the New York
Stock
Exchange he's known as the Einstein of
Wall Street and not just because of his
looks the excitement the adrenaline we
are the last human Marketplace in the
world
let's
go
bu how are you all good all good how are
you I'm very well give me about two
minutes I'll be right back please please
please please take a time please take a
time we can do
it okay okay me see if I can clean clean
the screen a little bit so I can have
a pict a great picture here let me see
if I
can ah there's a thing
here oh can you see me are you okay with
that yes yes it's absolutely okay sir I
can see you okay let me make sure I
rather have a little better
lighting yes cuz it's a sunny sunny
behind me so I have to yes yes Ah that's
better there you go okay cool great
what's your name my name is harit Sir
how do you say it again it's harid hasid
how do you oh harid I can't see that
harid okay harid how are you great to
meet you thank you all good sir thank
you so much for joining in I was really
waiting and I so excited to uh you know
see you and in person and ask lot of
questions and get lot of wisdom from you
and uh I I saw you I saw you back in uh
2017 and since then I had a dream that
one day probably you know I'll get a
chance to have a conversation with you
and ask some insight about it and today
is the day I'm so happy I cannot tell
you you know how excited I am at the
moment thank you so much sir I'm so glad
that you persisted and you got a hold of
me it is my absolute pleasure to uh to
speak to you and you have as much time
as you need thank you so much sir thank
you so much so uh sir my name is harid
pale and I am basically a Trader in
India I trade in index primarily and uh
I indan Indian Indian index or us index
Indian index sir okay Indian I I
primarily did in banking index it's
called Bank Nifty in India okay yes and
we explain to me so an index in India
like so in the the US when you have a
banking index it's all of the banks
together like an ETF yes right and then
we we have the S&P 500 right thep so in
India what what is the components of the
Indian banking index are they all the
Indian Banks together in one index is
that how it works uh sir in Indian index
it's basically the top 12 Indian Banks
and uh only 12 top 12 banks are there
not all banks are there just top 12
banks are there who are there in the
Indian back index
so yes so uh so basically I just started
my uh this Instagram journey and social
Journey Back In
2023 and I have the audience who are
primary retailers and they are the
newcomers basically so I I make a
content in a very simple term so that
they can understand the markets because
it's very technical and I try to bring
it down into very simple language and
within just one year by God's grace I
just went from 200 followers to 1.5
million followers and it was like no way
oh my God yes sir yes sir wow that's
unbelievable so I'm I'm honored I that
will be very exciting for me you know
sorry to interrupt you but I've had so I
have a large following in India I know
that uh for many many years already and
the frustration has been you know so I
have an I have an academy where we teach
technical analysis and things like with
my with my partner David green one of
the frustrations with speaking with
people in India is that you don't have
real access to trade us markets right
and so I and I and and also I know that
money you know the the way the the rup
is rupee right so I know that the rupee
and the dollar exchange rate is crazy
right
is right and you have crazy inflation
and and the CH the price of it I I'm not
I was aware of that I've spoken to
people in India before and very
frustrated because they wanted to take
my course but uh but they did not know
how to to transmit what we teach to the
Indian market but it sounds like if
you're trading indexes are you using
technical analysis I am sir I am my
whole base is onto technical analysis
only and where did you learn it it's all
primarily from the internet gathering
information from here then and I've lot
I've watched lot of videos of your also
and other people and just doing research
you know uh back back testing it a lot
of times and then reading what uh
previous you know famous fers used to do
and then somehow put the pieces together
and then figure it out okay now this is
working for me and now I've got my age
and now this thing is going on okay my
question is of the 1.5 million followers
so your content is is it technical do
you actually teach technical analysis or
are you just giving a a a education
about the markets the i i primarily make
videos on technical analysis the basics
of that like how Candlestick Works how
price action works and uh what are the
support zones what are demand zones and
all kind of these things what is a
breakoff structure when the Market's
breaking structure and all these kind of
things and I try yes go ahead go ahead
and I basically try to keep things as
simple as possible and I tried to make
the people understand the probability
terms also of the market that if you
follow one strategy then how probability
gets into your favor and then you can
actually make it rather than just
blaming from the market and just uh
messing it around I understand the
biggest issue with the people here is
people are very inconsistent in in
starting they have that enthusiasm that
okay I want to learn markets I want to
make money and within just one month
even though if they have let's say they
got one bad week they that the whole
enthusiasm just goes down and they just
they just go like now I think I'm not
going to be a Trader ever again and I
think I have to quit so the moral goes
down really really fast okay well look
maybe something that I will say will
help them look because that is a that
look that's obviously a problem that
everybody has and I think it's I think
it's a function of what how you teach
them right you know people are very bent
on the fact that this is about getting
rich quickly and that they need to be
made very clear that's not what it's
about it's a long process it takes three
it takes three to six months minimum to
learn how to do this correctly and you
know obviously for us uh we try and get
people to do simulated trading first on
paper for but not too long two weeks two
weeks Max we don't want them to spend
too much maybe a month you know but but
don't spend because you don't really get
the the sense of what it is like to lose
and to win when you're trading Trading
in a simulated fashion you will only
know what that feeling is like when you
actually have skin in the game and so
while it's important to learn the
dynamic of the keyboard and technicals
uh on paper but if you spend too much
time on it you know it's like unless
you're sitting in in a car driving the
car in traffic you don't really learn
how to drive right you can play you know
it's not a video game it driving is not
a video game trading is a video game so
um interesting that you know so have you
heard of um are Indian Traders allowed
to trade in US markets yes they are
allowed they're allowed sir they are
allowed they can okay they are okay so
there is a new thing in the market
now called Futures funded trading you've
heard of it yes I've heard I've heard
okay so it exists around the world right
now I don't think it's probably in India
but it is in uh in Eastern Europe in
America where they set up it's a comp
the company that we uh partnered with is
called TOP Step TOP Step is a Futures
funded trading platform what does that
mean that means that you open an account
uh I will explain it to you afterwards
if you go on my Instagram on the if
inside the link the link tree you will
see it will say TOP Step and you go in
there and for
$50 okay you can open up $ is the most
reasonable anywhere in most reasonable
absolutely so for $50 you open up an
account they give you
50,000 simulated dollars US Dollars and
they give you the access to trade
strictly
Futures so do you know do you know the
US futures market like you have what's
called e so you have the ESN Q these are
the NASDAQ futures and the and the uh e
mini uh Futures on the S&P 5
yes so you have so $50 buys you in for
$50,000 you have to be qualified so to
be qualified in seven trading days you
have to make $3,000 simulated okay and
if you make that you become qualified
then they reive you they they fill your
bank account again with
$50,000 so that you start with 50 and
then as you trade simulated you can
actually you can actually be paid to to
trade in all completely simulated so
people are being they pay you
70% of what you make uh trading in the
simulated Marketplace so it's one of the
most for us so in America to be a Trader
you have to have
$25,000 uh because if you don't you have
these law these called pattern day
trading rules right which means that
you're you can only trade three times a
week and you can't you can't trade intad
day right so they're very unless if you
have $25,000 you can do whatever you
want you can trade 10 a day you can do
whatever you want if you don't have that
then it's very limited what you can do
you can open up a cash account and trade
options you can trade this and that so
the this new platform uh where you have
can trade strictly Futures with
simulated money for $50 gives access to
so many people who would never ever have
the chance to trade and you can act you
can actually get you get paid 50,000 a
month real money I mean the trading is
simulated the money is real and uh so
that may be something that we should
open up to your uh uh to your followers
because everybody can come out if you
can't come up with 50 bucks then you
should be doing a different business but
Absol right but for 50
to be able to start if you really want
so you described that the immediate
satisfaction if your followers don't get
immediate satisfaction they leave they
go off to do something else this
platform offers the accessibility for
immediate immediate gratification if you
put in the work yes you can take the
money and literally within three weeks
you can be paid big money if you put in
the work you make
my partner in my Academy David Green yes
uh we now teach almost 70 we transition
from equities to Futures because it is
so accessible using this this new
platform and he trades uh this platform
TOP Step last month he was and he does
not trade big right because he's
teaching he trades small bits and he he
they paid him $70,000 last month last
month that's
amazing anybody that's to make crazy
money right So for anybody so uh that's
something we should uh talk about
because it's it's it's an amazing
opportunity anyway let's start go ahead
start the
interview sure sure so sir I have a few
questions uh few are there for the rator
side and few are there I want to
understand how do you think and uh it's
all it's going to mix with both of them
so my first question is is since you
have more experience than my age so how
do you look to the markets at the moment
uh what kind of uh thought process goes
into your head when you are planning a
trade or you are you know just trying to
understand the
markets okay so what I do in my for my
job for my career right yes it's
different than what I do when I teach so
what okay so it's a completely different
thing I do not use technical analysis
for when I trade for my customers all
right so okay so being a broker on the
floor of the New York Stock Exchange
gives you access to certain bits of
information yes and many many years ago
I uh I developed a trading strategy
around the information that broker the
floor of the New York Stock Exchange
get which orderflow for the opening
market and the close of the market it's
called it's called Market on close it is
the it is the volume that that um
imagine imagine for example you're a
hedge fund and you have a million shares
of um of IBM to buy yes and in the
market that goes up and down like we see
these days right can be down 300 up 300
very volatile very vola okay so the way
that somebody would handle this new
market would be you would buy a couple
couple 100,000 shares on the opening
then you would put 400,000 shares in an
algorithm from let's say 10:00 to 2 o'
and then you would put 400,000 shares
for the close Market on close so that
you could go back to your customer and
he would ask you what did you do for me
and all the customers have an option to
just use the the machine they don't need
a human being so I need to give the
customer a reason to use me as a human
being as opposed to
I will tell him that I was able to get
him involved he the the the prices that
he was able to get was over the day the
best price possible I got him involved
on the opening he was involved during
the day and he was also involved on the
close of the market yes this information
I have access to so everybody the big
hedge fund big institutions right yes
yes they they ex their order flow in a
similar fashion to this so all of the
people who want to be so one of the
other things a lot of the large players
like to embed their volume their bigger
orders where there is more volume like
on the o so the largest volume is on the
open and on the close of the
market you see that I'm same in India
where the that's where the volume is so
uh all the orders that everybody has for
the closing bell
auction I get to see it at 2:00 okay so
I built a strategy my so that's what
that's what they offer that is the that
is the benefit of being a broker on the
floor of the N Stock Exchange so I'm
able to see that order flow for the
closing BT so I built a strategy many
many years ago around that information
it's not inside information it's just
information and it's a what do you do
with that so we we built it and I work
my son is my partner and we uh we have a
wonderful team uh on the floor and we
trade that information so at 2 o'clock
we are given access to the order flow
for the closing bell and every five
seconds from 2 o'clock until 3:50 this
order flow change it's updated so it's
always changing okay so for me as a
career as a broker on the floor my
trading is based on this information
unfortunately not information I can
disseminate to you or to anybody even in
America absolutely absolutely so that's
what I do for my work but in answer to
your question for if I if I was
responding to day Traders which we do in
the academy right so there's look
there's a number of things the trading
this Market over the last number of
years has been while it's crazy and
volatile it's incredibly exciting
because day trade thrive on
volatility right that's that's that's it
price
however they need to be very strict
about the only reason to get into a
trade is price action and technical
analysis you need the charts to to tell
you when to buy and sell stock so my
partner and I so when covid came along
right everything changed right you had
Robin you have Robin Hood and webull and
all of these free trading apps suddenly
the accessibility to the market became
open all the doors were open anybody
with an iPhone and $100 can trade the
market yes yes before covid this was not
the case right you needed to be a
certified a qualified bro uh um what
what's the word a um I can't remember
the word I don't know certified or
qualified person in order to or invest
right to uh to trade the market but once
Co came along and they have these free
trading apps anybody can trade the
market so they made the market
incredibly accessible what they did not
do was they did not uh none of these
platforms and there are many of them I
don't know you you have them probably in
India I'm sure too where um have a
educational component to yes they
invited you to the party but they didn't
tell you the rules of the party right so
people came in like your C like your
followers they think it's about getting
quick they think that you throw throw
the dart at the wall and you hope and
you hope the stock goes up right hope
hope is not a strategy for trading right
you know fomo fear of missing out is not
a stry absolutely listening to the
internet is not a strategy there there
are these signal Services who tell you
when to buy and sell this is a scam
right so this is not a real legitimate
trading strategy in my opinion in this
new market that we are living in in post
co uh with all these 40 million you
realize that India by 2025 it's already
2025 there will be one billion day
traders in
India okay the largest day trading
community in the world right is in India
you have 1.5 million you still have a
lot of work to do yes lot lot of work
but it's your community it's amazing you
have an opportunity yes so you're you're
making trading good yes yes so as of now
it's like uh 30% of the amount which I'm
getting is from the classes and all I
take and around 70% I get from the swing
trades and uh sometimes I do scalp in
options so this this is how the balance
is going on okay and the Indian stock
market has options as well yes it has it
has
wow yes sir it is options options are
widely famous in India and and uh The
Regulators here are trying to cut it
down because the involution of the
retailers has gone so much that The
Regulators have thought that if they
will not put some restrictions then most
of the people are going to lose money
here so now we are getting into the
restrictions part slowly slowly so that
the retailers uh in basically in last
six months we have seen 30% drop in
volume in options so because of some
regulations because people are losing
money or because of people are losing
money people are losing money yes okay
so so what I find in this market that is
why my partner and I built our Trading
Academy is that in the new postco that
technical analis technical analysis is
the only reason the only strategy in my
opinion to trade this market right
fundament fun fundamental analysis is
out the door in this new
world where you know because you if you
watch the market you have companies that
come out with strong earnings very good
guidance goes down $50 right so there's
many different players in the game so uh
in in answering to your question uh you
know if anybody is interested in
learning to trade this Market technical
analysis is ke now what kind of
technicals do we use so my partner was a
uh he started on Wall Street with me is
David green uh started in the same year
as me in
1985 uh and he uh went from being a
squad he was a runner he was the lowest
you know in on the stock market we have
like a you you have a cast system in
India so it's like a cast everybody
starts at the bottom and they work their
way they work their way to the top
there's no training to become a broker
you have to start at the bottom and as
you develop
uh relationships with people and you
look you learn how to trade and you get
confidence and people have confidence in
you then you go from being a runner to
be a clerk and then you go from a retail
clerk to an option Clerk and option
clerk to institutional Clerk and your
goal is after many many years 15 years
to become a broker right that's the goal
that's that historically is the goal on
Wall Street uh
so so uh Mr Green started with me I
started as a telet typist I was uh
sitting at a computer entering entering
uh
orders were sued into a machine and that
was my start then I went I had a summer
job in 19855 that was my beginning and
uh I I loved it so much on the floor I
love the energy I love the people uh
back then so back then it was all open
outcry no technology right it was just
th we had 7,000 people on the floor
screaming and yelling like you see in
the
movies yes yes I've SE seen seen that
scene people are yelling shouting lot of
cros lot of shout lot of pressure at the
moment and it's it's it's it's it was
crazy and there were thousands of people
here everything was done with a pad and
paper the floors were full of paper by
9:30 10:00 in the morning there were
different rungs to go off to get to
where you really wanted to go which was
to have a seat for me that was the most
exciting thing I used to love that and I
I I resisted the technology very much
because I love that human interaction
yes yes so my partner started also as a
as a cler as a squad a runner and he
became a market maker so he he he did
very well he was I I was able to get a
seat on the stock exchange that is what
everybody's goal is a seat is gives you
the right to trade it's not somewhere
where you can sit down it's actually I
don't I have my badge here uh I don't
think so so a seat on the stock exchange
gives you the right uh it's like a
license uh to be
you I have seen your floor I have seen
your desk already uh I I'll put the
clips also for the people you need no
need to S any badge you you are a badge
in yourself so it's all it's
all does the market excite me when it
goes up or down yes am I a boisterous
loud obnoxious guy absolutely do I have
wild and crazy hair yes do I look like
Einstein absolutely am I half as smart
as him by no means I get really excited
about things that are upbeat and down
beat I get upset about things I'm
emotional guy for me it's super fun I
mean I love seeing my picture everywhere
are there pictures that have been out
there that I am embarrassed about not
particularly I don't get embarrassed
easily I mean look at me how can I get
embarrassed so the way I dress I also am
a super pricious guy I'm trying to get a
sense of where the Market's been trading
overnight Market trades overnight due to
headlines news any number of things New
York this room the floor of the New York
Stock Exchange even though we do the
volume we once did is the most
significant place that impacts markets
all over the world it was really very
few Outlets to get yourself onto the
floor you knew a friend and you came
down and you started at the bottom and
went to the top this room is where I
worked actually and there were thousands
of people here everything was done with
a pad and paper the floors were full of
paper by 9:30 10:00 in the morning there
were different rungs to go off to get to
where you really wanted to go which was
to have a seat that was your goal it was
an exclusive Club it was a real honor to
become a member of the stock
exchange the whole key to this game is
communication there's a lot less of it
going on now that we use these computers
I can hide in the corner send my order
flow out and nobody needs to know what
I'm doing but I tend to be one who likes
to interact with another human being but
I've been here through the crash of 87
9911 Trump brexit North Korea I've been
here through the financial crisis of'
0809 so every day here is stressful
every day is Super exciting to still be
a broker on the floor it's taken a lot
of Reinventing of myself over the years
because the business has changed I
really honor the fact that I've had to
Rebrand myself and make myself like
famous and the most noticed broker in
the world and nothing is required your
face is enough okay good yeah so so so
you know what I do so anyway so um um so
Mr Green ended up he was a market maker
when so a market maker so you know are
Brokers and there are market makers a
market Mak I'm sure you have market
makers in India a market maker right all
the orders come into the market maker he
has both sides in his hand and he
matches up the buyers and sellers yes
his his job is to create a smooth and
active market so what may do is he may
inject liquidity into the market so as a
market maker he is allowed to if there
are three Sellers and two buyers he is
allowed to buy stock to put to
uh to consummate a trade if there are
three buyers and two sellers he may sell
stock to consummate a trade he's he's
like he's flying the plane so just
imagine it's just like a you take a off
on a plane and there's automatic pilot
and you run some turbulence on the plane
the pilot takes it off automatic pilot
and he flies the planes the market maker
is the pilot of the plane that's that is
Wall Street right he is there to
organize the buyers and sellers he's
there to inject liquidity he's there to
create a smooth and active market and to
facilitate movement of stocks going up
the way the market moves and the way
people make money is when stocks trade a
thousand shares a million shares
whatever it may be but that's that's
what we try and do so I am a broker I
get order flow from customers I go up to
the market maker I ask him how is it
what what is the market he will tell me
that we have two buyers who can pay $100
we have three buyers who can pay $99 we
have two sellers at1 two sellers at 102
and we start a negotiation that's the N
of Market making and trading right and
eventually we will all come up to an
agreement that we trade uh 100,000
shares trade at
$100 right we buy I buy he buys this guy
sells Market maker sells and then we go
on to the next trade that's kind of the
nature of things work g g g so Mr Green
my partner ended up becoming a market
maker in some of the biggest stocks uh
in the world he was the market maker in
in Bank of America Merl Lynch some of
the big ones he was part of a so at one
point in
1999 uh there was a big takeover Goldman
Sachs you know who Goldman Sachs is yes
yes yes the largest brokerage firm in
the world Goldman Sachs bought one of
the largest market making companies it
was called spear leads they PA they
bought it for $4 billion and uh it in
fact turned out to be one of the worst
trades ever on Wall Street because four
years later it sold for 200 million so
it was a bad trade they over they
overpaid for it but anyway so Mr Green
was able to retire at the age of uh 38
years old uh after this takeover he he
got a whole bunch of money and he went
on to become of the market so he's been
teaching the market for the last 30
years
and uh uh and I've been trading on the
market so I never I was never a market
maker I've always been a broker and I've
been I've been on the floor now almost
40 years and so uh when covid came along
he and I saw that there were suddenly 40
million new traders in the market
because of look when Co came along we
had Robin Hood and and Weeble everybody
was sheltered at place and and at home
everybody's eyes were on on the market
right you had all these meme stocks and
GameStop and all that stuff and
everybody had a couple of dollars and a
couple of rupes in the bank and so
everybody was trading so you suddenly
had 50 million new traders in the market
that was the number uh uh that came
along new retail Traders came along
during covid right 50 million new
Traders so uh he David and I uh talked
about it and we realized that that's
that's an amazing opportunity
because these people are all trading the
the problem is they have no idea what
they're doing so we saw the opportunity
there's no educational component to to
Robin Hood none of these people teach
anything they invited you to the party
and it's a free thrw and like you like
your people most of them lost money yes
most of most of them bought the stock at
five it went to 30 they everybody told
them it was going to the Moon they never
sold it it went back to and they all
lost money right I would say 90% of them
lost money you don't know the rules 90%
of day Traders will lose money so we saw
an opportunity hold
on we saw an
opportunity to teach them technical
analysis the technical analysis he uses
and he's tried everything
right yes he we didn't invent it
everybody has many different ways of
indicators of way using tchs it's the
art of charting right yes so on any of
these platforms there's a hundred
different indicators that you can put in
your chart right and your chart looks
like uh you know it looks like air
traffic control and yes
exactly it's full of a bunch of lines a
bunch of candlesticks and it's
completely confusing and it's not not
very helpful at all so over the years he
developed the strategy using the most
simple methods uh uh uh which I will
tell which I'll lay out to you so
basically what we use only a few
indicators okay right okay so he uses
the EMA exponential moving averages yes
right there a bunch of different moving
averages the EMA is a little more of a
conservative moving average than I think
there's a a different moving averages in
the market so we choose the e the the
the EMAs that he chooses are the nine
the 15 the 30 the 65 and the 200 The
More The Wider the range of the moving
average the more significant the trade
is the 200 moving average is the most
significant so basically technical
analysis works on support and resistance
yes right that that's the nature of
technical so when when the a
stock chart hits a price of a stock hits
the 200 day moving average depending on
how quickly it it hits it right will
affect on how significant the reversal
of the market is okay so two we always
call the 200 day moving average is the
Wall of China that is the most
significant substantial moving average
to use if a right in in the absence of
technical analysis sh up at the 9 the 15
when it hits the 200 that is a
significance so about 80% of the time
when a market on the upside or the
downside hits the 200 day moving average
then you're going to see the reversal of
the market and a reasonable trade so
those are the the reason he uses those
many people use uh the the 45 and the 64
you know has their own method the reason
he uses what he uses is because it works
he's been trying been doing this for 30
plus years so that's what he likes
besides that we use the RSI
some people use some people use there's
any number of them RSI is relative
strength index it it signifies
overbought and
oversold yes okay and then we use what's
called pivot Points so if depending if
you you so for charts right we think or
Swim think or Swim is is uh the charting
service that is by uh from TD Ameritrade
and Charlie Bob right and I'm sure you
have access to it if you choose yes and
I I think it's a very cheap it's
everybody can get it it's a very small
fee uh the charting service for some are
are free if you open an account with $50
then I think charting is free so uh we
use the moving at EMA moving averages we
used RSI and these are all just by these
are mathematical calculations yes that
if you go into the charting service any
of the people on your in your in your
group can open up a charting account
and then you enter these things into
your charts right you enter the the
moving averages as you choose there's
you can use the five the 20 whatever we
tend to use we use the 15 the 30 the
nine the 15
the 65 200 yes and then we use RSI the
RSI we tend to use the most significant
number is in the RSI is if it's 20 or we
use 20 and 80 as ours right some people
use 30 and 70 but for us amazing amazing
amazing 20 and 80 are the most
significant numbers they're a little bit
conservative but when it hits the 20 or
it hits the 80 then it's either oversold
or overboard conditions yes we air on
the side of of conservative because the
market is so volatile okay yes now the
third uh the third the third uh uh
instrument the third index that we
what's it the third
instrument that we use indicator that we
use thank you called pivot Points pivot
Points are just a mathematical polation
nobody needs to what they are but it if
you download any charting service you'll
be able to look on all the different uh
they give you a thousand options of what
you want to put in your chart we use
pivot Points it's no need to understand
what it is in in the absence of other
support and resistance pivot Points can
be used as technical analysis can they
can be used the same as moving average
okay so uh that's all we use we keep it
very simple there's no
reason and this is a this is so David
Green who is uh my partner in Wall
Street global trading academy uh has
built this strategy um you know and the
reason he uses it is because it works
and this his own proprietary uh uh uh
trading strategy and we' in business for
five years and so the the every Thursday
night at 5 o'l all the students come
together and uh we talk about the trades
of the week the failures the successes
and uh everybody has taught they have to
journal all of their trades right why
they got into the stock where they took
their exit where they put their stock
order and that's the most important
learning tool of all and so we record
these uh Zoom coaching sessions every
Thursday night and then we put it in the
archive of the course so for five we've
taught uh over five years we've taught
25,000 students and so all of all of the
Q&A sessions are in the archives for
every new
student successful Trader is discipline
he follows the rules right and so for us
if somebody is a new a new Trader that's
the best student because they have not
developed bad habits already yes right
and so they don't use uh somebody who is
already trading is the worst uh Stu
student for us because they they cannot
let go of their old bad habits so they
use some of our our stuff and they use
some of their stuff yes the difference
between a successful Trader and
unsuccessful Trader is a successful
Trader is willing to accept the blame
when they make mistake right that's the
key you need to realize we're going look
we
we don't win on every trade right all we
do we win 51% of the time that's all you
need to do you're going to win some
you're gonna lose some but what's
important is if you follow the rules
you're never going to lose a lot of
money right so we are scalpers you
describe the word it's a scalper it's a
matter of am I willing to risk $50 to
make a $100 I do that all day long but
I'm not willing to risk a $100 to make
$50 $50 absolutely because then if I one
losing trade I need two winners to break
even right so so in the US markets do
you have an Indian market stop orders
yes we do have okay so every order has
to have a stop order right and I know I
know that re retail Traders have this
conception in their mind that they don't
want to use a stop order because the
market Mak the market maker sees their
stop order and them absolutely
absolutely let me just tell your
community that is that is the biggest
misconception in all of trading that
market maker I I work with market makers
every day and I've gone back to them day
after day I bring guests on the floor of
the stock exchange who are retailers and
I make them confront the market maker
and they ask the question we understand
you guys see our stop orders and you
take the stock down there then you take
it out take us out and you run the stock
up yes and yes they will impress upon
these poor young Traders first of all in
the old days they used to be able they
could do that but they didn't now it's
not even possible they do not even have
access visually to retail stop orders so
I I beg for your whole Community to
understand that see what happens is when
somebody refuses to accept unsuccessful
traders who don't use stop ERS love to
blame somebody for losing money and so
who do they blame Market maker market
makers right they don't take
responsibility for themselves so I beg
everybody if everybody wants to follow
my David Green standard of practice for
every order you enter you must have a
stop not a mental stop you never move
your you have to have a stop order the
stop order should be about
1% of the price of the stock so for
example if I buy a 100 shares of XYZ at
$50 I have a stop order at 49 a half
okay if the stock goes down to 49 and a
half I get stopped out I lost 50 cents
it's not the end of the world and I move
on to the next trade yes people need to
also understand that they need to start
taking money off the table immediately
there's no point in buying something at
50 it goes to 52 I don't take a profit
and then I watch it go to 48 right and
then more and I average into the stock
these are the mistakes that unsuccessful
Traders
make I will give your your community the
five secret the five Secrets successful
day trade number one number one you have
to have a plan when you get into a trade
why am I buying this trade only two
reasons for reason to buy a stock it's
because the price action and the
technical analysis tell me to buy it not
because Herby on the internet told me to
buy it not because a sign service told
me to buy it not because I hope that
it's going to go up not because I don't
want I'm afraid to miss out on a trade
that somebody told me was going these
are none no good reasons only is because
the chart tells me to buy it the second
thing is they should have a Target
amount of money that they want to make
in a day
if I'm trading a 100 shares of stock I
should my goal should be
$100 if I trade 500 shares of stock my
goal should be $500 a yes when I hit
when I hit my goal I turn the machine
off and I go I go to I go to town and I
buy myself a schwarma whatever you want
to do you turn the machine off right you
never overtrade right if you hit your
goal that's the best it's going to get
in the day you need to turn the go so
everyone needs to know when to stop
trading when they're making money and
know when to stop trading when they're
losing money okay so rule number one
have a plan why am I the stock number
two is have a target a goal amount of
money you want to make in your day when
you get your goal turn the machine off
and go to the beach go hang out with
your family number three number three is
have a stop order on every trade you do
without question I mean it or otherwise
you have you you're just going to lose
you're going to blow up your trading
account stop
order four is what we call never turn a
winning trade into a losing trade what
do I mean by that that means if I buy a
100 shares at 50 and it does and I have
a stop order at 49 and a half and it
goes to 50 and a half yes I sell half of
my position I just made 50 cents I moved
the stop order from 49 and a half to 50
so I break guaranteed break even so now
I just made 50 cents and I guaranteed
myself break even I cannot lose money on
the trade the confidence the confidence
as a new Trader that I just made 50
cents and I can't lose money is the one
of the greatest tools of successful
trading okay
absolutely that's the key to the
business then stock goes to 51 I sell 20
5% more of my shares and I move my stop
off order to lock in a 50cent profit so
I move the stop to 50 and a half so I
just made a dollar on 25% and I
guarantee myself lockin profit of 50
cents there's nothing better that
feeling and the more you develop that
confidence around it that you're making
money you're protecting your downside
risk right and you cannot and not losing
money is the greatest tool in world so
you need so that's that's the key so
you're never you're going to be you're
not you cannot turn a winning day into a
losing day there's no point in selling
in buying stock and watching it go up
and then not making a sale nobody got
broke taking a profit that
ke rule number four rule number four is
if I'm having a bad day and I have three
max loss trades I'm in a trade I lose 50
cents I'm in a trade I lose 50 cents I'm
in a trade I three losing trades I turn
the machine off I go home okay I do okay
that's that's the most so I'm saying you
need to know when to stop when you're
making money you need to know when to
stop when you're losing money because
the other person the person who does not
what are they going to do they're going
to Revenge trade yes they're G I got to
get my money back so they're going start
more and more and more they're going to
become irresponsible they're going to
make mistakes and they're going to turn
$500 loss into a $3,000 loss yes yes you
will not you'll come back if you're
having a bad day you'll come back from a
bad day you'll come back from a bad week
but you will not back from a $8,000 loss
right that is that makes no sense so
that is the key know when to stop when
you're losing money okaying then never
never turn a winning day into a losing
day so what does that mean
if I'm in a trade and I'm making money
and I I I I can't turn the machine just
guy I think I'm doing great my I have
done hands I'm having a great day and I
just can't turn the machine off and I
have to keep trading it's called the 20%
rule you make a deal with yourself that
if I keep trading and I give back 20% of
my profit then I have to turn the
machine off there's no reason to have it
that up be up at that there's no worse
feeling than to to be up $1,200 at noon
and then go home down $3,000 at the end
of the day because I didn't know when to
stop when I was up right so you never
turn a winning day into a losing day and
so and those are the those are the six
rules it is it it couldn't be any
simpler right I'll tell you the example
of the opposite somebody who doesn't
listen and doesn't do have the
discipline they they have no they they
just they get to a stock because they
hope so that it's going up they don't
use a stop order right they buy it at 50
it goes to 52 they don't sell it and
they goes to 49 to 48 47 right they get
into a trade they're up $ th000 doll
they think they have Diamond hands they
have to keep trading next thing you know
they're down
$3,000 that's an unsuccessful Trader so
I gave you the two scenarios of somebody
who does this and makes money somebody
who does this and loses money those are
those are the that's the scenario
doesn't get easier than that and and
I'll tell you it truly defines why
you're called Einstein of Wall Street in
India they don't know uh by by they
don't know you by this phrase but now
after this video everybody's going to
know that okay we are we have Einstein
of Wall Street with us and that was
really really I'll tell you all the six
rules are of my golden rules it's it's
whenever I teach also I always tell them
that these are the golden rules if you
can't can't follow I don't think that
you'll be able to ever make it so that's
that's really well very well defined
they're not my rules they're my partner
David's rules I am I'm here to motivate
you and inspire you to be a good Trader
David green master teacher in the space
yes right this those systems those
things that he taught and those rules
are his those those are the six
Commandments that's good that's
good the last thing I will tell you
there's only one way to blow up a
trading account oh two ways only two
ways this is the last commandment number
seven there's only two ways to blow up a
trading account yes not have a stop
order and to average into a trade now
what does that mean to average into a
trade if I buy a 100 shares at $50 and I
don't use a stop order and it goes to 49
and it goes to 48 what is my first
impulse I have to buy more so I buy more
at 4 I buy more at 48 it keeps going
down 47 46 I buy more I'm averaging into
the trade hoping that my entry price
will be better and better and better it
goes from
4850 down to 40 I keep buying more and
more and more by the time it gets to 40
I can't take the pain in I'm down $5,000
I sell it inevitably the stock goes
straight back up because that's where I
should have been buying it and that's
where I'm selling it so those are the
things the only two ways is to really
blow up an account is to not have a stop
order and to average into a train
amazing amazing that was that was very
well explained that was very explained
and I hope that Indian audience
understand this thing because what
happens in India let's say they they see
me they see some other guy who have
experience of four years five years here
we have 40 years of experience saying
these words so I'm pretty sure that
everybody who is going to watch this
they should be understanding this the
the main ideology of the day trading
part that was it thank you so much uh
for giving this you know your wisdom and
I'm sure the audience is going to
Enlighten and they'll understand the
real value and moreover the gray here
speaks a lot you know your name your
face speaks a lot so I'm sure the Indian
audience are going to understand the
importance all those six rules they are
going to follow that and I hope they
become a very good uh Trader and uh we
see a very good
response thank you so much thank you so
much sir for joining thank you always a
pleasure we are be in touch absolutely
always sir always always thank you thank
you so much pleasure be well my friend
bye thank you sir bye sir bye
that was it
I something really big is coming all the
best