so you guys have seen me turn $11 into
$1,100 you guys have seen me turn
$11,000 into $110,000 but have you guys
ever seen me do
this $1.1 million on my Forex account as
you guys can see now the question is
where did it start at how did I do it
what strategy did I use all these little
questions I know you're asking yourself
you're going to get the answers to all
of that in this video not only am I
going to show you guys how I turned it
into 1.1 million I'm to show you what I
started with I'm even going to show you
the strategy I Ed and the exact trades I
took to get to this point if you guys
enjoy content like this man let me know
down below I continue to push out
content like this man we get interactive
trades strategies all that good stuff I
know you guys love it so just let me
know down below and I'll continue to let
it out for you guys now if you have not
hit that like button if you have not
subscribed yet then um what are you
doing exit the video and never come back
cuz you already took too long I'll give
you one more chance hit the like button
hit the Subscribe button right now go
ahead done we good then let's go ahead
and move on now before I show you guys
what I want to show you guys I do want
to mention if you guys would like to use
the broker that I used on this account
make sure you guys go down below hit the
link you will find a link to the best
Forex broker around be able to do flips
like this with ease man you're going to
feel comfortable flipping whatever you
let's say you put a grand in you turn it
into 20 grand you're going to feel
comfortable with this broker they're
going to allow you to withdraw you're
not going to have no issues it's a
lightning fast broker man super super
razor tight spreads zero commission
accounts all kinds of good stuff man
click the link down below and you can
get started on that now let's get to the
history of this account and then then
we'll go Ahad and hop into the charts
and we'll go over how I did it so as you
guys can see man we have deposited
$550,000 into our account now of course
this is a large amount but again to make
a million dollar profit means that I did
what I didn't turn 500k into a million I
turned 500k into 1.5 million meaning
that I made 200% gains on my account now
one thing I want to mention about this
account is I have been using it for a
while there is you know some withdrawal
history on here I did deposit from the
wallet you know back back in October but
again this is the type of account where
I'm going to actually take my time I'm
only going to take trades if I feel very
very confident in them and if not when
it comes to my daily trading account
where I'm trading every single day I'm
scalping every single day well I have
another account for that at a different
price you know I don't have a certain
account for just everything I have
multiple accounts throughout that I use
for different things so again when I
want to make a large amount of money
like again in this case it's been quite
a few months since I've started this
account but I still made a million
dollar in that span so realistic
basically we're looking at like 300K a
month on this account by being careful
picking and choosing what days I trade
waiting for there to be you know the
correct amount of volume in the market
and all that good stuff now you guys can
see man I just traded NASDAQ that's all
I trade that's who I am I'm a NASDAQ
killer that's what I do but again we
have some serious trades here man the
losses are very small very tight stop
losses and I'll show you guys in a
minute why my stop losses are so tight
and my take profits or where I take my
profit are just just levels apart
there's a reason for that because I
personally you know if price kind of
turned on me a little bit I know um it's
probably time to get out okay so with
that being said man I want to get into
some chartwork I want to break down this
$122,000 win and I want to break down
the $170,000 win that we had on backtack
days just a couple days ago let's get
into the breakdown so before we get into
the breakdown I want to show you guys
that yes this is a real account
obviously you guys can see that I
withdraw uh but here you go you guys can
see that's also a real live account I
don't trade no demos no [\h__\h] uh it's
all real over here so you know this is
the channel to be a part of hit that
subscribe button if you haven't all that
good stuff so here are the two trades
that I wanted to show you guys these are
the two biggest winning trades that I
had on my account these made me a bulk
of the profits um and I felt very
confident in these trades and I'll show
you guys exactly why on a higher time
frame but these are pretty much what I
was looking at it's the same thing you
know I I trade breakouts I I love to
trade breakouts it's what I do but you
know there's a little more to this trade
in particular these two trades I should
say now typically I don't like to look
at higher time frames I do believe that
you know they can create a little bit of
fog mentally but in this case here's
what I was looking at okay earlier in
the week I had said that we are probably
going to be buying right because we're
in an overall Channel this is a channel
that a lot of people were not calling
out a lot of people weren't talking
about they were too busy talking about
the recession and you know the price is
falling but me personally I said if
price breaks out of this channel which
it did in this area well then I'm
looking for buys all through q1 maybe
even Q2 of 2023 okay things changed but
in this moment price did break out so
look if you're not in my clarity for app
it's 100% free app store Google Store Go
Down Below download it is like I said
100% free you're going to see things
like this all the time for free I told
everybody NASDAQ is heading way up and
look what ended up happening I said it
here we continued up for days we caught
thousands and thousands of Pips on the
way up and again take a look at more of
the clity Forex app which you're not a
part of yet which is just ridiculous I
said uh-oh is the gold bull run over and
then I said are NASDAQ and gold coming
down and I talked about why I think
they're coming down I'm going to mention
it to you guys right now but if you're
missing out obviously get the app so
there's a thing that I've been creating
over the last few months called The
Clarity algo now in this Clarity algo
there's just there's so much is too hard
to explain but there's Buy sell signals
okay we have a beautiful beautiful
beautiful Buy Signal coming in right
here saying that it's time to buy and
price did buy we had a short signal come
in here and price did sell now this is
not for the public yet but it will be
soon so be on the lookout for that but
again when the clarity algo said it's
time to buy we broke out of the channel
I knew it was bullish and when we broke
out of that 200 day moving average I
really knew it was bullish and we flew
from there caught major Pips now I want
to show you guys something else with the
clarity algo so the clarity algo has
something called reversal zones now what
a reversal zone is is it's a Zone where
price most likely will retrace because
it's overbought if you look at the
reversal Zone with the clarity aggo here
NASDAQ was overbought yes we had a buy
push yes we had indicators saying it's
time to go up but it was over pric is is
really starting to hit this reversal
Zone and reject now when price typically
hits this reversal Zone we do see a push
whether it's small and then price
continues we see a push down so I said
okay I'm done looking for buys I'm done
investing I'm going to look for short
position this is why I felt so confident
taking short positions on the smaller
time frame because I have these
indicators telling me it's time to go
down and again going back to the 5-
minute time frame we have beautiful
Market structure saying that we're going
down although here we have bullish
Market structure realistically if we
look at the overall trend we are heading
back down I mean if we take these highs
and we connect them we're heading down
right it's just a little bit of a
retracement back up but we're still
heading down we haven't broken that full
Market structure to where we've become
you know a bullish market so again
keeping that in mind knowing that
overall I'm looking for sales because
the higher time frame is extremely
bearish we have what I like to call
resistance now we have resistance being
made price cannot break these highs we
hit it once hit it twice three times we
still could not get above this
resistance Zone and we can draw lines we
can draw a Zone area I typically like to
draw zones because every broker is
different I want to get in that area of
where it's at because not every broker
is going to show the exact area so I
don't really like to use line now when
we saw this resistance you know be
created and price start to come down
with a very large engulfing bearish
candle I'll put this in replay mode to
make this a little easier for you guys
to understand but when we saw this right
here we knew it was it was time it was
time to go down because not only do we
have resistance that cannot be broken we
have an engulfing bearish candle and we
have a trend line break I'm a breakout
Trader if it's not a support breakout
well then I need it to be at least a
trend breakout which we got here
beautiful trend line a beautiful break
below and guess what else we have guys
we got that Clarity algo telling us that
we are now in a bearish market now the
clarity algo again it's not out yet it's
coming soon it is a killer on the
smaller time frames nobody's got an algo
out there that really kills the small
time frames so be on the lookout for
that when it does drop and again I'm not
saying that you need it you can be very
successful without it in fact I've been
very successful without it my entire
career but now this is just giving me
more Confluence and making it a lot
easier to trade just unbelievably easier
so we have that red right we have the
red showing which means we're going into
a bearish market we're breaking below
the trend line we have the resistance
the higher time frame is showing that
we're dropping because we are in a major
reversal Zone and realistically the rest
was history we came down we retraced a
little bit we still stayed below the
breakout we were stayed below that trend
line break and we
plummeted major moves major moves we
stayed in that red bearish Market
according to the clarity algo according
to our Market structure price action
everything told us that we're still
staying short so we held strong and we
caught close to a lot we caught a lot of
Pips okay it's 1,100 Pips we did fairly
well on this trade now I want to get
into the next trade but before I get
into the next trade I also want to show
you guys something else obviously we are
in that reversal Zone area but again
there's other indicators that are going
to be able to tell you exactly when it's
overbought or it's oversold now not
every indicator is going to be a
complete accurate indicator that's just
deadly dead deadly deadly accurate
listen to it every time you have to
still use Market structure use your
brain be smart with things but the RSI
is saying that we are extremely
overbought as well we're getting ready
to come down I mean this thing is loaded
with red it's time to drop there's a lot
of different reasons we're looking for
short positions it's not just the
clarity algo which again you don't have
to get but there's just multiple things
saying it's overbought we have a huge
push which could mean it's overbought
just based off of candle movement RSI
reversal zones a lot of things are
telling us that it's probably time to
look for sell positions and if you
really don't feel like doing anything
I'm going to show you guys another Tool
The Clarity algo is about to have I mean
we have a complete pattern breakout
pattern indicator that is going to
literally tell you if there's a breakout
occurring and again we have a perfectly
drawn I mean this thing almost drew it
dead on with me and I'm a human I can
see it that's pretty good we have all of
our bottoms connected all of our tops
connected and if price is going to break
out above we take buys if it breaks
below we take cells it literally broke
above the breakout pattern and then
guess what we went up for almost 10%
that's big now here's the big boy right
here man this trade right here alone
made us
$122,000 unbelievable trade I'm going to
show you guys exactly what I saw again
it's a very very similar concept overall
the higher time frame says we're going
down the smaller time frame says we're
we're really going down I mean this is a
absolute bare type of Market this is a
complete bearish [\h__\h] Market I mean
there's no other way to put it it's a
it's a bearish market now this is what
we need we need to see a reversal for us
to get a break if we don't reverse to
the upside for a little bit we can't
create a bullish trend line to break
back down to the downside now there's
multiple ways you can look at it you can
look at it as a trend line break you can
look at it as a support line break
either way it's a break you need to see
that break so I'll put this in replay
mode show you guys a better example I
tell you guys all the time I do not take
trades on close I take trades as they
are moving so I didn't wait for this
candle to close I would have lost out on
these Pips but instead I waited for
price to start to break through this
trend line/ support then I took my sell
position as it's coming down I took my
sell position right about here had a
stop loss fairly tight man it's a 1 to
eight trade right here a lot of my
trades were even tighter stop losses
this one was fairly whatever I I would
typically like to be more like that
because if it does reverse even a little
bit because I'm getting in as it moves
um then I want to get out but I had a
little bit of a you know more broad stop
loss here but again we got in price and
that's actually very good I think it was
more so up here but that's good that we
had a higher stop loss because we would
have gotten stopped out so that helps
for sure price continued to drop drop
drop
and as you guys can see it dropped it
like it was hot until we finally hit
massive th000 pip uning real now again
if you guys want to see more examples
like this you want to see more trade
breakdowns strategies all that good
stuff download The Clarity Forex app
it's 100% free the broker I used to do
this flip down below in the description
click that as well I love you guys I
appreciate you guys I'll see you guys in
the next video man leave some
suggestions all that good stuff nobody's
even here anymore retention rates are
about 2% right now and I'll see you guys
later peace