so I was going to say something and say
some words of Courage but all I have to
say is set him forget that's all I got
to say it's week five of me trying to
turn a $100 into a million day trading
last week we ended up taking two
unnecessary losses because I broke my
trading plan you
good oh that that doesn't seem very
good that's why we have the Punisher for
every single time that I break my
trading plan
has to drive this car for 24 hours last
week the account was at $155,000 and we
were trying to take it to
30,000 but now we are left off with
$99,000 because we lost $6,000 last week
on two crazy trades that we broke our
trading plan on so annoying market
update currently right now 9:26 in the
morning not good currently we are down
let it load let it load $3,000 so [\h__\h]
man and last week we learned a lot from
those two losses those losses were
Lessons Learned for now this week to
take these $99,000 that we have in the
account up to
$18,000 let me tell you I see some great
Market OPP o I smell like ass let's go
to the markets and go see these good
opportunities let's go good morning
ladies and gentlemen it is officially
week number five turning $100 into a
million a [\h__\h] you got to have to oh you
heard it you're going to have to edit
some more major cracking
noise yeah this week we got a make up
for last week's [\h__\h] [\h__\h] slack
all the catch chairs you got to blame
yourself you got to hit your chair we
actually got a new chair by the way so
this chair I'm going to auction it off
for $5 million cuz I've made over $5
million trading in this chair so whoever
buys it can also make $5 million HS in
this chair we're going to build that
chair probably today or tomorrow it's
week number five we're back at it all
right guys so this is week number five
starting balanc right now of the
challenge oh by the way if you guys see
think that I'm red it's because I went
to bimin on my
[Music]
boat 2 hours to cross the Atlantic Ocean
from the United States to the Bahamas we
crossed this right here and this is the
from Miami to Bahamas that is the
ocean with no name or maybe it has a
name I don't know but the point is that
we crossed it we got sunburn but now
we're back this week starting balance
for the week is going to be drum roll
please $
8,949 so last week we took two losses on
the challenge which absolutely suck
there were unnecessary losses and we
paid the price for those losses which is
our new vehicle that we have gotten
which which is the Volkswagen and the
name is this right here I don't know the
name yet we're going to decided by today
or tomorrow so editors are going to edit
it in and every single time I break my
trading plan I have to drive that Beetle
for 24 hours and whether I win or lose
if I take a trade against my trading
plan and I win I still have to do it
because I broke my trading plan and if I
take a trade and I lose I still have to
do it because I broke my trading plan
holding myself accountable taking myself
back to the roots so this week we
actually have some interesting markets
some repetitive ones from the last weeks
and then we've actually added some
cryptos into the chart because I'm
actively looking to invest into some
type of crypto but we'll probably drop
that later throughout the day so let's
start off with pair number one is going
to be
gbpusd so
gbpusd as of right now on the weekly
time frame we are currently having a
beautiful retest of this previous
structure level right here very strong
double weekly dogee and clearly this
move right here is bullish on the weekly
time frame and we can anticipate a push
for the upside if I simply get this line
chart right here and I take it to the
structure points which are the bodies of
these candlesticks you can very clearly
see how well structured this looks any
textbook trade will tell you that that
right there is setting up for a buy it
simply makes more sense for this trade
from this point right here to head to
the upside versus to the downside that's
all we're trying to do at the end of the
day with this challenge especially after
two weekly does but you then go down to
the Daily time frame and we can clearly
see that we are under this very strong
level of support and resistance and also
this EMA which can indicate to us that
the daily time frame can potentially
have a rejection to this point right
here and then when you go down to the
4-Hour time frame the 4our time frame is
kind of in the middle it's kind of
rejecting now it's breaking above I
personally want to take this trade as a
buy with the higher time frame of the
weekly so in order for me to do that I
would have to wait for this time frame
to body close above retest and then head
to the upside cuz that is literally
exactly what it did right here we broke
up retested and headed to the upside
whenever we are under we head to the
downside whenever we are on the upside
we head to the upside whenever we're
above we head to the upside so in this
case I got to wait for it to get to the
upside if not I'm going to be looking
for some potential cells once we kind of
break out of this little inwards
triangle so I mentioned in the last uh
100 to the middle challenge that I hate
trend lines that trend lines are
subjective trend lines you can literally
put them from Wick to body body to Wick
Wick to Wick body body and it's just
extremely subjective and there's no real
strategy behind trend lines it kind of
just gives you an idea of what the
market is moving like is it moving in an
upwards channel in a downwards channel
is it moving in a triangle like is it
consolidating into one spot where it's
going to potentially break out but I
would not ever use a strategy based off
of trend lines so for all all of you
guys are asked on why I don't use trend
lines it's because it's so subjective
for example I can literally use the
trend line from Wick right let's say we
started off from this Wick so then let's
say we're going to use this Wick as a
continuation or if you do it like that
this looks completely different or if
you put it to the highest Wick then it
looks like this or you do it to it to
that Wick it just looks completely
different but then let's say we do it to
the bodies and we do it to this body
right here oh yeah it broke and retest
it out or if you do it to then this next
body and it's like oh it's breaking out
to the upside it's just too subjective
right so I don't really like using it as
a confidence I just kind of use it to
get a visual visualized understanding of
where the market is actually squeezing
into so basically I use this trend line
to identify this market right here that
the only way I will be interested in
selling is if we have some type of
breakout like this which realistically
all that matters it's going to be a
break and retest of this structure point
right around here so looking for the
temporary cells they can be shortterm
cells from this point to then this point
right around here and then down here we
can potentially be interested in buys to
execute over the long run or we we can
just wait for the break and retest above
to then take this trade to the upside
that's GBP USD next is going to be
nzdusd so I [\h__\h] take this [\h__\h]
because I always analyze the markets on
Sunday with the students cuz I got on a
call on every single Sunday with my
students for like 2 hours where I
literally break down every single one of
these markets so look you guys can have
an idea I don't only trade just these
markets right here I analyze all of
these markets right here here and out of
all these markets I find the best
trading opportunities in them and which
one have the highest probability in
going in One Direction versus the other
using my strategy and by the time that
I'm done with that call that's 2 hours
I'm [\h__\h] drained because there's
thousands of students that join they ask
a bunch of questions and I'm always like
all right we'll start this series on
Monday right we'll start it tomorrow
don't want to start it Sunday night cuz
I'm just tired the energy is not there
and then this [\h__\h] happens where the
trades play out right before I can even
begin on Monday so this one yesterday
we've identified
nzdusd that it was retesting this
beautiful level of support and
resistance so clearly whenever we're
above we're going up whenever we're
under we're going down whenever we're
above we're going up clearly we're above
and all we were waiting for is for price
to body close above this structure point
right here so a body closed structure
point right around here then we would be
interested and a buy so we would have
entered this trade right around here but
obviously it played out extremely fast
which kind of sucks because you know you
guys can't see it I personally didn't
catch it cuz it was very late I already
know students in the Discord caught it
because there have different time zones
all around the world and you know by
when I'm sleeping they're awake so
currently right now what I'm waiting on
nzdusd in order for me to enter this
trade safely is going to wait for a
retest of this structure level so the
ideal entry would have been here but now
the only way I could enter is if we have
this retest to then head to the upside
so I have to be very patient on this
trade next is going to be
nzdusd this is going to be a absolutely
beautiful trade so you guys can tell
here on nzdusd we are bearish on this
daily time frame because we body a close
under that structure point and then the
weekly time frame is bullish you can
clearly see that the weekly time frame
had a high a pullback and then here can
have uh potentially have a push to the
upside daily time frame we are clearly
rejecting this level of resistance
resistance can now potentially be used
as support and what a coincidence we
also have that daily EMA so we've had a
very strong push and the pullback has
started to slow down right around this
area now this is setting up a absolutely
beautiful trade that is going to be once
we body close Above This Zone then once
we have the retest we can enter this
trade now what's that going to look like
that's going to look like a very nice
juicy daily bullish engulfing
Candlestick then after that bullish
engulfing Candlestick all we have to do
is wait for a little quick retest to
then take this trade to the upside this
is by far going to be a very very clean
and solid trade as of right now from
what I can tell it's already having a
reaction but we cannot buy right into
resistance this is clearly a level of
resistance it's push price to the
downside so we can't just buy right into
that we have to confirm that once price
is broken above that we retest it and
continue heading to the upside next is
going to be GBP CAD we analyzed this
last week for selles and we missed it
but this week we are interested in now
buys because that was the counter Trend
trade pullback now we can be interested
in taking the trade to the upside you
got to be realistic and ask yourself
after such a strong weekly bearish
Candlestick like this do you think the
next week is just going to completely
engulf that probably not it's just not
ideal it's probably going to need one
weekly dogee Candlestick of just slow
move here and then the next week we can
potentially have the push exactly how we
did right here this pulled back two
candlesticks one week a chilled then the
next week it then had the push the exact
same thing but now here we just have to
be extra patient so for that I'm going
to be waiting for price to have a very
clean break and retest to head to the
the upside on this market right here
next is going to be Euro USD which we're
analyzing last week as well to keep it
very simple we took the degenerate cells
on this market right around here and we
got stopped out but now we're going to
continue to wait for the pull back here
we're not going to force this trade and
once we get here then we'll be
interested in the Buys so at this point
we'll be looking to then buy this market
and then the next markets are a Euro AUD
and Euro GBP but they're like so far out
from being like tradeable that there's
no point in wasting time actually
breaking them down so that's exactly
what it's looking like let me show you
guys the my effect book to start off the
week so as you guys can see this is a
real account you can tell by the
starting balance that we are $
8,449 and you guys can tell down here
that currently we have a profitability
of a
71% meaning that 70% of the trades we
win 30% of the trades we lose and 100%
of the trades that we have taken have
been a short so we have not taken any
long positions so far in the challenge
and our average duration on a trade is
20 hours and 48 minutes this is just
this is actually longer before but
simply because the losses that we took
were obviously fast you know we pretty
much entered a trade within the day we
got stopped out that's why that time
actually went down a bit because you
know it was a bit higher it's almost
like 2 days but I guess because the
losses it average it out a little bit
differently but yeah this is day one of
the [\h__\h] week five the goal is to
take these
$99,000 pretty much up into
$118,000 which sucks because that
literally just puts us about $3,000
above last week's starting balance so
this week what we're basically doing for
the artist to go for this week is to
recuperate what we lost all of last week
and just put us a tiny bit of So
currently right now it is 851 in the
morning and let's see where today takes
us all right so we just ordered a new
chair so I've had the same chair for
about I don't know like a year the last
chair that I had I made over a million
then I got rid of it so now you have it
and now this next chair I've already
made over $10 million so now I'm going
to get rid of it now this is a new chair
with my goal is to make $25 million so
the previous chair was a like a it was
Shaquille Neil's chair it's a really big
comfy office chair really bad for my
lower back so hopefully this is more
comfortable this is not an ad like I'm
not even going to promote them I just
want to see if it's actually if it's
actually comfortable I'm going to
obviously shout them out and [\h__\h] but I
have had I think 15 different office
chairs and none of them last more than a
week just because they suck the last
obviously the two that I just mentioned
were the best ones and I stuck with the
longest but if I use it for 2 3 days and
I don't like it I literally just throw
it away so we're going to build this
[\h__\h] real quick it's black I thought I
ordered it white
[Music]
passes the vibe check I know how does it
look looks like a regular chair does
does it really yeah I mean it looks like
a regular office
chair
um looks like a car center chair that's
what it looks like yeah I feel like a
[\h__\h] feel like a nin to F in this
[\h__\h] I definitely feel like my par is
better though so it least like this does
hug the [\h__\h] out of
me but then it doesn't stay
stuck what do you think
hey hey what do you
think you have like a collection of
chairs going on in here yeah so this is
uh your guru's chair this is your
mentor's chair right here this is what
they look small and soft cuz they're
small and soft see the connection there
so this is the old one right we made $10
million in this chair now is this going
to be the chair where we made $25
million honestly I don't know yo but now
that I'm sitting here it's it's actually
feeling very very comfortable
like I feel like I can actually
[\h__\h] pull up
here I don't know like my arms aren't
super down let's see how it feels do a
quick trade update
so right now currently it is let's use
this phone it is currently 857 who can't
show you guys a new car whoa Alex got a
new
car
interesting oh let me tell you this
right now I got more than a new [\h__\h]
car I can't say I can't say all I let's
just say I'm going crack the [\h__\h]
internet you know what this is a hint
right here this is a hint right here if
you know you [\h__\h] no remember Tesla I
I I don't know I don't know trade update
so it's currently 8:57 in the evening or
in the in the night oh this is already
oh this is already a problem all right
we're going to put it lower we're in
here all right Perfect all right so
trade update we have
gbpusd as the number one pair so
obviously earlier we were looking at
these counter Trend trades and we did
not take them simply because it did not
have the break and retest under the
structure level like I mentioned so
we're simply going to continue to wait
for that in order to take this counter
Trend trade if we decide to if not we're
going to wait for the break and retest
above to head to the upside next is
going to be
nzdusd
where where we've had the push very
strong daily bullish engulfing
Candlestick now in order for me to enter
this trade I simply need to wait for
this next daily Candlestick to have a
pullback to this area so I can actually
find an entry so it'll look like that on
the daily a daily Wick then on the 4H
hour it'll look just like a little more
of a 4our pullback retracement into here
to head to the upside so actively
waiting on that USD CAD we've had a very
nice daily bullish engulfing Candlestick
rejection of the EMA not as strong as I
want it to close I would want it to
close stronger but we got to do what we
got to do and then we have a somewhat of
a shift the structure but I wanted to
break above this and then have the
retest just need more confirmations and
then lastly GBP CAD we're going to be
waiting for a better break and retest
above so technically right now the only
one that is actively looking close to
being ready is USD Cad and the GBP USD
so just to show you guys actively right
now we have no trades on the account and
it is 9:00 p.m. EST I don't believe any
trades are going to be ready tonight in
London session it's still very early so
we'll probably have to check back in in
the morning tomorrow and let's see what
happens then so I'm going to test out
the chair throughout the whole night
and [\h__\h] I thought was [\h__\h] I thought
the same I thought the same thing
earlier [\h__\h] I was going a bu we test it
out and then we'll let you guys know how
it is tomorrow check in in the morning
all right guys trade update so day one
with the new new chair I don't know I
don't know if you guys are understand
but there's a really big importance of
the office chair it's like I spend more
time on this chair than in my bed so
it's a very big deal that you have the
right and ideal chair because this is
what's going to make you feel
comfortable so you make the [\h__\h]
[\h__\h] money you know what I'm saying
currently right now trade update it is
currently 10:19 in the morning so last
night kind of like I mentioned we
weren't going to be interested in taking
any trades the account is currently
still sitting at the same balance we
haven't taken absolutely no trades but
we might take a trade in the next 40
minutes so pay attention First Trade is
going to be USD CAD where currently we
are having the little pullback that I
mentioned very nice daily bullish
engulfing rejection Candlestick the 4our
is pulling back exactly how I would love
for it to pull back and it looks like
we're closing with a 4our bullish
engulfing Candlestick obviously we still
have 2 hours and 39 minutes into the
that Candlestick closes for me to enter
this trade right now I literally just
need this Candlestick to body close
above that neckline right there cuz it
created pretty much a double bottom and
then it would be the breakout of that
double bottom and pretty much confirm
that this might be the area where it
could push through this zone right here
now it is a higher risk trade because
I'm technically buying right into this
level of resistance clearly it is used
as a level of resistance and it is
respected all through throughout here so
the ideal trade is actually once it
breaks above it then it retests it then
this is where we should be entering when
we use this as a support so it is a bit
of a higher risk
trade but [\h__\h] it now it's not a trade
that I'm breaking my rules keep in mind
I am following my rules I'm not taking a
cter trade I'm buying at an area of
Interest I have my entry signal
everything that I look for in a trade
Trend everything now it's just a higher
you guys got to understand the meaning
of that there's a big difference in
between a highrisk trade and a trade
that does not follow your trading plan
taking a highrisk trade doesn't mean
that you're breaking your trading plan
the way I grade my trades in my trading
plan I can give it a so I every single
trade is graded right it's either graded
100% 90% 80% 70% based off of how many
confluences we can add into this Market
to make it make more sense that it's
going to go in One Direction versus the
other now if it's a very low graded
trade that means that it's a higher risk
trade so let's say for example this
trade has a total of five confluences
right that would be a
50% grade which in the US that's a d
popup here the grading system in the
United States of America this is what I
barely graduated high school with so 50%
is a bad grade which means that it's a
higher risk trade now let's say we were
to get 80% on this trade in terms of
points and you know things that we were
to add to confluences now this has a now
now it's not as high of a risk trade
because you have more confidences for it
to go in One Direction versus the other
so this is a higher risk trade because
it doesn't have that many points does
that [\h__\h] make sense makes sense all
right if you understood let me know in
the comments below but the point is that
we're looking to enter this trade very
soon next is Euro AUD so I know this
wasn't on the watch list earlier this
week but we just added it right now well
it was at the bottom of our watch list
but we just didn't prioritize it cuz it
didn't look that clean now we're
actually going to implement it I don't
love the daily time frame simply because
we're bullish but we are under this very
strong level of resistance resistance
resistance support resistance clearly
whenever we're under we're rejecting
whenever we're above we're rejecting to
the upside and right now we're clearly
under I love how the 4H hour is bearish
and it's creating these very clean lower
low and lower high legs now we have a
pull back right into this level of
resistance how it did here break retest
and we can expect that sell break retest
and we literally expect that same
[\h__\h] sell did you see here two
little Candlestick pullback two little
Candlestick Bull Pack boom boom boom
boom that's what the [\h__\h] we can expect
to happen now I could be wrong but this
is what I'm going to look for in order
to enter this trade so in order for me
to enter this trade I just needed to
have a better engulfing so I needed to
just like reject that area again and if
it closes with an engulfing like this
I'll pretty much just enter that trade
it'll be very clean and very solid so
what I'm going to do is put an alarm
under that structure level so I can know
when it's going to body close under next
gbpusd had the move so obviously we were
looking for shorts yesterday the shorts
never broke and retested under this area
right here how I just mentioned so what
happened we avoided that lost patience
[\h__\h] pays patience pays you have to
have patience if we had have taken
another one of these trades we would
have literally lost we didn't lose cuz
we're patient so this right here is a
prime example of why you need to wait
now this is where we are going to look
for buys now the buys are obviously a
little bit far not even going to focus
on that nzdusd which is a trade that we
had for last night the trade never
pulled back as far as we wanted to to
enter the trade
so it did end up having the move exactly
how I anticipated which
[\h__\h] sucks so literally out of all
the markets that I've been predicting
I've been pretty much calling literally
every single move so I'll update you
guys in the next hour or more or less if
I end up taking USD CAD or Euro ad and
today I have my swim shorts on you know
might go out on the boat today cuz uh we
got nothing else to do so literally I
don't know 5 minutes later this is
currently almost breaking breaking the
neckline so you guys can see how it's
flickering right now it was just
breaking above that neckline but we
still have 27 minutes in order to
actually enter this trade so like you
see it's actually like flickering
through like about a break above but we
cannot enter a Candlestick if it has not
closed this if it were to Clos like that
bet I enter but it has 27 minutes to
actually close so this right now for all
I know it could be creating a
Candlestick like this it could be
creating a a big wick or it could be
creating a I don't know right I have to
wait for the 30 minutes to close to see
how this closes so this where a lot of
Traders make mistakes that the enter
trade-off of how that Candlestick is
forming right now when it's not a real
Candlestick you can't count that as a
bullish Eng golfing because it's not a
bullish Eng golfing until it doesn't
close look so look that right there you
guys would enter off of that Candlestick
and call it yeah poition golfing it's
like well no it hasn't closed it's and
in the next 30 seconds it can literally
just and be something completely
different so we'll update you guys in 30
minutes all right guys so I'm on camera
Duty right now so I have to step out
real quick but what I'm about to show
you guys is literally one of the lessons
that it took me probably a year or two
to really accept it and understand and
become patient and I'm just showing it
to you guys on this video so easily and
it can go right over a lot of your heads
if you're not in the right head space to
pay attention and learn from this
because I like it's not about how much
money you can make it's about how much
money I could save you by just avoiding
voiding these stupid mistakes and you're
going to make more money by avoiding
these stupid mistakes because you're
going to have more money to bet and risk
by not losing money on these stupid
things look at this so this as you can
clearly tell is about 15 minutes from
when we were last looking at the charts
you can see there's 12 minutes left in
the Candlestick and you can see how this
did not stay above it's exactly what I
said you cannot base a trade off of the
Candlestick that has not been fully
closed yet this Candlestick has Clearly
Now rejected has created a fake push and
that's exactly what I said for all I
know this Candlestick could be creating
a Candlestick just like this one that's
exactly what it did so Alex of four
years ago would have taken a loss here
because he would have entered off of
that push thinking that that Candlestick
was just going to completely ripped
through the [\h__\h] screen but no that's
not the case you have to wait for the
Candlestick to close and look at that we
avoided a unnecessary draw down right
cuz let's say that this does that push
from the upside we avoided unnecessary
draw them so you have to wait for your
entry confirmation so for now the next
step that I'm going to be waiting for is
just same thing just going to be waiting
for a body closure Above This retest and
head to the upside so I think it's
proper to say that we should go spend
the day at the boat we got nothing else
to do today all right guys trade update
so that is exactly how the Candlestick
has closed as you guys can see a new
Candlestick has just opened and we have
55 minutes for that one so yeah let this
be a lesson uh for waiting for the
Candlestick to close you can't take a
tradeoff of an impulse and that right
there is what experience gives you so
that right there shows you why
experience pays now this is something
that took me like two years to really
really get so don't let this go over
your head pay attention so we're going
to check back in probably later today
just waiting for another retest of that
the other markets are exact same spot
kind of slow day in the markets so let's
go out on the boat today and uh set I
forget all right guys trade update it is
currently 4:37 in the afternoon so the
daily time frame Candlestick is about to
close as you guys can tell we're all
sweaty right now because we're trying to
move the Punisher it stopped working so
we thought it was gas it did not run out
of gas we went to go buy a jug of gas
brought it back f it up we pulled like
pulled it you know if you cars that are
manual if you pull it you jump start it
throw into second first nothing I think
there might be something with the spark
my opinion I'm not a mechanic but I've
[\h__\h] up a lot of cars in the past and
that's what I think is going on so
they're going to take it to the shop now
next to my Rolls-Royce Phantom next to
my Porsche GT3 and next to my what are
the cars in the shop parking lots
looking a little yeah I know it's
looking little empty right I feel like I
feel like one of these wannabe Guru
traders that are trying to blow up right
now like I feel like them right now like
dude I only have one Ferrari I only have
one mayback and I only have one $5
million house and only one $200,000 AP
got to get them rookie numbers up buddy
[\h__\h] I feel like such a
[\h__\h] all I can say is that next video I
mean I hope it's next video cuz we're
giving them blue balls now yeah no it's
going to be next video so all I got to
say is next video I'm going to crack how
do I say this all I got to say is that
next video I am not going to disappoint
this
driveway will no longer be empty trust
me believe me believe me so now we're
going to push it back into place oh and
the Cyber truck separate trick right now
is getting service so we have four cars
getting service right now that's why
driveway is looking kind of weak but
next week it's going to be on fire uh
this first the car back in trade update
let me show you guys currently the trade
that we were looking to enter earlier
never gave us that bullish engulfing we
never entered the trade we avoided a
loss by simply remaining Patient next is
gbpusd price never came back and gave us
the pullback nzdusd is gone the other
trade we're looking to enter is Euro AUD
which we have not had the rejection
Candlestick that we're looking for so as
of right now no trade for the rest of
the day now we're going to look for to
enter maybe early London session tonight
so stay stay
[Music]
tuned all right so we just left Jordan's
house right now just to check up on him
and see how he's
doing Jordan is getting better it's just
you know it's slow recovery it's his
third time doing the surgery so his body
just takes longer every single time to
recover but we're going to come back
later do an ice bath with him so you can
kind of just get rid of the information
and swelling now we're going to go hit
the gym I haven't hit the gym in like 5
days
oh
[\h__\h] oh
[\h__\h] we're good oh oh that's Miami fa it
was just raining a block before now
right here it dries I ifess nothing ever
happen this right here this is our drift
Street this so you guys don't know I'm
actually legally blind I I was negative
750 in my eyes I did lasic on both eyes
but I didn't recover 100% so I'm
probably like negative 1.25 right now
[Music]
ready never does Justice
I
[Music]
[\h__\h] trade update guys trade update it
is currently 1:00 in the morning right
now so dude I've just been tired like
every single day that I work out I get
really tired later throughout the day
but trade update looks like I stayed up
for this time [\h__\h] nothing I hate
staying up to late and literally not
entering a position that I would want to
enter let me just show you guys so
currently on Euro AUD you guys can see
I've been waiting for a rejection from
this area and we did but like always as
soon as the Candlestick rejects I always
wait like for a little bit in order to
to confirm the entry and then pretty
much we just started to have push back
up also we were not in session you can
see down here that it was not right
before London session I always look to
enter a trade right around this time
which is about to be 1:00 a.m. ideally
now I don't always have to do it but
it's where I have the best probability
trade so obviously avoided some draw
down on this position I'm still actively
interested in entering it I'm just going
to probably wait for now another
rejection from up here how we've done
here in the past rejection will make me
want to enter this trade USD CAD
obviously the daily Candlestick closed
under so we avoided that loss to
Perfection I still want to enter the buy
but once and only we manage to break and
retest above this so something like this
and I'll be interested in entering this
position which honestly could happen
this week just having a beautiful 4 Hour
lower low so if it does shift would look
perfect and then yeah pretty much
everything else is just waiting for the
deeper retracement gbpusd deep
retracement to buy
nzdusd we are having current oh my God
what the [\h__\h] oh wow I just saw this
right now so
[Music]
nzdusd I'm actually laughing because one
of my friends called me earlier he's
like yo what should I do with nzdusd I
entered earlier this week Sunday night
when you sent it out on Sunday SS this
is one of my friends that I went to high
SCH with literally one of the only close
friends that I have outside of you know
my my team and he told me he's like yo
should I close nzdusd or do I hold I'm
like dude if you hold it can have the
risk of having a pullback I don't think
you should hold I think you should close
he's like nah nah no no I'm going to set
him forget I'm like brother you have to
know when the set him forget and when to
not set forget this is not the time you
don't want to like not close this trade
and I'm laughing because I know he is I
know I'mma call him I'mma call him yeah
so I'm not friend that I'll call you a
100 times I don't give a
[\h__\h] y yo you're
sleeping have you seen your
trade yeah [\h__\h]
you bro [\h__\h] [\h__\h] me I told you bro you
tell me to Hell a pullback not a whole
[\h__\h] move straight down
that's what I told you bro I told you I
was going to have a pullback bro you
don't [\h__\h] listen to me dog what do
you think you told me set and forget no
no no no no no no no I told you don't
set and forget this trade it's going to
have a pullback you didn't listen to me
bro yo no no I literally told you bro
I'm like yo it's G to it's going to have
the pullback if you keep holding the
trade you're probably going to get
stopped out dude no I know I really
don't care and I'm really going to tr to
figure I I don't care anymore oh all
right that's on you all right I'll let
you know that next
trade
[\h__\h] he didn't listen to me he you guys
you guys don't get it you know but it's
funny cuz he he doesn't trade he's just
like bro dude you you motivated me so
much off off of your Instagram stories
that I just deposited 500 bucks he ran
it up into like 15,000 and then he's
like you know I'm going to take these 15
to like a 100 I'm like yeah you sure off
of what you don't know how to trade he's
like yeah but I just copy you I'm like
dude that's not how this works you just
you got to know so yeah so back to the
charts now clearly ndd USD is now having
a much deeper retracement than I
anticipated and I'm actually liking the
buys I just have to wait for a solid
rejection of this level uh in order for
us to enter this trade so I'm actually
going to move this Market to the top
with the other ones because I'm very
interested in it next is GBP CAD no pull
back back your USD having a push without
retracing where I wanted to and then
your gvp not interested so basically USD
CAD waiting for the breaking retest
above Euro AUD waiting for a rejection
and then nzd USD waiting for a rejection
so yeah guys that is pretty much it it
is currently pretty much 1:00 in the
morning I am going to knock out probably
in the next 30 to 45 minutes maybe I
just sit here in front of the computer
watch YouTube videos I get educated on a
lot of stuff and uh yeah so I'll
probably see you guys tomorrow in the
morning so I will see you guys then good
morning ladies and
gentlemen what do you know about that
profitable Trader [\h__\h] Market trade up
there right now it's currently 9:30 in
the morning last night you know it's
kind of funny right because I don't know
how this works or the science behind
this and if you guys know let me know in
the comments below but it's a little bit
it's a it's a bit weird right so last
night I Got 5 hours of sleep and it says
I got 70% recovery but the majority of
my sleep
was what like 2 hours and 47 was
restorative sleep right so then if I go
to yesterday I slept 6 hours I took a
nap and it savs 50% R so I slept almost
30% more and I got 30% less recovery
right I come here to the next day well
this day I really didn't sleep anything
4 hours but still that much then this
next
day look at this oh yeah 20% recovery so
I slept 3 hours that night and then I
took an hour and a half nap the day
before slept 4 hours yeah so I don't
really be sleeping at all if you guys
can kind of notice this why I get so
much [\h__\h] done I'm literally up 90% of
the day those you guys that sleep 90% of
the day that's why you don't get nothing
done but market update so let me show
you guys where the market is so last
night you guys can see that I was
waiting for another confirmation
rejection from this level to enter the
trade that did not happen so we did not
enter the trade even though we did get
that it's just not what I wanted it's
just not it's not it doesn't look like
the right price action in order to enter
the trade so we avoided another loss on
this market now what I could be
potentially looking for is going to be
for Buys so if this daily Candlestick
body closes above
we're going to wait for a retest to then
buy exactly how we did right here body
close above retest and then buy but that
can probably be something for next week
because we're already on Wednesday uh so
you know technically we only have about
like a day and a half left Friday you
don't want to take a trade on Friday so
that's Euro AUD next is going to be USD
CAD which we are still anticipating for
this price to have a break and retest
above currently just moving very very
very slow looks like the market momentum
is just slowing I mean look at look at
look at this week's price action versus
last week's like there's a big
difference this is where you want to be
trading this is where you don't want to
be trading and last but not least it's
going to be nzdusd so it looks like we
are having some type of accumulation
from this area I don't love the fact
that we are having a ginormous daily
bearish Candlestick pullback and we are
can potentially close like that cuz that
Candlestick only has 7 hours hours and I
don't think within 7 hours we can
completely retrace and reject this level
so what I'm going to be waiting for is
to see how the daily Candlestick closes
so I can potentially enter this trade
lendon session tonight if we keep
accumulating like this I might be
interested in taking this position I'm
not super excited about it I'm just
keeping my eye on it it looks like the
only active position that the market is
actually giving us so this is the only
trade I'm actually looking to enter
depending on how it rejects GBP CAD just
waiting for the pullback GBP USD waiting
for a deeper pullback so this is the the
loss that we avoided earlier this week
from here we had a ginormous push and
we're waiting for a retest at this level
to react but I actually wanted to retest
this level before the other so yeah
that's pretty much it um slow week so
far and I told you guys this at the
beginning I don't know if I told you
guys here I did tell my students in the
community though cuz I get live with
them every single Sunday so I literally
told them like look guys I don't want to
say we got lucky but we timed the
beginning of this challenge very well so
I was telling the students that at the
beginning of the week don't approach
this week as if it were to be last week
or the week before or the week before
like we started the challenge at a week
where the market momentum was moving so
fast and it was giving so many so much
volatility that it wasn't normal and you
know you just simply look left you
statistically look to the left and you
can see that the moves that were
happening in the last week or two
haven't happened in 2 years so so keep
that energy that hey just because it
happened these last two weeks doesn't
mean that it's going to happen next week
you got to look at the trend this is uh
I don't know Black Swan event right
that's what they call it that this
Market has moved this much in these two
weeks and it's also a Black Swan event
that we started the challenge on this
week so it's a really good start to the
challenge but it's not the realistic
event of what the market is going to
give us for the following week so kind
of don't have that approach to these
following weeks because the market does
not have these type of moves every week
now that's just a higher level of
thinking a lot of new Traders won't
understand that if you're a new Trader
you just literally won't get it if
you're an experienced Trader you'll get
it you know that there's good weeks and
you'll get it that there's bad weeks you
just got to know when to be involved in
the good weeks and when to avoid being
involved in the bad weeks it's not about
being involved every week it's about
knowing when to be involved and when to
not be involved and how do you know that
by Simply Having experience and being
here every single week so this week and
last week I kind of explained a little
bit of them like look I don't see the
same Market moves that we've been having
at the beginning of the challenge now so
we should you know sit back a little bit
and wait for those opportunities to come
now we're going to [\h__\h] lose so this
week I don't think we're might enter a
trade and if you know we do that'll be
great if not we just wait until next
week I've been 30 days in the past I've
been a whole month like a month and a
half almost without taking a position
cuz there was just no opportunities I
don't think that's going to happen now
obviously but I don't know just going on
a [\h__\h] R right now well we'll check
back in 9:30 in the morning we will
check back in in couple hours all right
so right now trade update it's 111 funny
enough but there's these kids in the
neighborhood that always pull up and it
just like talk [\h__\h] they're like fans
but they're like really F last time they
hustled me they sold me some candy some
cheap ass old candy for like 100 bucks
like I got robbed you know what I
respect the
hustle up okay you over they just met
you a minute ago what's going on just so
going
on yeah this so who's this Charlie you
guys want to see my cat fight it I saw
it you want to see my cat fight it yes I
want to see a fight you want to see a
fight no no yeah bro it's it's three
against one bro it's it yeah I'm not all
right this see how she acts it's a go
down oh
no
scared oh oh I didn't oh
[Laughter]
oh her nails are cut so don't
worry oh
Daniel oh yeah this is my office this is
where I trade all right do any of you
guys do any of you guys know how to
trade trade no no
do you guys know what trading is I know
trading is all right somebody sit down
who wants to be in the H you know my dog
are you sure you want that spot yeah you
sure saw the videos when you're like
showing the trading all right is this
going to go up or down it's going up
it's going to go up raise your hand for
up all right two raise your hand for now
dude you haven't even looked at the
charts all right so you think this is
going to go down why what about this one
do you think it's going to go up up or
down right here so Price is Right Here
Right Now do you think it's going to
continue going up or do you think it's
going to go down I think it's going to
go
down lowkey two for two you think this
is going to go up or
down clearly going up yeah that's going
I think it's going to go up dude they're
actually they're actually getting it bro
that's actually kind of crazy you guys
have not gotten one wrong huh yeah you
have not got well all right like not
like the whole move but like a piece of
the move you guys haven't all right
let's go boys I got to get back into
some meetings got to get back to some
work trade update it's currently like
5:00 no trades the right now going to
play some basketball and hit the gym so
better I'll make it
backwards you didn't make it know
oh it's crazy the community is in
English Spanish all over the world it's
crazy now I got to make this now
I made it I know you actually
did all right ladies and gentlemen
market update it is currently
904 in the morning Thursday morning you
know what I've realized this week has
just consisted of dodging bullets like
we've been off [\h__\h] week like like
literally like let me make sure this
just not
all week has consisted of dodging
bullets now yes this is a real gun it's
never been shot it's never been loaded
don't worry for the people in the
comments that are going to be sensitive
I know how to handle some type of
weapons so yeah I I I I've gotten
trained on how to handle weapons I am
very educated on weapons I respect
weapons very dearly um I have many
weapons so for those of you guys in the
comments that are going to be sensitive
don't worry I bit educated on but yeah
this week has consisted of dodging
bullets uh we have had some trades that
we could have entered and uh obviously
they were on the higher risk side of it
currently right now you guys can see
that the account is exactly the same we
have not executed any trades so far
which kind of annoying because we took
stupid losses last week and now this
week we the same losses we took last
week that were counter Trend trades we
could have taken them this week would
have made us the money CU that's what
the majority of this week has consisted
of counter train trades and price having
pullbacks but it's okay it is what it is
lessons everything happens for a reason
but it's just been dodging bullets we've
just been missing all these different
types of Trades so let me show you guys
so to start off is going to be Euro no
nzdusd so yesterday we anticipated for
price to have a pullback and then
obviously we're looking to enter at this
area if you notice I've been calling all
these pullbacks perfectly it's been
getting right to the area it's been
giving the engulfing which is the entry
signal but then obviously you know we
don't have the full shift the structure
and everything we're looking for to
enter the trade like we do have it here
but I mean this happened at 5: in the
morning dude I was knocked out at 5: in
the morning so this is a trade that I
would have possibly taken but again
missed it because of the time zone I've
been dodging bullets all week on this
another pair is going to be Euro AUD so
EUR AUD we were looking to enter the Cs
here about a day or two ago and then we
had the break then on this pullback we
were looking for a buy now we broke
under and then we're looking for the
sell now we're breaking back above and
now we could be looking for the buy it
has just been an absolute [\h__\h] show all
right next is going to be USD CAD so USD
CAD we had the pull back of this level
of area of Interest the morning St
formation rejection from this level and
then again avoided that loss because we
had the push to the downside no sh the
structure but now we're under this air V
just whenever we're under we're going
down whenever we're under We're Going
Down Under down under down under down so
we can't buy if we are under looks like
we're breaking above which is where
we're going to be looking to enter this
trade and after it breaks above which is
this right here we're going to then have
a retest so we avoided a loss here on
this area avoided an unnecessary loss
here if we were looking to sell simply
because we were under it's just been I'm
telling you I
[\h__\h] so those are the trades that we
could be possibly taking now for sure
GBP U is the be interested in next week
this is not going to be ready for this
week GBP CAD is going to be ready for
next week as well we had the break but
never had the retest Euro USD look at
this just having a major pullback this
[\h__\h] like I don't even like I'm not even
looking at Euro GBP is now finally
having the pullback as well so I'd say
the main focus could be gbpusd for a
deeper retracement right around here to
go long nzdusd possibly it'll retest to
go short so we're going to going to
remove this and remove this cuz we're no
longer looking for that now we can do is
look for a retest of this neckline of
the headed shoulders retest of the round
psychological level
60,000 retest of the EMA retest of
previous structure level to then head to
the downside so you guys are seeing how
it looks good like that's why you have
to find these killer support and
resistance zones because whenever you're
above it you're just ready to buy
whenever you're under it you're just
ready to sell that's I say that's why
it's the second most important thing the
first most important thing is Trend
second most important thing is going to
be the area of Interest so Euro or no
nzd USD that's what I'm looking for Euro
AUD is same thing you know we're going
to be waiting for rejection from here
this is probably the only trade that I
could take maybe today depending how it
closes um and then USD CAD we just got
to wait for a retest so I put Euro AUD
as number one ndd USD as number two GBP
USD as number
three so you guys are see oh exactly
what I [\h__\h] said look at this we
remember that Channel that I drew out
that I had to take out because it was
pissing me off at the beginning of the
week well look at that how about now H
how about now you see this the same
theory that I had we have this humongous
Channel we then break out of it we
retest it and then we head to the upside
you look at it now here on gbpusd the
ginormous Channel we break out of it we
are now retesting it and then we're
going to have the push to the upside wow
said and forget once again giving you
guys W that's crazy patience patience
patience that is literally the key to
this just waiting for all this to play
out so today we have podcast um I'm
going to go tour a penthouse I'm going
to be getting a penthouse very soon here
in Bickle brickl Miami um and then
Sensei is going to go buy some cars
we're just going to go with him I think
my car is almost ready we might pull up
and see it might give you guys a little
sneak peek and then after that we are
going to see where the day takes us so
take a ride with us today on a little
Vlog that we have cuz there's no trades
that are going to be ready anytime soon
from what I'm seeing here so it's a
little Vlog day that we have to do today
so podcast Penthouse tour and then new
cars all right guys straight update as
of right now still no trade in the
account it's 11:30 in the morning gbpusd
is having somewhat of the move so we can
kind of see that it's having the
rejection I did not expect that for it
to happen right now which kind of sucks
so we're going to see if we can possibly
enter that later today maybe I don't
like entering trade I mean the last
thing that I like entering a trade is
Thursday night so then Friday morning
hopefully has a push and then we can
just close right before Market Clos if
I'm not in a good amount of profit and I
don't want to hold for the following
week so I don't know we'll see how it
goes right now we're on our way to do a
podcast with the students after the
student podcast we're going to go eat
currently on a fast and then after we
eat we're going to go look at the new
Penthouse that we might
potentially add to the collection of
[\h__\h] that we have and the [\h__\h] out the
way dude oh by the way for those you
guys that don't know the ferari has the
craziest horn so does not beep here like
the horn is literally like right here
so so and then there's also one on this
side right here so you have like both
your
thumbs so after we look at the penthouse
we're going to then go watch s say buy
new cars and we're going to go see if my
new car is right so we'll update you
guys as the day goes
[Music]
[Applause]
yeah we are not we're not waiting that
not happening this is how we do it
I mean so the these are all NPCs right
like look I I'll give you a perfect
example right I guarantee you this next
car it's just somebody
automated that might be a
cup this other in drive whatever this is
right whatever this is it's just it's
not a real person it's just a bot that
they're just driving no they're just not
driving anywhere you know like when you
enter the lobby room in GTA and it's
just cars driving going nowhere same
thing these people just driving it's not
real and it won't affect any of their
Journey cuz they're not going anywhere
like I can just cut look look I can just
cut off this car right
here nothing happens right it's just
they're
[Music]
NPCs all right so we're going to be
looking at literally that top floor up
there you see that top top top top top
top top
four yeah we're going to be looking at
the one right
under no it's not this building but we
are literally going to be at the top top
top floor you guys are going to see now
in just a second after this podcast it's
crazy like I like where I live right now
it's a very suburbs area far from the
city which is where everything is going
on right now and I whenever I got to do
something I got to always drive to the
city it's like 45 minutes I'm like dude
you know what I'm I'm tired of this
right let's just let's just got a spot
in the city whenever I want to stay
there I stay there whenever I want to
stay far away I stay far away because
bro it's not it's not worth this
commuting every time this is 45 minutes
right now no traffic if there's traffic
it'll be easily an hour something for
sure oh [\h__\h] holy [\h__\h] wait so you you
threw in like your own mix yeah so so I
basically I've changed it to trade and
made simple so TMS [\h__\h] that's sick yeah
cuz that that's my logo right there like
the S and you added the TMS sick
profitable Trader that's how you know
all right no what kind of foods do you
like and I recommend you to a spot
anything what what what do you like to
eat I like sushi you like good sushi
place I've never had it but I'll try it
you've never had sushi no I tried I
tried fish last night so I had uh crab
cakes hold cupcake
shrimp you never had sushi we're going
to go e some sushi after here bro I'm
going to actually invite you to some
sushi y have you ever used Chopsticks
no all right
try all right first thing attempt we
haven't taught him
anything how do you pick it
up I taught him how to train now we got
to teach how you stop go like this Mo
everything around don't get St right you
got it so now you're going to move
inside and you're going to add this one
on top so you're going to leave the
middle finger up yeah yeah yeah but not
not up here no no you want to be back
over here like further the
better so then like this you just you
use the middle one to go and grab yeah
literally exactly how you do just go in
and you just grab it secret
[Music]
learner really good yeah so this is wagu
Yas with some truffle have you ever had
[Music]
truffle you going think we're faking
this
bro so this is truffle right here
truffle is like a it's like a butter so
get the Truffle just try it like that
yeah
good
right it's like an interesting T it
tastes better with food see look you're
now you're natural bro all right go
first
one it's
good Che
[Music]
virginity thing earlier that you never
been in a high building
no how does this feel bro literally the
top of Miami
trade update right now it is currently
3:55 in the afternoon still no
trade yeah I I couldn't drive the
Ferrari now we we'd be
sink
wait oh
wow it's literally
sinking yeah so Miami has a flood
Hazard sucks
every trade from you I get [\h__\h]
smacked from behind dude you're going to
win on both you always win on both do me
dirty like a dirty [\h__\h] all right so
we'll flip we'll flip a coin 17560 170
yes and uh how about the GT3 how much
you want what' you pay [\h__\h] 350 Grand
I pay
400 what do you owe let's do 230 230 you
want me to go to
business puppy I want to be here I got
like you know I want to be able to do
this with you guys who okay okay okay
hold on he talks fast that's a trick
that's a trick that they do 165 170
that's done we shook hands 240
250 dude the
course this is what I do deal Hey JC
give me give me my lucky quarter that's
double-sided okay
fire I I feel that they have
something go ahead Tails never failed
[\h__\h] what is it
let's go your F
Dy Okay go again all right now this this
is for the
mayback
[Applause]
Tails so 270 and 240 man let's go huh
don't you like that 250 165 let's go
who's your daddy why you won this one
yeah it always lands on
always it's a it's a d angle it's a dle
I'm going to tell you the proper way to
do a coin toss is get you're supposed to
let it fall that's the proper way to do
it see
look that's the proper way this was easy
I was like all right cool I'm not going
to say
nothing headss you're the problem buby
hey Bubby the money came to friends
that's all that matters come on trade
update so right now trade update Euro
AUD haven't had the rejection that I
want in order to take this trade to the
upside nzdusd just consolidating not
interested May might be interested in
buys if we bring and re this above
gbpusd currently has not had a pullback
so have not been able to enter a trade
USD CAD has not had the break and
reaches above how we wanted it and then
GBP CAD is just something ready for next
week all right guys so
waking up a little late today actually
not really currently is 9:15 in the
morning today's going to be a crazy day
today is going to be a long day we got a
lot of [\h__\h] going on so we have jayon
juice coming today he came all the way
from Canada he canceled the trip to go
see his family in the Middle East to
come see me instead of going to see his
family which is [\h__\h] crazy so we're
going to actually bring him with us to
go get the car the new car that I have
just gotten and I'm telling you right
now the new car that I have gotten is
more expensive than this house that I'm
in right now yesterday we took the
previous student to go the podcast to go
eat and then we went to go tour the
penthouse with him now this student
we're going to go pick up my new with oh
[\h__\h] I said the name well they blurred
it out um so if you're not part of the
Swing training lab student Community
you're missing out so let me give you
guys the recap for the week so as of
right now we did not take absolutely any
trades this week which kind of sucks
because it somewhat sets us back a
little bit from the momentum that we had
going and there was great opportunities
this week in the market but we just
simply did not enter any of them and
they were missed and we did avoid a lot
of losses so let's get into it so to
start off let's start off with Euro AUD
so Euro AUD we originally started off
the week interested on sells once price
had retest this level avoided the losses
then once price side to the upside we
waited for a pullback to then buy
avoided one of these losses as well and
then we were looking to sell down here
and then it decided to start having a
push up so we avoided three losses on
Euro AUD that we were interested in
taking just by buying Above This support
level and selling under this resistance
level all right next is going to be
nzdusd so earlier this week we
anticipated price to have a push from
this area to the upside we never had to
pull back as deep as we wanted to so we
missed that trade then when it pulled
back we were anticipating to enter the
buy here here if we would have entered
this buy here it would have been
something like this and we would have
probably gotten stopped out so we
avoided this loss but now it looks like
the actual trade is having the momentum
that it does for it to head to the
upside which is good because this trade
is going to probably be my number one
pair for next week all I'm going to
simply be waiting for for this pair for
next week is going to be for a quick
retest of this area right to then head
to the upside so this is
nzdusd next is GBP us D which once again
we have this channel right here price
broke out of the channel retested the
level of resistance retested the level
of support headed to the upside
beautifully exactly how Euro USD did it
we had the channel we broke out to the
upside we then had the retest and then
we took the trade to the upside so this
trade was actually missed I should have
[\h__\h] taken this trade right here
which would have been a beautiful let
say I would have taken it somewhere in
the middle of this Candlestick here so
this high right right now it been easy a
1 to 2.5 ver to reward but it is what it
is my anticipation is next week after
this very strong weekly Candlestick it's
going to have a pullback then the next
week it's going to head to the upside
and blah blah blah blah blah right so
daily time frame it looks very very very
clean we're going to leave this here
because you know I do this like what
what I'm giving you guys a quick recap
right now is what I do every single
Sunday with my students but in detail so
I do the whole recap of what the week
was like and then I anticipate the
following week with the new trades that
were interested in taking so gbpusd had
the breakout had the retest is now
heading to the upside I think it could
come back retest and continue heading to
the upside this Market structure is very
very clean so this is another Market
that we predicted but we missed and then
this sell from right here we actually
avoided that loss right at the beginning
of the week next is USD CAD so USD CAD
we were anticipating for price to have a
rejection from here and head to the
upside we avoided this loss because of
this very strong bearish Candlestick if
we would have obviously taken this trade
right around here and now it looks like
it's accumulating at this area where it
could potentially head to the downside
or if it breaks and retest it could head
to the upside which is
truthfully the ideal situation but for
this one we're going to have to sit on
our hands and see what the market is
going to do GBP CAD price did have the
break above how he wanted to never
retested it and then your GBP is going
going to be a trade that we're going to
be interested in on this following next
week so you guys got to tune in to next
week to see exactly what this Market is
going to do it's very easy right we have
level support support support we broke
it retested we're going to look to buy
at this area it's pretty simple and then
lastly Bitcoin right so I've never done
Bitcoin here on YouTube I believe I
strongly do believe that Bitcoin is
going to have a rejection from this area
head to around here you notice I have
multiple different alarms notifying me
of areas where I want to buy so I am not
a BTC Trader I don't know how to trade
BTC but I am looking to invest some
funds into BTC and this is something
that I literally do every single Sunday
with my students it's part of the setup
forget Community if you want to know
more about it the link is in the
description below but I literally share
with my students the trades the
Investments that I'm looking to do every
single Sunday it's a live Zoom call you
can literally ask questions directly to
me of whatever Market is you want me to
break down whatever questions you may
have I answer every single week and I
give you the top markets that I'm going
to be trading for the week ahead on this
exact challenge so if you literally copy
the trades that I am sending out you're
going to have the same results as mean
the student from yesterday I was I'm
copying the 100 to a mill challenge but
I put in a grand in it instead I at like
30k I think right now that's crazy so
that I thought I'll copy that and I
thought if I can get that to a mill that
would be insane you know what I mean
that that's a massive Live account
because I don't risk 1% for trade EV cuz
I think it's [\h__\h] he literally said
he turned $11,000 to
$330,000 following the same exact trades
that he's been seeing on Sunday swings
which is absolutely legendary and that's
the fourth person that has done that so
it's a four for four out of the four
people have joined the podcast four of
them are having the same results copying
the same exact trades that they get on
Sunday swings which is sick so if you
want to know more about that the link is
in the description below and yeah now
Jay and juice is going to pull up in
about a couple of hours and then after
that we're going to bring him with us to
go see the or you could blur it out you
could yeah so we're going to we bought a
[\h__\h] now if you can guess the color
of this if you can guess the interior if
you can guess the what what else if you
can guess the the mileage on this you
win I know you win but you win so we're
going to bring Jay and juice with us to
go pick
up because it is going to be a crazy
experience for him and yesterday we took
the student with us uh to go see the new
Penthouse that we were looking to do and
today you know what I like giving this
experience to you guys out there because
you guys trust in me and I'm like you
know what let me just give you guys the
access to this lifestyle that you guys
can very easily obtain by simply showing
up every single day so Jay and Juice
literally did not go see his family to
come see me so I'm going to make sure I
made this experience worth it so just
stay tuned for another day in the life
with me all right so currently right now
it is 3:54 in 3:50 in the afternoon so
Jay and juice is literally about to pull
up so he pulled up late he was psted up
earlier for a podcast pulled up late so
what we're going to do is we're going to
go now to TPT pick up a watch and then
we're going to go straight to go pick up
the Bugatti so Jay and juice is a
student from the 30-day boot camp and
has had one of the craziest results
anybody from the boot camp and we're
about to meet him right now in person
theice is balling out here
huh look at this ain't know is real when
your students P up on a crazy wh lers
up oh yo what the [\h__\h] yo I didn't turn
it off cuz I don't know where you want
Park brother what's up I hear the accent
bro really y one of my boys is from
Montreal from Montreal Montreal really
I'm in downtown man yeah he has the same
accent as you actually my accent is not
Canadian no no i' like I've only been
there for like 3 years since oh what the
[\h__\h] you picked him on the quick all
right so we're on on a time and strength
um where do where where do I park no no
you got to follow us I follow you okay
follow us to uh we're going to go to Neo
TPT and then so we're supposed to do the
par wait do you know what we're doing
today or no yeah yeah I know
barely yeah we lost
D so I like putting people's driving
skills to the test see how good or bad
people
are oh he's behind us oh [\h__\h] there's a
key on how to like actually like race
like the point is not acceleration or
deceleration the point is handling like
everything I've just done right now is
pretty much the car in like neutral it's
just like where you
at I'm coming I need like 9 minutes
where you
at can't do this [\h__\h] cuz this car is
not mine like I can't drive the way
you're driving over here that's crazy I
know I know no no no I taught you how to
trade I I'll teach you how to drive soon
I'll teach you how to drive yeah yeah I
got it I got it I got it son
all right bet all right I'll see you
there so literally right now we're going
to [\h__\h] go up pick up the and then
insane literally like right now I'll
show you some watches bro like on RM cuz
you have everything else now you have
Rolex you have AP Paddock is not uh yeah
maybe you could do a p one day I just
show you just to keep you
entertained but this this is still my
favorite piece
dude if you did want it bro I'd hook you
up honestly on that because I have two
so I got you this is insane insane
Factory diamonds like the baby blue
looks so good I know I know and the
price is good on that
too and that's that's a bubble right
yeah Factory you don't have any bubbles
bubbles yeah these are bubbles up here
black with white very nice combo you can
put white crown and black with red the
black ones are limited editions yeah
both 50 it's not what's up with this is
big ass that's a solid gold 1103 and
that's the solid so look they make it in
in titanium rows so the top B rows and
the sides titanium this is the solid
gold case and it's actually like a
$50,000 difference Alex for the sides to
be gold but people notice it like if
you're wearing that it's like it's the
most solid 11 you can buy the solid gold
how much is this bro I'll hook you up I
got you here we go here we go hook you
up hook you up he's going to go on he's
going to go in the marketplace you got
to sign papers just like him bro he's
going to go in the marketplace and add
50,000 look at my chain bro oh lit foret
got you said and forget with this bro oh
so black and blue no nowhere near
nowhere near no
near that's let's just say it pink you
won't be disappointed I would be
disappointed in pink
though just VI way okay okay but why why
would you be disappointed cuz who buys
makes pink bro do it with
the but then so when somebody says you
know what I don't like the color like
what color is your
[Music]
now I bought a new car so you don't
ready yeah you don't know what car about
right you don't no all right you're
about to know in a little bit so like I
was going to I was just going to do this
by myself you know but I'm like dude
you're one of the students from the
30-day boot camps I'm going to give you
like a little bit of the inset the
lifestyle you craziest one yet yeah it's
a crazy yeah trust me it's the craziest
[\h__\h] ever you're going to trip
out me I love cars like oh dud you're
going to DP out the guys not going to
expect that but this is what like an
everyday kind of looks like bro we're on
missions all [\h__\h] day so I was going
to say something and say some words of
Courage but all I have to say is set and
forget that's all I got to say you think
bro I have no words to say honestly and
it's you're the only one that knows bro
no no no I I I'm speechless honestly I'm
not going to say anything I I'll leave
it for you guys to see it