so you want to become a better scalper
you're tired of being unsuccessful
working a nine-to-five job whatever the
case may be i got good news i'm here to
help you guys out i want to give you
guys six or seven tips that are actually
gonna make you either a professional
scalper or at least a way better scalper
day trading swing trading it's cool but
it's boring it's a lot more exciting you
can make more money coming in and out of
the markets multiple times in one day
instead of just like you know one you
know swing traders will take one two
maybe three trades an entire two week
span don't know how to do that but you
know you can do that it's great but it's
not for me and it's not for you because
you're watching this video right with
that being said i do want to let you
guys know i still have my clarity forex
app that's down in the description i'm
teaching you guys how i scalp for free
every single day i mean there's
breakdown videos outlook videos recap
videos there's so much free content on
this app and it's like it's ridiculous
nobody's doing that nobody's teaching
people how to trade for free every
single day literally 100 free it's all
down below so go ahead and sign up on
the clarity forks app today so you guys
can become better scalpers like that
smash the like button it helps me out a
ton i can keep getting these free videos
out for you guys and if you're not
subscribed make sure you guys subscribe
because a lot of you guys aren't
subscribed it doesn't make sense you
want to see these videos right away hit
the subscribe button and i'll see you
guys in the actual video all right so
before we get into the tips i do want to
say follow me on instagram where you're
going to get more free tips content my
daily life a lot of good stuff it's all
going to be on my instagram so make sure
you guys follow me at mamba fx training
it'll be right here on the screen mamba
fx trading follow me on instagram for
more free content and let's get right
into the tips tip number one start slow
when i say start slow what i'm kind of
trying to tell you guys is don't rush
into trading you have to really take
things slow whether that's demo trading
or you don't recommend it but using
lower amounts of money so you don't like
really hurt your psychology you have to
do it you have to start slow you really
have to get a feel for trading because
it's not something that's easy you have
to test the market see the way they move
and just go slow you don't want to just
go out there and just start taking buys
and sales on the one-minute charges
going crazy trying to make all this
money don't do it it sounds fun you want
to make a lot of money i understand you
hate your nine to five whatever the case
may be but just trust me coming from
someone who you know been trading five
years and two of those years very
unsuccessfully you have to start slow so
just move slow trade on the demo use a
very very small amount but i really
recommend demo trading but if you're
gonna trade money use a very small
amount to practice with first but i
would really recommend uh demo trading
until you get the hang of it that's tip
number one just start slow slow down
just don't rush in the trade depending
on how you trade it's gonna you know
affect this kind of differently but most
importantly tip number two is don't be
afraid to lose because losing is okay
and losing is normal everybody who
trades i don't care who your favorite
mentor is they lose the last month or so
i've taken about 30 trades i lost four
of those right so i think i went 26 wins
four losses and it sounds like that's
crazy but this is a really really really
good month but there is going to be
months where you don't have you know
wins like that compared to losses like
that the thing about forex is you can
take a loss you could take two losses
you could take three losses and only win
one time and still be successful the way
i trade is very simple right so my stop
losses when i trade gold they're like 15
pips 20 pips at the most but my take
profits my main targets are anywhere
from 100 to 200 pips so what does that
mean that means that i can easily lose
three four even five trades in a row and
then have one winner and i'm gonna be
profitable i still made money so
understand that losing is okay and when
you scalp you you're gonna lose right
because it's if you're in and out
there's a lot of times where it doesn't
go your way because it's so fast-paced
so with that being said hey if you have
a good wrist reward which you should and
you have a tight stop-loss which you
should when you scout you're going to
lose because it's just part of the game
it happens i take so many losses in my
life in real life too by the way but in
trading that you just get used to it you
get used to losing and realizing you're
still profitable trader so understand
you will lose in this game you're not
going to just go out there and win win
win win i don't care who tells you that
and you know whoever's telling you that
whoever your mentor is is lying to you
because they're not going out there
they're not winning every single trade
that's that's literally ridiculous
that's pretty much impossible with that
being said tip number two you're gonna
lose so get used to it but understand
that losing is a part of the game and
you're actually going to learn from it a
lot tip number three is to set yourself
some limits okay you have to have limits
when trading okay especially scalping
this is very important for scalpers you
cannot go out there and take 30 trades
in one night you just can't you don't
want to do that you don't want to mess
with your psychology that much because
at the end of the day you're just
damaging your long-term success really
because once your psychology is gone
with training you're pretty much done
you're toast unless you come back from
that which is very hard you're done so
don't ruin your psychology by taking 500
trades in a single night i understand
you're looking at the minute or the five
minute chart but you can't just sit
there and you know oh i took a 10 pip
loss i'm going to re-enter oh i took
another 20 pip out i'm going to re-enter
and go for a 300 pip game it's just not
it's not like that right when i scout
i'll take my loss 20 pips i won't even
trade for the next day will it be a
scalp the next day again yes but i'm not
going to continue to re-enter unless
that trading strategy says it's still a
good trade right but don't over trade
set yourself a limit only take you know
maybe three trades per day at the most
or whatever you want my rule is i can
only take three trades max in one day so
if i take a loss on the trade and i want
to re-enter and then i lose again the
third time i mean i say three but i
think two is better but i will do three
if i really have to but really after two
losses you should stop and wait till the
next day let the markets refresh a
little bit relax you know get your
psychology back on track and then trade
again but don't sit there and just keep
entering and doing crazy stuff just
because you have tight stop losses trust
me those tight stop losses those little
baby stops they add up fast if you start
to get crazy this is a really serious
tip because i've seen a lot of people
trying to scalp and just re-enter
re-enter range or re-enter and then just
all day you know the market's just
killing them you have to treat this as
if you're day trading or swing trading
and just be very like strict with
yourself don't take a billion trades
tip number four this is a really big one
for new traders track your trades every
trades you take screenshot the result
screenshot the beginning of it and write
down why you took that trade what you
saw and what happened at the end of that
trade the reason you want to constantly
track your trades go over your wins and
your losses is because it's gonna
actually imprint certain things in your
mind right so you lost because you know
a certain pattern happened right so
write that down it happened again next
week okay write that down now you're
teaching yourself mentally hey every
time this pattern comes up it's always a
loss or every time this candle pattern
happens i always get stopped out now
you're actually importing stuff into
your own brain that's going to actually
help you later down the road for me i i
don't track trades no more but i used to
track trades when i was first coming up
and it really helped me to realize that
hey certain patterns happen every single
day certain ways that you know the
markets move happen every day you have a
breakout and the candles this big every
time that candle is that big on a
breakout pattern always just plummets or
every time some person in fundamentals
right some person says something about
the markets in this way gold drops gold
rises things like that you want to
always write that stuff down and
constantly track it because you're going
to always remember that right if you
write it down you have a better chance
of remembering what happened like i said
later down the road when it happens
again you're going to remember oh last
time this happened i got stopped out let
me just get out early because this
doesn't look good anymore boom saved
yourself from 10 pips which is a lot for
scalper so that's a really big one track
and really constantly check and go over
your losses or take profits and all that
good stuff but constantly constantly go
back at the end of the week and look hey
win win win loss loss loss why did i
catch this win why did i catch this loss
and go over it so you can mentally
imprint that into your brain so tip
number five find a strategy and run with
it and what i mean by that is don't go
around looking for other strategies all
different ways and take different
courses and do all this crazy stuff you
have to find one strategy and run with
it now you guys are getting advice from
me so i'm gonna actually you know not
promote but give you guys some insight
on you know strategy you can take and
it's my strategy i have a new app it's
called the clarity forex app where i've
given out free everything like
everything other than signals right
everything's free you're gonna see every
trade i take broken down in depth you're
gonna see my outlook videos where i'm
telling people hey this is what i'm
looking at this week so look for this
and you're also going to get recap
videos there's a pip count there's a lot
there's a lot in there and it's all 100
free so if you guys want a free in-depth
strategy and it has a course on that or
anything like that just get the app it's
clarity forex best forex app out there
literally right now that's free so mess
with that app it's going to teach you a
lot but back to the tip find a strategy
that works for you and don't look back
because when you start to look at this
strategy and this strategy in this
strategy you start to implement things
from each strategy and it just messes up
the entire strategy that's kind of like
a big one because a lot of people do
look for data here data here data here
youtube videos courses um take this
person's signals why are they it's just
too much you're already messing with
your psychology which you don't want to
do when trading forex and my last and
final tip for you guys is
use multiple time frames and i know it
sounds like oh but we want to scalp
using whatever no listen instead of just
looking at your five-minute charts to
scalp you use your h4 and your daily
raise a really higher timeframe compared
to the five-minute 10-minute charts
whatever you use but you're going to
realize hey am i going to look for buys
or sells on those smaller time frames
because you can only go up or down right
so use your daily and use your h4 to
realize market structure which way is
price going where are we trending are we
having fibonacci retracements up or down
what are we doing on the higher time
frames and you know look at fundamentals
what's happening with the news positive
news coming out for gold positive news
coming out for whatever pair you want to
trade you have to use higher time frames
to realize are you going up or are you
going down once you realize okay we're
in a bullish market right whether it's
above your moving averages or any of the
other reasons okay now you're going to
go to your five minute your 15 minute
whatever you want to use i use the five
minute to actually see hey the way i
trade is very simple i look for
breakouts on my five-minute chart and if
you have the clarity forex app then you
know i trade these patterns and they're
very simple and easy to find it's all
there for free i show you guys breakouts
the upside breakouts to the downside how
i made 10k how many 20k one tray
whatever it's all there so that's kind
of how i do it i look at the higher time
frames okay it's a buying market let's
go to the five minute and let's look for
a beautiful breakout to the upside on a
five minute chart very tight stop loss
huge take profit i'm going to trail my
stop-loss all the way up i'm gonna make
a lot of money right and that's how i'm
training it's very simple and that was
the final tip of the day i hope you guys
enjoyed the video if you do please smash
the like button follow me on instagram
i'm on the road to 100k we just hit 70
000 followers on instagram so go follow
me let's hit a hundred thousand and um
yeah that's pretty much it take these
tips with a grain of salt do what you
gotta do but just pay attention to a lot
of them because they're very serious and
it's gonna help you become a better or
even a professional scalper in a small
amount of time appreciate you guys if
you want the clarity forks app it's all
down below anything i offer it's all
down below in the description check it
out and i'll see you guys in the next
video peace
don't tell me how i'm feeling when you
really don't know still be my little
shotty at all on my show yeah bust a
couple shots if you focus
[Music]
but i really don't care