[Music]
you know i love more than beating my own
record on this beat my wife's cheeks
all right on a serious note you guys
came back for another video you see i
made 250k in one day i want to know if
it's possible how you can do the same
thing i'm letting you know right now you
can do the same thing it's very possible
but it's uh going gonna take time like
you're not gonna just make 250 000
[\h__\h] dollars tonight and then you
know go tomorrow and buy a mclaren or
something but you can get there because
you gotta remember someone when it comes
to trading forex it's the most scalable
business possible you choose how much
you make you can easily scale a hundred
dollar account to a million dollars not
gonna happen overnight so don't just
take this and clip it and post it
everywhere this guy's [\h__\h] crazy
no i'm not saying it's gonna happen
overnight but you can take a hundred
dollars to a million dollars so you can
slowly compound to 10k then to 20 then
to 100k 300k up to a million dollars
it's very possible i've done it i i did
it that's why i'm here started off with
100 200 i mean i didn't start with a
million dollars
um so like i said you can do it it's
very possible all you really need is
some guidance you need some help right
so i got something special for you guys
a lot of you guys already know this but
i have a new app it's called the click
it's not even new anymore but it's
called the clarity forex app it's on the
app store it's on the play store and
it's 100 free you get free content free
courses free strategies free breakdowns
all these trades that i'm taking and i'm
showing you guys on youtube i'm there
posting it every single day or every
other day so if you guys are missing me
on youtube because i'm not posting on
youtube i'm on the clarity forex app
posting all the time so get on there
i'll leave a link down in the
description you guys can sign up this
morning like i came in for a tool
getting a tool
all right get your tools and get out
that's one of five kids so it's busy out
there but anyway so like i said the
clarity forex app it's free you've got
all this free content on there and you
guys are gonna actually see all the
trades that i take broken down for you
guys so you guys can become great
traders and get to this position one day
down in the description you'll find the
clarity forex app i'll say it one more
time for you guys that won't pay
attention it's free so go download it
enjoy the content learn from it you guys
can become great traders as well
main reason you guys click the video is
because you want to see the actual
breakdown on how i was able to make 250
000 in one day right one nasdaq trade
make me 220 000
just in one day i mean it took like
maybe an hour and a half it was so fast
just like that but you guys want to see
that so we're going to break that down
for you guys today show you guys exactly
how i did it the training strategy i
used and all that good stuff so you
clicked on the right video today just
sit back relax and just do me one favor
two favors three favors like the video
you gotta like the video if you don't
like the video then you'll never be a
good trader you're gonna like the video
that's for good luck second thing is
subscribe if you're not subscribed
already the third thing is follow me on
instagram at mamafx trading you're gonna
get more content all that good [\h__\h] and
then the fifth thing is you're gonna
actually uh get the clarity forks out
because it's gonna help you out a lot
okay with that being said here we go
before we get into the actual breakdown
here is the trade how much i made the
history tab all that good stuff as you
can see 269 thousand dollars made on the
day but i think 220 000 made on the
actual um nasdaq markets themselves so
we're gonna really get into the beef and
like show you guys the nasdaq trade
everything else is pretty much the same
strategy so i don't have to break down
every single trade but this was how i
made 250k in one single day let's get
into it man smash that like button get
the clarity forex app and let's do it
let's break that down before i break
that down i do want to actually show you
guys the clarity forex app to show you
guys hey like this is legit this is the
signals that have been sent out and
here's where we are last night we had
100 pip move on gold beautiful move uh
we broke even right before that but then
we actually re-entered at a lower rate
nice nice nice nice 100 pips okay but
let's really look at the big trade right
the bulky trade and that's this nasdaq
nas 100 trade we took that caught us
2950 pips ridiculous like it literally
it made more pips than i did money
because i got out early but it kept
going like it wasn't going to stop
almost made 3 000 pips on this one move
this was sent out to everybody on the
clarity forex app who paid right is not
the free version of it but paid version
which i recommend you guys get if you
really want to make a lot of money and
learn at the same time so you can
actually see my trades live and see why
i'm taking those trades with breakdowns
and all this good stuff combined it's
gonna make you a great trader faster and
get you to where you need to be so you
can make 250k in one day like i said
it's not easy this could take you three
four five even 10 years to get to but uh
if you work hard start now you can get
there a lot faster with that being said
29.50 um 100 pips last night i can
actually show you guys real quick that
gold trade from last night um very nice
trade as you can see it was 100 pip move
uh very nice very nice there's a one to
four ratio we only send you know good
ratios as you can see it's i only sent
good is it one to five right here right
here we have a uh what does it say one
two four
it's only good ratios okay one to four
and that's pretty much it that's all
you're gonna see is those really good
ratios anyways lots of break a lot a lot
of breakouts i mean i really do this i
really do this but let's go ahead and
break down the trade let's break down
why i took this trade what i saw and all
that good stuff okay it's very simple
it's a very simple setup um that i take
every single time and i will take it
continuously every single time if you
look at our five minute chart right and
it's always better to start on a higher
time frame so we'll actually do that
real quick just to show you what i saw
but we're looking at the daily where are
we on the daily we have a nice rejection
right a big big rejection candle on the
daily in what zone well i like to call
this a little bit of a clutter zone this
is a zone where price is actually having
you know resistance actually you know
this is supply we have supply here okay
right here more supply so there's
actually more of a supply zone which
should now kind of turn into a little
bit of a demand zone slash support
resistance different ways to look at it
i talk about it more on the actual
clarity forex app but um look at this
look at the perfect zone it rejected
this area so if we go down to our h4 and
we look for more confluence well guess
what guys look what we have we have
support this is a support zone we've
created support here it's pretty simple
guys price has created support when
price creates support a lot of the times
we reject it and we move up so when you
have more confluences you're not just
looking for support by itself so now
that we've seen the h4 we've seen the
daily we know that we think we're
looking for buys now and we have
confidence to look for buys on a smaller
time frame all i did was go down to my
five-minute chart and guess what i found
i talk about this every single day in
the clarity forex app it's a breakout
pattern and for me i don't like to trade
the breakouts necessarily but the
pre-breakouts i like to get in there
before it breaks out when i know it's
going to break out so i can get as much
pips as possible for example in this
trade if i would have took in the actual
breakout we would have actually took in
this buy until right here right and
that's the difference of a lot right if
i was taking a buy right here on this
breakout candle i would have missed
potentially 1200 pips imagine missing
1200 pips because you didn't pre-break
out trade okay it's a big deal so with
that being said not only do we have a
beautiful breakout pattern right and a
breakout pattern is very simple it's
just the tops or the bottoms of a trend
if we're going down we're looking at the
tops we're looking for price to break
out of this trend okay overall price is
coming down but we're at that support as
i said on h4 the daily so we can kind of
predict that price is going to break out
of this trend it's pretty simple now if
you're looking at it the other way and
you want to find sell opportunities like
i said you draw from the bottom on the
uptrend and then boom you have that
breakout this is a more accurate trade
because overall price is trending down
and then you just have a pause you have
it coming up now and then breaking out
to the downside okay it's pretty simple
pre-breakout trade right here we see
that we are also at a support right we
have support on the five-minute chart so
we can have our stop-loss nice and tight
right under this zone only wrist about
30 or 40k so this is basically like a
one to five trade or like no let me see
one one to 3.6 trade excuse me um so you
know i risked a certain amount that i
was okay with i was comfortable with to
make a really large amount okay and
that's kind of the way you want to play
the game with that being said we have
support we have pre-breakout but don't
forget h4 and daily is also telling us
we're going up all these different
things telling us we're going up is what
you want to see and that's how you can
make your strategy perfect is to have
confluence okay you want to have
confluence you want to have different
things telling you the same thing
different time frames telling you the
same thing okay with that being said
we're on that support right we have
support we showed the h4 and the daily
is going bullish we have the
pre-breakout pattern we have a lot of
things telling us hey we're gonna buy so
i took my buy and i waited it out okay
right here it took another entry on an
actual breakout because now you know hey
we're really breaking out okay and um
you would have made even more money but
with that being said stop loss previous
high previous high on this actual trend
line that i have drawn previous highs
right there guess what would have
happened if you would have um actually
tried to keep holding this to this high
like you want to see what happened
my take profits are better than anybody
like nobody has better take profit zones
than me
to the t almost every single time it
comes to the t hit take profit and then
goes back the other way because i know
what i'm doing and i know that this is
actually supply and when price comes in
the supply zone we may actually see
price fill orders and continue back down
okay you have to remember that
because a lot of people they will try to
hold for too long and they'll get
stopped out break even and then you're
really upset your psychology's off and
you're messing up all right now with
that being said these are the trades
that i'm taking every single day on the
clarity forex app this is life this is
what i do if you guys want to get in on
here get the free content get the free
courses get the strategy breakdowns all
that free stuff download the clarity
forex app it's down in the description
if you want the signals it's an option
it's on there get the signals if that's
what you want but you don't got to get
the signals you know i mean it's that's
completely up to you will it help you
grow fast yes but you don't have to do
it i give you guys free options because
i'm here to help you guys i'm here to
really benefit the community and help
you guys out 100 for free
with that being said i love you guys i
appreciate you guys coming back for
another video i know it's been a long
time since i've created a video but i'm
trying to come back i'm posting on
clarity4x every day if you really want
to see me you want to see my content
it's on there almost every day weekly
outlook videos breakdowns all that good
stuff it's all on there so go get the
clarity forex app today sorry i keep
plugging it but i really want you guys
to know where i'm at because i get
comments all the time where are you post
another video posting the video i am
posting videos they're there you're just
not in the right spot okay with that
being said my filmer told me that i say
with that being said way too much but uh
with that being said smash that like
button if you enjoyed you want to see
more videos like this
i got you just let me know
all right i'll see you guys next video
don't tell me how i'm feeling when you
really don't know still be my little
shotty at all on my show yeah bust a
couple shots if you [\h__\h] with my bro and
then you're thinking that you're wrong
cause you know what i don't started at
the bottom and you used to be
here seeing that i'm up and you say it's
not fair you wanted me back