You clicked on this video because somewhere along the line
you will have to learn trading. I know,
you must have a hope that what
is the actual plan and how to trade,
what is its way, what is the reality, how
can we actually make money in the market?
So we understand everything and move ahead with a complete
plan. Okay, what are the
things you need to learn because beginners do
n't have a plan, a road
map. Because there are so many
things available on the internet. You know, someone is
telling one strategy, someone is
telling another strategy. So what is the reality of all these and
how can you actually master them,
understand everything without wasting time. Let's go. So, to do
trading, first of all
you have to understand which markets are there. First of all, there is the
Indian market, then there is
cryptocurrencies, then there is forex, then there is the
commodity market. These are the four places
where we trade. Now, actually, do
n't look at trading as if I am
using a particular different thing for intraday and a different thing for commodities.  The
reality of trading is that the
first tool for trading in the market, through which you
analyze the charts
and then take a trade, is technical
analysis. Now, what are the steps to learn technical analysis? So,
what should you do?
Make a note. First,
write at the top: "Step One of Trading Learning
Technical Analysis." Now, if you do
n't know even the basics of buying and selling, then leave
me a comment. I will make a dedicated video on crypto
currency, forex, Indian market options,
stocks, and all these things. It will be
easy for you to understand how to buy and
sell. If you don't know even that much, then as far as
I expect
you to know how to buy and sell, if you know how to buy and sell, then simply
write "Topic One" here, your "Step One for Trading." And
then write "Learn
Technical Analysis" below. Now, there are
many terms in technical analysis. If you are
going to do this, then candlestick chart patterns, EMA
indicators, you know strategies, etc.  There are many
things. What is their structure?
I am explaining them to you. All the other
things are interlinked with each other. This
means that if you learn the first term from the beginning
and then when you
learn the second term, then the second thing you are going to
learn without
clearing up the first term has
no meaning. So the first term is
candlesticks in technical analysis. Now, what do
candlesticks actually do?
What happens? First, let's understand that
when a candlestick is formed in the market, it is
not representing a drawing to you that if this happens then
you will do this, if this happens then do
not do that, there is no benefit in that.
You also know that there are many such chart patterns.
If you search on the internet, you will
find 30-35 candlestick patterns. The
reality is that if you sit down to memorize them all, then
you also know that
you can practice as much as you want by memorizing or by pasting posters. So,
you have to run
after the psychology of
why the candlestick is actually closing.  We will
also bring a dedicated video, but for now,
understand the essence of the candlestick. The job of a candlestick is to
tell you the psychology of the market. Now,
how a candlestick is formed consists of four things: an
open, a close, a high, and a low.
Open means where the
price started. So, what is the price?
Whenever you are betting for 5 minutes,
a candle will form there in
5 minutes, that is, how much the price is moving within 5 minutes,
you will
understand that in the candlestick. This is
ultimately the job of a candlestick. The open has happened,
after that the close means when the 5 minutes are about to
end, where has the candle
closed? High means how
high the market reached and low means what is the lowest point. Through this,
you have to understand the psychology of the
buyer and the seller, what is actually
going on between the two and what is the
main, you know, trying to tell us that price, because
ultimately, price is God.
Everyone must have heard this. Now, the
second term that comes after the candlestick is support.
Resistance sounds so basic.
What is support and resistance?
Such lines have been drawn, but the reality is
not like that. Just lines won't do anything.
You have to understand its psychology. If the
price is coming to a support, will it
go up? Has it become over-exhausted?
Over-exhausted means that we already
know that when it is coming to support, buy.
But when you look at the past,
how many times has the market tested that support? The sim
goes for resistance. We will
make a dedicated video on this as well. The first is
candlesticks. The second is support-resistance
candlesticks. When you
merge support and resistance, your
trading will be accurate. After these two terms, the
third thing comes: price action.
Price action tells you the market trends, which
trend the market is currently following: whether it is going on an uptrend or a
downtrend. Along with that,
you can also understand trend reversals with the
help of price action, at which particular
level the market has now become exhausted and the
trend is about to reverse.  The
fourth term is supportive
indicators and volume. I'm merging them
because volume is also a kind of
indicator. However, volume
tells you
how many transactions have taken place in the market. There are some
sets of indicators that actually
work in the market. If you know its
direct use case,
yes, this particular indicator is useful for this purpose. When
you know its use case, then when you
merge it with your analysis, then
your strategy is formed. And similarly, I
also have an ATM. I use it. Apart from that, I have
830 strategies that I have created myself,
which also work well. Many
people have already done better than this, you know.
But the reality is that
strategists are different. Now, if that
strategy copes with your mind, that means
you are good to go. And if it doesn't, it means that no matter which
strategy you adopt, you are going to fail. So, it is
better that you study all the fundamentals.
Meaning, all these
technical analysis, price action
support, you will first understand them, learn them and your
strategy will be formed automatically, now the second
thing is the process, let's assume that
you have done trading at 40, now trading at 60
comes in the process, we will
understand that in the next part, if this
video gets 1000 likes then we will make a
part two of this, tell me whether you understood it
in easy terms or not and how did you like it, just let
me know all the best