i don't know how many sips i will have
to drink out of that cup before i will
actually film an intro for this video
it's not because i'm super thirsty just
because i'm so excited to be finally
back on my youtube channel on 2022 and i
hope you all the best for this year so
in today's video i would like to discuss
a strategy that was requested long time
ago and i'm finally able to make it and
that's including a whole moving averages
the majority of forex and stock traders
they are using different forms of moving
averages and that's absolutely brilliant
however the main factor with any
indicator that is based on moving
averages is the lagging aspect for
example long story short when it comes
to trading i always like to use my 25
and 50 moving averages however when i
found out about the whole moving average
strategy my mind was like i need to
share this with my followers my
subscribers because it's just insane
it's like a beast when it comes to
trading so buckling guys and let's get
started so one of the most frequently
asked questions many people see the
whole moving average is how does it
differ from a normal moving average
that's a great question to start with
and let me show you an excellent example
so you can see the difference yourself
here is a child with three different
moving averages i added on a 50 period
simple moving average that's in pink
color a 50 period ema that's in dark
blue and we have a 50 period whole
moving average in orange the first thing
you will notice about the whole moving
average is that it has the tendency to
follow prices considerably more closely
than both the simple moving average and
the exponential moving average and when
i was back testing this strategy on all
the currency pairs i can definitely spot
something that you might found it
helpful so during a market shift from a
non-trending to a trending one you can
see that the three moving averages are
staying relatively close together over
here i will add an example so you can
see yourself but for example here when a
market shifts into a trending one so
it's either to the upside or to the
downside you can see that the whole
moving average is very quick to follow
the price and it remains relatively
close to the candles however the other
two movement averages so that's ma and
ema they lag behind the price by a large
amount until the market stops trending
and the three moving averages are once
again they are near to each other so
therefore this explains why the whole
moving average is totally different from
other moving averages and in general the
major goal for the whole moving averages
is to eliminate that lag that is
associated with the normal moving
averages while still ensuring the
smoothness of the indicator before
jumping into the whole moving average
strategy let me guide you on how you can
add this indicator to your chart so step
one of course is to go on
tradingview.com and on the left hand
side you will find an indicator section
all you have to do is press on it and
type hma which is whole moving average
and basically double click on it now
because you have them on the chart they
come up with the default settings but
for this strategy we will have to adjust
them so simply choose one of the moving
averages and change from default to 50
and the second one will be 25 and
basically click ok so for the sake of
explanation i have included a basic
moving average with a period of 50. so
let's take a brief look at this chart we
have a clear uptrend we have a whole
moving average in orange and we have a
simple moving average in blue now
consider the point at which these moving
averages begin to trend upward and
follow their bullish momentum the simple
moving average was sloping downward
until this zone when it began to trend
upward so let's compare this move to the
whole moving average well the whole
moving average also sloped downward but
it had rapidly started to trend upward
and as a result the whole moving average
produced less lag when compared to a
simple moving average simply because it
includes the weighted moving average in
this formula to help it out so the main
question is how you can use whole moving
averages in your trading well the first
thing you should know about this
indicator especially if you're looking
to employ numerous of the whole moving
averages on your chart is that it was
not created to be used as a crossover
signal you may be surprised to learn
that in every other trading video that
have been using moving averages that
crossover is like a heart like a base of
the strategy am i right but however you
will find out later on why the hormone
average strategy that i've been using
today is not to be used as a crossover
signal of course in a trending market
the simple use of a moving average would
be an effective way to employ because
once the crossover is produced you may
buy or sell depending on the market
condition so let's say if we replaced
moving averages with whole moving
averages you would notice that there is
an enormous number of crossovers that
happened and if you traded all of these
crosses you have lost much more money
that is why i keep advising the people
who are watching my videos that is so
important to get that knowledge about
the strategy about the actual tools you
are planning to use because it will make
a major difference because you will be
able to use them in your advantage and
to get back to basics the whole moving
average is used to determine the
direction of an overall trend in the
market and also it's been used for an
entry and exit points but not 4a
crossovers so to give an idea of how we
use the whole moving average take a look
over here when the whole moving average
is trending up we would of course use
that as a confirmation to look for buy
opportunities only on the other hand if
the whole moving average is sloping
towards the downside we will look out
for cell traits only and once you have
identified a strong trend with the help
of the whole moving average we can use
it as an entry signal as well so when
you're using this indicator i recommend
using a lower settings to make that more
visible so what i mean by this when i
mentioned you can use numerous of the
whole moving averages the one can be for
the trend and another one can be four
and entry and exit signals and just like
with the ema or sma you can increase the
length of the whole moving average this
changes how far back the indicator looks
into the price history when analyzing
market conditions so here's a little
sneak peek at the trade i performed
using this strategy i have gbp ncd on
the 30 minute time frame of course if
you're looking to employ whole moving
averages in your trading you'll have to
begin by analyzing higher time frame
analysis you'll have to search for
support resistance trend lines and any
chart patterns that will help you along
with the strategy so what i was actually
waiting for is for a nice bounce of the
moving averages to support my setup
which of course has occurred on the 30
minute time frame because as you can see
we had a nice bullish engulfing candle
bouncing off the whole moving average
and one hour time frame had a nice
confirmation as well that was a bullish
engulfing candle bouncing off a
trendline which is also a great sign to
support my setup so as you can see by
now on the right side of your screen
these are the profits based on the
strategy for the gbp nct trade and my
overall opinion is that this strategy
has a very high expectations and profits
if it is applied correctly in order to
succeed so that was it for today i hope
you enjoyed my first video of 2022 and
if you found this video helpful you can
leave like you can comment down below
how i did or what would you like to see
next and i will make sure take care of
it so once again thank you guys for
watching me and i'm so excited to see
you next time bye