my name is mom fx and welcome to my
mixtape
if they try to come rob you she can go
running wake up learning session and
check him on the trains i lost at least
five pounds in there though and then i
gained it right back i'm gonna then spin
the wheel again and it's gonna have an
objective
what's good snake gang welcome back to
another video on the channel if you're
new here make sure you hit that
subscribe button let's be honest
everybody on youtube and the 4x
community they're doing the same [\h__\h]
it's all [\h__\h] fake trade breakdowns
buying cars it's all the same [\h__\h] it's
super boring obviously i do the same
thing but no more no more what i have
for you guys today is a spin the wheel
of forex challenge it's gonna be called
spin a forex how this is really gonna
work this is gonna be pretty simple
there's gonna be six episodes per season
right now we're obviously in season one
so season one episode one that will be
right now we're gonna be spinning the
wheel two times all right first wheel
spin is gonna tell me what 4x pair i'm
going to be trading for the week i
shouldn't say for the week because
that's not true after i get the forex
pair situated and i know what pair i'm
gonna trade i'm gonna then spin the
wheel again and it's gonna have an
objective now thing about these
objectives is
whoa
i can do some mouth exercises before you
come hey yo
[Music]
oh my god that was terrible
now look when it comes to the objectives
these objectives can change they're not
always going to be the same it's
actually a big list of objectives and
some of them are actually pretty [\h__\h]
crazy we have things such as trade three
times you only get three trades with
that pair that you spend for or we have
my wife trades for me blindfolded trades
flip a coin trades only buys only sales
only tokyo like there's so many options
on this wheel it can get crazy depending
on how this really goes in season one
we'll see if we can even flip the
account but if we get you know three
weeks in a row of like my wife trading
and then only buys and then blindfolded
trades we could easily blow the entire
account so it's gonna get crazy it's
gonna get intense and all i want for you
guys to do is just sit back enjoy the
video because it's gonna be enjoyable
it's going to be a lot of crazy moments
uh this week's vlog is going to be crazy
i don't know what i'm doing but a couple
different things and you'll you'll see
that later also i'm starting with a
thousand dollar account i have deposited
a thousand dollars into the account my
goal is to try to flip it to like maybe
six weeks six episodes i mean 10 000
would be cool it just really depends i
can't dictate that because i'm not going
to be sitting here trading like i
normally trade or trading the pairs that
i normally trade on the wheel i mean
there's you know gbp jpy there's gold
which is great but then there's also
pairs like euro
gnd i don't know i think that's a real
pair but there's a lot of different
weird you know currencies out there that
we don't normally trade or talk about
but i'm going to have to be trading them
so it's going to be fun it's going to be
a challenge it's going to be exciting i
appreciate you guys for coming along for
the journey um before we get into that
which we're gonna get into in like five
seconds i do want to do a subscriber
spin the wheel so whatever this wheel
lands on you guys at home have to do
just to start things off right so let's
go and spin this wheel lots of different
options holy [\h__\h]
whoa
out of all the ones i could have landed
on you guys gotta hit that subscribe
button so go down below hit the
subscribe button smash the like button
it helps me out helps youtube algorithm
and it's going to help me uh get this
video to more people which you guys want
to get this to more people because it's
exciting and i'm going to keep doing it
so without being said i love you guys
and i'll see you guys in the video
enjoy
all right
in my hand i behold behold i hold the
key to either my failure or my success
in this challenge now on this ipad i
have my major wheel i have you know the
wheels that we're going to be using and
challenge
i i can't talk let's let's just like
kind of run that back inside this ipad i
have my spin the wheel challenge app i
have everything loaded in whether it's
the pairs or the objective for the week
it's all in here and it's about to go
down really quick before we actually get
into spinning the wheel and figuring out
how this week is going to go i want to
go over the rules one last time now you
guys got to remember no matter what
parent lands on that is the pair that i
can trade and only that pair mixed with
the objection okay the objective wow the
objective now the objectives range from
my wife trades for me to 48 hours to
even a few days worth of trading it just
depends on what i land on there's some
pretty crazy stuff on there like flip a
coin or blindfolded trading like there's
some stuff on there that can definitely
knock my entire account down to zero
like that so this is gonna be a very
exciting challenge of course i'm
starting with a thousand dollars i'm
gonna try to grow that to as much as i
can in six episodes and that would equal
season one don't know how many seasons
i'm gonna do i could do five i could do
a thousand i mean it just depends how
you guys like it if you guys really love
it you show love you smash that like
button because it always helps me out
well then guess what i'm going to
continue to pump this out for you guys i
know there's a lot of series in the past
that i didn't complete and i gave up on
but let's be real the love started to go
down people got bored of them and i just
i didn't have interest in doing it but
this is exciting like this is super
exciting my wife may have to trade for
me i may have to trade for me with a
[\h__\h] blindfold on like it can get
pretty crazy right so uh without any
further ado let's get into spinning the
wheel super nervous i hope that we can
at least start the week off at least
episode one off on a positive note maybe
something simple like gdp jpy or gold or
something that i like to trade but of
course there's a lot of pairs on there
that uh i don't like the trade so
here we go the magical ipad
oh my god almost just [\h__\h] dropped
yeah
all right guys i got the wheel loaded up
i'm looking at the pairs and uh i'm
starting to feel a little nervous i'm
not gonna lie i'm starting to feel a
little nervous because you know i see
things like gj on here i see gold looks
good but then i see things like uh usd
mxn or euro sgd okay these prayer
prayers prayers i need a prayer jesus
pray
pairs that i have never traded in my
entire life are on here but it's okay
because i i don't think i'm gonna get
one of those i think we're gonna be good
um but let's start the episode off i
hope you guys enjoy the series and here
we go with our first spin ever
[Music]
gbp in okay i don't even know i don't
know what country that is it's gonna be
all right it's gonna be that's fine i
can do that
nope no problem gbp knock
why wouldn't i be able to trade gp knock
that's that's simple just
excuse me for one one minute
[Music]
yeah gp knock it
easy it's going to be easy you know let
me just really quick i want to just kind
of
just real quick look at it because i
don't think i've ever looked at this
pair my entire life
and um
yeah it can't it can't be that hard to
trade nor win
chrome there we go norwegian no
norwegian nothing wrong with norwegian
okay looking at the five okay wow we
have a a a crazy spike right there so
that's
something to look out for that doesn't
really happen on
gbp jpy it doesn't look crazy i mean
we're down trending right now overall go
to the four hour
yeah it's not it's not
terrible i mean it moves decent right i
mean it looks like it moves like similar
to gdp jpy i mean not as
clear i mean we have a lot of
action here but it's it's not a problem
i can do this i could i can definitely
do this
[\h__\h]
okay so gbp knock here we come we're
gonna kill it we're gonna make a lot of
money here's the fun part guys i mean
yeah you know we got the pair and that's
great right whatever the pair may be we
have it and it's secure we're gonna
trade it but this is the part that's
actually [\h__\h] terrifying and that's
the objective what am i gonna have to do
this week with this pair and try to be
successful doing it okay i want to show
you guys some of these objectives really
quick okay we got blindfolded trading
only buys only sales imagine we can only
take buys ourselves of course i can
decide when to take that by but it has
to be there or we have 24 hours five
trades only tokyo session flip a coin
wow this is this is scary this is really
scary so let's go ahead and spin the
wheel and uh
we'll see what we get here we go
[Music]
okay i mean that's not bad that's that's
not bad considering we could've got some
stuff that leaves no control to me like
my wife trading or blindfold trading
like that that's gonna be bad if we ever
get one of those but uh you know three
trades is not bad you guys know the
rules i kind of explained it a couple
times now but we're going to have to
trade gdp knock and we're only allowed
to take three trades this entire week
this is gonna be uh it's gonna be
exciting but it's gonna be very uh
hear my son in the background screaming
he he knows it's not gonna go well i
think he knows so this is gonna be fun
that's all i have to say i want to get
into this vlog i don't want to waste no
more time i want to hop into the
challenge i want to begin looking at the
charts figuring out what we're going to
do and um gp knock here we come three
trades see you guys in the vlog oh my
god
all right guys so as you can see we have
a fresh thousand dollars in the account
excited to see what we can do with it
and the only pair that we have right now
is gp knock one thing that scares me
it's only 12 o'clock so the spreads
usually aren't bad but the spreads are
not the greatest on here and i like the
scalp so it's gonna be kind of scary
we'll see how things go
but the spreads being that bad it does
it does scare me a little bit as a
scalper especially if i decide that i
want to get in and out of a trade really
fast um with spreads like that i want to
trade the one or five minute time frame
like i always do it could be uh it could
be risky so see some sweat on my head
i'm literally sweating i'm that scared
about this challenge but guys i'm very
excited for it i'm very very excited for
it i think we're going to do well i want
to take probably one trade right now or
then the next
we'll see we'll see if there's a set up
there actually but uh within the next 20
minutes hopefully we can find something
for the morning trade i want to trade
again either tonight or tomorrow morning
and then again tomorrow night so we only
have three trades remember that three
trades to try to make something happen
with this account for episode one season
one of forex wheel spin that is not what
i named it spin of forex there we go
what start saying random [\h__\h] sometimes
but one thing i haven't showed you guys
is the office so i want to show you guys
what the office looks like really quick
because i've made some changes we have
the sign up there and things like that
so let's get into what the mamba fx
office looks like and then after that i
actually want to go upstairs and show
you guys my inner room office and uh
we'll go up there and hopefully find a
good trade take check out the office
guys as you can see we got the stuff
back here and [\h__\h] but check it out
[Music]
so yeah guys this is like this is my
happy place this is where i come to
trade i come to breathe relax make some
money and um yeah a lot of good things
go down there obviously but really quick
i want to show you guys the actual
office upstairs like a little mini
office it's like a uh you know a little
computer setup so when i'm chilling in
bed with the wifey and everything i can
still trade i can still see the charts
been a while since the vlog but just to
show you guys like i said i'm with the
wifey chilling watching tv whatever the
case may be i don't feel like going to
my office so wow room's a little bit
dirty so we'll just kind of like not
show the room but show the office
hold on hold on let me see if i can just
turn this a little bit on cover and boom
there it is baby so if i'm laying in bed
relaxing like i said i could just look
over i have of course little sitting
spot table uh main pair we're looking at
in this case gbp knock i have my little
students messages right here trading
history as you can see we're up seven
thousand dollars on the week and then um
my signal room and all that good [\h__\h]
still have gj up here because that's
pretty much what i'm trading right now
but um i need to change that to gp knock
[Music]
that's pretty much what i have for the
upstairs office i'm always looking at
the charts up here downstairs wherever
i'm at i'm looking at charts i'm always
looking at charts making sure that i can
better perfect my craft get better at
what i do and make sure i don't miss
super good trading setups i don't want
to miss anything you never want to miss
anything because if you're a scalper
like me like that a trade setup can
happen and you miss it you're done so
you're done make sure you're paying
attention always looking at charts have
multiple setups whatever you got to do
uh upstairs downstairs or just bring an
ipad everywhere you go you can get
simple with it but always have something
like that so you can always check the
charts and make sure everything's going
good but um i'm gonna actually get into
a gvp knock trade right now i'm looking
at it set up and um yeah let's let's go
take a look at it alright so because i
want to get in this trade really fast
i'm gonna show you guys like this and
the next couple trades i'll get on the
screen recording so you guys can see the
actual screen the full screen but um
what i'm seeing here on gbp knock i'm
looking at a break of a you know support
slash you know breakout zone we're on
the five minute chart by the way this is
a basic little bit of a support but it's
a pre-breakout setup we have the
downtrend starting to form with the
triangle wedge and then under this would
be considered breakout material however
i like to get in early i like to take my
trades before they happen i like to
maximize those pips and if price starts
to respect the support and move up we'll
get out of the trade it's that simple so
i'm going to be going short right here
on gp knock i'm going to go ahead and
pull this up to show you guys what i'm
pretty much looking at okay my stop-loss
will simply be just above that zone and
then we will go ahead and target into
this resistance area okay so as you guys
can see this is the trade we're gonna be
taking uh it's a nice little uh one to
four point five so a really good risk to
reward but there it is you guys can see
it here i'll show you guys on the screen
more in depth after it goes either good
or bad i guess but um we're going to
enter this trade we're going to do
probably a zero point hopefully like a
0.10 to 0.30 something around that we'll
see what it lets me do but there's our
first trade let's see how it plays out
all right we entered our trade we're
chilling we're going out um you know a
lot of traders they they like to party
they do all the stupid [\h__\h] whatever
blah blah blah whatever they like to do
it's their thing i don't care but not me
that's not what i like to do so what
we're about to do right now me and my
girl she's choking over here
so what we like to do is a little bit
different all right i'm gonna surprise
you guys and when we get there you'll
see but we're not going to party we're
not going to the mall we're not doing
none of that [\h__\h] about to go have some
real life fun so you guys will see where
we're going in a minute and after that
we're actually going to be going to an
ultrasound to see hopefully if we're
having a boy or a girl it's super early
so we might not be able to tell yet but
uh we're going to at least try and see
if we're having a boy or girl this is
baby number
what number is this
baby number six so this is baby number
six i lost count after about four i'm
just baby number six so we'll see how
things go we're hoping for a girl but
you never know you never know my name is
mom fx and welcome to my mixtape
[Music]
okay
uh
[Music]
holy [\h__\h] you want to try it yeah
let go before it flips you
it looks like you're on a giant boss
oh [\h__\h]
[Music]
i'm gonna
fire well that was fun
but
i feel like all that did was remind me
that i weighed 220 pounds i lost at
least five pounds in there though and
then i gained it right back god damn it
well the cops are in there they're not
going to see me swerving we just got
done uh jumping around you know getting
some exercise in having fun because
that's what it's really about and that's
what i like to motivate you guys with is
that you know like i'm being goofy or
whatnot but at the end of the day i'm
able to go to a trampoline park three
times a day every day if i wanted to and
that's simply because i worked hard i
got my dreams or i worked for my dreams
and now you know i can do whatever i
want i can pull up in a mclaren to a
trampoline park and jump around and
again that's never to flex on you guys
that's just to motivate you guys to help
you guys realize that you can get this
too i say it every video you can get
this too and you will get this too if
you really put in the work put in the
hours and you work hard if you want to
weigh 220 and barely be able to jump at
a trampoline park because
all you do is eat and sit around all day
but you could do that because you ain't
got to work a nine to five because you
worked hard now i'm just rambling
anyways we're on our way now to go to
the ultrasound to uh oh my god i'm in a
tray i literally forgot i was in the
trade so we're gonna check on that right
now when i get to the
ultrasound but
um we're gonna go see hopefully if we're
having a boy or girl hopefully we can
tell again she's only 11 weeks and what
three days three days 11 weeks three
days six ounces we'll see how everything
is going when it comes down to the
genitals of the baby all right i'll see
you guys in a few we just pulled up to
the ultrasound tech place um i'm gonna
look at the charts real quick how things
are going and uh yeah all right so price
is moving pretty slow uh we're down six
dollars right now i'm gonna pretty much
just keep watching it as the day goes on
and we'll see how things go
all right let's take a guess boy or girl
boy girl i'm gonna say
girl girl
you said going off the pelvic bone it
would be a girl
all right let me get let me get closer
i'll tell you what it is
it's empty it's a girl we're good
something could pop up a couple days
well it didn't do nothing um couldn't
tell if it was a boy or a girl not 100
sure what we're having uh we gotta wait
till friday to find out thank you guys
for coming along the journey i'm gonna
pretty much just go home and relax i
will come back to you guys when the
trade is actually uh either taking
profit or hitting stop-loss or whatever
the case may be but um the hell's the
engine doing but yeah that's where we're
at i'll see you guys in a little
bit just got home what's up son yeah so
we just had this one right here and
obviously she got another one inside her
so back to back to back to back
to back to back to back in right now um
after this one we're gonna have another
three or four before we stop right we
want nine kids
so we're going for nine kids trying to
beat the the record for forex traders
with kids i'm just i mean i'm just
chilling like trades not moving at all
like literally consolidating all day
hopefully during london session we get
some movements but um at this point it's
like wow this is going to be a lot
harder than i thought gbp knock knock
however you want to say it it's terrible
i'm tired i'm about to knock out get it
you heard that was that good yeah that
was good
anyways i'm going to sleep wake up
learning session and check in on trades
all right so just entered another trade
on gbp not because of spread we're down
already pretty bad just because spread
is just not on our side with this pair
and this is going to be a very hard
challenge to complete here's pretty much
what i'm looking at i'm going to go and
break down on the computer and then
we'll see how it goes obviously it's
already not going great but
that's part of life that's part of
trading and uh yeah let's just let's
just talk about
it i'm going to kind of go over what i'm
looking at on the gp knock as you guys
can see we have a little bit of a
breakout pattern right here for me right
a beautiful breakout break re-test in
this area and then a breakout pattern on
this supply or support zone i should say
sorry i mean now a retest under that
resistance zone all on the one minute
time frame the last trade we took was on
the five minute but um this is gonna be
a one minute setup i really like the
setup i think that it could drop heavy
of course this is gp knock which i'm not
familiar with this is not gj so you know
anything can really happen here but it
looks like it's gonna start to move in
our favor soon hopefully um the only
concern i have here on this trade is
that we already had a beautiful
one-minute breakout pattern this morning
missed it and as you can see it didn't
work out perfectly for i think like
probably 70 pips or so if you held down
to here yeah 70 pips so beautiful
breakout pattern right here that i
missed on the one minute time frame
because we were you know closing the
five minute breakout that we had uh but
as you can see we do have another little
mini pattern coming down here i do i
think you can fall for potentially 70
pips and that'd be really big for the
account it's like another 150 bucks
probably so we'll see how things go with
the spreads being as bad as they are it
is really risky because price could come
up in this area and it could take us out
because of how bad the spreads get
during tokyo session so we'll kind of
just see how things go see how things
play out but as of now i'm going to be
holding this short position for a while
see how things go so we'll see how that
ends up going pretty simple setup i want
to show you guys really quick gj last
night this is what i trade right i'm not
gonna gp not but you know it's part of
the challenge it's exciting it's fun and
i do want to see what we can do on this
spin the wheel challenge you know in the
span of six episodes but what i really
like to trade is gj right now i'm a
master of gj ambassador of gold we have
a break and a retest of the support
slash resistance but we also have a
breakout right we broke out of major
support and we're falling to the
downside this is something i like to see
all the time um this is pretty much the
only way i trade is breakouts as you can
see we have a beautiful breakout here
take profit was hit for like 50 pips um
i set this out in my clarity forex
signals group and as you guys can see
plus 50 pips uh the night before another
plus 50 pips so these are one to five so
i have a 10 pip stop loss 50 pip take
profit and uh we've just been smashing
it like just killing it making people so
much money in this group it's ridiculous
um so you know just just been killing in
the signal room just wanted to kind of
bring that up to you guys if you guys
are ever interested in getting my
signals and making money with me um it's
clarity forex it's an app on the app
store or play store you just type in
clarity forex and then you can actually
get my signals and if you don't want to
pay for the signals there is free
breakdowns free videos and all kinds of
stuff like that on the app for free you
do not have to get signals but they're
there if you want to get signals like
this or
the night before
like this okay so that's pretty much
what i'm doing there other than that i
do want to kind of just keep an eye on
gbp knock and see how things go price is
looking decent we should still see
pretty good droppage here if not well we
take our first loss and we move on to
our third trade pretty much how it goes
with that being said though appreciate
you guys for uh tuning in to this video
hope you guys are enjoying it thus far
and um yeah i'll see you guys in a few
events
it looks like price is going in our
favor however because of spread we are
not up very good i want to show you guys
so that's kind of where we're at as you
can see price did break and it's
continuing to fall down it looks really
good um but again
as you can see due to spread we're not
up as much as we should be right now but
gonna continue to hold and we'll see how
things go we're about to actually head
down to beverly hills rodeo drive and i
want to look at some rolexes and cartier
watches i've always wanted to buy myself
like a 20 like 40 000 you know bust down
all diamond watch so i want to kind of
go look at that been trading like crazy
lately to make a lot of money and i just
feel like you know it's time to reward
myself something different other than a
car so uh we're gonna look at watches
and kind of uh see how today plays out
with this trade and everything else so
stay tuned price is continuing and
continuing to fall is looking uh it's
looking pretty good i'm gonna go ahead
and put my stops to break even here and
uh we're gonna go enjoy our day and just
wait for take profit or obviously stops
to break even to get hit hopefully
obviously hopefully stops don't get hit
but i just want to secure the safety of
the account and make sure that we don't
lose any money today um because we are
up so much price is going in our favor
so much i just uh i want to play it safe
i definitely play the same so i'm gonna
put stops to break even right now and
deal from there we do have stops at
breakeven just below so we don't lose
any money hopefully spreads don't take
us out and hopefully uh price continues
to fall and hopefully you know price
obviously hits or take profit but we'll
see how things go man it's looking
really really good so far i'm just gonna
pay pretty much stay patient and wait
but you know we're gonna take off right
now go look at some jewelry some watches
and um yeah see you guys in a few
[Music]
so
just hit the [\h__\h] door on that [\h__\h]
didn't you i saw you
you hit the door on the wall
and then you hit me in the arm right now
that's crazy that's how you feel just
got back from chase i had to pull out
about you know 30 grand just to be safe
trying to get this watch and i don't
want to have to pay with the card
because then they got to call chase and
uh you know they're probably not going
let me just swipe for 30 000 because
that's pretty rare so we pulled out the
big bucks today and again i never try to
flex on you guys this is pure motivation
you could get this too if you work hard
enough you could get this too that's all
i'm trying to say i'm not trying to like
oh look at this [\h__\h] like i'm not like
that that guy that's like [\h__\h]
no you can get this too i'm motivating
right
okay guys let's get you a
[Laughter]
we'll see you guys when we get to peter
marco
right now we're driving down to pierre
marco in beverly hills so i'm about to
close this out at about a hundred and
twenty dollars but you know um just put
a little profit i'll show you guys the
history tab for the week so far we're up
264 dollars which would be of course 26
on the account
so yeah we're doing pretty well man i
want to go ahead and go get this watch
chill out and then tonight i want to
take our third trade probably during
london session and hopefully we can get
a big boy trying to get like maybe 50 of
the account overall but i'm happy with
the 26 percent that we have grown the
account as of now
um we're doing really well especially
considering we're trading gbp knock
never [\h__\h] heard of that pair so
we're not doing bad we're not doing bad
at all but uh yeah that's kind of where
we're at when i beat you guys on the
first two trades we got one more to go
so let's get to it
fire alarm goes off
[Music]
so this one's on a jubilee band it's
fully iced out face sides of the links
everything it's got an arabic dial
with red enamel
and this is two-tone rose gold stainless
steel
nice okay and this one has a box and
papers as well
oh yeah
i mean how much is that one this one you
say this one for 30 000 that's taking
care of you okay okay that's nice let me
keep looking but that's that's a good
option for sure i just don't know how i
feel about the red in it yeah i was just
gonna say you like the reddish yes
that's the only thing i don't know if i
like the wrap
what about that one so this one is
another example just like this one of a
datejust where it's rose gold and
stainless steel the only difference here
is that it's not an arabic dial it's got
roman numerals and it's in black as
opposed to red okay i like i like that
roman numeral and it's still very iced
out sides of the wings done whole face
okay
that's nice too what size is this this
one specifically is a 40. okay
[Music]
this one's really nice yeah this one's
really nice how much is this over here
this one all under the same price is
this one okay
did you see the video
which one shines harder
how much is this one
how much sounds
[Music]
thank you
gotta hide the cash and the girls purse
when they get they try to come rob you
she can go running and they think i got
the money now she takes the cash all
right trying to get this out
one two three
there's 30 of them big boys right there
yeah for sure appreciate it
show's a rolex by the way
five minutes later
have you been enjoying
no we're done we just need to check
all right guys i just got home really
quick want to show you guys that gp
knock ended up playing out almost all
the way to the t uh we end up taking
profit up in this area sold ourselves
short really bad i mean we could have
took profit down in here and probably
made like another 60 bucks which is
pretty big for the account however uh we
still took what we took i'm happy with
that i'm gonna come back to you guys in
a few i do want to take another trade
tonight before i go to sleep hopefully
we can catch another hopefully two three
hundred dollars i'm gonna up the lot
size a little bit maybe do like a 0.50
instead of 0.30 and um you know see what
we can do but i'll come back to you guys
when i see a setup either on the one or
five in the chart and we'll uh we'll go
over what i'm gonna do what i'm gonna
see and what i'm gonna take made no
sense but i'm tired i'm tired but i've
got to get the rollies up
some something to to motivate me to
continue to work hard because it didn't
pay for itself but not now i gotta uh
gotta get that money back so as you guys
know i'm talking too much i'll see you
guys in a few i'm about to get in a cell
on gp knock um tomorrow morning i'll
actually break down i don't have the
energy to break down nothing right now
super tired tomorrow morning i will
break down the trade how it went and
we'll see where our counts at whether it
was positive or negative and we'll do a
full breakdown on the trade it's a
pretty decent setup so um i think it's
gonna go good but
hey are you doing crazy
huh storm
storm
you're going to sleep now you can't go
to sleep now all right well that's what
i have to deal with tonight so yeah i'll
see you guys in the morning we'll see
how things went
the next day all right guys so i'm just
waking up in the morning um trades going
uh good i'm gonna close it here i'm
gonna explain why in a second uh so
we're gonna close here at 313
dollars
all right and um you know great trade
right is a great trade we're at 57 on
the account super good 312 but um i want
to show you guys why i don't sound too
happy about it so let's kind of go over
really quick so as you guys can see we
had a nice break of a trendline and then
a break of a support zone so it's a nice
breakout trade however i fell asleep
take profit was so close did not close
did not move stops to break even do none
of that and um missed out on potentially
a six or seven hundred dollar move and
that's why we're only closing at 300
bucks so a little bit depressing i'm
gonna break down this trade for you guys
show you guys where it went right where
i kind of went wrong and how i secured
300 but obviously lost you know we're
left on the table another 300 which is
kind of depressing but it's still fine
it's still good trade a good win and as
you guys can see back to back beautiful
sell positions on this pair we didn't
hold the first trade obviously you guys
saw i closed out early on that as well
so back to back two trades that i lost
out not lost but kind of just left a lot
on the table kind of sad kind of sucks
but there's still good wins they're
still great wins i just definitely
should have uh won a lot more we'll
break it down we'll talk about it and
we'll see where we ended up this week
and where we are and how next week's
gonna go looking at the actual you know
wins for this week we took all cells as
you guys can see we obviously deposited
the thousand dollars we made 148 120 and
then 312 we doubled the lot size on that
so each trade was really around the same
amount of pips caught um you know i do
want to say one benefit that i think
that i had this week is because
obviously i trade the gp jpy a lot
especially that in gold so you know
trading gp jpy my main account plus
watching gp knock move it's very similar
in the sense that you know gbp was very
bearish this week like bearish as [\h__\h]
so as gdp kept coming down gp knock was
also coming down so i was able to take
similar if not the same type of setups
coming down to the short side and that's
why you see we took all sales so
me being the actual you know dedicated
slash professional whatever you want to
call it traitor that i am um i'm able to
realize these things in the markets and
it's going to help us along the way with
this journey there it is that's episode
one i'm gonna actually break down this
trade for you guys real quick to end it
but we are up about 50 on the account we
almost not doubled but we got close to
doubling the account halfway there um
just in one episode trading some
[\h__\h] pair i've never traded and only
having three trades so hopefully next
week we obviously can get a better spent
maybe uh 48 hours or five or the whole
week actually and a better pair
especially like nasdaq or something we
can really grow the account or lose the
entire account of course because these
things happen but um you know we'll see
how things go but i want to actually
break this down for you guys and show
you guys exactly what i saw on this
trade looking at the trademark obviously
the trade last night uh or the not
traded last night and trade yesterday on
the one minute time frame ended up
working out perfectly of course like i
said we ended up closing up in this area
could have closed way down here so
that's unfortunate but we're looking at
a five minute setup here on uh gp knock
last night it was a pretty simple setup
so if i actually put this into replay
mode i could break this down better for
you guys but what i originally had saw
obviously we had support in this area
but again we have a trend line that had
formed on the five minute chart right
here if this trendline broke it's a
breakout trade and it's gonna come to
the downside in my eyes right and i'm
gonna have my stops slightly above price
did break obviously i didn't enter on
this candle i entered as it was moving
as it was breaking i like to get in
pre-breakout before it's actually broken
out but it's still coming down and it's
starting to come out that's what i'm
going to get in took my sale position in
this area and then price closed here the
price closer so let's just put our stops
way up here i mean it's kind of high but
still i wanted to target really low on
this and unfortunately obviously uh we
didn't reach that and you'll see that in
a minute but you know this is still a
good one to seven wrist reward trade and
we ended up closing at like a one to
four so still a really good trade um but
you know one thing for me in this trade
i wanted more confluence i wanted to see
price close below this support to really
say okay i can go to sleep i'm happy
with this trade it's probably not going
to reverse on me boom price continued
down that's kind of like creating
support right there so i wouldn't
consider that a break yet but you know
price did reject that was a little scary
but came back to the breakout zone
happens very often you're gonna see this
all the time i talk about this in a lot
of my videos but um price will come back
to your breakout zone and then continue
down you can actually re-enter on this
sometimes if you want to actually make
more profits but as you guys can see
price created more support and then
eventually we did have that beautiful
candle that did break below which
indicated that price was going to flood
because now we broke below that trend
that i have here this trend line plus
the support zone meaning price most
likely will plummet and that's exactly
what price did it literally uh plummeted
hard
didn't hit my take profit though that
i'm so upset about that oh my god even
watching it right here is very very
upsetting and then we end up taking
profit just about there so overall i
mean that's just unfortunate what is
that it's a one to three point nine
still we still closed at about a one to
four but oh my god that freaking
hurts that tremendously
uh just
hurt
bad so that's unfortunate with that
being said man i appreciate you guys for
coming along this journey this is gonna
be a really fun and exciting challenge
and i want to just keep killing it try
to grow as much as i can and see how we
can finish off season one within the
first six episodes or within six
episodes because that is season one um
if you enjoyed it please leave a like
comment down below if you guys are
enjoying this and you really want to see
more so i know and i can keep getting
this out i appreciate you guys i love
you guys i am tired gassed out from
training this crazy pair and i'm gonna
go ahead and see you guys in the next
episode peace