today we are talking about my Platinum
trade that got me to a 100k this year oh
we got a lot to talk about so first
things first this was a $24,000 trade
amazing I love that for me I closed
early this could have been a $50,000
trade that would have been my record
trade here's the thing we've got
psychology involved here I closed that
trade because I knew exactly how much it
was going to take to get me to 100k this
year that was all I was looking for I
wanted to be able to hop onto YouTube be
like hi guys I'm at $100,000 for the
year it's only April 30th how cool I've
only placed six trades I'm I'm amazing
I'm I'm the best I'm so cool I'm amazing
blah blah blah okay but here's the thing
I didn't trade based on my strategy I
simply just wanted to get on here and
tell you guys that I'm up 100K and
that's not okay that's not good for my
trading that's not good for my students
they can't replicate this I I closed a
trade purely based on just what price
was at so that I could hit that 100K
Mark now profit is profit that's amazing
I cannot complain about
$224,000 trade that's incredible not
many Traders can even do that not many
Traders are even in a position where
they can trade 20 contracts of platinum
to make $24,000 in like 3 days but I I
didn't trade based on the the strategy
so if we look at it over here you guys
can see entry of platinum right here was
at 92.8 20 contracts long I've got a
safety line right here so risk is on the
other side of the safety line we've got
higher risk initially and then as price
progressed we we were able to cut that
risk in half so then the risk just
trailed along the other side of this
upward trend line and we're feeling good
we're up you know about 12 13 14 15ish
it came back to break even ooh didn't
like that but I'm holding and I'm fine
and I'm comfortable and I'm used to that
and then price came up oh my gosh I'm
looking at at at 9:00 in the morning I'm
up 24,000 and then boom we closed at
9451 20 contracts sold and then I got to
continue to watch that go higher and
higher and higher and higher and it just
ate at me it was such a crummy feeling
like the amount of fomo that I'm getting
I'm kicking myself I'm like giving
myself bad selft talk it's just like
it's a lot of things were happening I I
didn't have a very good day that day one
I I missed out on a possible record
trade of you know $40 to $50,000 and
then two I just I didn't follow the
strategy so I put myself in the perfect
position look at that entry I'm talking
like sniper entry that could not have
been more perfect we had a break of a
downward trend line let me replicate it
we got point a here at that last high
point B down here at this 928 we got a
break of this downward trend line it it
couldn't have been more perfect and then
even more so we had a break of a trend
line before right here I didn't take it
now that could be intuition why did I
not take that one that wasn't the one
that wasn't the move that wasn't the
break it very well could be because I'm
just I'm watching Platinum I I know
Platinum so well I just I didn't take
this trade I didn't feel good about
about this downward trend line one
because it had just it had continued to
be broken we've got we thought this was
point B it broke we thought this was
point B it broke I just wasn't convinced
by this last time I said this is the one
took that long position it was an
excellent entry I mean congratulations
good job Tor you did it the exit was not
was not pretty that wasn't cute honey
try again let's do this let's do this
better next time let's stay in for the
entirety of the move like you always
talk about I'm working on it still you
guys get to see an inside look a Trader
who's been doing this for 9 years yes I
made the transition from day trading to
swing trading yes I'm trading bigger
positions so the dollar amount is
getting to me a little bit more than it
usually does so these are the things
that I'm working through I want you guys
to see from the other side what this is
like maybe a lot of Traders don't talk
about this or the struggles that they
have even trading for so long but this
was something that I it really took a
toll on me this was daunting this was
tough to feel and experience that fomo
of closing a trade early to not follow
the strategy to have a perfect entry and
then see the exit not be perfect it was
just it was a tricky one this felt like
a loss to be honest it was a $24,000 win
but it felt like a loss it took that
much of a toll on me so these are some
things that I struggle that I'm working
through but it got me to 100k this year
yay love that for me that was fun that
was cool but I mean I've got a goal of
200k this year so I'm if I had been able
to hold like my strategy told me I'd
actually still be in this there's a
possibility this could be this could be
a wild trade and this is why I love my
strategy so much is because it puts me
in position for these crazy moves and
instead I clipped out early and was like
no I'm done can't I want to get to 100k
this is just kind of me venting to you
guys expressing the the struggles that I
go through the psychology that's so
heavily involved in trading outside of
just the strategy the strategy got me
the entry and the strategy would have me
still in this trade but tor's psychology
ended up closing so let me know if you
guys have experienced something like
this when you're scaling up in positions
or when you're learning a new strategy
or you're making transitions to
different time frames do you find
yourself just like getting so frustrated
with not beautiful entries not beautiful
exits and you've got to just sit in it
and be not happy with yourself let me
know in the comments if you guys
experiened very similar things if not
I'm glad I could shed a light on it cuz
this is what it's like but thank you
guys for watching if you have not yet
hit the Subscribe button hit the like
button drop a comment and don't forget
to hit the bell for notifications I will
see you guys in the next video