what is my strategy what is the secret
sauce it is incredibly simple it is
Elementary if you will I truly just
trade with trend lines and some support
and resistance the trend lines are going
to be the meat of the strategy the
support and resistance gives me just
some added confirmation some added
confidence about my positions so let's
get into how I would get into a trade
based on my
strategy I always use trend lines I'm
going to come in with one touch point
two touch points here and this is
platinum this is a great example
Platinum has been just respecting these
trend lines to a te absolutely beautiful
price action here we've got one two
three almost four touch points here on
this upward trend line I would get into
this position only because the trend
line was broken so we'll just say for
example purposes we've got one two three
touch points on this downward trend line
three touch points on this downward
trend line and then boom we've got a
break of a trend I would take a long
position here now we are following up
we're going up up up up up I would stay
in this position for as long as the
trend is happening so a lot of people
will ask me where do my take profits go
when I get into a position I don't know
how long the price is going to Trend in
this direction for I don't actually have
takeprofit so when I get into my
position I'm truly just trying to stay
in for the entirety of the move the
entirety of the trend and my indication
for when it is no longer trending in
that direction is when price breaks that
Trend so the price of platinum was
trending upward along this line from
December 7th all the way until January
2nd did I know January 2nd was going to
be the day that Platinum no longer
trended up I don't no so I will close my
position and take my profit when the
price of platinum is no longer trending
along the current Trend that I'm in this
is also an excellent place for an
entry closing my position or even
considering reversing my position now
let's look for another downward trend
I'm going to take this downward trend
line we've got point a and point B here
now this is another Trend where we've
got one two three four touch points here
excellent four touch points I'll take it
all day we had a break of an upward
trend line now we've got a new downward
trend line let's try to stay in for the
entirety of this move the entirety of
this trend did I know that the price of
platinum was going to Trend down from
January 2nd all the way to January 18th
no so when when I get into this short
position I get into it allowing the
trend to play out for its entirety I
don't know how long it's going to Trend
along it but I want to stay in for as
long as I can I want to collect as much
profit as I can now I'll never reach
these highs and these lows but I will be
able to get at least the meat of the
trend I'll be able to get in for the
majority of that price movement the
majority of that Trend what gets me in
and what gets me out is going to be the
trend line so what got me into this
short position was the break of an
upward Trend now I'm in a short position
what's going to keep me in this trade if
price can continue along the downward
Trend that it is now following along I'm
going to stay in so you can think of
this downward trend line as my trailing
stop if the price continues along this
downward Trend I am going to stay in
this trade but as soon as it breaks
which it did here on January 18th I am
closing my position and taking my
profits that is essentially my strategy
in a nutshell so thanks for tuning in
and I will see you guys next time