if you guys know the eclipse is coming
up soon so I figured this is an
excellent time to use the moonphase
indicator which I'm going to be honest
with y'all is a big fat load of
I'm just kidding to be honest I really
wanted to try
this this is the trade this is platinum
we're looking at a 4-Hour time frame
some of you guys if you don't know my
strategy maybe this looks like a little
bit of a laser show to you if you guys
do know my strategy and you do know that
I trade with trend lines and areas of
support and resistance then you
understand what this looks like all of
the red trend lines are where I try to
find downward Trends the green trend
lines are upward Trends bullish or
bearish I'm trying to figure out which
one the price is actually going to
follow so you can see entry is here at
this blue arrow I got in at
98.7 20 contracts yes I realize that is
a hefty position I am at a point in my
trading career now where I can buy 20
contracts very cool I've been trading
for 9 years now I have made the
transition from day trading to swing
trading as well well so now I'm going on
year two this is the second year of
being a swing Trader and wow it's
incredible let's talk about why I
entered this position first things first
what you need to do is go to indicators
and what we're going to do is turn on
the moon phases if you guys know the
eclipse is coming up soon so I figured
this is an excellent time to use the
moonphase indicator I have to
incorporate two things into my strategy
one if we're incorporating the moon
phases which I'm gonna be honest with
y'all is a big fat load of I'm
just kidding to be honest I really
wanted to try this I truly experimented
with the moon phases I kid you not in
this trade I'm like you know what I've
always made fun of you know different
indicators and different ways to trade
and different strategies how hilarious
would it be coming up on the eclipse
coming up on the moonphase indicator if
I could place a trade that coincides
with both aspects my trend line trading
strategy and the phases of the moon and
here we are we're looking at my record
trade to date Point Blank period both of
these came into play both of these
played a role in this trade it's
ridiculous now we can go back and retest
and be like listen let's back test and
see it didn't really work here didn't
really work here didn't really work here
so you can see many times in the past
where it didn't work did work over here
did work here so it's just it's comical
let's go back to at least this one right
here we've got buy signals here coolest
thing ever is I'm not getting into a
trade unless a trend line is broken so
even if this Moon indicator is telling
me now is the time to buy get in the
moons are aligning the stars have
aligned do it I still need my own
strategy to tell me when to get in this
just so happens to be both case scenario
where I got double confirmation from the
literal Moon out in outer space saying
you know what somehow this moon has
something to do with these charts so
it'll put on the chart the day of the
waning or waxing moon or the new moon or
full moon I'm not sure which one of the
two to be honest these are I did take
this position over here to go long so
let's talk about why my arrow or why my
position over here is on the 26th and
not when it broke here on the 25th so I
made a rookie mistake on the 25th last
week I got into my position one I'm just
very excited to make content talking
about the moon phases indicator and the
solar eclipse coming up and how I
already kind of poke fun at the
different types of strategies there are
out there because it's endless and how
you can truly become profitable with
many different strategies so I was just
really excited about this trade so I got
into the wrong contract I got into
Platinum but I got into the contract
that was expiring maybe within one or
two days but I got into the contract
that was getting ready to expire come on
Tori you can't be making mistakes like
that I really beat myself up about it I
also hadn't traded for almost all of
March I had closed a trade at the
beginning of March and then we're
looking at the very end of March now and
I'd only placed one trade so I was just
feeling really I was putting a lot of
pressure on placing a trade I was
excited about content I really beat
myself up about it I was really bummed
that I got into a contract that's
getting ready to expire like I should I
should know by now I shouldn't be making
rookie mistakes like that that was
something that I I was bummed about and
it messed up my I'm so overly concerned
about the the stats of my trading to
share with you guys because I want it to
be so aesthetic and so perfect so
amazing and to have to close a position
and then re-enter with you know plus or
minus this tiny little profit it just
messes everything up so now my win
percentage is messed up I shouldn't let
these things affect me there's so many
things that are coming into play that I
need to clear out and clean up and just
focus on the trade itself you know bring
it back to square one and just
understand that yes you are an
influencer you are an educator you are
an entrepreneur but I'm also a Trader
and I need to be the best at that so we
can't be making rookie mistakes like
that I beat myself up about it I had to
close that position with a $22,000 loss
and then re-enter on the current trading
contract long story short that is why
you won't see the position here you'll
see the open position here a few days
later I had to take a little loss when I
got into my long position here pulled
back about 2,000 bucks closed it and
then had to re-enter a few days later
here that is why you'll see the entry
looks a little bit late best case
scenario everything went according to
plan I didn't mess up I didn't goof
entry would be here on this break of the
downward trend line so you guys will ask
what qualifies as an entry and it is a
break of a trend line also with that
being said I truly have to be convinced
that this thing is breaking the trend
line it can't just touch the trend line
it can't just peek out of the trend line
like I have to truly have conviction
that the price is changing direction is
breaking out of the current Trend it's
been following along now I'm in a 4-Hour
time frame so I've got plenty of time to
get that conviction or to be convinced
to wait a few hours until I'm really
convinced this thing is going absolutely
qualifies for an entry now on Lower time
frames that might be a totally different
story maybe waiting for the candle to
close or a retest there's other things
that can qualify as a good entry on the
lower time frames but on the 4-Hour time
frames this is my heads space entry is
here at 98.7 20 contracts in Platinum we
had a wild ride what an interesting few
let's see when did we get in on March
26th Tuesday wow how long was I in this
so I was in this just about over a week
so this seems to be still the average of
my hold time all this year is About a
Week a week in a day a week minus a day
plus or minus that's been my average
whole time all this year we enter our
position we're going to say it
constitutes for back here in my original
position but I got in late it is what it
is or I I made that mistake of entering
my position at not the right contract
entry is the break of a trend line we're
thinking long positions we're feeling
good and then boom we got a snap back
all the way to my safety line if you
guys have watched my live streams my
Instagram reels or any of my strategy
videos you understand that I have an
action line and a safety Line This
upward green line was the line keeping
me safe it pulled all the way to it and
literally kissed the freaking trend line
I I was a little bit nervous I was
sweating a little bit it came right to
it I'm like if this breaks my safety
line I have to solidify this freaking
loss it's going to be the first loss of
the year I'm like all right getting
ready to have to stomach the loss here
we go and then it turns around I'm like
oh man if you guys can relate to that
sense of relief when price starts coming
back in your favor it's like you have a
good day again now you can talk to
people you're feeling good it's quite a
funny sensation oh my gosh so came right
to the trend line right to the safety
line kissed it and then turned around
we're feeling relief now we've got about
2 3 4 four five 4our candles go by and
then we get another snapd down very
close to the trend line again feeling
the heat getting a little sweaty again
and then turns around okay now I'm
feeling good the sense of relief is
there I'm really thinking this thing is
going confidence is there I'm posting
screenshots all over the place yeah
still in my trade still feeling good it
stayed above my safety line I had no
reason to close it and then we get a
news day and then it snaps down we got
another snap now this time it happened
much quicker we've got two 4our candles
where that thing just did nothing but
completely retraced race and yet again
for a one I mean we'll talk about here 1
2 3 4 a fifth touch point when I tell
you guys how much I love Platinum I
cannot express it enough my strategy is
a trend line trading strategy and to see
Platinum respect these trend lines it
just does something to me it is the
freaking coolest thing it truly respects
these trend lines to a t not two touch
points not three touch points we're
getting like five freaking touch points
on trend lines here and then when it
breaks the trend lines it just goes it's
just I cannot Rave enough about it how
much I love Platinum Platinum I think
today we're going to go ahead and
solidify it right here April 3rd at 3:33
p.m. you can see it here on the chart on
the screen share it's official Platinum
is my new favorite oil I'm sorry I love
you my guy but Platinum is my main man
now oh my God Platinum I love it jeez
it's incredible so anyways we've got one
two three four five touch points when it
pulled back here I got very nervous the
nervousness never goes away nobody loves
taking a loss like yes I understood the
loss that I was going to have to take I
understood where my loss was going to be
if it didn't work out so I knew where it
was going to happen and when it was
going to happen and if it happened but
it's still never fun so I'm sweating
I've got my cousin Lauren texting me
like are you still in your trade and
she's in a trade and I'm like yes I'm
still in I'm in draw down but yes I'm
still in it I've got some other students
you know showing their trades too and
I'm still holding I've got no reason to
close but man was I sweating when it
kissed it for a fifth time on this trend
line and then that immediate sense of
relief and then it goes away then price
is turning around okay we're back to
this area of resistance where it has
finally broken we really thought it
broke here and then snapped back then it
finally just took it out as if this
921.6kbps
line I didn't draw until just this
morning at like 5:00 in the morning I
finally got a solid point a a solid
point B A very convincing area where the
price came up pulled back and then
continued in that same direction I was
very confident in this point B here when
it did show me okay we've got a pullback
and now we're continuing those pullbacks
I always feel like I need to wait for
and be much more patient for in the
4-Hour time frame I'm not ever inclined
to really draw very steep trend lines in
the 4 Hour that just don't make sense to
me this one is too steep here I wouldn't
have drawn that I truly am waiting for
the price to give me a much clearer
price looked like it was turning around
and then continued in that direction and
same for over here over here if I had
entered when the very steep trend line
was crossed that would have been the
greatest time to get in some of my
students took that trade they got in to
a long position right there good for you
guys amazing now for some of you guys I
don't know if you've continued to hold
through all of this but if you did
amazing good job wow I did not I wasn't
convinced enough on this trend line I
waited for a better area where price
came up and then started rolling back
back over and then gave me a much more
convincing point B point a point B two
touch points then entered on that break
that was my thinking on the trend line
placement the touch points of the trend
lines the pullbacks now so here we are
making a third touch point on a much
higher time frame downward trend line
and I'm thinking okay this might
actually roll over and it didn't just
this morning 5:00 in the morning that
thing just continued up okay so now
let's talk about the trade the numbers
I'm up a record amount only by like
1,000 bucks like maybe $1,300 am I now
officially up my record amount so my
previous trade I believe was $29,500 I'm
currently up we'll say we're going back
in time about just a few hours ago
currently up $30,000 $300 I'm wrestling
with it man oh I'm wrestling with it I'm
thinking do I call my uncle to help me
kind of talk through this I send some
messages to some other Trader friends
that are a little bit more even more so
experienced than I am or just they have
more experience with these larger
position sizes so I'm just I'm kind of
seeking advice and luckily I didn't get
any today so I think that's I think
that's for the best I made this decision
on my own I'm just struggling with it I
should still be in this the entry was by
the book textbook trade on my strategy
the exit was not I should still be in
this trade I should be in this trade
Until It Breaks this upward green trend
line which is now my new safety line
which is where my profit will now Trail
along my stop- loss will now be in
profit and it will Trail along this I'm
just feeling a little bit of fomo right
now the price is at 952 I got out at
9.48 these are true real real raw
motions I'm happy that I closed another
record trade that's really freaking cool
so far I've got four trades total now
we'll say technically five technically
five because I made a freaking rookie
mistake and got into the wrong contract
for platinum and had a $2,000 loss and
had to re-enter but we're going to say
if I hadn't made that mistake we're
looking at four trades for the year it's
April 100% win rate is what it should
have been but here we are I messed it up
with that stupid freaking trade which is
driving me crazy what a crazy day it's
an interesting day at first I was very
anti-climatic there wasn't much emotion
going on okay okay this is me processing
the emotions right now as we
speak I feel a little bit sick to my
stomach I wish I hadn't closed it maybe
let's let's talk about the wins let's
talk about the pros profit is profit a
record trade is a record trade congrats
Tori Dude That's so exciting future me
watching this video is going to be so
proud this is cool we've got four trades
for the year it's so cool that I can
count how many trades I've placed on my
hand and remember every single one of
them this is wild first trade of the
year it was in Platinum $10,000 second
trade of the year in Platinum $30,000
third trade of the Year oil $10,000
fourth trade of the Year Platinum
$30,000 so this is where we're at let's
um show a little bit of numbers here oh
and then also don't forget at the
beginning of the year the very beginning
of March when I closed my third trade I
went ahead and withdrew $50,000 I
withdrew everything that I had made for
the year already so far I was like you
know what you're doing great let's go
ahead and pay ourselves let's do the
biggest withdrawal we've ever done a lot
of Records here we're doing a lot of
things that we've never done before so
now the account size was down 50 and now
we're building it back up we've got
another 30 in here so it's just it's
very cool it's very cool man it's cool
I'm excited now so here we go you have
made it to the end of this video the
realized profit and loss for this one
trade in Platinum 20 contracts held for
a week and a day we're looking at
$3,138 it's pretty freaking cool so I
hope my explaining of the strategy made
sense to you guys the entry the exit we
all know wasn't according to the
strategy one last little tidbit or one
last little thing that I'm experiencing
specifically in my strategy is my exits
this year are becoming more dependent on
the money and not the strategy and I
think it's because I'm putting so much
emphasis on these personal bests these
record trades these bigger positions so
I am closing much more often because I'm
up x amount I think that's what I need
to work on Q2 we got to stop looking at
the dollar amount honey you're doing
great entries are amazing exits amazing
profit is profit but now let's stick to
the strategy even more so let's truly
hold these guys for as long as they're
supposed to run let's stay in for the
entirety of the trend like you always
talk about do as you preach that's what
I'm going to be working on for Q2 less
looking at the numbers that is going to
be huge for me and Q2 let's get rid of
the dollar amounts and just trade purely
based on the strategy I hope you guys
enjoyed this video what a cool freaking
Journey that you guys get to be on with
me if you have not already subscribed
hit the Subscribe button because there's
going to be so much bigger trades to
come so much bigger goals to hit you
want to be here for this journey so hit
the like button drop a comment and share
this video thanks thank so much for
watching guys I will see you on the next
video