this was the year I moved to a 4-Hour
time frame just so that you can see all
of the red days here I couldn't even
imagine $100,000 trades these guys are
making stupid amounts of money just a
lot of things that came into 2023 we've
got backto back win win win win profit
profit 100% win rate just excellent
execution I knew this was going to be my
last month trading I had students
counting on me looking at every trade I
placed okay I still see some red we
ended
up you have
waited a very long time for this you've
waited three months for this and I have
promised you guys that we would do a
full breakdown of my entire year of
trading in 2023 and here we are it's
official we're doing it it's happening
today oh my God it's happening it took
me a little while to finally get all of
my data in one place if you guys have
used trade Zella before it's incredibly
intuitive it will automatically sync
with your broker you don't have to input
any trades the only push back that I had
was when you sing trade zow a trade
station it gives you 6 months of data so
I had to manually import the previous 6
months before that we've figured it out
we've got January 1st all the way to
December 31st we're going to go through
every trade I'm going to try to remember
the emotions that I had the mistakes
that I made going through each one of
these months to the best of my ability
for the most part you guys have hard
numbers trade expectancy profit Factor
trade win percentage we got the average
win to loss so everything that you guys
want to see about the strategy that I
use is here we got the whole N9 yard now
one thing to keep in mind is this was an
experimental year with a new time frame
I made the transition from I guess
officially day trader to swing Trader
this was the year 2023 so you'll see the
struggles that I had with it kind of
making the transition into it getting
comfortable with it truly actually
staying in the 4-Hour time frame so
you'll be able to see everything in this
breakdown but just remember keep that in
mind uh the beginning of the year was a
little bit tricky getting a handle on
the 4-Hour time frame so most of my
trading career was in the 5 minute time
frame and the 1 hour time frame this was
the year I moved to a 4our hour time
frame let's go ahead and dive right into
the very first month okay let's look at
the numbers just for January so we're
looking at the net p&l here I lost
$6,295 in January what a awful start to
the year what an awful start to swing
trading what an awful start to me
sharing my journey on social media that
I get to show you guys wow I lost six
grand in January I didn't trade
correctly and I kept moving from the 4
Hour to the 1 hour I was placing too
many trades I was getting freaked out by
holding so long I would close a loss
early I would take profit at only $178
so you can see I truly struggled with
this new time frame we've got a lot of
red here a lot of red we've got a
somehow a win percentage of 20 we've got
then average win to loss is 1.38 you
guys can see all the stats here but
regardless we'll just count January as a
dudy it was an extremely excruciating
month I was wrestling with just trying
to stay in the 4-Hour time frame now
let's move to February let's go ahead
and change our date range from February
1st 1 to February 28th okay we made our
loss back we're in panic mode I think
when you take a big loss like that
especially the beginning of the year
with all this excitement and goals like
I went into overdrive overtime and I
just I really went inward thank gosh I
made the loss back that's a start so we
ended February with
$873 and we we got less trades I'm doing
something right I'm heading in the right
direction we got a few $3,000 trades we
got a $3,000 loss $1,000 Win $5,000 win
and then you guys can see to the left
here these are all the trades I had
quite the variety of symbols here I
traded oil the NQ the ym gold and the es
wow I'm going be honest you guys I don't
even remember trading all those indices
but I guess I did I was experimenting
maybe I was trying to find my sweet spot
with swing trading but as you can see
oil ended up being my best trade anyways
I made five grand in oil now we're going
to go from January February March let's
see my Improvement for March March 1st
to March
31st all right what are we looking at
here okay I still see some red okay we
made 2,000 so we're we're making
progress here we're still in the green
and we've got even still less trades I'm
still working on that time frame I only
made three trades I think we can
consider ourselves a swing Trader at
this point we've made three trades in
the whole month we are sticking to the
4-Hour time frame and now I remember in
March this is quite exciting I can see
this $110,000 trade that was my record
trade I came out of the month with only
2,000 so yes I had a record trade I
remember being excited talked about it
on social media and then 2,000 at the
end of the month but I remember just
being able to hold for $10,000 was such
a milestone 10 grand was exciting I
remember I closed it early and this was
the one where I talked about how my
family had convinced me to close it
early cuz they're like oh my God you're
up 10,000 that's plenty take it and I
did this could have been 20 but it is
what it is could have should have would
have the fact that I was able to hold
for 10,000 was just something to be
proud of we're still in the green we're
still continuing to to master that time
frame now let's go to April April 1st to
April 30th ooh all right we had another
hard month another $6,000 loss we've got
I'd say still a significant amount of
Trades so it looks like maybe I got
ahead of myself maybe we're looking at
only two symbols so I traded gold and I
traded oil took some significant losses
in gold gold is where I I dwindled that
profit down we took a $4,000 loss in
gold on the 27th at the end of the month
my headp space I can't quite remember in
April I'll be honest with you guys I
think I was in panic mode I'm sharing
you know this journey with you guys and
then I have to show another $6,000 loss
I feel like maybe I shut it out can't
recall my mindset in April but I can
tell it was probably not the best one
looks like we may be relapsed a little
bit with the higher time frames let's go
to the next month and see if there was
any improvements so let's go to May May
1st to May 31st all right so we're we're
on the up and up there there seems to be
a trend here when I take a hard month a
hard loss month I seem to just double
down and really just turn things on go
inward so we ended May with a $20,000
profit for the month so we're in a 4.38
profit Factor 83.33% win percentage so
we're we're feeling good we still got a
fairly significant amount of Trades they
look fairly spaced out so I would say I
probably still stuck to the 4-Hour time
frame but maybe I got ahead of myself
Let's see we only traded two symbols
crude oil and gold I'm going to be
honest with you guys I didn't realize I
traded gold so much last year crude oil
I made 7,000 lost it then I made 5,000
in crude oil we're done with crude oil
for the month then I picked back up to
Gold I made 2,000 I made 2,000 I made
8,000 I think I remember remember these
last two trades and I'm almost certain I
went back to a 1 hour time frame I don't
know what to tell you guys it's making
that transition I'm just used to that 1
hour in that five minute I've spent most
of my entire trading career we're
talking like five years six years of
just that time frame and maybe in case
you guys are trying to make that
transition yourself just be prepared
you're going to have a few times where
you go back to the lower time frames but
if you can just stay at that higher time
frame you guys will be able to see there
is truly only an upward side there's
only benefit to that I reap the benefits
of truly staying in for the swing
trading staying in for the moves you
guys will be able to see that as we kind
of walk back through an overview of the
entire year as we move on from these
month-to-month overviews but you'll see
that kind of net profit and loss let's
see May June before we even move to June
this was the FX Summit just so many
things there's so much that plays a role
in your trading and it's cool to kind of
go back and be like oh I remember the
mindset I was in here or coming back
from a $6,000 loss for the month and
then coming back with 20K all right I'm
sure we're feeling good we're probably
feeling a little cocky let's see June
June 1st to June 30th
all right we are down 7even Grand and
we've got a record loss here we've got a
loss of
7,834 I had one great trade right before
I went to the FX Summit I remember this
one it was easy I made six grand right
off the bat on the 8th of June we're
feeling good we're getting ready to go
to the summit I'm like okay this is
awesome right after the summit I take
$1,000 loss followed by a $3,000 loss
why did I take such a big loss that was
a record loss at the time and let me
kind of break it down I'm hanging out
with a lot of these influencers who have
been trading for close to about the same
amount of time as I have and just to see
the level that they're at compared to
the level that I'm at I couldn't even
imagine $100,000 trades these guys are
making stupid amounts of money I get to
see them on stage I had the opportunity
to moderate and ask some questions of
these guys that have been making stupid
amounts of money on markets I got done
with the summit and found myself
comparing just a little too much and you
can see this is a direct result I
believe I remember I went heavy in this
position this was more of a hope trade I
didn't follow the strategy there was an
exit point where I needed to close it
but I didn't just going back and
realizing okay June I remember was tough
I compared myself to others and I traded
based on hope not the strategy and
that's where it gets you and it was also
the NQ so now we can see there's at
least less instruments that I'm trading
um we've got the NQ and we've got CL oil
here so those were the two that I traded
for June let's move on keep going
through the year we've got July let's
see what July has to to offer all right
July yet again we're back with a $23,000
profit and we've got another record
trade here on the 12th of July
$21,000 so not only did I you know hit
another Milestone but I doubled my last
one how freaking cool that okay sure
like it would have been cool to make
$111,000 profit or $155,000 instead I
just completely doubled it it's very
interesting to go back and see the
numbers and compare it to the mindset
that I was in I tend to be incredible
when it comes to having to work in like
panic mode there was a lot of things
that came into play in 2023 I made the
transition from day trading swing
trading I also was much more prominent
on social media so now I am sharing this
journey I'm sharing my trades I've got
everything I'm doing under a microscope
the amount of pressure it almost broke
me I had never had a massive audience
putting a magnifying glass on every
single trade I placed the pressure was
on so every time I ended the month in
the red I had to come back just twice as
good it was a lot of pressure and I've
got people counting on me I've got
people that I'm inspiring it was hard
just a lot of things that came into 2023
now we're in 2024 the pressure is off I
feel like I'm used to social media
picking apart my trades I'm so much more
confident in the 4-Hour time frame 2023
was just a year of experimenting a year
of new things I'm thankful for all of it
let's keep going through we've got a few
more months and then we'll just do that
quick overview let's do August August is
my birth month let's see if that shows
in my trading okay it does I kept up
that 20,000 so we didn't have to double
down and come back harder because I took
a loss for the month we continued that
$220,000 month so now we've got another
consecutive $22,000 profit and 100% win
rate absolutely shows that that was my
birth month we are on our a game we've
got 1 two three four five trades total
for the month still a swing Trader still
staying in that 4-Hour time frame and
we've got backto back win win win win
profit profit 100% win rate excellent
execution congratulations Tori good job
so we got the very first trade on the
second right out the bat we got a $6,000
profit in it is crude oil then we got
Platinum this might be the first month
that I started getting back into
Platinum so August we've got crude oil
and platinum I only placed one trade in
Platinum I was kind of Dipping my feet
back in to see I always want to make
sure that I have a relationship
developed and built with whatever
instrument I'm getting ready to trade
the fact that I was confident enough to
place this trade means a lot we got
$6,000 profit $2,000 $7,000 4,000 2,000
so we're just win after wi we're feeling
good we're hitting it we're we're in the
time frame we're in the groove let's
move to September to September 30th ooh
H all right not good I think we took
another red month all right we've got a
$166,000 loss for September I'm trying
to you know go back and see was my
confidence too high did I start coming
into heavy on positions there's a lot
that probably played into my loss in
September but wow I'm going to be honest
with yall I shut that one out I I don't
remember that all right so we've got on
the first we made okay we had a nice
little $1,000 trade in Platinum feeling
good and then it looks like on the 11th
we took a $4,000 loss in oil and then we
took a
$113,000 loss in oil all right we had to
solidify a loss there this might have
been at the end of one of my
accelerators if I can see how many
contracts let's see if I went in way too
heavy in this position we went short six
contracts that's not wild we'll have to
save this one for a breakdown more in
depth specifically on this trade because
there's a lot that I want to dissect
about this did I go too heavy did I hold
this loss too long did I trade at all
according to the strategy so this one I
want to dissect a lot later all right
we'll go back and go to the next month
October I remember was my next
accelerator okay here we go back on our
a game I wonder if I didn't have anyone
holding me accountable in September I
wonder if I didn't do an accelerator
this was me trying to maybe experiment
it's a fascinating one but I I know for
sure October I had students counting on
me looking at every trade I placed
everything had to be done by the book
when I do my accelerators I can't teach
if if I just happen to close a trade
just because that's not something that
they can replicate in October I know
everything was done by the book I came
out almost $30,000 total month I made
$26,000 profit on the second then a
$4,000 profit followed by that so we've
got a a big month a lot of great trades
here even some losses by the book I took
a $2,000 loss that was according to the
strategy so if my students took the same
trade maybe at a you know a smaller
position size they would have taken that
loss with me all of October it couldn't
have been more by the book entry because
a trend line either got crossed or is
bouncing off of one and exit was because
a safety line was crossed October it
goes to show this is what an average
true month looks like for my strategy
there's no room for trading based on
emotions and feeling because I can't
teach that so this was just a direct
reflection of okay I've got a 100 people
putting a microscope on every trade and
trying to follow and replicate this
strategy there's no way I can just say I
closed cuz I was up x amount and if
we're looking at just October we've got
a 66
6.67% win rate we've got a profit factor
of 3.20 trade expectancy is
2,617 average win to loss is 1.6 we've
got an average win dollar amount of 5.71
and then an average loss of 3.57 and
then the total came out dollar amount
wise almost 30,000 that was for the
month cumulative and then not too many
trades we've got 1 2 3 4 five 5 to six
we're still in that time frame there was
no way that I went back to the 1 hour
because how could I I have my entire
student or Community holding me
accountable I can't say I'm sorry I
relapsed I went back to the one hour
absolutely not I truly stuck to swing
trading on this I stuck to the 4our time
frame we're also in October so I should
have a handle on it by now and it goes
to show that I did now let's go to
November November I believe was the last
month I traded I took December off so
let's take a look November 1st to 30th
we got a $23,000 month in November we've
got 100% win rate here 1 2 3 4 five six
trades and I do know one of these I
closed within the hour I believe it
might have been a news day and I hit my
profit Target pretty quickly this one
ended up working out pretty well it was
also the inq so I traded two symbols in
November it was platinum and the NQ you
guys can see I started to get a lot more
comfortable with Platinum this month I
placed four trades in Platinum so the
confidence is there I truly feel like I
have developed this relationship with
Platinum I felt very comfortable diving
right back into it we're fully trading
Platinum now I I didn't even place any
trades in oil for November there's not
many stats here you can see because the
profit Factor every trade was profit win
percentage is 100% net total was 23,000
I'd say good month in November I knew
this was going to be my last month
trading so I don't know if that played a
role in the amount of Trades that I took
if that played a role in how early I
stopped trading I still had a week left
of November and I still took off so I
was truly picky very picky with these
trades because I knew this is going to
be the last one of the Year this
determines whatever stats I get is going
to be put into the pot of my entire year
review so there was a lot of pressure in
November I remember let's just double
check that I didn't play place any
trades in December December 1st to the
31st nada nothing okay all right now
let's just wrap it all up let's do that
full overview how much did I make in
2023 drum
roll January let's look at this guy this
is a entire representation of my 2023
this is the Daily net cumulative p&l the
fact that I said cumulative that well is
impressing me right now January 1st to
December 31st we've got this beautiful
literal just climbing up Mount Everest
here you can see I had a tough time at
the beginning of the year we are in the
red we are below sea level here and then
as each month I'm getting better I'm
getting better I'm holding my winners
longer I'm staying in that time frame
longer we've got this beautiful chart
here to where we finally get to that
$94,000 close to 100 I'm sure that was
my goal but I will take 94 all day just
a beautiful representation this is
exactly how my year went if you had to
just put it all in one little photo one
little graph this is it very rough start
to the year it's a true beautiful visual
representation of consistency and
sticking with it and discipline and
commitment just all of the above right
here in this one beautiful little graph
if there is anything else you guys want
to see drop it in the comments I'm sure
I can go through my trade zeala stats
and give whatever info you guys need
that was my 2023 year in review my
wrapped for my trading stats my trade
Zella info that's all I've got thank you
guys for hanging out with me and I'll
see you guys next time