this year was a year of many records
because I didn't want to have to tell
the whole wide world that I was wrong
video which is my playbooks and the win
percentage is Tori a scammer is any of
this even
[Music]
real hi guys we have made it to the end
of 2024 now is the time for me to go
over all of my trading stats the
nitty-gritty dissect my entire year of
my trading performance we're going
through the profit Factor the trade win
percentage the winto loss ratio
everything profit and loss percentages
ticks whatever you guys need to know
we're going through all of it today in
our 2024 trade performance breakdown I
made a total of
203,000 in just 17 trades so I decided
to continue this trend by doing another
year review after the feedback I got
from last year I did my entire 2023 year
review showing you guys that I placed 57
trades I showed you guys the struggles I
had in January the total profit and loss
so I'm going to continue to Showcase all
of my trading my skills for 2024 last
year I was making the transition from a
day trader to a 4-Hour swing Trader it
was tough I was struggling the first
month I think I was down $6,000 brought
my account from
$20,000 down $6,000 so I already had to
make so much more of an effort to
continue through the new time frame in
2023 whereas this year this year was
completely different I was able to just
see this 4-Hour time frame click I
didn't have to second guess overthink no
hesitation the 4-Hour time frame swing
trading this year year completely
clicked for me the differences between
last year and this year is I've just
really found my confidence in swing
trading whereas last year I was still
trying to find out what swing trading
was and kind of find my way staying in
the 4-Hour time frame leaving the 1-hour
time frame behind and this year I did it
with Grace so even though I didn't have
the same struggles that I had last year
I found new struggles so being a swing
Trader I have found that holding trades
are exhausting and it is a skill you
have got to develop over time with just
purely experience you got to hold trades
for weeks on end being in draw down
being in profit watching it go back and
draw down and then closing the trade and
being completely exhausted by the end of
it so that's just something you will the
experience you'll get through just
holding longer just purely being in the
new time frame being a swing Trader and
those were the different struggles that
I had so not to say that I didn't have
any this year cuz there were still
struggles but very different than I had
last year last year was just purely
trying to get a hold of Swing trading
kind of leaving the day trading mindset
leaving the lower time frames and then
looking at a bigger picture so those
were the struggles last year this year
I'm struggling with trade exhaustion I
am taking on higher risk this year as
well so seeing those bigger profits and
not wanting to just immediately close
because of a dollar amount so talking
about psychology we can get a little bit
into when I actually dissect some of
these trades but now let's actually get
into the trades so I will start with
just breaking it down by month there's
not very many trades so these are going
to be very easy to go through so let's
get into the stats that I had for
January before we get into it I want to
show you guys the dashboard that I use
and the site that I use to track all of
my trades so that I can convey all of
this information to you guys so I use
trade Zella this is a trade journaling
platform it automatically syncs to my
brokerage and I don't have to do much
work it will sync to my brokerage
anytime I open and close a trade all of
the stats get shot into this program so
the only work that it requires on my end
is to go back through and actually
dissect the trade as a whole why did I
enter why did I exit and kind of Journal
my thoughts but this is an incredible
platform where you can showcase your
profit Factor you can see your net
profit and loss your win percentage you
can truly dissect everything about your
trade trades your trading stats your
year as a whole your month your week
this is the kind of like the Google
analytics of trading so highly recommend
trade Zella if you guys haven't signed
up click the link below and now let's
get into my stats for January all right
January 2024 I placed One Singular trade
I already remember the mindset I was in
I was having fomo I was I hadn't placed
a trade for most of January we're at the
last week of January and then finally I
was presented with an entry I was
confident I took the trade and closed it
on January 29th for a profit of $10,000
let's dissect this trade as a whole the
coolest part about trade Zella is I can
go back and actually see the chart in
real time where I was the entry the exit
where my lines were now there's going to
be a little bit of a discrepancy for
some of these instruments because I'm
not sure if Trad Zella has the ability
to toggle the bid adjustment on and off
so you guys might see a little bit of a
discrepancy here on where my lines are
at versus where the entry was but you
guys can see I have the entry here at
91399935 40 it was a long position I
traded 10 contracts I was able to
capitalize on 2,141 ticks and then let's
kind of just go through all of it so I
won't do too much as far as the the
journaling because I have many videos
where I kind of break down how I Journal
my trades why do I give my trade a three
and a half star rating why did I label
it as high risk trend line break three
touch Point Break why did I label it as
a fomo mistake so I'll go through as
much of a broad overview as I can on the
the journaling aspect but I have plenty
of videos that you guys can click the
link down below to see or watch one of
these videos where I totally dissect my
trading journal okay so this was my
entry we were looking at a trend line
break the price broke through this
downward trend line I took a long
position at $93.99 and price continued
in my favor we were in draw down and
then boom we finally got a good enough
move to close my position at
93540 now I've got different playbooks
we're going to get into this at the end
of the video I have two different
playbooks that I'm going to go over and
it is a two touchpoint break and a three
touchpoint break we're going to go over
the stats of each one at the end of the
video so stay tuned little sneak peek is
going to show you guys that win
percentage does not mean anything but
this right here was a two touch Point
Break I went long after the price broke
this downward trend line that had two
touch points long position here we're in
draw down it's within my parameters it
is abiding by my safety line and boom we
got a spike up close the trade I closed
it because we were at a horizontal level
of resistance here this 9388 and I was
happy it was my first trade of the Year
let's capitalize on 10 grand I'll take
take it let's move on to the next trade
okay so all of January that's it One
Singular trade $10,000 let's move on to
February so being a swing Trader coming
into 2024 in the 4-Hour time frame I was
experiencing a little bit of fomo I
hadn't placed a trade for the first half
of January I didn't get into the trade
until January 23rd so this was a little
bit of a I'd say a rushed decision
ideally I like a three touch Point trend
line break I want enough information I
want an A+ clean setup this one wasn't
you know A++ this was like a mediocre
setup but I think fomo and getting into
the already the end of the month of
January starting out my year there was a
lot to dissect here so comparing it to
my year last year I had a little bit of
PTSD my last January was awful was
completely awful was embarrassing I had
to Showcase that I lost six grand on
social media while simultaneously saying
that I'm going to become a swing Trader
follow me along this journey and it
sucked I was really hesitant a lot of
hesitation coming into January I wasn't
sure if the price action was going to be
clean so we're looking at week three of
January finally I placed my trade not
ideal not A+ a little bit fomo driven
but regardless we've got a profit
nonetheless so I'll take it definitely
some psychological stuff was taken over
for most of January but now let's get
into February February I also placed One
Singular trade we have a $29,000 we'll
call it 30 $30,000 trade in February no
trades at the first half of February I
didn't get into this trade until
February 12th now let's break this one
down as well this one right here was a
three touch Point trend line break entry
let's go over the position so we took a
long position in Platinum at
88872 I was able to capitalize on 1.9 R
I gave myself four stars for this trade
setup and it just felt a little better
so we were already able to kind of rip
the Band-Aid off for the first trade of
the year in January now we're coming
into February a little bit more
comfortable a little bit more confident
taking a little bit more of an A+ setup
right here with this three touchpoint
trend line setup so let me zoom out so
you guys can see a little bit clearer
idea here we've got 1 2 three touch
points on a downward trend line price
broke we took a long position here and
then closed at a level of resistance at
91852 so this one was pretty easy this
was I felt like I was getting the
momentum I was getting to hang on things
so let's talk about the profit here so
we're looking at a $330,000 trade in
February a singular trade open and
closed $30,000 profit one thing that I
want to kind of express to you guys is
that this year was a year of many
records I hit personal bests back to
back to back so if I'm being honest with
you I'm not sure if this was my record
trade at the time I think I could be
wrong but we'll we'll kind of dissect it
a little bit more as we go through the
year I'll be able to remember my $40,000
absolutely because that's still to date
one of my record trades but this one
this $30,000 trade I can almost
guarantee was my record trade at the
time so there was a lot of emotions it's
a very exciting thing to not only have
just placed two trades in the year we're
only in the second month of the year
both profits we're feeling good but also
close a record trade it's an incredible
feeling all right so we're looking at
two trades already for the year first
two months of the year both profits
let's see if we find any losses here
let's get into March okay so March we
closed a $10,000 trade that put me at
$50,000 for the first three months of
the year that is so exciting I wasted no
time and decided to withdraw all 50,000
on the 7th of March and used those funds
to actually completely furnish my new
apartment in Nashville it was incredibly
fulfilling I have a video where I kind
of did a walk through it was more of
like this surprise I gave these interior
designers like an idea or a vision and I
got to completely fish my entire new
home in Nashville and to use 100% of the
funds from Trading was mind-blowing to
me so March was an awesome month we
closed $50,000 trading profits for the
first 3 months we withdrew all 50,000
and put it towards Furnishing my
apartment in Nashville but there's one
more trade at the end of the month so
we're looking at two trades this one
right here we have our first loss I took
a
$2,800 loss at the very end of March
let's kind of dissect this trade here
okay so if you guys have been following
along for many of my videos this year
there's probably one video that you have
seen many of times and it is me beating
myself up about getting into the wrong
contract for platinum when I'm swing
trading and I trading the Futures Market
there are expiration dates in these
contracts and to make sure that you get
into the right one is fairly crucial
otherwise you will get into a contract
and it will expire in the next few days
and your position will be liquidated so
I got into the wrong contract in
Platinum at the end of March so I went
ahead and closed my position I
solidified a $2,800 loss and then
re-entered into the current contract
where we then in turn made a profit I
wouldn't have had to solidify that loss
so whether it was a loss based on the
strategy or a loss based on just poor
execution it's a loss nonetheless so we
have our first loss of the Year $2,800
in March let's move on to the next month
we've got an awesome beginning trade 3rd
of April we closed $30,000 let's dissect
this trade it is a three touch Point
trend line break I was able to
capitalize on 2.04 R and the chart isn't
as beautifully marked up as most of mine
are but here you can still see we've got
point a point B two touch points
downward trend line we've got a break
and I was actually in draw down for most
of the beginning of this trade then
finally price took off we were able to
close at
94889 for a profit of $30,000 I went
long 20 contracts and was able to
capitalize on$ 6,31 ticks I will say
being in draw down in this trade as long
as you have proper risk management or
proper safety line placement draw down
is natural it's normal you're going to
have losing trades you're going to have
moments where you enter and you're
immediately in draw down so without risk
management you are at risk for losing
all of your money so let's have proper
risk management or proper safety line
placement so we've had an entry long
position 91873 closed it at 94889 we
capitalized on $30,000 so the mistake
that I labeled on this trade was
consolidation I excel when prices are
trending and I happen to make a mistake
and enter when markets were
consolidating and it's way cool to be
able to label your trades like this okay
so that was just the very first trade of
April let's see if I plac any more
trades in that month spoiler alert I did
all right third of April close close
$30,000 I didn't trade for two almost 3
weeks after that but then finally we
opened a position on April 25th and
closed it before the end of the month we
closed this position on April 29th for a
total of $24,000 this one was a two
touchpoint trend line break I was able
to capitalize on 1.55 R and let's break
this trade down so notice this is
platinum right here this is the second
trade that I placed in April and also
only the second instrument that I have
traded in the entire year I'm only
trading platinum and crude oil okay so
let's break this trade down we've got a
downward trend line only two touch
points here point a point B price broke
out and we took our long position here
at 9279 price continued up we closed as
you can see I don't have a horizontal
level marked up here but you can kind of
see just visually where this red
horizontal is at 96620 Price got to this
level of resistance I closed one thing
that I want to start talking about this
year because this is something that I've
noticed is that most of my exits if not
all were based on a level of support and
resistance and I can tell this is one
because of trade exhaustion and two
because I am taking on more risk this
year I am more inclined to just take
profit because I am simply up a dollar
amount I am trading bigger profits than
I have in the past I am closing
positions that are bigger than I have in
the past it's more that I'm comfortable
with more than I'm used to so when I see
$24,000 or $30,000 simply just because I
see the dollar amount I am so much more
inclined to close it whereas you guys
know that I am a trend line Trader I
have action lines and safety lines and
my strategy excels when I can hold P the
trade out for its entirety wait for the
safety line to get crossed you can see
here in almost all of the trades this
year the exits were based on support and
resistance or a horizontal level here or
a key level not based on a safety line
getting broken so you can already see
this is kind of one of the things I was
struggling with this year specifically
psychologically is the bigger dollar
amounts so I'm working on it you will be
able to see kind of I work through it as
the year progresses as I continue to
place more trades but this is a very
obvious first point that I can see I was
struggling with was just the dollar
amounts so higher amounts I was more
inclined to close it whereas I should
have waited for a safety line to get
broken so just one thing I can already
see going back through and dissecting
the years so far $224,000 we got an
entry we got an exit we did 20 contracts
we were able to capitalize on 4,862
ticks here and my R was 1.55 so that was
April let's see what we got next so we
are on the sixth trade of the year now
we're at end of April trade closed month
closed let's see what I did next May no
trades I was in a position to take an
entire month off of trading I was
satisfied with my trading I'm hitting
personal bests I'm making withdraws I'm
on Cloud9 so I gave myself an entire
month of no trades all right I gave
myself yet another month now maybe this
wasn't necessary two months of a break
probably didn't need but I took all of
May and all of June off of trading I was
focusing on content creation on my team
on some new business Endeavors so this
is the coolest part about trading is
when you reach a level or a goal that
you're satisfied with or you're happy
with you have the ability to just take a
break you can quit for a month two I
don't know if was completely necessary
but I gave myself two months now let's
get into July July oh oh I remember July
this is a beautiful example of what you
shouldn't do as a Trader when you have
ego you've got a big head you're
thinking you're the best Trader in the
world then you're thinking why don't we
just experiment with crypto Futures I
got into an ethereum trade held for 3
weeks was down $30,000 somehow the trade
came back up and and I closed with $46 I
have an entire video of that trade
breakdown it was a mistake in every way
shape or form I held through draw down I
got rid of a stop- loss I was willing to
risk at all for ethereum futures wow but
somehow I came out positive on that
trade so I can already see
psychologically ego way too high
confidence maybe too high there to
experiment with a new instrument
especially crypto features something
I've never done before I remember social
media was involved here I made a video
on social media talking about how this
is a great entry and it did really well
and then I felt like I was obligated to
take that entry since I told social
media this was such a great entry and
ended up being a complete flop it was
just it was a mess it was a nightmare
and I continued to hold purely because I
didn't want to have to tell the whole
wide world that I was wrong and somehow
luckily I got out of that trade with $46
you guys can click the video here to see
that entire trade breakdown it's not one
of my best but I at least broke it down
for you guys all the mistakes I made and
how to not do what I did but we did
Place Another trade we came back so
we're done experimenting ing we're done
throwing our strategy in the trash we're
done kind of veering from whatever path
I should be on and we're back to it
beautiful trading beautiful execution we
got into a Futures trade on the 26th of
July and then closed it on the 31st for
my record trade to date so after that
nightmare of a trade I was able to lock
back in and we got into a trade on the
26th of July and closed it on the 31st
for my record trade to date this is
still my best trade I've ever had it is
a $440,000 trade let's break it down it
was in Platinum a three touch Point
trend line break I was able to
capitalize on 2.9 R here let's look at
the chart here we've got a three touch
Point trend line break point a point B
Point C here price broke we took a long
position no draw down here bar after bar
after bar it's working we're in profit
now this one I will say we closed yet
again because it got to a level of
support and resistance it acted as
Support over here acted as resistance
over here I closed at
9883 looking at this chart you would
think that I knew something that
everyone didn't I happened to close here
at the high it made at the time did I
know it was going to completely turn
around and just fall off a cliff after
this I had no earthly idea no I closed
this trade simply because we got to a
level of resistance does it make you
feel good closing at a top absolutely it
does and does it make you feel good when
it's an absolute record trade yeah I'm
feeling great after this trade so we got
a lot of Records here a lot of personal
bests especially to come back after such
a huge mistake in experimenting with
crypto Futures I love that I can just
lock back in and then boom we got a
record trade here so we went long 20
contracts I was able to capitalize on
7,939 ticks here and our R was 2.92 that
was a great trade love that one for me
so recap of July two trades one awful
somehow closed at
$46 after being in $330,000 worth of
draw down and then closed my record
trade $40,000 on the 31st of July August
I'm a Leo usually my August months are
incredible this time around
anti-climatic
I placed one trade on the 13th closed it
the next day for $3,000 and then took my
first official loss of the year I know
we talked about the one that I had had
by poor execution getting into the wrong
contract but this one was an official
loss based on the strategy and I was
incredibly proud of this loss okay so
let's go over the first trade in August
it was a $3,000 trade this is a two
touch Point trend line break I was able
to capitalize on0 26r and let's look at
the charts Okay so we've got a two
touchpoint trend line break point a
point B here we took a short position
but you can see I closed very shortly
after I will be honest with you guys
this was an accidental close I did not
have order confirmation on trading view
on my phone so if I accidentally hit the
X trade is gone it is over poof whereas
now I have order confirmation on so if I
hit the X it says are you sure and then
you hit yes and then the trade is closed
you live and you learn so I was still
able to capitalize on almost $3,000 I'll
take it sure but you can see the exit
there was no Rhyme or Reason here that
was because of an accidental trade the
exit should have technically still been
at the same price but days later okay
the next one was a proper loss based on
proper risk management I love going over
good losers so let's go over this one
here next this was a $6,500 loss let's
see why I entered and why I exited we
have got a three touchpoint trend line
break so according to the strategy this
is A+ it's low risk we've got three
touch points on our downward trend line
we're thinking long positions let's get
in price broke up we're thinking long
and it simply just didn't work out it
faked us all out so it looked as though
it made everyone think we're going up
we're going long and snapped right
against us we got out so you can see the
exit was because the safety line was
crossed so this right here is where I
excel especially when the markets do
move in my favor is when I can close the
trade based on the safety line getting
crossed and not the price getting to an
area of support and resistance now I am
still doing incredible by closing those
trades at the support and resistance
levels or at these key levels here but I
excel and I'm able to capitalize on the
most when I can close when the safety
line is crossed so this is an example of
when the safety line is crossed but it's
a loss instead of a winner entry here at
965-4456 4 so let's talk about why I'm
excited to go over a loss and why I'm
happy about this loss one I am always
happy to have small losers versus a
blown account versus a giant fat loss on
my hands truly just being able to see
proper risk management we love I will
take a small loser over a giant loss any
day of the week write that down we're
paying a fee we're not taking a giant
loss that's kind of the way that I like
to look at my losses as fees they're
small they're tangible they're properly
managed and this is the coolest part to
see all right I took a long position it
didn't work out I'm happy to give the
market $6,000 of my cash versus my
entire Capital so you can see even after
closing the trade yes we took the $6,500
loss but market conditions were shisa
anyways it didn't go anywhere we made
everybody think we were going up and
then we went down and then we made
everything everyone think we were going
down and then we went up so
consolidation spiked everyone out faked
everyone out not fun anyways I'll take a
loss to avoid that any day of the week
okay moving on okay August 20th that was
all of August all right we have made it
to the end of August 10th trade total
for the year I'm still mind blown I have
finally done it I've made the transition
from day trader to swing Trader and
doing it beautifully 10 trades out of
the Year absolutely that's a swing
Trader and we're only in August eight
months so far let's get into September
September I placed a little bit more
trades so now I love that I just said
how proud I am of being a swing Trader
and being very picky about my trades and
staying to that higher time frame and
then we come in September with three
four trades 1 2 3 four we've got four
trades in just September let's talk
about it here we go we're getting closer
to the end of the year I have publicly
told the internet social media that I
have a goal of $200,000 in trading
profits you can imagine as we're getting
closer to the end of the year there is a
little bit of urgency I'm ready to hit
that goal I'm a little bit nervous what
if I don't hit that goal I want to
capitalize on the market conditions as
they were in September they were great
market conditions in September we had a
lot of movement I I was able to place
four trades that's more than I would
have liked as a swing Trader but I
already know I'm thinking okay we've got
it publicly at the end of the year
either say I did it or I failed you guys
and there's a lot going on
psychologically to get into these trades
so one we placed too many trades that's
all right I can see just overview
September yeah we over traded especially
for a swing Trader we came out on top
profit of $53,000 love that so let's get
into the first rate of the month it was
closed on September 6th we were able to
capitalize on $188,000 I think I
remember closing this in a sauna I
experimented with a bigger position size
I was able to feel something new for the
first time in a while I got nervous
because of a bigger position all thanks
to my strategy though I'm still able to
properly manage my risk but I did close
this trade purely based on dollar
amounts and it was kind of fun to
experiment with a new feeling uh bigger
dollar amounts bigger risk a bigger
position than I'm used to I will say
that's probably my only one for the year
where I really just went heavy in a
position just to see what it felt like
so first rate of September done and
closed exposure therapy check next trade
all right this one was in crude oil 20
contracts we're back down to reality
here we've got a two touch Point trend
line break and we were able to
capitalize on $
26,6 let's look at the trade here now
this one was closed pretty quickly the
price moved aggressively within just a
few hours so I didn't have to hold this
for a week or a few days I was able to
close this the next day we made a pretty
big movement in the markets and price
ended up getting to an area of
resistance pretty quickly so I was able
to capitalize on 2 $
6,656 20 contracts in crude oil and we
are looking at 2,669 ticks and I was
able to make 3.66 R so we got point a
here point B here price broke we're
thinking long positions we went long at
6796 and closed at 6930 so yes I was
able to capitalize on $26,000 here but
let's see how much I was willing to lose
if this trade did not work in my favor
so if we go down to trade risk this is
my initial risk if the trade immediately
went against me I was willing to lose $
7,29
now this was an instance where I made
money the price worked in my favor the
strategy worked out for me but if this
was to be a trade that didn't work out
this is what my risk management looks
like I was willing to lose 7 Grand if
this didn't work out love it all right
moving on third trade of September here
we go this was a loss this was a
$133,000 loss one of the biggest losses
and I think biggest losses total of the
Year this one right here
$3,574 this is yet another loss
according to the strategy a little bit
higher than I would liked but regardless
purely bu the book and let's kind of go
over what this looks like I love dissect
the losers much more than the winners
because I mean you can place a trade and
get out because you were winning but how
can you manage a loss how can you manage
risk effectively so we've got a two
touch Point trend line break here point
a point B price broke I mean it was a
clean break beautiful we're making money
immediately we entered at 98560 in
Platinum here you can see the downward
trend line price broke the downward
trend line so we're thinking long
positions we're in a long position 20
contracts there were days where price
went absolutely nowhere bar after bar
after bar nowhere nowhere nowhere we're
not making any money maybe we're up a
little bit we're down a little bit we're
up a little bit finally we're looking at
Friday September 20th we got some
movement not in my favor down Red Bar
Red Bar Red Bar and then here finally
the upward line is the line that manages
my risk this is called my safety line as
soon as price breaks the safety line my
capital is at risk so that is how I know
high alert red it's time to close the
trade luckily I have proper risk
management I have a great strategy to
tell me exactly when to get out closed
at
13574 now I did hold a little bit longer
I wanted to give this every chance to
turn around and thank gosh to my
strategy thank gosh to proper risk
management I closed because it didn't
turn around if I would have held
thinking okay maybe it'll turn around
maybe it'll turn around it would have
been yet another bar after bar after bar
against me bigger loss bigger loss
bigger loss so this is where risk
management comes into play make sure for
the third or fourth or fifth time you
have proper risk management when trading
all right the end of September we're
looking at two trades which I was
unaware of let's see so we've got the
25th and the 26th it's looking like
we've got two trades but we've got a
total profit of $21,000 let's break that
down let's see what this looks like here
oh okay all right so we've got one trade
in crude oil and one trade in Platinum
so these are two separate trades one was
a three touchpoint trend line break one
was a two touchpoint trend line break we
are looking at a long position in
Platinum and a short position in crude
the long position in Platinum got me
$2,000 $700 the short position in crude
oil got me almost $20,000 it got me
$1,066 let's go over the crude oil trade
first and then we'll go over the
Platinum trade crude oil two touchpoint
trend line break almost $20,000 why did
I get in why did I get out all right
zooming out here you can see we've got a
two touch Point trend line break point a
point B price broke love this setup here
low risk even though it was only two
touch points on the trend line still a
great trade nonetheless we've got an
awesome entry price continued to just
fall off a cliff here so the entry was a
short position at 7.01 and we closed
because price got to an area of support
at this 6906 so I actually closed a
little bit early I should have waited
until price got truly to this level of
support at 6766 would have capitalized
on a little bit more profit there but
I'll take it nonetheless we're getting
close to the end of the year the
pressure is on making sure I can tell
you guys at the end of the year guess
what I did it I made it to 200,000 so
closing a little bit earlier I get it
part of the process here but I closed at
the 6906 instead of 6766 but beautiful
entry love it no draw down Bor after bar
after bar completely fell we're looking
at a short position 20 contracts I was
able to capitalize on 1,910 ticks and my
R multiple was .97 all right so almost
$20,000 in crude oil now let's see the
trade in Platinum where I made $2,000
all right we have got a long position in
Platinum 2000 let's see what did I do
why did I get in why did I get out we
are looking at a three touchpoint trend
line break ideal that is A+ we've got a
three touchpoint trend line break it's a
lowrisk setup the price is incredibly
close to the safet line if this didn't
work out the loss would have been
minimal we've got an entry here at
95.7 and an exit at 988 52 20 contracts
we closed simply either because we were
at an high let me see if I can zoom out
and find a area of resistance here it
got close enough to the 1022 which is
what I was looking for the exit I closed
a little bit before at 9.98 so not a
huge one here very small profit in
comparison to the other trades of the
year
$276 but great entry so let's go back
and just kind of dissect and review
September how many trades and what was
our total looking like for September
before we move on all right so if we
look at the widget here in trade Zella
it gives you an awesome overview you can
see week by week how much you were up
how many trades you placed your monthly
stats here your trading days I traded
six total days out of September my
monthly stat was $53,500 for a total of
September and then week one boom we made
$18,000 week 2 26,000 week 3 nothing
week four 88,200 totaling us for 53,000
and $500 for September October we took
it way down scaled it way back back to
the theme that we took for the beginning
of the year one trade a month slow and
steady waiting for the A+ setup
September was aggressive a lot of Trades
there is something very special about
this One Singular trade placed in
October this trade got me to my goal of
$200,000 oh my god let's talk about it
let's get into it so I'm already
experiencing a lot of pressure I am
getting so close to my goal September
you can tell I was struggling I'm trying
to get so close to my goal of 200,000 I
am placing too many trades in September
I'm trying to just go ahead and hit that
goal and be done for the year I wasn't
presented with my $200,000 in September
but October did give me that last trade
to solidify it help me reach my goal
this was a entry on a three touch Point
trend line break great setup here
lowrisk entry all the stars aligned it
was a great trade the pressure was kind
of getting to me I made some videos that
you guys may have seen before where I am
just I'm struggling and I'm like you
know what do I need to punish myself for
wanting to place a trade just to Simply
get me to that goal I wanted to go too
heavy in a position cuz I could have
easily hit that goal if I just went
really heavy in a position and it you
know within just a few seconds moved in
my favor I could have closed it that's
not smart that is not risk management
that is not my strategy and this is what
I have to do being the kind of
influencer and educator that I am
everything that I do has to be
repeatable you guys have to be able to
see the structure the system the process
the risk management so I really had to
bring it back and be like okay you know
what I'm going to wait if I'm not
presented with an opportunity in October
then I'll just have to wait for the next
month and I finally was on October 21st
I was presented with a three touchpoint
trend line break it was a long position
in crude oil I went long here when price
broke at 7033 and then price continued
to move in my favor we closed it at 7090
for a profit of $11,400 that was it that
got me to my goal now there were moments
where I should have continued to stay in
this trade give me some credit here yes
I closed I was it I made it to the
$200,000 Mark I should have closed over
here still same price but a few days
later so you guys can see we've got an
upward trend line here price is moving
in my favor we've got some EB and flow
here touch Point touch Point touch Point
price finally broke my safety line the
line that manages my risk that tells me
when to get out or when to close in
profit right here at the same price but
just later on in the day so I would have
had to hold through some days of just EB
and flow here and then close it but
regardless nonetheless I will take it a
beautiful entry we were able to close at
11,4 $ and then we did it we made it to
$200,000 in less than 20 trades of the
year so impressive I'm very proud of
myself especially just seeing the
struggles that I had in 2023 just trying
to make the transition from day trader
to swing Trader trying to get a handle
on the higher time frames to see it
finally click and to see how proud I am
and just to see how how well I did for
the year I'm so proud of myself okay so
2024 year review stats total as a whole
we're looking at 17 trades total for the
year net profit and loss
$2,362 my profit Factor was 9.77 my
trade win percentage is
7647 my average win to loss is 3.01 and
then look at this Daily net cumulative
profit and loss this is what I like to
see there is ups and downs but we've got
this beautiful gradual increase in
capital all the way to our $200,000 goal
here this is my favorite thing to look
at at the end of the year is to see the
progress as a whole in one chart one
graph look look at the EB and flow here
we're making money we got a little bit
of a loss here we're making money
stagnant we're making money a little bit
of a loss and to see the growth this is
what I want to see okay so another thing
that I'm very excited about outside of
the Daily net cumulative p&l which I
love to see is the zeala score over here
the zela score is a combination of your
win percentage your win to loss and your
profit Factor when I tell you guys I got
a 100 I got a 100 A+ zeala score I'll
take it okay I'll take it if that is the
the grade that I get at the end of the
year for my Trading stats I'm here for
it 100% okay so we went over my entire
year my stats for 2024 now let's go over
something that I mentioned at the
beginning of the video which is my
playbooks and the win percentage let me
show you guys the importance and
significance of having a Playbook but
also how we don't need to rely so
heavily on the win percentage now I only
have two playbooks here but there are
many more that I use there are trend
line bounces there are candle closures
there are retests but these are the two
most important that played a role in my
trading this year is the two touch
points trend line break and the three
touchpoint trend line break now you guys
can see by going through and dissecting
every trade and giving it a label giving
it a Playbook you're able to see the
stats each one can give you so if you're
trying a new strategy you're trying
something new and you want to see what's
working better what's not working what
do I need to eliminate what do I need to
add this is a great way to do so so I
can see going over the year which one
was better what entry or scenario or
setup do I need to do more of next year
and do less of next year so the differen
is between the two touchpoint break and
the three touchpoint break win percent
perc you're thinking right off the bat
let's go for the two touch point because
we're looking at
85.71% and the three touch point we're
only looking at 77% but let's kind of
dissect this a little bit more so we've
got a net profit and loss we've got a
average winner an average loser a trade
expectancy very different so I want you
guys to keep in mind yes the win
percentage is higher on the two
touchpoint trend line break but my
average winner and my average loser is
not anywhere near as good as my three
touchpoint trend line break so over here
you can see yes 85.71% it was able to
get me
$80,000 but you can see the average
winner was $ 15,000 and the average
loser was 13,000 so I was risking a lot
more on these two touchpoint trend line
breaks versus let's look at the three
touch point the three touch Point yes it
only got me 77.78% percentage but I was
able to capitalize on
$123,000 and then here's the kicker so
my average winner is
$18,000 and my average loser is only
four these are much more lowrisk setups
and I was able to simply just make more
money on this three touchpoint trend
line break even though the win
percentage is less so I'm risking a lot
less than the two touch point and I'm
able to make a lot more than the two
touchpoint in the three touchpoint trend
line break so this is the coolest part
about going through your year I can see
the three is still the reigning Queen it
still helps me get A+ setups and
capitalize on the most amount of money
in the markets So based on these stats
simply by looking at my playbook I am
going to take the three touchpoint trend
line break next year and double down on
it okay so just this information alone
incredibly insightful and Incredibly
beneficial especially for the Newbie
Traders if you guys are learning a new
strategy or trying to find out what
works better and what you need to double
down on this is a great way to do so
with your playbooks now the moment you
guys have all been waiting for is Tori a
scammer is any of this even real well
I've got broker statements to back it up
if you say it's photoshopped at that
point I don't know what to tell you but
I have Broker statements from my
brokerage it is a US regulated Brokerage
in the US trade station here we go all
right trade station here we go my
official brokerage statement now I did
block out my address and my account
number you can see the last four of my
account numbers so that you guys can go
back and verify and cross reference all
of my accounts make sure the profit and
losses are adding up the account number
is the same across all of my videos so
now we're going to go through the
brokerage statements from trade station
this is January statement one thing that
I do want you guys to note here the
beginning balance I started my account
with
$112,000 here versus last year my
account balance started at 20,000 so big
difference here I'm trading with more
risk and I'm trading with more Capital
this year now let's move on to February
February
2024 March 2024
April
May
June
July August and there we have it October
31st 2024 my last trade of the year my
last brokerage statement with a trade in
it that was my entire Year's worth of
broker statements now I did show you
guys the initial balance when I started
so some of you guys are percentage
freaks you need to know I don't care
about the dollar amounts I want to know
how much she made in percentage right
here you can see I made
18057 per. that's incredible that's
impressive now if you guys want to see
something crazier I made over 400% in
2023 if you haven't seen that video go
back and check it out so this is what
profitable trading actually looks like
it's not about the fancy cars it's not
about the crazy lifestyle but it's about
being disciplined and following your
strategy this year not only have I made
$200,000 in profits but I've also been
able to help hundreds of students get
profitable and amazing results all by
just trading trend lines so if you're
looking to learn how to trade this
simple strategy click the link below to
book a call with me and my team thanks
for watching don't forget to like
subscribe hit the notification Bell so
you get a notification every time I post
a video and I will see you guys next
time with trendline trading tricks and
tips with Tory trades