it's week eight of me turning $100 into
a Million last week we took two trades
where one of them made us about $2,000
and then the other we lost a $2,000
biggest waste of time ever and now this
week we're going to come and Slash the
market where we're going to try and turn
these
$20,000 into
$40,000 good evening ladies and
gentlemen it is week number eight
turning $100 into a
million and all I can say is that we
usually start Monday morning very early
Monday morning because cuz Sunday
usually nothing
happens but not this time this time is
different you know what I think this is
the first time in the whole entire
challenge we start Challenge on a Sunday
and this might be the Sunday that we
just take a trade on Sunday night and it
can give us the profits for the whole
entire week so let's see currently right
now it is
1:58 in the morning so it is 2: in the
morning Sunday night Monday morning so
right now I'm supposed to be asleep but
I'm here about to take a trade so
there's a lot of markets that I am
interested in taking this week but 50%
of these markets are degenerate markets
now you guys know what that means
degenerate markets means I'm breaking my
trading plan if I break my trading plan
I have to drive the beetle now I haven't
driven the beetle in about 3 weeks cuz I
haven't broken my trading plan in 3
weeks but if I break my trading plan I
am a man of my word I will not drive my
3.4 million Bugatti to drive the beetle
to show you guys that you have to hold
yourself accountable every single time
you break a trading plan but as right
now we haven't done it so let's see if
we're about to do it so starting off the
week is going to be
audusd as you guys can see the
degenerate markets I have Beetle at the
top of it because these are the markets
if I do take this trade I'm going to
have to drive the [\h__\h] Beetle
currently right now audusd is at a high
of a resistance so you can see how we
are at a resistance level and resistance
level so you guys can see here on the
weekly time frame every single time
price comes up into this resistance one
we rejection comes up into this
resistance one we rejection and then
hits to the downside currently right now
we've had the pullup the one we
rejection just as it's done here and we
could anticipate a pullback we're at a
higher high so we could anticipate price
to take a pullback to then continue to
head to the upside now this is a counter
trend trade because we're trading
against the daily time frame and the
weekly daily time frame is still bullish
creating higher high higher low higher
high but the 4H hour time frame has
shifted bearish now we've used this
channel in the past in the last couple
of weeks and it has worked very
precisely not saying that we want to use
it this week but it's just so I visual
representation you guys can see how we
were bullish and now we broken under
that channel the structure has gone
bearish this was the higher low higher
high we broken under now we have a left
head kind of right shoulder going on and
this is literally exactly where I would
want to be interested in entering this
position literally like right like I can
basically take this trade right [\h__\h]
now like literally right now but I only
like taking positions right at the
beginning of London session especially
on a Sunday London session starts in 1
hour but this might have the move before
that is what literally driving me crazy
because if we go to the weekly time
frame the weekly time frame has already
created that Wick so usually what
happens is when the weekly Candlestick
opens it just either has the move but
then it always has to go back and create
the wick this has already created the
wick so it doesn't have to go back up
here so technically the trade could be
ready to be taken but I am going to wait
for a little bit more confirmation on
this position potentially going to be
another bearish engulfing Candlestick so
it's a confirmed rejection from this
area here us audusd is borderline about
to take it and if I take
it that means Beetle time or also known
as The Punisher next is going to be USD
JPY which is not a degenerate trade you
can clearly see here on the weekly time
frame we are very much bearish we were
creating higher high higher low higher
high and then we went bearish lower high
lower low and now we're retesting this
weekly structure level when you go down
to the Daily time frame you can see here
on the daily time frame this is a very
well respected level of resistance
support support support resistance
resistance support so whenever we're
above a rejecting whenever we're under
we are rejecting now I'm about to show
you guys some crazy voodoo magic [\h__\h]
and again this okay obviously it's not
[\h__\h] voodoo magic right let's be
[\h__\h] honest it's Market structure
repetition constantly the markets will
repeat it s because these patterns
happen time and time again this is about
to trip you guys out what I'm about to
show you guys if you guys like these
type of examples and they make sense to
you guys drop a comment below so I can
keep doing it because it's a very high
level of analyzation in the markets and
it's almost like where's Waldo like when
you have this big image of where's Waldo
and once you find them you almost can't
unsee it but before you find them it's
pretty much impossible to find them but
when you find them it's very hard to
then see it but I'm about to show you
guys right now you are not seeing it as
soon as I show it to you you can't unsee
it's going to look super clear so let me
show you guys so this market right here
currently is having a lower high
pullback and this is what this Market
structure looks like on this pullback
right we have some structure right here
and then we are now at this resistance
level if I take this same exact Market
structure move from right here and then
I simply move it to this Market
structure here with an exception of of
making this a little bit higher and
aiming this a little bit higher it's the
exact same move right here but instead
of it obviously being here it is now
right here it's the same exact move with
the exception of bit being a little bit
higher now what is the difference that
this had this [\h__\h] the structure up here
and that this one is having it right
here let's see what happened here to see
if we could anticipate for it to happen
here cuz we're expecting for the cells
and clearly this one to did this pattern
it then went to the downside so let's
zoom into this 30 minutes structure on
this circle time frame right here what
did we get when we were at this pattern
right here oh okay we got a left head
right shoulder okay cool left head right
shoulder retest then sell well let's go
to current price right now holy [\h__\h]
what do we have here left head right
shoulder [\h__\h] with me [\h__\h] with me if
you want me to keep showing you guys cuz
I see this all the time and I don't
always explain it because I it's just
normal to me this is my second language
third language and I see this literally
every single day it's very normal to me
but to a lot of you guys this might be
like what the [\h__\h] a wow moment and if
it is let me know in the comments so I
can keep doing this up for you guys cuz
it motivates me and it shows me that you
guys are actually learning so this
position we're actually very very very
interested in executing but not just yet
I want to execute this position once we
have some type of engulfing cont
confirmation as of right now I have my
potential entry right under this level
because when this Candlestick closes
under it it is a engulfing Candlestick
so just put my alarm under there to
pretty much notify me once we have that
engulfing Candlestick even the 15 minute
hasn't had the engulfing quite just yet
so we're going to stay up all night
tonight because that literally might
happen very very very soon next is GBP
JPY so this pair we've been anticipating
since last week and currently right now
we are at this resistance level once
again 4-Hour time frame we're just in
this consolidation this is very easy
break retest to then sell retest of
structure retest of EMA and retest of
round psychological level
190.5 next AUD JPY literally same exact
thing we're at now this very strong
level of support and resistance all
throughout here and I'm simply going to
be waiting for price to have a break and
retest under this level to then take
this trade to the the downside very easy
very straight to the point next
degenerate trade Beetle trade if I take
this trade right here which I should not
I will then have to drive the beetle so
this was a pair that we were interested
in last week that we were interested in
selling at the retest of this neckline
but that never happened and price had to
push to the downside now I believe this
is going to be the move that's going to
retest the neckline of GBP nzd and The
Head and Shoulders but I see an
opportunity on that retest this is the
degenerate trade you should not be
looking to take this trade that is a no
you should be looking to take this sell
but this counter Trend trade does look
pretty decent we've clearly created a
triple bottom and now we are potentially
going to break out of that area to then
take this trade the 1H hour time frame
is clearly consolidating and now we're
are about to break out of this area
along with the EMA in order for me to
execute this trade I'd basically need a
break and a retest and I'd only look for
a very quick shortterm buy to just
retest this neckline of the overall Head
and Shoulders pattern that we have right
here this is a counter Trend trade and
again when I take a counter Trend trade
I am breaking my trading plan and my
trading rules therefore if I do that I
have to go drive the beetle but as of
right now there is no break and no
retest but we're going to keep our eye
on it just in case if it were to do it
so this is the second degenerate trade
that if you were to take it we would
have to drive the Beetle and then lastly
nzdjpy not even that focused on it
because we have way better markets that
we're going to be interested in for this
week ahead so I'm going to keep my eye
peeled out on
usdjpy and on
audusd
so drum roll 2:09 in the morning see you
guys either in a couple of hours or
tomorrow in the morning s and forget all
right guys so trade update it is
currently right now
3:34 in the middle of the night so
usually what happens is that I'll start
falling asleep here at the desk so I
just literally go take a shower wakes me
up and I just come back so I just take a
shower right now and I'm currently
waiting for the market to give you my
entry signal probably be up for another
hour um just see what the market does
nothing's changed everything's exactly
the same let me show you USD JPY still
waiting for the rejection
audusd still waiting for the rejection
and the GBP still waiting for the break
under everything is literally still
exactly the same GBP nzd has started to
have the break so let's wait for that
retest now but I think USD JPY is going
to be the first one that I'm going to be
interested in taking so little trade
update at 3:35 we will see what happens
next if not I'll see you in the morning
good morning ladies and gentlemen ah so
last night we fell asleep at around 4:30
almost 5: in the morning and we have
just gotten up it is currently 9:58 in
the morning so Sebastian my filmmaker
usually is here with me but last night
he fell asleep at 52 this guy can't wake
up he can't hang can't hang with the boy
I'm already used to this whole sleep
schedule I am fried so I can fall asleep
at 5: and wake up at 7:00 like if I
slept 6 hours but I didn't and I did all
that for nothing nothing the markets
haven't done nothing this is what I hate
when I put it all this time and I
literally don't catch any trades or have
any high probability trade opportunities
but you know what it's part of the game
it's part of the risk to reward of this
business I got to suck it up a lot of
you guys got to do that too realize that
even if you stay up and there's nothing
happens don't feel timely invested and
like okay now because I've been sitting
on this chair for 6 hours I have to then
take a trade and the market has to give
me an opportunity no dude that is not
going to happen so let me show you guys
what I mean so beforehand you guys can
see that the account currently right now
is still sitting at the same
$2,000 and here the markets you can see
audusd currently has had the push to the
area of interest just how we wanted to
and we haven't had the rejection that
we've been looking for so we just had
that engulfing about 2 hours ago which
this is going to pretty much give me my
confirmation that I might be wanting to
enter this trade very very very soon 30
minute time frame I want to have the
break of this little neckline of The
Head and Shoulders before I actually
enter this position so it can just
confirm that it's rejecting this area of
Interest next is gbpnzd so we've
actually had the break out of this area
now I'm going to be waiting for the
deeper retest of it in order for us to
actually take this trade to the upside
4H hour looks very very very very nice
just waiting for the little higher low
to now enter this position to the upside
USD JPY currently literally did nothing
I thought this was going to be the pair
that we were going to take and it was
going to give us the opportunity but it
never gave us that rejection Eng
engulfing Candlestick that we were
looking for and it completely avoided
this loss to Perfection so for now I am
not interested in USD JPY GBP JPY same
exact thing we were anticipating for
price to have a break and retest under
this level and we didn't so we avoided
this loss as well and then AUD JPY
waiting for the break and reach the
under we didn't do it so we avoided this
loss as well so you guys can see how
pretty much some of the analysis are
playing out in our favor in terms of
what we're looking for to enter the
position and then the others just simply
didn't now what do we do in that case we
said and forget we we move on and only
focus on the markets that matter there's
no need to take a trade in a market that
we are emotionally invested to or timely
invested into it just because we stayed
up on night looking at it no we only
take trades that have a high probability
trade setup and if those trades don't
have a high probability trade setup even
if we looked at it for 30 days we simply
don't take it don't care if it's your
favorite pair don't care if your uh if
it's the pair has the same letters as
your name or if there's a birthday uh
all this superstitious [\h__\h] [\h__\h] that it
doesn't matter what matters is if it has
a high probability trait and none of
them don't so let's see if audusd or
gbpnzd give us the entry signals that we
need so once again it's currently 10:00
in the morning and I will update you
guys hopefully within the hour all right
guys market update it is currently
1217 in the afternoon so about 2 and 1
half hours is the last time we did the
last market update patience patience
patience I can't describe how much
patience factors in to becoming
successful in trading because it avoids
so many different losses I just avoided
three losses in one day because of
patience so let me show you right now
the trade that we were interested in
taking a couple hours ago and how we
just avoided the loss so audusd we were
interested in taking this trade as soon
as we broke and retested under this neck
line as you can clearly see it did not
break and retest under the neck line it
created the right shoulder but it never
retested and rejected it so we did not
take the trade patience patience
patience this is the key to success
right here you can't just get fomo
because you see this pattern right here
and you feel like you have to get in
because it's going to have the push if
it has the push phenomenal great that's
what you want cuz it's going to confirm
to you that the move is actually
happened and you just wait for the
little pullback to then enter but you
can't get foam mod just because you see
the pattern because the pattern happens
doesn't mean that it has to have the
move so we avoided that loss to
Perfection I I'm still very much
interested in it I just have to wait for
now this Market to have a better
rejection from this area of interest and
then gvp nzd we are still waiting for
price to have the retest of this
structure level to take the trade to the
upside oh look who's back huh been doing
trade up this by myself huh thanks for
coming back to work no you don't get one
of those until you haven't been here all
week I've been doing this by myself
holding the camera like this sucks so we
finally have seas back he decided to
come back to work welcome back brother
this deed to wake up yeah literally it
is right now 12:57 at night pretty much
about to be 1 in the morning trade
update the market has played out drum
roll
please we got a pump at the gym today
can you
tell one of these days I'm going to get
a cramp from that's going of suck but
yeah we hit the gym and the market has
moved exactly how we've been
anticipating so earlier on 8 UD USD we
were anticipating for price to have a
break of this neckline right here I was
showing you guys on the 30 minute time
frame the market did have the break but
I was waiting for the retest did not
have the retest and I [\h__\h] missed the
whole entire move but I do believe that
this Market could have a pullback now in
London session and then in New York it's
going to have the push again just having
to move very early on into the session
and I feel like it's not just done yet I
feel like this is going to Wick back up
on the daily time frame
feel like the 1 hour time frame has to
create that lower high it's going to
give us that beautiful entry to then
head to the downside gvp nzd never had
the retest how we wanted it so price
literally just went straight to the
upside good thing we avoided this trade
right here because
honestly I did not want to drive the
beetle so this trade made us avoid
taking the trade on the beetle fantastic
because now what we can do is put the
money at risk on the real position so we
avoided taking this counter Trend trade
and now we're going to look for the
retest of the cells of this neckline of
The Head and Shoulders next is USD JPY
currently you guys can see that we're
having some type of reaction but we're
having it at the top of this level of
support and resistance the only way that
I would be interested in this position
is once and if we decide to have a break
and retest at this level to then head to
the downside daily time frame Clos very
strongly bullish and the daily time
frame is now bullish because we've
broken above here the least that I can
ask for on this position is for the 4H
hour to go bearish in order for us to be
interested in this trade same thing with
GBP JPY we've had a push to the upside
daily creating above the level of
support and resistance throughout here
very strong resistance very strong
support we've closed above so it could
retest and head to the upside so not
that interested and lastly AUD JPY same
exact thing broke above the resistance
using it as support running out we can
potentially head to the upside now what
I'm going to be waiting for on this is
the same thing a break and retest under
so the main pair that is about to be
ready to enter is audusd like I said and
it had the [\h__\h] move we just missed
it now I'm just going to wait for this
trade to have the pullback to enter the
trade and gbpnzd a rejection to then
sell looks like it's going to be another
really long night don't fall asleep
today
[\h__\h] got my rest so all right
we're good bet stay tuned don't miss
another trade
[\h__\h] drum roll
please drum roll
please mother [\h__\h] trade update
19,000
[\h__\h] dollars in profit now what how
fast did this happen very fast let me
show you guys so right now USD JPY
exactly how I explained yesterday we
literally explained the only way we'd be
interested in taking this position right
here is if we have a break retest and
then sell price literally broke retested
sell exactly what we anticipated perfect
entry signal literally 1 hour ago as you
guys can see down here a 8:00 in the
morning currently right now it is 10:00
in the morning so as soon as we entered
this position Market immediately started
heading to the downside look how fast
this momentum of this Market is
currently moving beautiful 30 minutes
bearish engulfing evening St formation
15-minute time frame as soon as the
Candlestick close boom just completely
downside move which is absolutely
beautiful this is the trade that we
avoided yesterday and we avoided to take
the loss cuz never retested and gave us
the engulfing of this left head and the
right shoulder now avoided this loss we
can remove this now we're have this
position right here we're is looking
decent right obviously I'm just hyped
because I risked a lot more than I
should have because we're trying to turn
$20,000 into 40 so I can literally close
the position right now and then we will
have the $40,000 in profit that we need
literally oh oh [\h__\h] oh oh oh what oh
[\h__\h] what the [\h__\h] just happened oh [\h__\h]
oh oh whoa whoo whoo whoo wo wo wo wo wo
wo wo wo
wo don't you [\h__\h] do
it hold on I'm in the I'm in shock right
now yo I saw 50,000 it was it was at the
bottom of that Wick right there is news
happening right now probably well now
I'm on edge I'm going to put an alarm
right around my entry signal just to let
me know that it is up there I have to
put a an alarm at the bottom of this
Candlestick if we if we get a
Candlestick to go back under that Wick
we're pretty much good we are
good
okay you don't want
this all right so currently right now we
had a little quick uh spazz in the
markets this is what trading in the
market is this is why people go crazy
when they risk more money than they
should if I was risking you know 3 4 5%
like a normal human I wouldn't even care
oh right now $40,000 cting and profit
that's it all we care about next
audusd so yesterday we anticipated after
this lower low that we were going to
have a lower high pullback to retest
this structure level and then the EMA to
head to the downside price did not do
that so we clearly did not enter this
position GBP CHF oh [\h__\h] look at this
beautiful trade so we have pulled up to
the area of interest of the head and
shoulders time frame exactly how we've
been anticipating and we are officially
having our reaction Candlestick from
this area now if you go down to the one
hour you can very clearly see how we
shifted the structure right here we went
from higher high higher low higher high
to now lower low this is great
phenomenal amazing
Perfecto now what we have to do is wait
for a lower high to then sell this
position just exactly how we did here
lower low lower high engulfing sell
lower low need the lower high engulfing
and then sell so this is exactly what we
did here we had the lower low lower high
engulfing and then sell you guys just
seen the [\h__\h] pattern here it's
literally the same [\h__\h] every single
time this [\h__\h] got this [\h__\h] got me
hyped right now we we we can't even look
at it we can't it's going to [\h__\h] with
us we got to just set it forget if this
trade hits down here you know we'll be
like at 150,000 right you understand
that do you have that clear this
Candlestick just opened and didn't yeah
there was definitely news let me
actually go check if there was news okay
there you go so we actually did have
news right now at 10:00 a.m. Tuesday
September 3rd 10: in the morning USD red
flag I manufacturing blah
clearly you can see how fundamentals
always follow technicals this is the
perfect example of it obviously it's
going to have a little spasm like but
the overall move is going to follow the
technical analysis of
it so for now last market update to
right now at 10:04 in the morning so the
last update right now at 10:05 in the
morning is going to be
$225,000 in
profit said I forget
so by the way yes this is a real weapon
it's never been loaded before it's never
been used I kind of just like it for
decoration this sh was
$5,000 goldplated col 45 you know I just
feel like a feel like a narc with this
[\h__\h] you know
so trade update right it's kind of
annoying because every single [\h__\h]
trade that I predict I've been I've been
predicting them I've just been so
selective about it which is good but
it's also bad cuz I'm getting a little
bit of
a fear inside of me but I'm a man I got
this and I got to lead by example and
I'm showing you guys this is part of the
Journey of the 100 to the mill we
started off good not giving a [\h__\h] and
now I'm at the point where I'm giving
too much of a [\h__\h] cuz I don't want to
blow the account but I got to remove
that mindset it's a limited belief so I
can continue to scale the account trying
to get this across to you guys right so
trade up there right now the account is
currently at 3,00
,400 and you guys can see that the
position is actively pulling back
further than we anticipated and I
actually want the 4 Hour to close like
this I wanted to close a very strong
dogee because then the next Candlestick
should fill that very very very well the
1 hour just closed right now along with
the 30 minutes as as a nice 30 minute
dogee if this next Candlestick could
have this right here beautiful amazing
we we we need that cuz this would be
literally the same pattern is right here
to then continue selling to the downside
but I might close this position out to
then potentially enter gbpnzd Because
this is the one that is actually
retesting the daily neckline of The Head
and Shoulders a lot cleaner it's
retesting and rejecting the EMA the
round psychological level this trade
just overall looks a lot better and I
might just remove the liability from the
other pair and just transfer it to this
one so I'm going to be waiting for the
to pull back on some rejections here and
then there I'll determine the decision
that I made and it's so annoying because
we've been calling this position since
yesterday we never got the pull back and
the trade has been moving [\h__\h]
beautifully but it is what it is we're
going to continue to monitor this trade
literally every single tick like I am
here on the 15minute time frame watching
every single tick because if this
position comes into like look where I
have my alarm I had I have alarm set up
1469 that's about the 30 minute EMA 1
hour EMA if it gets there I think it
could just continue breaking to the
upside so if it gets there I'm just
going to close my losses there and then
just move on to the next one cuz I'm not
like at this point in the challenge if
the position from right away doesn't go
straight into profit and just stays
there I am going to Simply cut my losses
but if the position goes straight into a
loss I can't do anything about it but if
the position goes from a winning
position to then up to a losing one I'd
be dumb to not close it out if it was a
regular trade I wouldn't give a [\h__\h] but
since we're in the challenge I have to
be very strategic because clearly the
trade might not go in the direction that
I am anticipating a trade is supposed to
go from the moment you enter it straight
into your takeprofit or straight into
your stop loss but if it goes in between
and it starts going back like it doesn't
hit your takeprofit and it starts going
back up into your stop loss well the
trade might just reverse be a you know
be a step ahead and close it out at half
the loss so we're analyzing as we go so
stay tuned
today we're going to pay a stranger's
rent I'm guessing the rent can be 1,200
bucks how how much more or less do you
guys pay for rent in this area would you
guys
say okay one
second wait one
second I'm sorry what see
we always
get something else I can help you guys
out
with yeah yeah yeah like here
maybe help you guys out maybe
thank you so
much no guess you then I hope it can
help out for you
guys bye bye all right so we just got
back home right now from the giving back
to people and paying People's rent and I
am a firm believer that whenever you
give back you're going to receive every
single time there's not one time when
you give back to somebody or something
that it's not going to come back to you
but I've never seen it happen like today
as soon as I gave back something was
given back to me always happens but not
like the day where it happened
immediately so I just posted right now
on my Instagram by the way if you guys
don't check out my Instagram literally
hundred thousands of you guys check out
my stories every single day if you don't
follow me you're missing out so I
literally just posted right now that the
trade has hit the alarm what does that
say right there we are good s and forget
do you guys remember earlier when I put
the alarm on trading view what would
happen if it were to hit that point you
guys remember
the account currently is sitting at
$49 [\h__\h]
th000 showing you guys that when you
give back you're going to receive always
and it's just crazy it gives me Goose
ons because we just did it right now in
a natural format not even thought about
it too much and look at this it's coming
right back to us let me show you guys
the charts so you guys can clearly see
how earlier this morning price had
pulled back into then retest this area
of interest and the structure level and
I had explained if price price continues
to go up and hit this EMA we're going to
be looking to get out because it can
easily go into our stop loss but if
price reaches and it breaks under this
Wick we're pretty much good and we can
continue to set and forget this position
because it's going to then be creating a
lower low and as of right now it is at
$50,000 the highest the account has been
so far we have turned $100 into $50,000
in front of you guys every single day
and it's exactly what I explained on the
4H hour time frame if we were to have
this humongous 4-Hour dogee we're going
to fill that Wick it's just how it works
you have to follow the set foret
strategy so for now it is literally
clear traffic from here to here this is
the first takeprofit point that we have
for a one to three risk to reward which
if the account does get to there we can
easily close at
$70,000 now I know what you guys might
be thinking but Alex close the trade
there the profit for the week is 40k
it's like sure you're right but this
trade has so much more potential and you
know what I'm accepting the risk if the
trade were to reverse from here and go
back into my entry I'm not going to give
a [\h__\h] because I accept the risk I am a
firm believer that this trade has a lot
more downside potential than just this
move right here so you know what I'm
going to
do one more
time one more
time right here I don't think they're
ready
so we're going to [\h__\h] set and forget
we'll check back in later see you
guys drum roll please drum roll
please Market [\h__\h] update
[\h__\h] ah
oh oh no
oh there you go
65,000 [\h__\h] dollars in profit on the
account the highest we have been why
because we set and forget set and forget
now you guys can clearly see here on the
trading view yesterday we were
borderline [\h__\h] we almost went
straight into our drw down where I would
have closed out the position and this
trade would have went straight into
profit yesterday we had a lower low and
I'm like all right cool now we have a
lower high this is a good spot to Stell
new lower low now we're having a new
lower high for a new potential lower low
which in three [\h__\h] minutes if it
closes like
this boys it's sails to the bottom sails
to the bottom is that even a [\h__\h]
thing I guess it is now I guess it is
now cuz we can make anything we want now
we can I can make up a word called
br all right so this Market is looking
really [\h__\h] good right now dude I
would love for in the next 3 minutes for
this Candlestick to body Candlestick
close under this point right here so
even on the 30 minute time frame we
create a new lower low if we create a
new lower low then this can pretty much
be confirmed to continue to head to the
downside but I might want to close the
position right then and there because we
are approaching this level of structure
here and the price could have some type
of reaction to then the upside but I do
think overall we could continue heading
to the downside I just can personally
see this maybe having a little
retracement and then moving down and
honestly I don't want to be part of that
I just want to get my profits and bounce
so with the next 2 and 1 half minutes
we're going to find out and in those two
and a half minutes I'll just be updating
you guys on these other markets so
audusd we had the take profit pretty
much hit perfectly where we were looking
to enter this trade and then exit this
position right around here so price had
the move
perfectly
audjpy had the break how I was pretty
much anticipating but now we're having
the retest so now we can potentially
enter position cuz you guys got to keep
in mind dude it is literally Wednesday I
can close out this position right now
and I can still catch another position
and turn the say CL at 65,000 I can
still turn that to 120 this same week I
don't have to but if there's great
opportunity ities I'm going to do it so
this is literally a perfect example of
that this has had a beautiful daily body
Candlestick closure under now we can
have a quick lower high to then continue
heading to the downside
gbpnzd this this this this this John
right here is loading up if this daily
Candlestick closes as a dogee the next
day is going to be a very strong move
that's it done done it's just going to
happen [\h__\h] it done setting possible
scenarios it's just going to happen
because I said
so that's just how [\h__\h] Works nowadays
USD JPY no jbp JPY has had the break now
it's having a little [\h__\h] retest so
we're going to be waiting on that nzd
JPY BR and then this one's BR so
basically our only Market that we're
looking at right now is USD JPY to see
what we're about to do right now and the
GBP nzd for a little break and retested
and sell
and the audjpy for a quick read this to
S so usdjpy we got 30 seconds right now
33 let's just let's just do this
together right let's have this countdown
together so we have here
$66,000 and let's go on the 30 minute
time frame so we can see if it's going
to close on you know what want to know
what would suck so bad if right now that
should
just that would suck so bad all right
come come
on 9 8 7 6 5 4 3 two
one oh [\h__\h] oh my god oh [\h__\h] oh [\h__\h] yo
oh [\h__\h] yo no yo yo I can't yo I can't
make this up dude yo I can't make this
up dude holy holy holy [\h__\h] holy [\h__\h]
bro yo stoping
dude oh you 100,000 yo there's no
way yo there's no
way yo yo there's no there's no way oh I
kind of hurt
myself is my watch okay yeah it's fine
doesn't matter we could buy another one
oh oh oh dude oh yo we're about to be at
100,000 that's [\h__\h]
crazy yo the countdown is
legendary
yo no no no no we got to keep going we
got to keep
going got to keep going we got to keep
going 95
95 oh 97 yo it's going to hit 100,000 yo
it's going to hit 100,000 we got to keep
going look dude I think I think we got
into to
like dude do we got up to
there now now I just got to
focus what is this
on why did do
this this right here shows you guys that
the [\h__\h]
fundamentals will follow the technicals
all right I got to focus dude market
update boys market update boys and
ladies and gentlemen we have
officially officially closed the
accounts at no no no drum roll please
thank you very much we have officially
closed at
90,000 [\h__\h] dollars on the account
now not going to lie we were a little
bit impulsive I can't even lie I was
literally looking at this and I was
contemplating do I close do I hold do I
hold do I close do I close do I hold and
usually what happens when new Spike like
that happens is it'll come into here and
then it'll Wick it'll create a ginormous
Wick and you know what I said [\h__\h] that
I don't want to you know risk that so I
ended up closing the position somewhere
around maybe right around here so if I
would have literally just waited for the
Candlestick to close I would have
literally gotten a lot more profit
because the price ended up going all the
way down here if I would have kept a
hole down there I would have easily
easily gotten 106
$110,000 but you know what I am very
content I am very I'm more than
satisfied we doubled the goal for the
week because the goal for the week was
to turn 20 to 40 dude we turned 20 to 90
so the goal for next week we have just
done it this [\h__\h] week right now I
was literally just telling you guys I if
we close right now at 60,000 I can maybe
turn it into 120 this week dude we just
got so much closer to that goal right
now if we would have closed that 40 or
50 like we're already there on this one
week and it's only Wednesday it is
literally Wednesday at 12:00 we still
have a whole 2 and 1/2 days of good
market movement so for now I'm going to
continue to set and forget this trade
and I'm going to stay interested on GBP
nzd to continue sells to the downside
break and retest to the downside
audjpy is literally having the reaction
exactly how I explained we're having the
reaction from this level of support and
resistance to another downside so I'm
not going to chase this I'm just going
to wait to see it gives me a better
entry and the GBP JPY going to see if it
gives me a better
entry boys dude
where make sure that thing's good you
know
boys all I can say
is [\h__\h] seven forget so now you guys
may ask Alex what do you do after a day
like this what do you do honestly
nothing right you just it's just another
boring day but today's a bit different
coincidentally enough that we had a
crazy trade like this this we're going
to go look at new houses so I might move
into a new house probably in the next
month or two because I like moving every
year paying more in rent because it just
opens my mind more for forces me to make
more money and um I don't know if to
move to another house to a penthouse so
come with us to go tour these different
apartments and houses to see where we're
going to go to we're actually late so
let's go
[Music]
um I mean look at it dude literally I
literally felt like I was in Scarface
walking through this house bro they for
sure assassinate somebody in this house
no doubt and they for sure move drugs no
doubt I mean you look like you do the
same thing no I'm a Traer
bro what what did you think look at it
look at it I honestly s thought the same
thing but we we're going to have to
sacrifice a lot yo brother no parking
house there's no parking I like my house
right now like if I can put my house
there perfect done
[\h__\h] how much does that one go for a
month that one's going for $45,000 a
month that's [\h__\h] two times when
we're paying on hours I know but like
it's like the cheapest one in this whole
island just not because I'm looking for
the cheapest one is because there's just
nothing other like there's nothing else
available like look at this house you
think somebody that owns this house
is going to ever sell it no look at that
he has a pond in front of his house like
this guy's never going to sell that
house like these guys hit the gold mine
and then they just stick on it the
people that buy the houses are rich they
don't ever want to rent it out if I were
to buy one of these houses I would never
want to rent it out so the only ones
that are still available are these
little shitty ones right here look these
little shitty ones are the only ones
that are available you have to buy it
demolish it and then construct it into
something like this and there's
literally only probably 15 20 homes in
this whole entire Island left for that
type of opportunity because they're all
built up like this they're literally all
already being demolished and they're all
already fixing it up look there's
workers 24/7 fixing them up there's
rarely any ones available so right now
we're going to go to the flat iron again
to go view the biggest and craziest
Penthouse in all of Miami going for
$60,000 a month and then we're going to
go to the brand new building Austin
Martin we're going to go check out the
third biggest unit in the whole entire
building so I don't know we got to make
a decision you're not first you're
last
second if
you second place is the first loser
always always remember that always and
third place is The Biggest Loser in
third place dude who remembers the guy
in third place think about that some
people might remember you in second but
like ah he didn't get first
like it goes way that
way and then have the second floor and
then the third floor
rooftop 60,000 a month is [\h__\h] crazy
dude like it's it is but but but it
isn't like d with the trade that you
made today you [\h__\h] basically pay for
it yeah but trade almost say
sof um cuz for me just it's burnt cash
you get me it's literally money just
being like GT3
RS never mind GT3 um it's just burnt
dude like I'm literally just pixie dust
Gone Forever 60k on that's like some
that is like somebody that went to
college studied for 4
years Works
overtime that's their salary 60k a year
and I'm just paying it on rent bro the
disrespect uh towards money is crazy
just shows you guys that money is not
real it's not you just click a couple
buttons and make that money it's not
real you don't have to work for it you
don't have to literally like do labor
work to get that money back just use
your [\h__\h]
brain now we're going to go see the
Austin Martin which is that one right
there so this unit is literally the
newest and most prestiged unit in all of
Miami right now the only thing I don't
like is not as much of in the city it's
like dude like if we're going to be in
the city we're going to be in the city
but I don't want to be half ass in the
city they just sold the main Penthouse
or the second main penthouse for 2
million the unit that you we were just
at was a $20 million unit that's what
they're selling at so they either sell
it for 20 million or rent it for
$60,000 and then here I come being like
a dumbass and renting yeah I'll pay your
mortgage here let's go I'll do it
all right so Austin Martin sick
amenities can't even lie definitely one
of the best amenities I've ever seen I
mean what would you expect it's a brand
new building 2024
2025 but it literally looks like a JV
version of the unit that we just saw I
feel like such a [\h__\h] if I were to get
that and they're worth the same price
one is worth well technically this one
they're listing it for like 50,000 the
other one 60 but you know I get the
alexg negotiation like get [\h__\h]
done but no like my standards are so
[\h__\h] up after looking at that other
unit bro like what do you think we just
have to do the other unit bro three
floors versus one floor
mhm and it's literally the highest
building in that area versus here on the
other side of the yeah of the house we
have like buildings yeah that's super
cringe in my opinion and you walk in and
the first thing you see is the master
bedroom what the [\h__\h] that that honestly
didn't make sense yeah that was really
weird
sorry so
sorry whoa didn't see you there how's my
acting all right so I'm not mad but
trade update I'm not mad
but I would say emotions caught to me
I'm going explain to you guys why so
just to show you guys currently right
now it is 8:00 at night so I just got
back home about an hour ago from viewing
the houses and Pen houses you guys can
see the account is currently at 90,000
so we haven't obviously done anything
since we closed it but look at the
position look at this [\h__\h] so the
position was literally creating that big
push to the downside to continue going
to the downside so I close here on
emotion because the market had obviously
the big push at that moment and I was
just seeing more numbers than I should
have but I [\h__\h] up because I literally
was not practicing what I preach which
is watch the charts not the numbers I
was literally watching the numbers and I
got lost because I saw something close
to 100,000 like if that matters
obviously it matters for the challenge
but it doesn't matter for the charts so
this chart whatever it's doing right
here is going to directly reflect on The
Meta Trader so if I would have just
continued to set him for foret this
position right now we would be up a 1
to6 risk reward where we pretty much
closed out at let's just say 1 to 4 so
we could have gotten an extra two risk
to reward on this position meaning we
could have been right now floating in
profit
about30 to
$150,000 I'm not mad right I I don't
care but I am acknowledging the fact
that I did get emotional in that very
moment I was super hyped and I was
scared of losing the money and giving it
back to the markets I can guarantee you
if this would have been a regular
position that I was taking outside of
the challenge I would have probably
continued to hold the position simply
because the technicals still indicate
that price is going to continue heading
to the downside so I was emotionally
invested into the position
and the fact that I continue to hold
throughout two days of it going from
Break Even to then having the poten to
go back is already strong now to hold
after news fundamental like that I just
I just couldn't handle it I just wanted
to get my profits for the week and then
done so that's also another reason I
surpassed the go for the week I'm not
I'm not greedy but I am acknowledging
that I did get emotional and I'm not
going to let that happen to me during
now throughout the challenge because
boys we're getting close it's feeling
just like the it's feeling just like
when I was reaching the 2300k on the
last 100 to the
mill [\h__\h] starts coming up faster haters
are not coming up faster talking
[\h__\h] making some [\h__\h] up it's
all it's all happening again it's like
it's literally what I said when I turn
$100 to2 200 no one cares when I turn
200 to 400 no one cares when I turn 4 no
one cares oh but when I start making
more money in one day that they made in
their whole entire year oh now they're
pissed off well boys you're about to get
so mad cuz I'm going to do this I'm
going to turn the [\h__\h] $100 into a
million whether you like it are not
simple so this right here would have put
us a bigger step forward into that
challenge but sadly it has not because
we closed the position out earlier which
is fine it is still currently right now
Wednesday so we still have Thursday and
Friday so we still have two good days of
the markets audusd is currently having a
push to the upside which we're not
really interested in it AUD JPY had the
retest exactly how I anticipated and
then had to push exactly how I
anticipated which is you know not ideal
we can potentially wait for another
bigger pullback on The Daily to then
enter the sell to the downside which
would then create a 4-Hour double top
retest of this area to then head to the
downside GBP nzd is not having the shift
the structure how we wanted it to so we
simply are not interested in this trade
USD JPY for me the trade is done I not
interested in looking at this position
anymore I don't want to add positions I
don't want to scale in I don't want to
add nothing the trade is done whenever I
win a trade that's it I don't want to
look at it I don't want to deal deal
with it I don't want to get involved in
it because any decision that I'm going
to make on this trade right now will
have some type of influence on me
thinking that I can predict everything
that this Market can do simply because I
just caught a winning trade so when I
win a trade as soon as it hits my
takeprofit I like to stop looking at it
I just don't want to trade anymore I
want to find the same opportunity that I
took on just a different Market it's
kind of like when you take those other
kind of Trades like once you take the
trade and you hit take profit you bounce
you don't stick around you don't keep
watching dude you
bounce and you don't ever take the same
trade two times in one day never make
that mistake G gentlemen and ladies fine
you
don't bro I could have been a comedian
dud so when you take the trade and a
hitch take profit you bounce you s and
forget that [\h__\h] you look for another
trade so we're not interested in this
tradeing anymore so now we move on to
then
gbpjpy where we are then waiting for
this to come back and retest had the
retest how I wanted to but we were
obviously in USD JPY so we're not going
to wait for a retest of here to then
sell and then ND JPY same exact thing
we've had the break now we're looking
for the retest to then pretty much sell
so oh and GBP CHF [\h__\h] this I don't even
care about
it ladies and gentlemen it's been good
day long day I'm not going to go hit the
gy and then to see where the day takes
us so s and forget so s and
[Music]
forget TR up
trade up there no trades as of
right no trades as right now remember
that is the market when you see that you
see the market when you take a loss you
take it out on the market when you take
a win you take it out in the market so
get a figure in your office in your
space and label it
as the market so you can take care of it
right now trade update we are currently
up
850,000 no I'm kidding the day will come
though when I do say a trade update just
like that account right now is still
currently at 90,000 but we will be up
that amount soon trust me so as of right
now we are currently looking at GBP nzd
actually before that let's just take a
second to admire the set and forget
strategy playing out to Perfection by
following the trend with the trade this
trade if we would have continued to set
and forget would have given us over a 1
to 7 ver to reward doubling our profit
where we would have been at about
$170,000 in the account but let's just
pretend like that didn't even happen
anymore let's go to now a new trading
opportunity that we're interested in
trading gbpnzd yesterday we had a retest
of the neckline of The Head and
Shoulders daily dogee and rejection from
the Ma and round psychological level
21200 then here on the 4our we are
currently now having a beautiful shift
structure and the shift of structure is
a clear higher high higher low higher
high higher low higher high shift of
structure you want to count this as the
lower high blah blah blah we shifted you
want to count this as the lower high
it's still bearish but the one hour
looks beautiful why well because we have
a left head right shoulder retest from
that neckline retest of round
psychological level
2.200 and now the 30 minute is having
that rejection engulfing Candlestick
that we're looking for we have the shift
the structure 15 minute is bullish 30
minute is still bearish this is not a
bad trade at all to take right now like
if I were to take this position it could
be something like this my stop loss
could be somewhere right around here for
about 40 Pips and then my first take
profit let's just say we label it at
this area right here this can be a quick
one to three risk reward now the only
thing I don't like is that it is
currently Thursday so since it's
currently Thursday we basically have
about we have less than 24 hours in this
trade because this trade we take it
right now we have to let all of the rest
of New York session which is not much
currently right now it is 11:40 in the
morning it's a bit late so there's not
much volume left in the markets we're
pretty much betting on the London
session of tonight and a little bit of
the New York session tomorrow which
truthfully if you just look at the
weekly Candlestick you have to ask
yourself what are the odds of this
weekly Candlestick now having a wick
rejection to the downside within the
next 24
hours probably not that hot if you go to
the Daily time frame you got to ask
yourself what are the probabilities of
this having the full rejection that we
want in 24 hours probably not that high
what this is probably going to create
now is this daily dogee as well or maybe
like another little red and guling
Candlestick like this rejection the area
and then the next day we'll have the
pullback which this could be a trade
that we could be very interested in
taking come Monday or Sunday night so
just taking a little bit over on the
analysis on this Market these are all
things that you know once you're an
experienced Trader you just start
looking into an all different types of
angles and it just starts all making
sense cuz at the end of the day you got
to ask yourself yo what makes more sense
to take it now or to take it Monday well
why take it now why take it Monday you
build a scenario like this and it almost
just make sense right away so yeah I
we'll update you guys on these markets
right now it is 12:00 on Thursday today
let's see where the day takes
us so today so you got just the F right
now we're going
to get some gearing and get ready for
bumper
cars so today we have some special
guests with our bumper car challenge we
have Neil Jack DHI billionaire Barber
we're about to get some helmets mouth
pieces make sure the boys are protected
which reminds me of the Super
Bowl okay so if if you were to like
potentially be like a collision of a
vehicle which one would you want to wear
probably that one okay
black one on the bottom this one the
black one on the
bottom can you try it on let me see how
it look on come on you know who I am yes
bro I know you [\h__\h] come on you're were
to be like in a collision of a vehicle
would you would you think this would
work yes all right turny it
on C pillow oh yeah D this might do the
job try that on take a punch yeah don't
miss oh hard don't miss I I can hit it
hard though don't miss okay so just
straight into the yeah I'm hit it super
hard there you go really
good like that's not going to do
anything can you
try hold thank
you work yeah something won't get in
your eye you got protection man it's
better than no protection all right we
take we need five we need five of them
look at how you look dude
I think I'm ready you're making a mark
in history right now we don't need
that the we don't Litter we don't we're
good for the economy
[Music]
[Applause]
[\h__\h] the experience I I I'll take blame
I was late the cars were whatever we're
going to do it again but like double the
size bigger we're going to have ramps
and obstacles and [\h__\h] D give us like 2
3 days notice so we can invite more
people okay but you guys will pull up
again you actually get in the car yes
I'll do it next time I'll drive you got
my word okay you got your and take off
the [\h__\h] airbags okay but you pull up
again yes take the the windshield should
Beed even the
windows the windows is good I'm going
take this mou I'm mold it I'm bring a
helmet you bring it back and I'm
crashing into your ass it we good catch
me yeah well you
know that's how I get hurt they do all
that and then I throw one rock it
bounces off I'll throw your arm
yeah yeah I don't know if you know I
never said that I could yo I I used to
Fitch like a like a 90 yo watch out bro
I don't want no wait watch out yo watch
out watch
out see
that yeah I used to pitch a while
ago oh that was a long shot that was
nice all right let's see a left Lefty
Lefty what the
he's
excited like we're in the danger zone
head
up out not front
windshield what is that watch out watch
[Applause]
out don't be shoting [\h__\h] out here dog
that's a bad
idea nigg said
[\h__\h] this
[\h__\h] ra ra ra
ra oh [\h__\h]
[Music]
[Laughter]
you crashing the building
bro out of
gas where the [\h__\h] did Norway
go you can do the
honors that's it I should
break what the [\h__\h] is that oh [\h__\h] all
right trade update so you guys can see
here
audusd currently had a ginormous push to
the downside on oh [\h__\h] Dam that would
have sucked if you would have taken that
position
gbpnzd would have been a major major out
look D I have the podcast right now GBP
JPY no USD JPY bro if you would have
continued to hold this position right
here we would have literally literally
probably turned these same $90,000 to
about like $50 right now we're currently
at $90,000 on the account and um
actually let's go upstairs so I can give
you the better trade up there right I
can't I can't there's a surprice coming
that's why what surprise is coming dude
I don't know he's a little slow but he's
not supposed to be
slow this guy
[Music]
bro you're Savage dude bro you did it
bro congrat [\h__\h] dude he I was going
to get a it bro when did you do it what
the [\h__\h] last week last week how the
[\h__\h] didn't I know dude what the [\h__\h] no
I was going to surpris you bro yeah look
bro I was trying to get a 48 and then
the down was like 90k so I was like [\h__\h]
that a [\h__\h] that bro congrats bro yo you
think you you could you could you could
drift for sure don't bro that'd be
gangster bro we got to do it you don't
yo we got to do it 100% I'll help you
worst case I just hold the Ste with yo
congrats bro
yeah bro stupid gangster shoot the
Flames it shoots Flames yeah yeah like
900 horsep 8 900 horsepower
[Music]
[\h__\h] God
bro congratulations are the seats
comfortable or no right yeah they
actually really are bro yeah okay when I
when I finish meeting right now I'll
pull up on you let you finish this [\h__\h]
real quick and I'll pull up I see you D
hey bye congrats
[Music]
bro God what a Savage bro what a Savage
so this why want to do the trade update
outside bro we never do trade updates
outside so trade update huh sneaking
[\h__\h] huh that was uh sus I was
like dude we do trade updates in the
computer we don't do trade updates
outside like no we have to I'm like okay
now it makes sense by the way that's
crazy because like Jordan can't even
walk right now and the fact that he
traded his R8 and you guys have seen
Jordan he's been popping in and out
throughout the whole entire series
currently battling cancer and the fact
that he cannot walk and he just bought
himself a brand new 600 LT shows you
guys that he's doing whatever he can to
shift his mindset to getting better so
he could drive the car he loves cars so
he wants to drive drive the car now what
is he going to do he's going to put
himself in a situation where he has to
force himself to get better so he can
then drive the car so I don't know man I
think that's like super inspirational
and the [\h__\h] that he's going through is
ridiculous bro he's been battling this
now for like two three years he's doing
chemo now and stuff so about the Jordan
we're going to pull up on him tonight
maybe we get some clips of that if not
we'll leave it for next week we got to
introduce all the cars that I've gotten
as well you know I don't think I've done
a full-blown Bugatti intro on the car
the new G wagon maner that I got got and
I just added another thing to the
addition and we got to incorporate
Jordan we're going to incorporate Jordan
next week 100% see if you can do donuts
with the stick which would be super sick
so with that being said trade update
right so as you guys can see or as you
guys just saw the account last left off
at
$90,000 it pisses me out just a little
bit not a lot that we could have
actually closed this trade and a lot
more profit so this trade we closed out
up here impulsively because of the move
but if we would have simply continued to
set and forget this trade throughout the
whole entire week we would have ended
off with a 1 to n risk to reward we
would have literally closed at about
$200,000 on this one position right here
and you know it is what it is we hit the
goal for the week can get greedy and I'm
not I'm glad I didn't I didn't even see
this happen because I would have just
felt some type of weight but the
experience let me get away from the
charts get busy with other things so I
could only focus on what matters and
it's a different opportunity don't just
get fomo and want to chase this trade So
audusd currently on the market so taking
it back to
audusd we actually ended up having a
reaction from the takeprofit point that
we wanted to then price on the last 4
hours of Friday it ended up having a
ginormous bearish Candlestick rejection
left head right shoulder retest of the
neckline retest of the EMA Fe move to
the downside next week we're going to be
interested in taking this trade
continuously to the downside so we will
will be on the lookout for that if you
see it right now on the daily time frame
beautiful left head right shoulder
beautiful break of the neckline we're
going to now wait for a retest to pretty
much head to the downside and clearly
you can see last time we were up at this
resistance kind of created a little left
head and shoulders then we had a
ginormous push this is a way stronger
formation in the same exact Zone we
could expect the continuation pattern
from here and the AUD JPY we ended up
having to move exactly how we
anticipated but we never got the retest
how we wanted to even though we
technically did we did have the break we
did have the retest just wasn't as clean
as I wanted to gbpnzd avoided this loss
to Perfection due to what I explained um
and even though it does look like this I
this is a loss that I would have taken
like I would have taken this loss
probably consecutively for 2 years and I
would always ask myself why am I losing
why am I losing and it you know after
you get punched in the face a bunch of
times you have to realize to put your
defense up or to kind of get out the way
this is letting me know when to get out
the way from the markets because it is
simply not the right time to trade even
though yes it does look good and if this
were to happen on a Monday or Tuesday
I'd take it all day but towards the end
of the week I'm not going to take it
because I just know that the odds of it
playing out aren't as high as if it it
be a Monday or a Tuesday but the only
way you could actually get that is by
experience so don't you know break your
head or you know HTE yourself if you're
making these mistakes I made them for a
really long time now I just kept going
and learning from it and avoiding it now
so my win rate and my profitability is
not because of how many winning trades I
take it's because of how many losing
trades just like this I avoid remember
that so GBP nzd we'll update next week
exactly what we're going to be
interested in doing with it USD JPY we
already explained it GBP JPY had the
break and retest to sell and nzdjpy
never really gave us the entry so every
single one of these trades I literally
share every single Sunday with my
students I got on a live call with them
where I'm sharing with them every single
one of these trades where I'm looking to
get in where I'm looking to get out why
am I and why am I not I'm literally on a
live call with you guys answering your
questions and giving you the trades that
I'm taking in this 100 to the mill
series if you click the link in the
description below I have a video for you
that explains to you what the center
forget strategy is and how I do this
every single week if you join the center
forget Community you get my whole entire
course you get my private and Discord
Community where students are literally
discussing these trades all time look
let me actually show you guys my Discord
Community because I feel like I never
really ever show you guys this so look
this is my Discord Community there's a
little bit of an Insight so you can see
people here ask questions regarding the
challenge we have the actual trading
Community itself which is obviously
fully private and then we have the
success room where students are posting
you know profits and withdraw look this
guy why Cent Army is worth it um here
you can see this is last week's profits
he says he's learned a lot this guy
makes he turned $2,000 into $99,000 with
the trades that I literally just
explained that just happened right now
now um this guy right here made $16,000
on his funded account on ftmo like
literally this is all the profit and
loss from the students so this is all if
you guys click the link in description
below join the community you're going to
be able to see me live every single
Sunday at access to my course get access
to my community and my psychology series
if you're not part of the sun forget
Community honestly you're missing out so
next week is going to be week 10 of us
trying to turn $100 into a million and
the goal is to turn these $90,000 into
now
$180,000 which truthfully if we get a
nice one to four risk reward we can turn
the 90 to half a m and we're done in two
weeks baby when I'm done with this
challenge I'm out so join the set for
Community for abouts