do you ever wonder why some Traders are
consistently profitable and others
aren't using trend lines the difference
between the two is how each one uses the
trend lines or utilizes the trend lines
hi Traders welcome to my channel I am
Tory trades and I have been trading the
markets for over a decade now I'm here
to share valuable insights to help
elevate your trading so in this deep
Dive Master Class we're going to be
going over understanding trend lines
what they are and why they're
indispensable drawing accurate trend
lines step by step and then the strategy
how to implement these trend lines to
ultim Ely make decisions in the market
I'm also going to show real world
examples realtime examples with real
trades and real-time Market data and
even some Advanced
tips so if you don't already know trend
lines are the foundation of technical
analysis they represent the direction
and speed of a specific instrument and
they ultimately help Traders identify
Trends and possible reversals so what
types of trend lines do we have we have
two types of trend lines we've got an
upward trend line which connects higher
lows indicating bullish movement and
we've got a downward trend line which
connects lower highs and signals bearish
movement bullish trend lines bearish
trend lines upward trend lines downward
trend lines now how do we draw accurate
trend lines this is the fun part so
let's get into actually drawing these
trend lines and how I utilize them you
have to start with a time frame now what
does that mean you could be a day trader
swing Trader a long-term investor how do
the time frames come into play when
drawing our lines and the next thing is
Reliable Tools what tools are we going
to be using to draw these trend lines
I'm going to be be using a platform such
as trading View and I'll be using the
drawing tool to help me draw these trend
lines now let's get into some actual
chart time here we go all right we are
opening up trading view I've got a naked
chart on the screen right here in front
of your eyes I'm going to show you guys
how I mark up my charts how I use time
frames and the tools and which highs and
lows I use to utilize my trend lines and
how I draw them I'm going to start by
prefacing anytime I mark up my chart
with a completely new instrument I will
always do a top- down analysis I am
always going to start on the highest
time frame that I Poss possibly can so
right now we are looking at the ym this
is actually the M ym this is the micro e
mini Dow Jones this is a Futures
instrument and this is the micro version
of the Dow so if you guys know what the
Dow Jones is it's an index and through
the Futures Market you are able to trade
the indexes here or the indices all
right so we're going to start in the
monthly time frame so we're going to hit
the M up here in the top left and now
when drawing my trend lines the reason I
go to the higher time frame is because I
want an overall view I want to know
overall from the far left to the far
right the hard right Edge where the
price is trading at right now I want to
know overall which way is this trending
and I want to go ahead and mark up my
chart as well so we're going to start
from the beginning marking up our very
first trend line now ironically you
would think I would use the trend line
tool in trading view but I actually
don't because the trend line tool and
trading view gives a point a and point B
and it stops I want a point a and a
point B and then I want the line to go
indefinitely in One Direction so I
actually use the ray tool when drawing
my trend lines all right when drawing
our very first upward trend line on a
chart we're looking looking for the
lowest point we see on the screen that's
point a point B is going to be a higher
low where the price has not yet
intersected and the most recent higher
low so let me see if I can help you guys
understand this we're not going to use
this higher low here because price has
already crossed the line it's already
intersected so I like to visualize this
line as though it's truly holding the
price up now here would be pretty
accurate but I like to take this point B
and drag it to the most recent touch
point which would be right here back in
October 2nd 2023 so now we have our very
first upward trend line point a point B
Point c three touch points but when
using the ray tool it only gives us two
points to adjust all right we have drawn
our very first upward trend line now
this isn't the end so we have just
simply drawn one trend line on the
monthly time frame we need to continue
doing our top down analysis so that
means we need to work our way down to
lower time frames so we're at the
monthly let's go down to the weekly and
essentially what I'm trying to do is
modify my lines to make sure they're a
little bit more accurate as you can see
it's a little bit off now so I need to
adjust it to this new low and then what
I'm doing is I am capturing as much of
the movement of the price as I possibly
can so I'm going to continue to connect
these trend lines and it will start to
look like a fan of trend lines each new
line will use the previous point B as
its new point a and let me show you what
I mean so I'm going to continue to mark
up my charts and draw steeper trend
lines I'm now in the weekly time frame
I'm going to go back to that Ray tool
and now my point a is going to be my
previous point B that pre previous
recent touch Point boom and now same
scenario I'm looking for the next low
the next most recent low now you'd think
it would be here but there's an even
more recent low over here so I'm going
to take this point B and Boop move it
right here so now we've got yet another
one two three touch Point upward trend
line same as the last one that we drew
in the monthly time frame but now we're
in the weekly and now we have truly
capitalized or identified as much
movement as possible so we've got one
trend line and we've got another trend
line here we are truly following the
price in this direction that it's going
in we're we're utilizing all of the
movement here all right we're in the
weekly we got to continue to go down
we're going to go to the Daily now
there's going to be some instances where
you move down in time frame and there's
not anything different you can do
there's no other trend lines that you
can draw so you'll continue to Simply
move down time frames so we're in the
weekly let's move down to the Daily all
right in the daily time frame same
scenario here we're going to use our
previous point B which was right here as
our new point a and then we're looking
for the next most recent low Boop right
here without price intersecting all
right we're at the daily let's go to the
4-Hour time frame now as far as our
upward trend lines go we cannot come in
any steeper this is an instance where
there isn't a change or there isn't a
difference there's nowhere we can draw
an additional trend line from the daily
to the 4our but what I can see is now we
can finally draw our very first downward
trend line so we've got our upward trend
lines but now we need to find our
downward trend lines when drawing
downward trend lines it's the same
concept that we Ed for the upwards but
opposite so for the downward trend lines
we're looking for the highest point we
see on the chart the highest point I see
on the chart is going to be right here
at 45 224 is so that's going to be your
point a now point B is going to be a
lower high a recent lower high where
price has not yet intersected that's as
far as we can go with the downward trend
lines but I can see a steeper downward
trend line that I can draw right here in
the 4-Hour time frame without having to
go down to the 1 hour yet so I'm going
to come in with another trend line new
point a is always going to be previous
point B all right beautiful touch points
here now in the 4-Hour time frame that's
as far as I can go but now I can go down
to the 1H hour time frame this is where
we're going to stay how do you know what
time frame you stay in or which time
frame you stop in and that's going to be
which time frame you have committed to
or decided to trade in I don't jump time
frames I don't go from lower back to
higher looking for sooner entries I
commit to one time frame and look for my
entries and exits in that specific time
frame but when marking up my charts for
the first time I will always do this top
down analysis so that's how I know I'm
going to stop in the 1 hour time frame
but I do see some adjustments I can make
to my lines and I can see a steeper
trend line that I can draw so we're
going to continue to use our previous
point B as new point a and here we go
this is a lower high right here now I
can even come in a little bit steeper
previous point B new point a and here we
go all right if the price of the ym can
continue down right here this will be a
three touch Point trend line right here
now we've done all of our analysis we've
done all of our chart markups from top
down from the monthly to the weekly to
the Daily to the 4our all the way down
to the 1our time frame where I'm going
to make my trading decisions so I have
demonstrated how to mark up your charts
and how to accurately draw your trend
lines next how do we incorporate these
trend lines into our trading strategy
and how can they provide Clarity and
confidence we're going to go over two
different types of examples when trading
trend lines there are two options we can
trade a breakout strategy or a bounce
strategy or a combination of the two so
when incorporating the bounce strategy
when price gets to one of our trend
lines we're anticipating that the price
is going to bounce off of that trend
line suggesting that this is going to be
a trend continuation and I'll give you
an example in just a moment and then the
breakout strategy which is my all-time
favorite this is when price breaks
through a trend line in indicating a
potential Trend reversal okay so let's
go over the concept of trading the
bounce of a trend line so right here
where the price is at now of the ym
we're going to go ahead and take a short
position anticipating that this is going
to be a trend continuation that this is
simply just going to be yet another
touch point to this downward Trend and
it's going to continue down so this is
where we would place a sell order we're
in a short position now now how do we
mitigate our risk so we are currently in
a short position anticipating that the
price of the Dow is going to continue
down and just simply bounce off of this
trend line there's going to be many ways
of mitigating risk understanding the
capital that you have to trade the
capital that you have in your account
and how much percentage in conjunction
to the capital should you be risking a
great rule of thumb especially for
beginners is going to be anywhere
between 1 and 2% of your Capital now
let's say you have an account size of
128,000 that means we could risk
anywhere between $1 to $2,500 in this
specific trade so now that's a good rule
of thumb to know okay if this trade
doesn't work out we're willing to risk
$1,000 to
$2,500 but now let's see if we actually
need to risk that much in this specific
F set up so where do we put our stop
loss our stop loss is going to go on the
other side of our downward trend line so
if the price doesn't bounce off of this
downward trend line we know okay time to
close this trade time to take a loss now
in this scenario we only need to risk
$50 if the price comes up to
43,7 19 we know all right this wasn't a
bounce of the downward trend line I'm
willing to lose $50 on this trade so we
have our stop loss in place if the price
comes up breaks this downward trend line
and hits this
43719 $1 we have just taken a $51 loss
but now what happens if the price
continues in our favor the coolest part
about this strategy is we don't have a
takeprofit set now you're more than
welcome to add one and to have one if
you don't want to hold this trade for
that long if you're simply just looking
to get a quick Buck or build that
confidence or just rack up those small
wins absolutely use A takeprofit and A
good rule of thumb for take profits is
always to use an area of support or
resistance where the price is likely to
hit and turn around multiple times so
putting our takeprofit at
43,44 is an ideal takeprofit since the
likelihood of the price getting back to
this area which it's done in the past
and then turning around is very high we
could simply add a take profit here
making $91 for this trade or my favorite
way to do it is allow the trend to play
out allow the trend to move if the price
of the Dow continues in our favor which
I'll do a little path tool just to give
you an idea if it continues down pulls
up a little bit comes up comes down
continues along this downward trend line
we're able to take our stop loss and
Trail it into profit so it's no longer
at that negative $51 now we Trail it and
we move it along that trend line but as
soon as price breaks the downward trend
line that we're anticipating it to
follow then we know it's time to take
that profit so now let's say that price
does finally break that means we would
have been able to move our stop all the
way down to
43358 Knocking us out of our trade with
a profit of $129 so just think of it
like manually moving your stop into
profit as price progresses as price
moves in your favor along that trend
line and then you simply just wait for
the price to break out of that trend
line and take your profits or if the
trade doesn't work out you'll know
pretty quickly especially when trading
the Bounce by putting that stop on the
other side of your trend line where we
originally had it here at this
43719 now let's go over another scenario
the breakout method so we're going to
close this trade here and go over a
second scenario since we don't have a
breakout of price in this example I'm
going to draw an example with the path
tool so let's say that the price of the
ym continues down and breaks this upward
trend line using the breakout strategy
with trend lines we enter when price
breaks a trend line instead of bouncing
so we are anticipating that this is
going to be a trend reversal so a
reversal of this upward trend line now
this upward trend line was drawn in a
higher time frame so it holds a little
bit more weight so we're thinking that
this higher time frame upward trend is
about to get a reversal and we're going
to be continuing down on this new trend
here so let's say that we consider
taking a short position here we would
think short positions because price
broke instead of thinking short
positions because price bounced so we're
thinking short positions right here at
43,00 47 there we go we've got our short
position right here now how do we
mitigate the risk it's going to be the
same exact scenario that we mitigated
our risk using the bounce but what's
different about this strategy is our
entries are based on different reasons
so instead of anticipating a bounce we
are anticipating a trend reversal so
we're still thinking short positions
right here at this
43413 is and now where does our stop go
we're going to put as though if the
price was to come up and break our
downward trend line we would put our
stop somewhere around this
43592 if the price was to come up and
break we would think okay close me out
take my loss at it's probably going to
be around if this is the same scenario
it probably be still around that $50 and
this is going to be same scenario so
we're going to continue to stay in this
trade as long as the price continues
along this downward trend line so same
exact scenario for the exits you're
going to trail that stop if price
progresses in your favor you get to move
that stop into profit if the price
doesn't work out and breaks this
downward trend line then we take our $50
loss now we can increase position size I
just used one contract as an example
before but since this account size on
the the paper trade is 128,000 we could
risk anywhere between $1,000 and $2,500
for each trade here that 1 to 2% or
especially for the newbies and the
beginners just experimenting with one
micro is an excellent place to start
especially in the Futures market now the
exit criteria is exactly the same as the
bounce as long as the price continues
along this trend line we're happy we're
making money we get to move that stop
into profit if it doesn't work out we
took that $51 loss and then we're on to
the next trade now let's go over a real
world scenario where I used this method
on a live account so we have our upward
trend line here we've got one two three
touch points the price broke out of it
that was my indication to take a short
position since price broke out of the
upward trend line and then what kept me
in where did my stop loss go stop loss
went on the other side of the downward
trend line so I was willing to risk
$8,900 if the price as soon as I got in
broke the downward trend line and then
how long do I stay in for so remember
that scenario where I said if you're
looking to close profits to take those
small wins or you're not looking to hold
that trade for as long as possible you
want to look for an area of support or
resistance as a takeprofit so we have
our entry based on the break of a
downward trend line and then the price
got to an area of support where it's
very likely that the price of crude oil
here was to hit and turn around hit and
turn around it hit and turned around
here so I closed my trade here at this
7226 is area and made a profit of
27,600 I had a 3.11 r here and this is a
real example of an actual trade that I
placed using the breakout strategy so
here's a few Advanced tips for you
Traders already utilizing trend lines
when you done your top down analysis and
you've marked up your charts and placed
all your trend lines as price progresses
price will intersect and cross through
those original trend lines so you're
going to have to adjust your trend lines
on a regular basis to adapt to the
market that means utilizing new Point
A's and new Point B's steeper trend
lines or adjusting the trend lines that
have already been crossed to either a
new low or a new high making sure the
price hasn't intersected yet and a huge
one that I went over already is
incorporating the multiple time frames
incorporating that top- down analysis
seeing what price has done overall in a
much higher time frame gives you such a
clearer view of the overall direction of
a trend and then as you move from that
higher time frame you go into those
lower time frames and then you stop at
the one you've decided to trade and then
the last tip was utilizing those areas
of support and resistance for take
profits one if you're not willing to
hold that trade for as long as possible
and two if you're just simply looking to
rack up those small wins and look for a
sooner area to take profit so this was a
complete guide of how to do your top
down analysis how to accurately draw
your trend lines and utilize a strategy
to help you make decisions based on
these trend lines I encourage you guys
to mark up your chart and integrate
these strategies into your trading as
always guys hit the link in the
description to be part of my community
where I teach this strategy much more in
depth you can learn alongside my team
and my community all right friends
thanks for joining me today that's all I
have hope this was helpful