hello everyone and welcome back to my
youtube channel i hope you're doing
great and in today's session i will show
you a powerful trend trading strategy
using three indicators on trading view
to achieve highest success win rate so
without further ado let's go ahead with
the video trend trading strategy seeks
to benefit from a market by identifying
a continuous price movement that is
likely to continue in the same direction
and in essence it is a strategy that
seeks to follow the trend and benefit
from it as it develops so let me tell
you a very basic technique for
identifying the trend of the market so
for example if the general price
direction is upward and there is a
series of higher lows and higher highs
we may conclude that the market is
trending towards an upside on the other
hand if the overall price direction is
downward and there is a series of low
lows and lower highs we may reasonably
assume that the market is moving towards
a downside and i mentioned at the
beginning of the video that this stride
you would incorporate indicators that
are easy to access on mt4 or trading new
platforms some of the purposes of a
technical indicator includes trend
notification entry signal trade
management and determining when to exit
your trade so today's lucky winner for
this strategy is a simple moving average
indicator of period 200 and here is an
example how it works if the price is
trading above the 200 moving average we
will only seek for long trade signals
and vice versa if the price is trading
below the 200 line we will aim for a
short trade opportunity and we will also
add a two moving averages of periods 25
and 50 as they will assist us to
determine the exit and entry points so
let's open up a chart and i do really
love to use the usd jpy for this
specific trading strategy as an example
and there is a simple reason for that as
well in general usd jpy currency pair is
just tends to trend steady either to the
upside or downside there is no big mess
if we will look at the price in that
case it just creates significant
opportunities in the market to profit as
usd jpy has longer periods of stability
along with volatility but feel free to
use the strategy on any currency pair
that tends to trend so for example your
gpy or maybe aud usd but the choice of
your currency is really up to you to
begin the strategy we need indicators of
course to add all three indicators just
simply navigate to the indicator section
and type moving average so m a of course
on some trading platforms it could say
simple moving average so don't get
confused because it is the same as
moving average is just named differently
so there's no panic and let's keep on
going so now triple click on it because
we do need three of them and now let's
adjust the settings of it because we
cannot play with the wrong cards and
magically expect higher ends so to
adjust the settings just basically click
on this setting bar and go to the input
section and change the length from
default to 200 and do the same thing for
another two moving averages so it's
going to be 25 and as i said we will be
using 50 as our additional confirmation
for this strategy so the first step is
done congratulations to the ones who
passed it and now i like to use this
strategy mainly on higher time frames so
such as one hour or four hour is ideal
for entry points and maximum pip gain oh
and by the way guys i placed few trades
today based on the strategy so here is a
quick sneak peek on how it looks like as
you can see and the dsd been doing
nicely as well as euro usd they've been
in profit so far so i will keep
monitoring it because as i said i'm
happy to share this strategy with you
all so probably i will update with the
profits at the end of the video so stay
tuned so here's the rules to follow if
you would be looking for a buy trade
opportunity so the 200 moving average
must be trending below the candlesticks
which indicates that we are in a buyer's
site and guys please don't go against
the trend it is very crucial to follow
the trend in order to make those profits
but not against it and blow your account
i don't really want you to blow your
account by using this powerful strategy
to make the pips but not to lose them
and after you sort out the direction of
the trend following that 200 moving
average take a look at the 25 and 50
moving averages this specific duo of
moving averages works brilliant together
to show us a potential entry opportunity
by creating a crossover so in this case
we have a squeeze pattern formation
which is quite often patterned in forex
markets where a downtrend merges into
one point with an uptrend creating a
small room for the price to move but of
course if the buyer pressure is stronger
like in this case the moving average of
25 so that's this blue line will cross
over the
250 confirming that the bullish power is
there and this is what you should look
out for when applying this strategy we
can also notice that once the buying
strength was increasing it actually
broke this horizontal area of the
sensitivity and it's now acting as a
support for this trade the market always
moves in the push and exhaustion
scenarios so like in this example as
well we have this push small exhaustion
and now continues move towards an upside
we had a nice bullish engulfing candle
as a confirmation and probably this
trade was reaching more than
116 pips into the profit i will be
transparent as i can and i think you
should also know that these moving
averages also act as a strong support
for any trade that you might take and i
strongly encourage you to portion the
trade into tp1 tp2 and tp3 and of course
once take profit one reached you're
moving your stop loss so like in this
scenario let me just quickly grab this
other tool so once you take profit one
reach so let's say around um 20 pips
you're moving your stop loss to an entry
and now you're having a free trade and
you can also use 200 moving average to
plot your protective stop loss so you
can initially place it below 200 ma or
below the horizontal area of the
sensitivity and then of course you can
adjust accordingly to your trading plan
and risk management i mainly use two to
one risk score ratio but as i said it's
different when it comes to the
individual trader and to exit the trade
you should look out for the moving
average of 25 crossing below 50. this
indicates that reversal may occur and
the trend is changing to the bearish one
so moving on here is an example of a
cell trade scenario and what you should
follow to perform this strategy 200
moving average must be above the
candlesticks which indicate that you are
in a bearish side and after that the
moving average of 25 should be crossing
below moving average of 50. so let's
examine this short trade opportunity as
we can see the price has been trending
towards a downside we have a multiple
rejections on this trend as you can see
it's been shooting towards a downside
even on the last rejection over here it
definitely shoots towards a downside as
well it just basically shows that the
sellers are much stronger by not letting
the buyers to break the trend clearly we
can definitely spot this huge m pattern
formation as you can see we have kind of
double tops over here of course this
support zone was slightly broken with a
false breakout but then again it
definitely continued to move towards a
downside so most of the time these
specific empires formations we also have
a neckline so once that neckline being
broken most of the time we also have a
nice push exhaustion we can see we have
a bearish engulfing candle as a
confirmation the moving averages also
created a crossover recently so that's
again indicating that the buyers are not
that strong enough and as you remember i
said that these moving averages also
stands as a good support and resistance
so even if you will be taking a look
let's say over here as we can see we
have this huge vic so that's the
rejection of a 25 moving average
shooting towards a downside again it's
been bearish engulfing candle over here
that's 50 moving average is shooting
towards a downside again in this
scenario you can definitely place your
stop loss slightly above your moving
averages or slightly above your recent
horizontal area of the sensitivity also
by the way guys here is an update on my
trades your usd and usd been doing
nicely 306 dollars into the profit once
again guys thank you so much for
watching me and i will talk to you next
time bye
[Music]