Ch hum
ok are we
[music]
live I guess
refresh ok
perfect r live quickly everyone come let's start
let me just share with everyone
[music]
hum
alright how are you all Radhe
Radhe hello Pawan hi
yes it's the same the video of the class this
video is the same yes see the class I will share as many things as
possible here and
after a long time I am just live you know so it
feels very good to see after a long time I
got time to go live
so I think some uploads will be updated in the page as well I
think some shares have
probably not been updated so and here also
we will cover as much as
possible today we will take time and
cover everything completely so sit down relax
and take your notebook and pen we will start
we are going to cover a lot more things
okay good evening I am fine
thank you so much for asking Jai Jagannath
ok
let's go real mentor for me great thank you so
much order flow pe video order flow ko
again good  I will cover it from here, okay
first of all some people had doubts and did not understand, so we will
try to break it down in simple language.
Today our target is to
understand a little about technical analysis,
how to use it for trading etc.,
how to do it,
first tell me once whether everyone is getting the sound properly or
not and everyone quickly
like this video, okay let's
keep the target for this video, this class, let's aim
for 300 likes, okay let's keep the target of 300 likes,
tell me quickly whether the
sound is coming or not,
Jai Shri Krishna, Jai Shri
Krishna
Bhardwaj, this video will be uploaded, yes it will definitely be
uploaded, I will try to
come live daily and
explain and teach something or the other, Mena Brave, yes
Mena Brave, Jai Shri Ram, loud and clear,
perfect good sign, here very good sign, I am by the way in
this class, also Malik, you are also
great, okay so then let's learn all about you  We
know the things but once the revision is done
we will do it and I
am planning something very amazing, one of
my plans failed, well before the plan,
you all are connected right now, you all can see me, you can
hear me, right, all the
people who are watching this recorded, if you
skip the starting 15 minutes, then
you will be able to see the class from where it is going to
start,
right now I have come after a long time, so
I am connecting everyone, you know, I am
listening to everyone's talk and explaining to them
what happened, okay, so
first of all Radhe Radhe Radhe Radhe Virendra,
hey, thank you so much Vipul, the meet up second
video class will come, friend, there has been a file
error, I have told the editor to
correct it,
nothing could be uploaded, that is fine, first let me
tell you one small thing that we had a
surprise, we had a plan as to how to do what
and we were planning a big surprise, you
know that surprise might fail
How did I fail? What was my plan?
I will tell you, I will reveal it to you.
We have not done it now, we will do it later. My
plan was that all my students
etc. who were in the class, whom I
know personally, because the class was held
sitting in a limited space, so we all were
planning together that we will go to Ladakh Badda by
car and there will be
810 cars, whoever has a
four by four car or a club,
those people will go and travel, trade,
roam, explore, do many
things, all this was planned, that
thing could not be done right now, due to rain,
many people said that sir, it is
raining here, there is a fear of slide, due to this we
dropped the plan a little, but the effort is
that we will do the winter situation, the
effort is that the winter situation will be good, you know,
I am planning for that right now, so
many people were asking you,
I have told you about it, if I have your blessings,
we will also organize it,
okay, very well and it is going to be a
lot of fun for you, I mean you will have a lot  You are going to get some
learning and one thing there is
no extra charge for it so
if ever someone messages you like this that no yes
I will get you entry done nothing like that happens
okay so don't ever come
thinking of anything like this don't do that okay
you are also a traveler and I have
Himalayan of my own
thatchi can connect me on
whatsapp's start right now you guys
will see my screen in three to one let's go
papad is it done what happened
brother it is not working okay alright so right now
tell me everyone is able to see my screen or
not tell me this much
tell me right now I have read a lot I am
not able to understand anything in the stock market no
problem Sumit pay attention in this class
I will try to make you
understand everything from this well and your doubts will be
cleared okay so let's
start everyone
like it quickly it is easy right likes will give you
motivation let's keep a target of likes
let me type it in chat and it will be
fun
hey man has someone got blocked
suddenly pin  Did the message get pinned or not
brother, yes it is pinned, let's start, the like target is
300, okay, let's start now, see, keep one
thing in mind, as far as I know,
I never cheat when it comes to teaching,
I
try to teach everything with as much dedication as I know, so take your notebook
etc. carefully, sit and understand,
tell me once, should I
start from scratch,
because I told you I haven't understood anything yet, I am
studying from the body,
or should we directly start the technical part,
what do you say,
tell me, should we directly start the technical part,
or how should we do it like that, tell
me in the chat, I have been getting learning for a long time, I will tell you how can I start, right now,
how much can I start with, what
is the reality, I will explain, don't worry, what is
your net worth, nothing, it's just going well, by
God's grace, don't have anything like this, what
difference does it make to anyone, you come
and take learning, the learning is here, right, okay, let's
start from the basics  Absolutely from
zero, absolutely from zero, yes yes, so
many messages, okay, let's
understand a little from zero first, let's understand some basics, and then we will move ahead.
Okay,
look, the first thing to keep in mind is that
whenever we are
confused in the market after learning everything,
then divide yourself into two parts, that is, divide
your psychology into two parts,
not yourself, divide your psychology into two parts,
understand that there are two types
of things that happen in the market, one is trading,
why is the pain not working, is it
over,
look, one is
trading and the other is investing, okay,
most of the people are currently focusing
on trading because here you have to work, you have to
evolve, it will take your
time, so what is there in investing, we just do
fundamental research, take a lot of time,
plan things and leave it, and
after that, if the market goes up, then we make
money, and if it doesn't go up, then we don't make money, okay, that's it in
basic terms, now
after that, if we come to trading, let's
If we come to
trading, then what happens in trading is that there are
different types of styles.
Now it is okay to understand. I want to write a book on you right now. I
will explain. Don't worry. Don't worry, just
focus a little here.
If we talk about trading, there are
different styles in trading. Now
your job is to find out
which style is good for me, in which style I can do well. So first of all, the
style which you can
also call very risky and happens quickly,
we are doing it time wise, that is, first we will
move from lower time frame to higher time frame. So scalping comes first.
Scalping is done, after that
intraday comes at number two. And if we
hold intraday for a little longer time,
then at number three comes BTST
trade. BTST means buy today sell tomorrow. At number four
comes swing
trading. And at number five is our
positional and short term investing. Now these are
three, four, five types of trading
styles. Now you will know from these.  I have to choose
what I can do, what is best for my life situation.
If I give
you an overview of all these trading options, because I have already
done everything and am still correcting it.
If I were to give you an overview, then
understand it this way: we move from risky to easy,
which is the riskiest and which is the easiest. Nothing is
easy, and if you see that
everything is easy, you know, then everything is not easy. If you know, then nothing is
easy. But
still, at one point, which carries the highest risk, if
we look at it accordingly, then the
highest risk is
in scalping. Then comes
intraday. Okay, then after that comes
swing
trading. Intraday BTST is almost the same,
then after that comes positional trading. This is the
order. Your highest risk will be in scalping,
but the highest profit is
also expected in scalping, and that is why people
do it. Then they will make a little less money than
scalping, but
this is also risky. You can say, okay, that's
intraday, then after that swing trading, there
is less risk.  It's not like that, you don't make money. You do make a
lot of money, but it takes time. Nothing happens
instantly. It takes time to get
into positions and get it
right. So, this is how you have to approach it.
Now, I hope, whoever had doubts about this, that
I've been in the stock market for a long time,
but it was still unclear, now it's clear.
Now, I know where the problem lies.
Why do people make the most losses?
Understand this point.
[Music]
Second. Now, understand one point here. You know
why people make the most losses.
People make the most losses
because they don't understand what they should do. Not
everyone can do everything. This is the
reality.
You can do it. You're a trader.
You can plan for a higher time frame or a
lower time frame. But
when it comes to intraday and
scalping, these two things specifically
require a very dedicated mindset.
You can do it only if you have that mindset. Now, this doesn't mean you should
n't try it. The voice is low. Okay,
sorry.  Learn, see, you learn, try,
okay, after that see if you are getting results or
not, if you are getting results, it is a good
thing, if you are not getting results, then try,
you did not succeed, you tried one business, it
failed, the work is over, there is a high chance that if
you are not successful here in intraday
scalping, then you will get into swing, so do not
just look at trading as if
trading means that we
sit in the system and keep
pressing buttons, button after button, do you understand the point,
trading means that even if you are doing swing
trading, that is also trading,
keep this in mind, okay,
now because most of the people here are
beginners, then you have to think in every way,
if you
want to go more aggressive, then you
can do intraday scalping, if you are
set in your mind, that thing is a good
thing, now being set does not mean that
you tried it once or twice or you tried it 10 times, 12
times, you know, and after that it did
not work for you and then you gave up, no,
friend, time  It seems everything takes time.
I once
made a video, and I'm going a little off-topic. I said that to
master trading or
learn it well, you have to put in 10,000 hours.
People went crazy, saying, "
Oh, that doesn't happen. We
learned it in two months, we can learn it in six months,
but to learn it well, we need
10,000 hours." Two skills. The guitar is shown in the background. I haven't been able to learn it yet. I
try a lot, but I haven't put in
10,000
hours yet. I know that the
day I put it in, I will learn it, at least
professionally, but I will start making a good amount. You
understand the point, right? Treat it that way.
You need to change your mindset a little.
Okay, let's come back to the screen. Okay, alright.
Now you've understood all this well. Now let's
talk from here. A career can be made in trading. We'll talk right now. Learn it
first,
friend. Why are you so confused about career right now?
Learn the basics first. Okay, career.
What can I tell you, you know it yourself, you are
so active on social media, you yourself
know who is doing what and whether there is a
possibility or not, you yourself
should understand this, you must know about this,
so okay, let's come
back now, now we have
understood the basics, now in technical analysis we have to
understand what the terms are and
how we can use it,
okay and intraday, let's try,
if it is possible then we will do scalping intraday also,
else then we will do it like that,
okay, don't worry, let's do it, so now let's
come to
our
technical analysis, let's understand what is this,
what is this technical analysis,
if people who are completely new do not have much idea, you
know technical analysis is made about two things, there are
only two things, here
if I want to surprise you, then the
first one is
sorry, technical
analysis is the first one, technical
analysis is the
study of trends, this is the
first point and the second point is
Turning points are
just two things. If I were to summarize them
for you, they are all about
technical
analysis: trends and turning
points. These two things are all about technical analysis. If
you understand these two things, it means whatever you learn,
now there are so many things in technical analysis.
We will discuss them. I will also give you a
complete roadmap in a thorough manner
so that even if
we are not able to cover everything in this video right now, at
least you will have the topics. You
can do your own research. Okay, all right, because
ultimately this is learning. I hope you keep
taking screenshots or the video will be there. You can do it
now, you will see it
comfortably. There will be no issue later. Okay,
so technical analysis is all about trends and
turning points. When you
go to plan a trade, what do you
look for? Either you see that the market is
rising from here, so I
sit in a rising market and
enter a little here. If it rises a little, I will
sell it and make money and exit.
This is the first option, correct?  Suppose the
market appears to be rising, we
enter somewhere here, it rises here,
we capture this movement, and exit after making money. So, firstly,
trend analysis is done.
Second, you think that the market has
risen so high, this is the selling level of the market, if it falls from
here, I will short it
and if the market falls, I will make money. So,
two things have happened. Okay, like
I made candlesticks very simple for you.
You have so many
candlesticks, what do you
mean? If you literally search
on the internet, you will see 20-30
candlestick patterns. After decoding all those patterns, I brought them down to
three. There are only three
primary market directions
and three types of candlesticks. By
combining them all, I have created a complete buffet.
Similarly, technical analysis is a very
difficult thing, but there are only two
things to understand. And if you understand these two things like this, then
honestly, you do
n't even need technical analysis. Many
people like this.  Yes, I know some of the old school
people who do not use technical analysis at all
and they have been in the market for
around 30-35 years, you understand, right? If
you understand the trend and
know the turning point, then let's do it, then now
you have to keep your understanding in your mind. We will
talk about tax later, we will
talk about it in some other live, so don't even ask how things are going, right? Okay, let's move ahead
now, okay,
let's move on further, so now let's move on to
technical
analysis, now you have understood it well,
what is it, let's understand, the
first point is
candlesticks, this is done, the first thing in technical
analysis, the first step is candlesticks,
okay, the second thing is what we understand,
support
and
resistance, okay,
now understand the points, keep noting all these
because now we will understand further in this that actually there are
two things inside the candlestick
which we have to discover and understand, there are
three types of support resistance,
then  There is some spice inside as well to understand and
increase knowledge. Okay, so
first is candle, second is support
resistance, third is how to understand
trend analysis.
Now how trend analysis is done, by
reading the market structure.
I am using this trading method
in the notes of the other documents and
I could have written it well. Anyway, you must be
understanding this much. Okay,
we have three things: candlestick,
support resistance, technical
analysis, sorry, trend analysis.
In trend analysis, we
try to understand the market structure.
We understood these three things. Now, the fourth
point that comes after that is
volume or volume and market
profile. Okay, and after that, the fifth
point is these
indicators. These are five things. There are five things
which consist in technical analysis.
Candlesticks,
support resistance, trend analysis,
volume to read the market structure. And after that, there are supportive
indicators, in which you can take their help and do
something.  You try to discover such data
which is not possible for you to calculate humanly
okay got it
perfect okay like target is completed oh
wow what a great thing
[music]
wait light target is completed 1 mit ku let
me refresh for a
second what a great thing very good
well done
superb now after that it is up to you
everyone please like the
video okay let's understand this thing well I hope you have
understood it
well now let's understand one
point here let's come to candlesticks
candlesticks okay now understand now
two things happen with candlesticks
first you get entry entry
in the market means
trigger that is when some particular thing happens
you will enter the market love
from 28th June classes oh thank you so much finally
understood na point as soon as you get entry
you trigger there
your trigger is there okay make sure that many people like me a
lot of people had DMed me
this class which was just started  Yes, isn't it? The class on Story is going to
start on the 28th of July. I think the
new class is going to start from July,
live. Sir, I can't afford it.
How will I do it? How will I learn?
Learn. Okay, I need everyone's likes
here and please tell me whether they come or
not. Yes, sir, I DMed you and thank
you so much for coming here. I have
come especially for you people who can't afford it. It's
especially for those who can
afford it, they don't have any issues. They
have money, but those who can't afford it, their
learning shouldn't stop. Okay,
but you have to keep one thing in mind that even
if you go into trading,
you will need money for trading.
When you invest in the market, as far as learning is concerned, learn.
Okay, learn and work hard. Move
forward. Okay, which is that movie
dialogue? Remember that in your prayers. Just don't forget that.
Okay, let's
come back to the entry point. I will write a book. Don't worry,
okay. We will write an experience book. Okay, okay, let's
enter.  Let's
find out the trigger for entry. Now what is a trigger? A trigger is a
trigger. Suppose you have done your analysis
thoroughly, after analysis, there is
a point where you
need a trigger from the market that if this
thing happens, then I will enter the
market. A candlestick can do that
and give it to you. Look, I
DMed you. Thank you. Welcome
Vikas. Welcome, I welcome Lalat. Okay, you must have understood the trigger well.
I don't focus there. I would have focused here. The
other thing is,
what is the function of a candlestick? I want to
explain price psychology to you. My
handwriting is not quite right.
You guys should understand it. Okay, I want to
explain price psychology to you. These are two points. Okay,
your photo is in the trading room. Hey, thank you so much Nayan. Okay,
let's focus here now. Everyone, focus here.
Focus on the middle two classes. Okay, so the
entry trigger. And the second point is
price psychology. What is price psychology? I do
n't know whether you have ever
noticed this or not.  Okay, let's
see a live example of this, let's
come now, let's take a
little class on Nifty, it will be long,
how many minutes is the length, whatever it is, okay, we will
see it, whoever has the passion can see it, it's
not a matter of having to, okay, just right, one by one.  One second one
second what do I mean by price psychology
and understand it carefully, okay, price
psychology, look what I am doing now, this is the
time frame, we will change it and make it a
one week
chart of Nifty,
okay and please do not understand this like that, do not take it
like a call, just understand it like this,
Mike, okay,
what is the meaning of the price psychology that I am trying to tell you,
now see this is the time frame of Nifty, yes, one or
two people should join,
if someone is sending a message, then tell
everyone to focus on class, focus on class, okay, do not pay, it's
great, be it Eklavya, Tanmay,
I have seen your message,
okay, it will happen with this,
what will not be possible, okay, no problem,
understand it like this, I thought,
give the option to mark it, what is he explaining to you,
understand the price psychology point well, this
candle has opened here,
correct, from here the price went continuously
up, now who takes the price up, the
buyers take it, then after that the
price continuously goes down from here  It came and
went even below its open and in the end, there was an
attempt to push a little higher but the
market closed here.
Now, as we have understood so far, if we look at this candlestick
simply, it is a rejection
candle; it is that simple, but what is it
telling you on a psychological basis?
How was last week? The market was completely
dominated by buyers. The buyers tried their best, but now that trial failed. Wait just a minute, Alexa, stop. Yes, so the buyers tried their best, and after that, the sellers pushed the price down completely. So, now what clarity do you have in your mind?
This is the price psychology of the market last week. When the
market opens on Monday, I am
telling you my point. That's fine. I am not
telling anyone to go buy and sell, but
my thought process is clear at 50.
I have to look for short
trades. If the market
opens even slightly to the side here and if there is a slight pullback
or if it goes near any resistance, then
I will key in my short from there.  My
mind is clear. I understand how I came to see
just one
hammer candle based on price psychology. Seeing rejection is a different
thing. Okay, we can see that, but you have to
understand where the open occurred, how high it made, how low it made the close, and
how the price is trying to behave. Let me
tell you another good thing. This will
help you extra in understanding the price. For example,
suppose you
see a clear rejection here right now. Now
what you do is go to this rejection and
take the rectangle tool from here and mark this entire
area. Okay, oh, it's not marked,
okay, you've marked it. And
after that, you shift from here. Let's shift to the
weekly time frame, right? Shift to the one-hour time frame.
Now, what we were just discussing about the movement, this movement is
this movement.
Now you're getting a
clearer picture here: who is stronger
between the buyers and the sellers.
Look, right now,
I'm presenting you with a fresh analysis.
Yes, I haven't planned anything in advance.
Because I have
found another point in this to understand now, what I found to understand is that
last time when buyers
took the price up, look at this buyer
candle, look at this candle,
look at this candle, the market
held for some time after that, then a huge
candle
came, a very huge candle, but after that the
market took one hour, two hour, three hour, four hour, five hour
and six hour to come
down and when it was
time to rise, it went up in three times,
if honestly you know, it would have been like this that the
market would have risen by forming such small candles
and at the time of falling, it would have come down suddenly, then
this would have been an extreme bearish scenario,
you understand, so that is why right now the
market is looking a little bearish, but if
seen on a one-hour basis, it does
not look that negative, okay, but anyway, it is a
weekly rejection, so the first attempt will be to
short trade somewhere, if we find
resistance around here, then it will be better, okay,
now there is also an imbalance candle here,
after  I will understand that, okay, it's a bit of a
long topic, okay, so I will basically
try to short near the imbalance candle, okay, let's move
ahead now and let's get back to our original topic,
which we were discussing technical analysis,
this is what happens, I mean, I get so immersed that I
forget things, okay, anyway,
so now you understood,
two or three things happen with candlesticks, sorry, two
things happen, first, the trigger is done, second, this
price analysis, the trigger point,
you can
go and watch the video of the candlestick course, okay, okay,
which broker is good, I am currently
using Dhan, I also have Angel One and
sorry, Angel One, yes, Angel One also, but I
trade on it, for intraday trading, I am
using Dhan, okay, now I have
not used it, let's go back here, focus on
class, so you understood the candlestick part,
now let's talk about support and
resistance, support and resistance, now
support and resistance  There are
three types of it,
before that let us understand what its
actual function is, see, understand the point, you have to take the
batch, I will tell you now, I will tell you at the end, don't worry about the
class, okay,
first focus on what is support resistance,
if something is falling, you are falling
and suddenly someone stops you,
he gives you support, then the work of support is,
if ever the price is falling, either to
stop it or support is the place from
where the market reverses,
okay, I understood the point, this is the work of
support, now if we talk about resistance, then let's
explain it in as basic a language as possible, if we
talk about resistance, then suppose
you are trying to jump and if a wooden piece
like a plywood is placed on you, then
you will not be able to jump any higher, resistance works
exactly the same, resistance
works when the price is going up, then to
stop it, did you
understand, let's
differentiate a little from that, support
resistance works everywhere  Wherever the
market is rising, we
saw last time that the market has risen from here, from here,
all those places will become support and will
act as support for the market and
all the places from where the market is falling will act as
resistance, like right now if we
look at the live chart itself, what happens, so is
this area a
resistance for the market, absolutely yes, is this
area a support for the market,
absolutely yes, right now if we look at the market,
in which area is the market sitting, is it
sitting in the support area,
keep things as simple as possible, do
n't do anything complicated, okay, now I
hope this first point must have become clear well,
okay, let's move
ahead, now fix this in your mind properly, we will
talk about emotions in the video, that psychology class, okay,
Shubham, don't worry, now it will become public, don't worry, okay now,
understand one point, this thing should be
settled in your mind very well
that what is the work of support, support, its
work is to lift the price from here
or if the price is falling, stop it  If it
works, it will reverse
or stop the price. Every support is of three types.
Okay, what are the types? The
first is
horizontal, the second is
trend lines,
and the third is left-angle retracement.
These are three types of terms. Okay, the
job of every area is to
support the market and make it reverse from there. Now,
we can analyze and understand the market in these three ways. All three are the
best; all three
work. Do you know
what the reality is of intraday? Let me tell you the reality of
intraday scalping. Especially the reality of intraday scalping is that
we have three types of support and
resistance. Out of these three, we just have to
master one. That's it. These
multiple
things are useful. Especially in swing trading,
where more analysis is required.
Intraday scalping mainly depends
on execution, rather than just analysis. Okay,
analysis is a part, obviously you have to be
right. You have to understand to analyze,
but out of these three, you only
need one thing: support.  You
can master horizontal resistance very well. You can master just the trend line.
You can master just the
horizontal trend line here.
This is what I
told the students in class as well. I am
not telling you something else here in class
and
guiding you wrong. No, I am
genuinely guiding you. Out of these three,
you need to master one. Stick to
one. You should know all of them.
As a swing trader, you can see trades on all three.
And there is a point called
relation theory
where multiple things are indicating to us about the same thing. For example, if
you have planned any trade, it may be that a
flip zone is also being formed there. There may be
horizontal support there as well. The trend line is also
coming from above. Then that becomes very good.
Like on the same concept, I don't know who might have
seen the story of I think last week. Look at mine and I will
tell you if I find it.  Let me
just show you that point.
We discussed that in class.
Luckily, the topic was on. So, what happened was
that day, a
trend line was coming up regarding Nifty Bank.
Okay, what happened in Nifty Bank was that the
price was coming up like this from the beginning.
Now it was
in the rejection of its market trend line. It was in the
rejection of the trend line. Okay, that
area was also forming a Fab area. There were
two confirmations. One was for an intraday trade.
That trend line was
also on support and price. There were two confirmations
and from that area the market has fallen by 645 points.
Unfortunately, I was sleeping. I woke up at 1
o'clock. But this thing was discussed a day before.
Okay, that class goes on so long that I
miss my trades. 12 would come at
1 o'clock. Classes go on till 2 o'clock.
Sometimes because of that, I am
unable to wake up the next day. I miss my trade.  It's okay,
I'll
find that trade and tell you. Let me just try to find out
where it was.
Okay, sorry, it's Nifty, right? It was
Nifty
Bank. Okay, so you'll get some relevance. If I'm not sure, it was this one.
This area was this one.
This area was not that one. Sorry, my bad.
This wasn't it. Sorry, sorry, sorry. I took a
trade here. I had traded
that day. I made some profit.
Also, sorry, this was the area. I
remembered that the market was on its
fourth retest. Okay, this was the
area. Now, what is it now? If we mark the phi, it's
reversed. Look,
brother,
perfect. Now you see
how things are working. It was also on the train line. And
second, look, the golden zone of 0.61 phi. We have
two confirmations. It was
n't in the air. It was there in the
chart. And I didn't take the trade, but
some students in the class did. They
made good money. And it was very good,
meaning a very good move.  There was an impulsive move
here. Okay, so these things
work a lot in swing trading. If
you have the knowledge, you know everything, it's
good.
Without YouTube, it's not possible for me. Honestly, if
I try, it's not possible. I want to,
but I can't
find time right now. Okay, I want to
go live as well. Now, I can't go live
because of SEBI regulations and all, but I will try
my best. Don't worry,
when I get time. Today was Saturday, the
market was closed, I didn't have much money, so I
arranged the time and did it. Yes, alright, now I have
understood the point.
Now, we have discussed three things.
Where were we at? Recall, Support, Resistance,
Horizontal Trend Line and Foot
Correct. After that, what is trend
analysis? Now, understand what trend analysis is.
Trend analysis is. Let's say there are
two types of trends in the market.
First, understand one thing, two types, three types.
Understanding what makes the market move,
how does the market move, either the market is
trending, that is, it is moving upside downside well,
this is the first option,
secondly, the market then what happens, it becomes
sideways, the
market can move in two ways, now if we
talk about trend, then there can be two types of trends, either the
market will be in an uptrend
or the market will be in a downtrend,
thirdly, the market will remain straight sideways, so in
this way, there is
a zone near the market, now a very good
example of this is right now, you guys tell me right now
in this chat, which trend is this,
which trend is this, tell me
which trend is with intraday, or what do you
think, tell me quickly which trend is this, this
chch trend, judge this, is
moving slow, is my
sideways, yes, right now the net is not moving, sideways, sideways, sideways, sideways, sideways, sideways,
now the trend is not sideways, here
this entire area, if you look at it in 15 minutes, the
market is going completely sideways, right now
from here when
If we look at the days from now, the market has been completely sideways since July 11th. It has been moving in this range. In such a situation, we just had to see which was the resistance point of the market? Which was the highest point? Which was the bottom point? Now the bottom point has returned. Okay, so now if it breaks down from here, what will happen? Either the market will go straight up and shift into an uptrend, or the market will break this and shift directly into a downtrend. This entire area is sideways, so we have to make it sideways and a trending market will move by creating a trend. You guys understand that point perfectly. So, in trend analysis, we have to see whether the market is sideways or trending. And if it is trending, then where is the trend? Is the market moving on an uptrend or a downtrend? Okay, we can understand that on the basis of higher highs and higher losses. After that, the second point comes when we understand this. That is very important and a little bit  The most complicated topic is
market
structure. We'll need to take a dedicated class on this.
Although all the topics
are very lengthy, each topic takes
an hour. Let's assume
I'm teaching each topic in detail, it will take an
hour.
Market structure is
a simple class on how to read market
structure. Okay, don't worry, but
what do we look at in market structure? Especially
if the market is trending, which
zone should we enter to catch the trend?
If the market trend is going sideways,
or which is the area of ​​the market
where the trend can reverse?
We look at these two points. Okay, so we'll
basically understand two aspects of market structure. The
first is trend
continuation. The trend might be bouncing around a bit right now,
but that's okay.
What's important is trend
continuation. And the second is trend
reversal. You know, if you've learned all this,
I'm telling you all this because it's
not possible to cover everything right now.
So you can do your own research, work hard
and you will get good results, then for that,
okay, I understood the point,
good. Now after the trend, then there is
volume. I have already
kept a live class article for you, you can check that out, we will
cover it again here as well. But
anyway, volume is there. Now what does volume do?
Volume simply shows you
how much participation there is in the market. It is
very simple,
not complicated.
Okay, and it has three or four divergences.
You have to understand the divergence whether the market is
relating to the price or not. It is correlating, it is
moving in the opposite direction, it means
something is wrong. Then, at the very end,
come the
indicators.
Now, there are two types of indicators in indicators,
leading
and lagging. Lagging indicators are not bad
and only leading indicators are not good. It depends on
how you want to use them.
You have to understand, you have to analyze
and then after that we go on to that. Okay, so
this is all technical analysis now.
Now let's understand the most important thing first
because most people are not going to get into it right now,
look, let me just put it, what was that,
yes, intraday and scalping, okay, let me
cover
intraday scalping, let's
cover these two things first because
most people are crazy about this, okay,
look, I am working on this right now,
I am not able to work on this right now
because I am not able to find that much time,
for this you will have to have a lot of discipline, you
know what discipline, to be
present in the market from 8 am to 3:00 pm,
I will try my best, I
try, but that is not happening right now, that is a
lot of things, by the grace of God, right now everything is
growing up, trading is also going on,
well, that is also being managed, it is happening because that is what we do
from the beginning,
but right now social media is also growing very well, so I have to
teach in it, connect
with you people, you know guide also, so
because of that I am not able to do intraday also,
that is why I am only  I
am scalping, but I am not doing it with main capital
because the market is currently in such a
zone, it has become very indecisive,
so forget the capital, I am just doing it.
So the first thing is that in intraday, if
you have around 6 sec hours to
give in the market, then come to the market, then
make intraday your style, otherwise don't do it.
By the way, both these trading
styles come under day trading
and when you are a day trader, a day
trader does not have anything else to do,
he has to
focus completely on this only, so now you decide
whether you have that much time to give.
Suppose you are a student, you go to college,
now you think that friend, I don't have that much
time, if I sit for intraday scalping,
my college will be over, or
suppose you do business or suppose you do a job,
then can you go into intraday? You cannot go, you cannot go,
this is the reality, you have to understand that
intraday is not for you.
If you have the mindset, then you can do it,
otherwise  Scalping isn't even available, so the
ultimate option is swing and
positional. You understand, and the problem
arises when
people can't afford it. Afford
means giving time, brother. If you give time, that's already done.
You'll have to leave your things.
When you leave me and come here and devote your full
time to this, only then will you have some chance
of success in intraday and scalping.
Okay, you're doing some other work, you've made
a couple of trades on the go, you're a day trader,
you know, everything is already planned out, so nothing is lost
in punching an order.
But it's very, very, very difficult
and very important to understand. Also, that
point is, this
is intraday. If you have six hours, then do intraday.
Secondly, the most important
point is intraday scalping. It's fine for both.
Then we'll explain it in the next part. It'll be very
long now, otherwise this video will get
worse. Look, if we're
scalping intraday, how many of you are you?  You
can start, you know
I am talking about starting,
okay it is not about making money,
forget about making it, it is all about starting now,
20000 okay, you are going to start with this much
and if you are going to do it on your own,
okay, this will also seem a little different to you,
friend, I cannot afford to
lose this, but if you are ready to lose ₹, are you
ready to lose 00 or whatever you are starting to believe from 20000, are you
ready to lose, then
intraday scalping or you can say even
swing is also for you, it is not
money, you will have to pay a fee to the market, let's
assume that I will invest 0000, I will
invest 20000 and I will make money from that, it
only makes money,
but either you have learned it very well
and you have experience as well, then
you will make it, a learned person
or someone  He who has experience will make it, he will
make it with Rs. 10,000, but as a beginner will
start with Rs. 10,000, he will lose all that money, it may happen
in beginner's luck that Rs. 10 may become Rs.
15,000, Rs. 20,000, Rs. 00,
but that money of beginner's luck will go into the
venture in the market as a fee, so do
not consider it a loss, consider it as a fee
and do not get frustrated, whoever is saying this, do
not pay attention to that,
focus on yourself, increase your knowledge and keep
continuing, okay
and be ready mentally, if you cannot afford this Rs. 000, you
cannot afford to lose it, that
friend I cannot afford this, then do not do it,
then gain knowledge when you  It's like this,
many jobs can be made from here and there, now see, do anything, make money,
then come into trading, then there are chances of
success, okay, this is the intermediate cup,
so or that's all for today, right now we'll
take some questions,
ask me some questions quickly, I'll
answer the questions, the rest, the next part will make the
video very long, this is okay, like
target, we have 574 likes,
very good, 575, well done, everyone,
where does that confidence come from, it doesn't come in this, okay, no, anyway, so
or here is the confidence,
well done, well done, well done, well done, get the
Haikin AC indicator done, let's
cover Hike A a little quickly, okay,
I have seen the question in special demand,
see what is Hike AC, here
we will go, where did it go, where did it go,
Hike Yer, okay,
why didn't it come,
brother, let's go on
demand, now you must be seeing that when this candle is
rising, it is rising, if it is falling, it is
falling.  How does Hike work? It
works
on the average that if the market opens at a particular point and then
closes after that,
even if it comes down, but as long as it does
not break its average, then the
Heikin Ash candle, even if it
comes down, will go up and closes up, then
it will show green only.
Okay, so Hike Nashi are basically
good for catching the trend.
How to understand it, suppose once a green
candle starts forming continuously, then
if we are in the trend, then we will not
exit the trend until a red candle is
formed. We will not exit the
trade. Then you will get to
catch such trends. Till here,
sorry, till here only, it is okay in
these short Hike Nashis, alright. So, or
that was it, I hope you enjoyed it and understood it now.
Okay, this video will be
uploaded in the app as well. And I think the
class I took in P as well, I don't know, there is
some glitch in it, maybe it has not been uploaded yet
in the free content section.
Go and see there you will see it being uploaded,
okay, is the market choppy now days I am doing something, right, no,
you are not doing something, but the
market is very
choppy, wait a minute, let me show you, one second, recent, let me
tell you about
yesterday, yesterday I was
trading and I was up 20, I was up around 29000,
okay, and in the last trade,
I skipped from 29000 and I
came back to 1000, the market is so
choppy right now that I am
trying very hard, I mean I am working with so much focus right now that
if there were normal market
conditions, then probably my capital, I
started from five, then it became six, then it became
8, then it became 10,
this was the month of June, one thing is that many
people do not know, I basically know
astrology and neurology,
I understand it a lot and I
follow a lot of things, lucky  It's the seventh
month, seven months. Okay, if you look at my win rate, you'll be blown away.
So far, I've
traded for 12 days. Out of those 12 days, I've
only had three losses. I've been profitable for nine days.
Now, I believe this is
my personal belief. Seven was my number,
and I just got lucky. You can say seven is
my number, but the market is so choppy.
If the market wasn't so choppy,
maybe this 10 lakh would have turned into 20 lakh within
this same seven month, within the seventh month. But
because the market is so choppy and
my luck is with me, I'm assuming
that while others are mainly making losses,
I'm at least in the green. I have
n't made huge profits, meaning I made a
big profit on just one day, July 5th. All the other
days are okay, meaning they're average. Some
days have been average, some days have been okay. I ca
n't say it's amazing. The
market is so choppy these days. It's just not just you.
I'm
dealing as a professional.  There is difficulty,
many people are facing it,
not just you, it is okay, but still a seven
number, then I got lucky, okay, so this is the
thing, so do not worry at all,
how much is the fee for the life class, 9852 9852, okay,
scalping will be fine for us, or intraday,
see, I am a student, I will only be
learning scalping for us, or intraday
scalping, Sachin, it can be right only when you have this
in your mind that I have a limited
fund, whether I know it or not,
practice for that, learn it, in the beginning
you will have to pay money, enter the market with this in
mind because
people are not able to connect the meaning with one thing,
if you are ready for the verse, then everything is
best, okay, so that mentality will be
fine, what else
is good for you, until I
cannot talk to you on a personal level, or you
evaluate yourself,
what is my nature, am I of hyper nature or do I have
patience, you will evaluate yourself in this way,
if you a little  If you can go on the patient side then
intraday is good, if you are a little hyper
then you will not be able to survive in scalping intraday, you will take
FOMO entries and you will incur losses.
Okay, how much should you start investing with? You should have a decent capital for investing
and the
definition of decent varies from person to person. For some
decent can be 1 lakh, for
some 1 lakh is nothing. Now if a
person is earning 5 lakhs a month, he may
say what will I do by investing 1 lakh at
least, then that person should start with 10 lakh or 12 lakh, so
it depends. Okay,
all right, which app is it? It will come,
we have to conduct a class, I will share the link right now. Don't worry, if I
trade Pushkal, then no, you will not,
Pushkal is in class, only I
trade only, one second, I trade only support
and resistance, so do I need to see the trend, or
not Pushka, or to see the trend. Okay, now
see Pushkal, understand this way.  In our class, we
discussed this point that whenever
we look at the market from the beginning and if we
find out that the market is in an uptrend, then
in the uptrend we will mainly focus more on support
rather than resistance. This is the case
for others as well. If the market is trending and
you have seen a trend, we will
focus more on support and a
little less on resistance. Till the time the market is
not reversing the trend, then what should we do? We have
collated the concept and
trading will get better. Okay, right now
I am doing S-sping,
not intraday trading. How much charges do I have to pay,
how does the FT get activated,
all that will come to you on call, then it happens in the form of a firm.
Thank you so much Abhishek. Thank you so much
Guru Purnima friend, I forgot today. Guru
Purnima is
great. Send the questions one by one.
I am not able to read it. It is getting stuck, I will have to
hold it.
Oh, it's
great. How to swing? What is
liquidity grab? We will
understand it by doing a dedicated class on
liquidity grab.  You can understand that whenever
a big position is opened in the market,
first it comes down and then it goes up, and when it goes down,
everyone's stoploss gets hit.
Yes, thank you sir, thank you so much.
Sachin, great, the best
liquidity group, one by one,
thank you so much. Please publish your
book very soon. The book will come very soon. I am
trying hard. I will launch the book very soon.
Okay,
Madan, I have taken your game play.
How to swing trade? For swing trade,
you will have to learn technical analysis.
After that, you will have to go there and
learn the process part. And then you have to go
for swing. Okay, how to
pick a swing stock. Let's
keep a class dedicated to all these points.
Okay, then you will understand well,
especially how to pick stocks. All these
things. Right, there will be a
class today. Yes, there will be a class. Why not,
why not, there will be a class. So, there will be a class. Classes happen
daily, right? There will be a daily class.
Thank you so much. Thank you so much for Guri Purna.
Thank
you.  How to deliver a fake breakout?
For a fake breakout, understand it like this.
You have created a point which shows resistance.
After the resistance, if the market has
given a breakout and after the breakout, an immediate
reversal is giving you an entry, then from there
also plan for a short. Okay, it is fake because
if it is a fake breakout, it will stop, it will
not continue. Immediately, let me
tell you about the right amount of beneficiary class. I will tell you right now.
I will put the link right now. Wait
a second, I don't know where it is. I will have to
find the link.
Firstly, I don't see all this. Give me
five or two minutes. I am telling you. Okay, give me
two minutes. I will check it and tell you.
Okay, till then let's take some more questions.
Tell me about SMC. Look, SMC, yes,
Smart Money
concept is not a new thing.
All the things that are there in Smart Money concept are already there.
If you combine support, resistance and trend analysis, then Smart Money concept will be formed.
Only its names have been changed.
Break of Structure, Change of Character,
Equal High, Equal Low. And what else do they call
orders?  Block, mitigation, block, it's all the same, support,
resistance, and price action.
Okay, so it's not a big deal,
where is that right class? I can't do it in live trading.
Nikhil, what you're doing, I can't do it.
I can't
take the risk. Okay,
otherwise I would have been doing live trading. I've
even uploaded videos of live trading, but right now I ca
n't find the time. So, I don't upload it.
Wait a second. Hey
man, look, once it's pasted, it'll be done. This is the
class link. Okay, the
internet isn't working
[music].
This is the pin replace. Okay, look, I've
pinned it. Okay, and those people who don't even have
capital left for trading, please do
n't join. I'm teaching here. Learn, don't
worry. Okay, tell me about the AMA.
I have a ready class.
Go and search once. 8im strategy by wiz dar will come up.
Okay,
one by one. Questions are not ICT concepts. ICT concepts are
not ICT concepts. The
name of the ICT guy is Inner Circle Trader.  There is a
trader, he
created a concept based on the knowledge he gained, which is called
smart money concept, in it they say how
big money flows and all, he explains it,
okay, but understand it like this, when you
understand support resistance, understand price
action well, understand trend analysis, then
you will understand that it is the same
thing again and again, some advanced things in it like fair
value gap, it works well, it works well, you just need to
understand some such concepts, in short, it is a
type of language, you can say like this,
okay, minimum capital for safe trading, see,
minimum capital is safe trading is never safe, if
trading is not safe then
put only that much capital as you can lose, it is
simple, okay, ITC is the name of the stock
20, okay, thank you so much for super chat, let's do it,
great, I have taken this recently class, will you
teach from basic, yes everything,
basics, what a nice name
you have kept, don't worry, everything starts from basic
in this class.  Okay, let's start with how to
improve psychology. We are going to do a
dedicated class for psychology, you should wait for it.
Whenever I come live, whether it is on
Saturday or Sunday, if it is live then
watch it late in the evening around
4 o'clock or 5 o'clock, then we will do it there.
Okay,
what happens in IV crash IV, the
volatile market falls and the
premium does not increase. That is the SMC
live class, and will do the option Greeks will do it. Let
me end it now. Okay, did you
enjoy it? Tell me whether you understood it or
not? Did you learn it
well? Right now I am just ending this meet. I hope
you liked it. Bye, see you tomorrow.
All the best, take care.