this was an easy trade this one ended up
going right off the bat why I got into
this trade my net profit and loss was
34. 94% but I got out and it just so
happens to have turned around the
biggest loss I took this year
[Music]
was today marks yet another Milestone I
feel like you guys are probably getting
sick of him to be honest you're like
every video she comes out with is a new
record something she's never done before
yet again and here we are with yet
another Milestone another record Another
personal best I don't know what to tell
you it just it is what it is maybe
that's that's what's content Worthy is
like the records the highs the lows that
I have recorded this year are quite
minimal the biggest loss I took this
year was $2,000 trade but this is where
we're at so let me walk you guys through
my record trade of my entire trading
career of 9 years I closed my biggest
trade I've ever had yesterday I made
$40,000 so let's break it down let's
what is the trade how much did I make
what percentage did I make what is my
profit Factor what is my win percentage
what is my average win to loss you guys
want to know all the nitty-gritty I'm
going to do a quick little tangent here
it's very important and it is something
that's been on the brain is I've had so
many people try to pick apart my trading
to analyze overanalyze if you will and
dissect every single move I make in the
markets to try to find their own success
or to try to find some sort of flaw or
discrepancy or anything so that they can
maybe make themselves feel better or
think that there is some secret formula
to being successful in trading when in
reality I think you guys that the ones
that try to dissect it are the ones that
actually do know the answer they know
the answer and it is truly just time it
is getting the chart time in and
dedicating the years to trading like I
think that's it you don't need to
dissect all of my traits you can and
I'll continue to do so because I'm I'm
an educator in the space and I feel like
it is my duty to share my my actual
trading results my broker statements my
percentages my trade expectancy all of
the analytics as much data as I can give
you guys to to be able to dissect it but
you're not going to find it you're not
going to find the secret sauce or the
the one thing you've been missing or the
one thing that you need to truly make
you feel better about the position that
you're in in trading or to think that
you're going to get there much sooner or
you're like ah this was the missing
piece she is a fraud you're not going to
find it cuz I'm not and you know the
answer it's not going to happen in one
missing puzzle piece it is just time and
dedication so now with that tangent
being said and done and over let's get
into the trade let's go over why I got
into this trade I'm going to show you
guys exactly where my lines were
disregard the trade that is on here
there's two arrows in one candle I went
live last night on YouTube and showed
everybody my trade and then all the
while accidentally placed a freaking
trade on the live stream cannot believe
that happened I have instant order
placement I hit this freaking button by
accident trying to move the chart around
so disregard those last two arrows this
Arrow here which says 20 contracts buy
at
948.025 so I'm going to pause for a
moment here and allow you guys to drop a
comment in the chat just test yourself I
know you're going to get the answer to
this obviously in a moment but take this
challenge look at this view based on
where the lines are at and the types of
lines that I have on the screen some of
you guys may think it's a laser show
some of you guys may be able to actually
find a method to the madness and it
might be a little bit clearer than you
think according to where the lines are
at on the screen what do you think told
me to get into this
trade I'll wait I'll pause I'll think of
some small talk while you're typing and
while you're looking at okay we've got
downward lines we've got red lines we
got upward lines we got green lines we
got horizontal lines we got yellow lines
out of which one of these lines and the
entry that you see here on the screen
the candles that you see the trade the
movement what do you think got me into
this trade I've done enough small talk
now to where you've probably typed in an
answer and hit send now I will tell you
the answer and let's see if you were
right or wrong if you guys know me as a
Trader and know my social media have
watched my content before you guys know
I'm a trendline Trader so that's already
first and foremost let's look at the
trend lines here we got a few on the
screen we've got this ever so slightly
steep or ever so slightly upward green
trend line this one's going back from a
higher time frame and then we've got
these two downward red trend lines this
downward red trend line has one two
three touch points boom we got three
touch points we've got a break of that
downward trend line I am a breakout
Trader I trade when the trend breaks out
and then try to stay in for that new
trend and it's essentially just that
over and over and over again I get a
breakout of a trend now I'm trying to
stay in for the new trend and then when
I get a breakout of that new trend I'm
closing my position and then reversing
that continues we do that over and over
again so if you put because we got a
break of a trend line you are correct
good job ding ding ding we have a winner
if you put because it bounced off of
this support 9 35.2 you were wrong now
that doesn't mean you're wrong maybe
that's your strategy but that is not
what opted for me to get into this trade
now it did give me some added
confirmation and it made me a lot more
confident about my trade because it was
rejecting off of this 935 point2 but
that is not what indicated an entry for
me I am a trend line Trader a trend line
breakout Trader specifically I need a
break out of a trend in order to take an
entry in order to get into a position so
we have a break of a downward Trend
where is my risk everyone wants to know
where is my stop- loss going the stop-
loss will always go on the other side of
the opposing trend line at the time
guess what this steep trend line was not
there I did not know that was going to
be there I did not know what was going
to happen in the future and know exactly
where to put my upward trend line no at
the time I only saw this candle that's
it we're looking at a 4H hour time frame
we got a break of a 4H hour downward
trend line my stop loss has to go on the
other side of not only this area of
support but also this upward trend line
stop- loss goes on the other side of it
it's not exact to the scent to the te to
the dime I am simply dragging that stop
loss and putting it on the other side of
that as long as price can stay above
this upward green trend line and this
area of support I'm happy and I'm
staying in my trade well as we continue
to watch what price does we can see this
was an easy trade this one ended up
going right off the bat I think I was
barely in draw down for maybe a few
hours and then this thing is just going
continuing did I know it was going to do
that no I get into my trade expecting
either outcome this was either going to
be a fake out and continue to turn
around and hit my stop loss or it was
going to keep going I didn't know how
long it was going to continue to Trend
up for I didn't know how quickly or how
aggressively I just took the signal that
we got a break of a downward trend line
that is my inkling that okay we may no
longer be trending down because we broke
the downward trend line so now I could
have tried to track price steeper upward
with these candles here but since I
almost have like this relationship with
Platinum when I'm in a 4-Hour time frame
I just know the steeper the line the
more likely it is to get crossed price
does not respect these steeper trend
lines very often in the 4-Hour time
frame so I will always opt for the less
steep so I am continuing to stick with
my original trend line my less steep
line we've got a lot of wiggle room here
I could give my profit back and some but
I want to have a more obvious point B A
more obvious pullback to track price
steeper so so I'm allowing price to
continue all right we're going we're
feeling good ooh we got some pullback
here we're getting a little bit
nervous all right we got some sideways
movement here
okay all right now we got a pretty
aggressive candle here so now we are in
profit significantly I want to try to
capitalize on that now we've got at
least enough data to work with we've got
enough candles we've got enough time
that's gone by I feel comfortable Now
tracking this steeper now with not as
obvious of a pullback but it's it's
something if I want to try to at least
maintain some of this profit I have to
track this deeper so then this is where
I come in with my Ray tool my trend line
we got point a and this last low that's
all we're working with here and let's
continue to move these candles forward
okay looking good looking great I
probably exited right
here now we'll go back and see but now
the strategy I should be staying in this
trade until price breaks this upward
trend line I happen to have this
reoccurring theme here or this habit
this year where since I am trading
bigger positions this year and I'm
trying to do this almost like exposure
therapy experiment I am I'm working on
bigger capital and bigger positions and
I'm also letting these dollar amounts
influence my decisions so when I saw
that I was up $40,000 I closed it
clipped out one it was a record trade oh
my gosh amazing two that was a really
big amount and three I did not want to
give that back
so if I had removed the dollar amounts
and purely traded based on my strategy I
shouldn't have exited until price
crossed this line right here at this 974
that is according to the strategy that
right there would have been a texbook
trade beautiful profit we would have
given the opportunity for platinum to
continue up it could have gone all the
way to 1020 but we allowed it to show us
what trend it was going to follow along
if I would have traded 100% by the book
according to to the strategy entry would
have been at the break and exit would
have also been at the break instead I
got out and let's go ahead and get out
of Replay mode yes instead I got out at
9988.hk
so did I know something no I didn't I
didn't know that was going to be the
high at the time that was just luck but
I did take my entry based on my strategy
not based on luck I got a break of a
downward trend line we got three touch
points really nice I love it we got a
lot of data behind it A+ setup here low
risk because of how close the price was
to my opposing trend line everything
checked out but the exit I did not know
was going to be high at the time my true
exit according to the strategy should
have been here this 974 is area that's
where I should have closed my trade so
let's talk a little bit more now about
the specifics of the trade and the
nitty-gritty of the trade cuz I know
that's what you guys want to know what
was my Capital how many contracts did I
trade when did I enter when did I exit
what is my percentage profit and loss so
let's go through that part so right here
the entry 20 contracts at 948.025
it was somewhere on the other side I
simply take the stop loss and I drag it
make sure that it's on the other side of
this 9352 and this upward green trend
line exit 20 contracts at
9988.hk trying to show everybody my
trade so if we can disregard that that'd
be great if you don't want to okay then
don't but let's go into the trade so I
made about we'll say give or take like
uh 1 or 2% because of that accidental
trade but my net profit and loss was 34.
94% if we want to go over my stats for
the year look at the win percentage from
January 1st to August 1st it says 11
trades there's a few trades in here that
I made for YouTube content I did some
day trading I I wish I hadn't we'll go
through these numbers and you guys can
see the bigger trades are going to be my
swing trades and then there's going to
be like three maybe three trades within
that that are experimental day trading
trades that I did for content on YouTube
which I regret because now it throws all
my stats off but it is what it is we'll
go ahead and count it anyways my net
profit and loss for the year so far is
125.81614610
sure we're all the day trades but we'll
we'll go over them anyways and my
average win to loss is 22.9 my trade
Zella score is 100 that's awesome didn't
know how I did that but love it okay now
let's go into the trade themselves okay
here we go let's start from the
beginning January 22nd 2024 10,000 bucks
February 12th 2024 29,000 in Platinum
then the very end of February February
27th $10,000 in crude oil this one I
remember vividly we've got March 25th
accident trade I got into the wrong
contract of platinum had to close attive
2,837 took my first L of the Year love
that for me and it's so unfair that it
was an accidental one but it was my
fault I was not paying attention to the
correct contract I should have been in
pln 24 instead I got into PLJ 24 so next
trade we're going in strong we're in the
correct contract for platinum we made
$30,000 then the next trade we're
looking at April 25th
$24,000 then we've got one two day
trades here I placed a stupid day trade
in Copper lost
$267 placed a stupid day trade in crude
oil lost $66 and then oh my god let's go
over actually I'll save this one for
another video I experimented with
ethereum but I stayed in the Futures
market so I still stayed safe I placed a
trade in ethereum within the Futures
market so it was the Futures version of
ethereum and I was in that for 3 weeks
maybe even four weeks it was
excruciating the amount of volatility
the draw down the profit it was
nightmare it was a roller coaster and
then after those 3 or 4 weeks I ended up
closing it with a whopping $46 that was
excruciating and then we've got my
record trade here of oh 39,6 61 when I
hit the button so maybe it's there's a
little bit of spread there maybe I was a
little bit late so not quite 40,000 but
close we're going to go ahead and call
it $40,000 in Platinum the trade opened
up on the 26th and I closed it on the
31st so I was in that trade for 4 days
18 hours and 44 minutes and then this
one as you guys can see The Accidental
trade there it was I was in it for one
whole minute in 33 seconds lost $264
love that for me but this is the one
that we really want to get into this is
the record trade here plv 24 okay entry
price
94864 exit price 9883 net Roi
4.18% net profit and loss
$39,600
939 ticks and then the duration of the
trade was 4 days 18 hours and 44 minutes
hold on everyone's going to want to know
how much dollar amounts was I willing to
lose on this trade so let's go back
through and walk through it I'm going to
have to guess and say it was maybe like
10 to 13,000 that I was willing to lose
to make the goal was 50 but I ended up
settling for 40 I don't know the exact
dollar amount I will tell you that I
place my stop- losses and plan my risk
based on dollar amounts and not on
percentages is it's not a fixed
percentage it's not a fixed amount every
single trade it is dynamic it is all
dependent on how close the price is to
my safety line which is the line that
keeps me safe the line that mitigates my
risk so that was the full breakdown of
my $40,000 trade my record trade of my
trading career well if you guys have any
questions go ahead and drop another
comment you should have already placed a
comment on what you thought got me into
that trade if you didn't rewind let me
know what you think would have gotten me
into that trade although you've already
made it to the end so you know what got
me into the trade but if you guys have
any questions on the trade specifically
I'm going to be posting my broker
statements on the community section of
my YouTube so stay tuned for that and I
will see you guys in the next video
thanks for hanging out don't forget to
like subscribe smash that noty Bell and
I will see you guys in the next video