in the summer of last year I shared the
full coding of my scalloping year it got
a bit of interest and a lot of people
started asking me if they can apply it
on profone challenges and my answer was
no because the codes were not written in
a way that was suitable for Prof from
challenges but it got me thinking if I
can make the modifications and the
tweeks necessary to apply it on propone
challenges in this video we're going to
look at all the modifications and the TW
each and the additional features that
have added including a panel to track
our progress I will share all of the
codings with full explanation and
details with no more Shenanigans let's
start
in order to find out if this scalping
robot can even work on Prop Firs I
created a new account separate from my
regular one in order to just trade the
scalloping robot on that I applied it on
Euro USD gpp USD usdjpy NASDAQ gold and
Bitcoin the key settings profile
depending on whether it's a currency or
other asset class on a 5- minute chart
starting at 600 hours and 2100 hours
with 100 bars in I explained the bars
and in quite a bit of detail in my last
video so I'm not going to go over it
today then standard settings for the for
pays and these settings for the other
asset classes news filter on to avoid
NFP Joels non-farm payroll and interest
rate and only for USD currencies because
that moves the market really rapidly I'm
applying the RSI filter but not the
moving average filter currently and then
if you look at the results from the
first of Jan until today the 30th the EA
has made about 21% profit looking by
pairs we have 1% on usdjpy 4% on gold
with a big trade of
$161 7% on bitcoin because Bitcoin has
been in a very strong
Trend 2% on gpp USD 5% on Euro USD again
with one big trade and 1% on
NASDAQ allog together 50 trades that are
amounting to 21% profit let's look at
the report it shows the total from the
mid of December when I actually created
the account we had a couple of losing
trades in the beginning before I shut
off the year for Christmas and New Year
but from there on the year has performed
really well so there's $100 in one week
of December and $1,000 in full month of
gen on a base of
€5,000 well not much to show in this
step almost equal long and shorts by
simpol as we saw Bitcoin did very very
well due to a very strong Trend followed
by EU and gold but most importantly the
draw
down which was about 4% during the month
owing to a very high win rate so
consecutive losses do not happen that
much we had one loss trade on the 15th
of Jan and one on the 17th of Jan these
are the only only two trades that went
into losses in the month of Jan now I
cannot claim that this is how the year
is going to perform month after month
weeks after weeks years after years but
it does seem to have the right profile
for a prop fform challenge now guys I
know a lot of you rush to the store to
download it if you're not even going to
spend the next 12 15 minutes to
understand the functionality of the E
and its most important settings just
rushing to download and apply the EA
will be completely
useless the key reason that I said this
EA cannot work on a Prof fir is because
it requires an extremely aggressive
trading stop loss which on my broker is
not a problem because there is no limit
to how close you can set a stop loss to
the price but many Brokers do have that
requirement and a lot of prop forms as
well and if the trailing is stop is not
going to work the entire strategy is
based on aggressive trailing so the
strategy is not going to work so one key
change that we're going to make to the
EA is to check for minimum stop-loss
distance required by the broker and if
the user input is smaller than that then
we're going to override that input and
use that minimum so we know that the TR
stop loss will work even if at a
slightly bigger distance the second
change we will make to the EA is to
introduce a panel so we can track the
progress on key rules at all times and
also to stop trading if a certain draw
down for a day has happened or a certain
draw down for a week has happened or a
certain draw down overall has happen and
we will have the ability to set these
thresholds a little bit below the prop
from challenge rules so there is some
safety margin and if we want to change
something we still have room to do it so
let's take a look at this visually say
we run the year on bitcoin we start from
the 1 of gen until today so we have to
select the setting percentage of price
profile which you are familiar with from
all of the other videos that I made on
scalping robot and don't worry if you're
not because we're going to go over the
key settings in details anyway we take
2% risk on every trade we run it on 5
minutes chart and then at the bottom you
define all the Prof form rules you
define when the challenge started so we
can calculate the weeks and the months
correctly because you might start the
challenge in the middle of the month and
then you define the Max draw down
allowed say if for a day the max allowed
is 5% then we put 3% to give ourself a
little bit of buffer and safety margin
then if for a week the max allowed is
10% then we set 7even and then we set
the same seven for the month and then
for the entire challenge as well say on
the fdmo the requirement is 5% Max draw
down for a day and 10% for a month so we
keep the safety margin let's run a
visual test so we can see how this
entire thing works the very first thing
that the E is now going to check is what
is the minimum stop-loss distance
required by the broker and if the input
by the user is lower than that then it
will override with the broker's minimum
so we know that the triling is going to
happen it be it a bigger distance from
the price and then with the second
modification you can see the key stats
in the panel which is going to be on the
screen what balance did you start the
challenge with what was the balance at
the beginning of the day beginning of
the week which is then used to calculate
the profit percentages at the bottom so
you know where you are versus the target
so how much profit today this week and
overall but more importantly the equity
high points because the draw Downs are
not calculated versus the opening
balances they are calculated versus the
highest Equity points so during the day
during the week whenever we have hit a
peak for that week for that day we store
that point as a highest Equity point and
then calculate the draw down versus that
so we look at today the last 7 Days the
last 30 days and overall which is the
most important requirement of the props
managing the draw down and with the
modifications you have it here in the
panel in one glance then the other
setting we're going to change is the
loss size setting so before you only
used to have risk as a percentage of the
balance but now you can Define as fixed
slots as a percentage of balance as a
percentage of equity so in case you you
have other open trades because of
another year the Year also takes that
into consideration and then also has a
percentage of free margin because if you
have other trades open on the account
then free margin is more relevant than
the equity itself depending on what you
select you need to Define as a risk
percentage if you are using the risk
percentage either of balance Equity or
free margin and then if you are defining
it as fixed Lots then you need to Define
what your fixed lots are going to be
here and the last modification that
we're going to make to the EA is for the
trailing stop loss now in the normal
scalping robot video we have the
trailing stop loss as an extremely
aggressive trailing stop loss so as soon
as the price moves into profit we start
trailing the stop loss very aggressively
until the price comes back and hits it
but then I've have also added other
types of trailing stop losses the first
time the stop- loss is going to move is
when the price moves into profit so it
will be like the normal default trailing
stop loss but once the stop loss has
moved to break even then you can select
the default Trail type which is the
aggressive Trail type but now you also
have the possibility to Trail the stop-
loss on previous candle in case of a buy
it will be trailed on the previous
candle's low and in case of a sell it
will be trailed on the previous candle
high and then you have to Define here
how many candles do you want to Trail it
by so if you say one then it's going to
be on the previous candle if you say two
it's going to be on the previous from
previous and so on and so forth another
way you can Trail the stop- loss after
it has moved to break even is on fast
moving average in that case you define
what that fast moving average is going
to be so there is a little bit more
distance than just the last candle or
the last from last candle and lastly you
can also decide to trade tril it on the
ichimoku 10 consent line in which case
once the price has moved in profit and
the stop loss has moved to break even
after that the trailing is going to
happen on the 10 consent line I will
share all the course and explain them as
best I can but the panel that is going
to require quite a lot of coding
including all the mql classes and stuff
but buckle up because it's going to be
some
effort now before you apply this e you
do need to understand what the E
actually does so we need to look at this
strategy as well we defined the last
last high and last low in the market and
then we place buy orders and sell orders
and when the price comes and hits those
levels again what we are basically
banking is that the price is going to
continue to move in that direction by at
least another couple Pips so as soon as
it moves in profit we start trailing the
stop- loss extremely aggressively which
is the reason why the win rate is 90%
but this comes at a cost because the
profit trates are going to be small and
one is stop loss hit is going to be
larger but what we're counting on is
that with a high win rate the small
amount profit trades are going to more
than offset that one big stoploss hit
and this brings us to the last key
settings which is the bars end value
which is what we use to define the highs
and lows in the market so let's say if
you put the value as five then the year
is going to try and find the price
structure where there are five candles
to the left and five candles to the
right all below the middle candle and
then it's going to call it a high but if
you put the value as 100 now the EA has
to find a price structure where there
are 100 candles on the left and 100
candles on the right all below the
middle candle before the es say that it
is a valid high so with a small value
you're going to get a lot of these highs
which is going to work amazingly well
during a strong Trend because you want
to trade every time there is a new high
for me but when the markets are just
simply drifting then you don't want to
be trading every small new high that
appears because the price is going to
take your order and then it might zigzag
back to the stop loss before continuing
again in the same direction so with a
higher value of 50 or 100 it's going to
be on the more established price point
that you place your orders but there are
going to be fewer trades and a smaller
value trades are going to be more
frequent as the EA is going to continue
to trade every new high that forms in
the market so it's a
trade-off before we start with the
modification of the EA some of the very
key settings that you definitely need to
understand the first one is the correct
profile there is the fixed pip profile
which if you select that then you define
all of the stop-loss DP trigger of the
stop loss and the trailing stop loss
here and this one is when you're using
the Forex Pairs and then there's the
percentage of price profile to determine
stop- losses TPS and trailing Etc and
this is because other asset classes they
can vary in prices so Bitcoin used to be
$220,000 and $40,000 and $50,000 and now
$100,000 so fixed Pips on such varying
prices do not make any sense at all so
for Bitcoin gold and NASDAQ or Dow Jones
if you want to use that we use the
percentage of price profile and then we
Define the TP and the stop- loss as a
percentage of the price here and then
Define the trigger of the trailing stop-
loss and the trailing stop loss as a
percentage of of that is stop loss so if
Bitcoin was $11,000 when we took the
trade then 0.4% will equals 100,000 *
0.4% so $400 so the TP is going to be
set at ,400 and a stop loss at 9,600 and
then the trading stop loss will trigger
once the price has moved in our
favorable Direction by 10% of the stop
loss so taking that $400 10% of that is
40 so only when the price has moved more
than $40 in profit that's when the
trailing will start and then the
trailing is 5% of the stop loss so $20
so at any point in time the distance
between the price and the trailing stop
loss will be $20 going up and then the
minimum order distance because you
cannot set an order here when the price
is already above it so you need to have
a distance to that order and also we
want to make sure that when we sending
the order there is a distance between
the order and the price that's is going
to be based on 50% of the stop loss as
well so it's going to be $200 so the
price needs to be $200 below that point
where we're sending the order then the
news filter is self-explanatory so which
news do you want to avoid and on which
currencies so for example interest rate
on USD then the RSI filter is to stop
trading when the price is in extreme
condition so when the RSI is above 80 or
below 20 on a higher time frame chart
such as 4 hours we stop trading because
now the markets can be very chaotic and
then the same for the moving average
filter but in a different way so it
looks at 200 EMA and then we say what
percentage the price needs to be away
from that moving average up or down
let's say 3% so if the the price is that
far away from the moving average it is
in an extreme condition and we don't
want to be trading further because it
might reward back then the trading
Allowed by day which is not so relevant
for Forex paays but say Bitcoin trades
over Saturday and Sunday as well and you
might not want to trade it because of
lower liquidity and lastly the prop from
settings so what's the initial balance
when you start the challenge because you
if you turn off the EA in the middle and
then reapply it the EA doesn't know
where you started what is the profit
Target so the EA stops when it has
reached that profit so has not to lose
anything after that then what's the
start date of the challenge because we
need that to calculate the 7day draw
down the month draw down Etc and if you
started the challenge in the middle of
the month the EA needs to know that and
then the Max draw down settings for the
challenge best to keep them below the
actual requirement so the EA stops with
a little bit of a safety margin in case
you want to make some
changes now guys I do have to say that I
do not use Pro funds myself I don't
really see a point I have traded myself
over the years and grew a customer base
and thereby a fund that manage also I
believe that the business model of the
Prof Firs is completely based on you
paying for the challenge and then losing
that's where their profits come from
much like the video that I made on the
Brokers and how they stack up everything
against you I believe the profunds do
the same banking on you to lose the
challenge so they can keep the money
that you paid and their funded accounts
are probably not even funded accounts
these are just virtual accounts as they
believe that even if you pass the
challenge you will probably blow up the
account anyway but with all that said
here are the modifications required to
make this scalping robot more suitable
for profer challenges as well because a
lot of people do want to use
it we're going to start with the
scalloping Robo including the gold
Bitcoin indices with the filters so this
video basically where we're going to
start from let's first save the file as
Bitcoin
indices and I'm going to change it to
including mods
filters and additional
features and two more features that
we're going to add before we go to the
prop features are going to be is trading
Allowed by which day because on bitcoin
it also trades on Saturday and Sunday
and there might be a lot of people who
do not want to trade on Saturdays and
Sundays and in that case you can just
simply turn this to false and that the
system knows not to trade on Saturday on
Sunday and the other setting that we're
going to change before we start with the
prop from things is to have a drop- down
where we're going to have the lot sizes
based on either fixed Lots or percentage
of balance or percentage of equity or
percentage of free margin and in case if
we select fixed slots then we need to
say what is the value of the fixed lots
and then if we go for anything else
which is a percentage of balance Equity
of free margin then we need to input
here what is that percentage so these
two features we're going to add first
because they are not related to prop
firm as such there just general part of
the scalping robot and we'll help
everyone and then we will focus on
converting this EA to prop firm so back
again in metat Trader we're starting off
from where we left off in this video and
the first thing I'm going to do is I'm
going to get all of the enums and put
them together so let's make a place
above here where we're going to gather
all of the
enums Just to clean up a
little only the news filter enum I'm
leaving down below here because it is
related only the news
filter okay so now we have these drop
down enims that we created before and
now I'm going to add one more enum to it
which is an enum for lot type and we're
giving the values of fixed Lots
percentage of balance percentage of
equity or percentage of free margin so
now when we use this enum the user will
get this drop- down possibility to
select then we come down to Common
trading inputs and this is where we will
ask the user what type of lot type do
you want so we're saying input enum lot
type which is this so it's going to give
this drop down to the user so the user
can select a value and whatever value
the user is going to select it's going
to be stored in lot type I'm putting the
default value as one which is the
percentage of balance so when the user
loads the year in default the default
Position will be percentage of balance
in the drop down but he can select now
all these four values and his selection
will be stored in this variable that we
created as lot type then we already have
the risk percentage variable so we only
need one more variable which is going to
be fix slots so in case the user selects
fixed slots in the dropdown the value of
the fixed slots is going to come from
this variable and then the risk
percentage is from before so we already
have that and then the rest of the time
frame magic number they remain the same
I'm currently using the es bars 100 so
I'm going to change this to 100 as well
in fact normally I would change it here
directly but just in case if someone is
following this video the default values
that I'm using these days is bars and
100 and nothing else changes anywhere
then we come down to the bottom and this
say we're going to create a group
trading Allowed by days and we will
create these seven variables so is it
allowed on Monday is it allowed on
Tuesday Wednesday Thursday Friday
Saturday and Sunday and I'm setting the
default value to be true and then we're
going to need one more variable for
which we don't need the user input so
I'm not putting it as an input but
directly as bu so as a true or false
variable and I'm calling it day filter
on which we're going to use to check
whether or not the user has selected a
certain day to be true or false so this
is for the inputs and then to implement
the first option which was the lot type
selection we're going to go down to
calculate lot size and this is where
we're going to implement the change so
we'll start with whatever is the minimum
volume for that symbol on that broker so
you basically request from your broker
by using the function simple input
double sending the symbol value and
asking what is the minimum volume on
that pair Allowed by the broker and
whatever value comes back we store it
into the Lots variable then as we giving
the possibilities to have lot sizes
defined by percentage of balance
percentage of equity and percentage of
free margin so we need to know those
values so the first thing I'm asking is
the account balance by using the
function account info double and asking
for the balance then I ask for the
equity value and store it into a double
variable Equity balance and lastly we
get the free margin value so what is the
free margin on the account as we speak
now so we get that value from the broker
as well because you might have a few
open trades from another EA or if you're
manually trading in the same account
then you might be interested in getting
the free margin and basing your lot
sizes on the free margin and not the equ
with your account and then instead of
Simply assigning the risk value using
the account balance now we have to see
what has the user selected so I'll start
with risk value as zero and then I'm
going to switch between the lot types so
the variable that we created up top the
lot type which is this dropdown so
whatever the user has selected here we
stored that value into this lot type
variable and now we're going to switch
between those values so we're going to
go through all of the values one by one
I open the bracket so I need to close it
and then within this function we're
going to switch between different values
so we say if the case is zero which is
the fixed Lots then the lots are equals
to the fixed Lots variable which is the
variable we created here in that case
assign that fixed Lots value to the Lots
variable that we have created here and
then just return so exit the function
don't don't need to do anything else we
have already assigned the lot's value
but then if the value is one which is
the percentage of account balance in
that case we say risk is going to be
whatever is the account balance that we
have gotten here multiply it by the risk
percentage variable that the user is
defining here we don't return like here
because we if that is the case then we
need to continue but in that case we say
break meaning if if this was the case
and you have done this break this
function don't do anything here and then
go on to these lines then exactly in the
same way we say if the case was two then
the risk equals Equity balance times the
risk percentage and if the if the case
selected by the user is three then it's
three margin times the risk percentage
which is to say here this is case Zero
case 1 case 2 and case three in every
case we break in this case we don't have
to but a good practice to break the
function so when the when the system is
going to come here it's going to start
with lot size as minimum then it's going
to get the values of these then it's
going to start with the risk value of
zero and then it's going to go through
the lot type switch through it and then
depending on whether the user has
selected fix slots account balance
Equity or free margin it's going to
assign either the Lots directly and then
exit the function or it's going to
assign the value of risk in absolute
terms so that then we can run the rest
of the function to calculate and then
return the losss nothing else else
changes in this function so we compile
and we get one error which is the
variable is already defined because we
already defined the variable last time
and now we're defining it again so this
is the definition now and this is just
the assignment if I compile
again then we have zero error and then
if I go back to meta Trader now we have
this drop down available to us and
depending on what you select the system
is going to calculate the lot sizes
based on whatever you select here either
using the percentage value for these
three options or in case of a fixed loss
it's just going to take the fixed loss
from here so that's the first change
that we made and then for the second
change which is about whether or not
trading is allowed on a certain day
let's go down to the bottom and we'll
create one more function let's call that
function is trading allow by day the
first thing we're going to do is we're
going to create an mql datetime variable
which is and call it today an mql
datetime variable is a variable that
stores the Val of the date time
separately for the number of day the
month the year and everything that way
so for example if you had to say today
and then you hit dot you will get the
value of day day of the week year hour
minute so it breaks down into a
structure the mql DAT time which has now
that is structure so by day day of the
week hour minute so we can break it down
the time and that then gives us the
possibility to create a variable a
string variable day today which is what
is the day today and then we can say can
convert the enum to string get the the
today's day of the week value which is
basically this today day of the week
whatever is the day of the week so is it
day one day two day three take that
convert it from the number of the day to
the name of the day so Monday Tuesday
wedn is the Thursday and because it's
going to return the value as an enum so
we need to convert it into a string so
we say enum to string therefore we're
going to get the value of Monday or
Tuesday as a string that we store into
day to-day and then the life becomes
very easy because we just simply say if
the allowed Monday is true which is here
we're asking the user is monay is
trading on Monday allow if it is true
and the day today value which is
returned is Monday and it's all in caps
this is how the value comes back it's
not going to work if you write it like
this or if you write it like this a lot
of people make the mistake of not
following the the case mql is case
sensitive so you need to say Monday all
in caps so if Monday allowed is true and
day-to-day value returned by this
function is Monday so just return the
value of true from here so exit the
function and return the value true and
we do the same for all the rest of the
days so is if allowed Tuesday is true
and return value of this function is
Tuesday then fine if trading is allowed
on Wednesday and today is Wednesday then
of course return true and so on and so
forth until Sunday now if any of this
value was false so if the use user had
selected false here then of course
allowed Sunday is going to be false and
day-to-day return will be Sunday so then
this function is going to return the
value of false and then following the
logic that we had here for printing the
messages for rsia for ma filter for RSI
filter and for news filter we're going
to use the same logic to say that if
trading enabl com is equal to blank so
there is no value in the trading enabled
com with just to refresh the
memory is a string that we created here
in the global variables to store
whatever comment we want to send so if
that value is blank that means there is
no comment stored or if the tra enable
value is printed because once we print
the value once we will change the value
of this variable to print it in that
case we don't want to print it again and
again and again so either if it's blank
or its value is not equal to printed
that means then we need to print a new
message so then we say trading enabled
com becomes trading is not allowed plus
whatever is the value of the day coming
from here and then if nothing if none of
the above is true then just return
false and that covers this function
let's compile it we don't have any error
so far so now we have created the
function and now we need to use it so we
go back up here on the ontick function
where we were always checking for all
the filters the news filter the RSI
filter the ma filter we're going to add
one more condition here that if the
value of the is trading Allowed by day
comes back as a false and this is why
saying not is trading Allowed by day
because if it is allowed then it's going
to come back as true and if it's not
allowed then it's going to come back as
false so in case if it's false then you
need to close all of the orders which
are currently on the broker server you
need to change the trading enabl to
false change the color of the chart to
whatever the user has selected as to be
the color of the chart when the trading
is off and then if the enabled Comm is
not equals to printed then print the new
commment that we just wrote here the
trading is not allowed on certain day
print that and then after you have
printed change the trading enabled com
variable to print it so the next time
the year goes here oh but it is equal to
printed so it's this condition is false
so it's not going to print it again
otherwise you're going to have a list of
the same message going until the time
the trading is enabled again and it will
just continue and this is why we use
this logic of printed print and then
return meaning exit this entire function
of ontake don't run these codes below
now one thing you can do to make the EA
a little bit more efficient is take the
if is new bar and move it up here to
after the trailing
stop because everything before this is
going to be run on every tick and I
don't know if you want to run this on
every tick maybe you just want to check
it on every new candle which is going to
be every 5 minutes or every 10 minutes
if you do want to check it on every tick
then you just need to leave it here and
have this a still above I prefer to
change it to checking on every bar
because you're not going to be running
this scalping year on a 4H hour chart so
it might still be okay to check for
these conditions every 10 minutes 5
minutes of 15 minutes but if you are
planning to use it on a 1 hour chart
better to leave it below here so in that
case the E doesn't end up checking for
these conditions every hour it checks it
on every day so that's the tradeoff I
compile I have no error and now we have
in our scalping robot the possibility to
assign the lot sizes by fixed Lots
percentage of balance percentage of
equity or percentage of free
margin and also we have the ability to
say whether or not to trade on a
specific big day so this covers the
first part which is the normal scalping
EA additional features and now we can
move on to the stuff that we have added
for prop funds now on to the
modifications that we're going to make
for prop funds so the first one we're
going to make is to check for a minimum
stop-loss distance because many Brokers
have a requirement for how far away the
stop loss needs to be from the price and
this scalping year is completely
dependent on trailing the stop- loss
aggressively so in case if on your prop
firm they have a limitation on how
aggressively you can Trail the stop-
loss the strategy is just not going to
work so not only that we're going to
check for the stop loss minimum distance
on the broker and then set the value
accordingly but then we're also going to
add many different ways of trailing the
stop losses so if the aggressive
trailing is not possible then at least
you have other methods of trailing the
stop loss then we're going to simplify
the profiles currently we have Forex
profile Bitcoin profile gold profile and
US indicis profile separately but the
Bitcoin gold and US indicis profile is
more or less the same because here
you're defining the PPS and stop losses
as a percentage of the price so we can
combine these together and simplify
stuff then we're going to add a panel so
that we can track the prop from
challenge stats and also we're going to
add enabling and disabling of the
trading once those draw down limits have
been hit so for example if on your prop
firm the draw down requirement for the
day is 5% then you don't want to be
trading once it has already been 4% draw
down so we'll add a feature where you
can Define probably like 3% so once 3%
draw down has been hit on a certain day
we disable the trading automatically and
then we start the trading again the next
St so these are the five modifications
that we're going to make so we start now
with the scalping robot including mods
filters and additional features and we
save it as another file into a new
folder and let's call it scalping prop
form and use an underscore or something
because the way that we're going to
write the code we're going to have to
reference this file location in that
case there can be no spaces so I'm
putting it as es scalping uncore prop
form and then I'm going to call this is
scalping
underscore prop firm version once again
with underscores because we cannot have
spaces so now that we have that we
create a new and this time we're going
to have an include file because that's
where we're going to create our panel so
we're going to create an include file
and let's call it prop form panel again
you cannot have spaces so I'm combining
it together as prop from panel and it's
in the include folder and we have finish
and this is what you're going to get as
the mph file I'll clean it up so you're
basically left with this then we're
going to use two include files which are
here in the controls the dialogue and
the level and what this does is it gives
us all of these pre-written codes that
mql has written so that we don't have to
write it and we can use it by
referencing and the dialogue is going to
create that small panel within which
we're going to have all of our steps and
levels are basically levels so it's
textt that you can write within that
dialogue so we're going to reference to
these two files then we're going to
create an input group and call it panel
parameters because this is where we're
going to store all of the variables
where we ask the user to provide their
input and here we're going to ask the
user how much should be the width of the
panel and how much should be the height
of the panel so they can adjust it then
for the text size within the panel what
text size do they want so they can
increase or decrease the font size if
they want to and then we're going to ask
them for two more colors for example if
your target profit is 10% once that
Target profit is hit 10% we're going to
stop the trading but we also want to
change the color of the chart to
something else so that the user can one
glance see that oh it's green now so
that means that the entire target has
been achieved and also when the draw
down has been exceeded for that day or
for that week we also want to turn on
the trading but we also want to change
the color of the chart then to whichever
color the user selects that they can see
in one glass that the trading is
disabled and then they can look around
okay why is it disabled and what do they
need to do so we're going to ask for
these two colors as well and then we're
going to create a class and we're going
to call it C prop from panel that's the
name of the panel that we're going to
create and we're going to use the C the
the ca dialogue function from the
dialogue include file and it's going to
be a public function so other functions
and other files can access it as well we
close it here and then we create two
different parts of this class one is the
private and the other part is public so
everything that we're going to write
here is going to be accessible only to
this function and this portion that
we're going to write here in the public
section is going to be available to not
only this mq file but also anything
that's referencing to this mq class is
also going to be able to use it in the
private class we're going to create a Bo
function by the name create panel which
we're going to have to create here as bu
create panel so this is a function that
we're going to write later but we're
going to be able to call this function
from the private portion of the CPR from
panel that we have created here and then
within the public section we have to
create a Constructor for prop from panel
which is going to be exactly the same
name as here so these two names should
be exactly the same and then we also
need a d Constructor which is with this
stilla sign before the see prop form
panel name which is going to be used to
destroy this panel then once we have
created it we also need to initialize it
so we're going to create a bull function
by the name on in it to keep it
different from the on initialization
function here we're going to use a lower
case for in it so that we can
distinguish between the two and the last
one is going to be a function by the
name panel chart event where we're going
to create the panel chart events and
these are EXT standard values that you
need to send to this chart event so it's
ID it's long parameter it's double
parameter and it's string parameter so
just copy it like this exactly and now
let's create this function at the bottom
and within classes you have to create
the functions like this so you say void
and then reference to the class and then
with these two columns then you give it
the name of the function so the name of
the function is C prop form panel in the
class C prop form panel and we don't
need to write anything within so we just
open the function and close the function
and same as for the Constructor we also
need to create one for the deconstructor
as well so it's going to be again the
same so it's in the class c pro from
panel but the function is with the
tilder so that it's basically
referencing to this then we need to
create this onit function which is going
to be exactly the same way so we say
Bull and the name of the class and then
the name of the function we open the
bracket and here we create the panel by
saying that if this meaning this class
this function when you create the panel
this is a not sign so if this is not
successful then return the value false
so basically run it but if it fails to
run then return the value of false
otherwise return true and then we close
the bracket to close the function and
this create panel function we also show
should have written it exactly the same
way within this class type c prop from
panel create a function by the name of
create panel and within that we're going
to do exactly the same thing as for on
in it so we say if we we create this by
saying this do create and then passing
on the values null is the chart this is
the name these are the width parameters
and here we're going to use the input
width and input height parameters from
here and otherwise if it fails to create
it then return the value your false
after that we asked to run this try to
run it and if it's not run meaning if
you fail to run it then return false
otherwise redraw the chart by saying
chart redraw and return the value true
so if you're able to run this if you're
able to run this then chart redraw and
then return the value true if I compile
it I forgot to put a colon here I put a
colon and then compile yeah we don't
have any error so now that we have this
we can go back to to our scalping prop
from version that we had created and now
here we can reference to this file by
saying include prop from panel so this
file. mq which is saved in the include
folder as prop for panel. mq this is the
one that we have just written if I
compile it now it says that the
Declaration of POS hides the overall so
I'll change all of the POs to POS info
and .
info we go to the
top we go to the top so POS info and POS
doino Dot and then we have match whole
words
only so in that case it's going to pick
up here for example p. select so that's
fine to replace this is okay to replace
replace replace replace place so
wherever there was POS dot we
were where we were using the POS
value to get the position info I'm
changing it to position info because I
think mql uses POS somewhere else as a
variable so this is it wherever there
was POS we changeed it to posos info and
let's compile to
see yeah everything is fine now so we
included this file so now we should be
able able to add the class that we add
as prop form panel so this class that we
have written
here this class that we have written
here that we can now call here and
within that and I am and I am assigning
it to a variable that I'm going to call
panel so now this panel is basically
referencing to this class CPR form panel
that we have just created and with that
now I can go down to our initialization
function and here here after putting the
magic number now I can reference to that
panel variable that I've just created
and I can reference to its own init
function that we have created here which
is going to create the
panel and then return true so we can say
on in it and then that and if we start
it then we also have to on the
initialization we need to destroy it so
I'm going to say destroy
and I'm just going to say reason so
whatever is the reason if I compile it
now don't have an error still and now if
I go back to meta Trader then here this
new one that we have just created if I
attach it to the Chart I'm seeing the
panel appear here and the panel says
challenges stats which is the name that
we have given here as challenges stats
this is the input width and input height
here and if I now look into the settings
I will also see see these panel
parameters which we have created in the
prop from panel so even though they are
not here they're is still accessible
because we are referencing to this file
so it's picking up all of the input
values from here as well this is how we
create the panel and now we will need to
start getting the values that we want to
assign here and actually putting these
values and refreshing them if I open up
the one that I've already written and
apply that one the one which is already
complete then we're going to see this
panel so this is the end result of the
panel writing what you're going to see
is four categories of stats so beginning
balance Equity High draw down and profit
and within each one of them there are
four levels so we're going to look at
the beginning balance and Equity High
and the draw down and the profit as
today 7 days 30 days and all time so
these are the total stats that we will
collect and we will print into the panel
so this is what it needs to look like in
the end so Al together we're looking at
20 different levels that we need to
create so I'm going to go back to meta
editor and within the private section is
where we're going to start creating
these labels the first one is beginning
balance with these four stat types so
here I'm creating five different labels
the first one is beginning balance and
the other fours are these ones so I'm
calling it BB for beginning balance so
beginning balance one day beginning
balance 7 Days beginning balance 30 days
and beginning balance all time then I'm
going to do the same for Equity high so
I'm creating Equity high and then
shortening it to eh Equity High Equity
High 1 day Equity High 7day Equity High
30-day and Equity High all time and the
next one is for draw down so I'm
creating these five the C lb will draw
down and then draw down day one draw
down one day draw down 7 Days draw down
30 days and draw down all time and then
the last one is for profit so I'm
creating these five for profit so profit
profit one day profit 7day profit 30-day
and profit all time and this is where
we're going to print all of these labels
which are going to be printed here now
that we have these labels we can go down
to the create p panel and after creating
the panel that's where we're going to
start creating these labels so if I
write the first one which is the
beginning balance this one and if you
open the bracket you're going to see
that it asks for the chart value so the
chart value is zero because we're going
to apply it on the current chart then
what's the name of that so it's
beginning balance then the sub window is
zero and where do we want to print it so
I'm giving it from the X and Y 10 and 10
and then one and one for the Y value 2
and Y value so these two are important
and then the x value and the Y value on
the axis of where I want to print it
within the panel so if I say 10 and 10
that means it's going to be printed 10
pixels from the X and 10 pixels from the
Y if I said 50 it would be printed
somewhere here with 50 distance to the X
and 50 distance to the Y then for the X2
and Y2 value I'm just giving it one and
one and then once we have created it we
have to give it values so what's the
value of this beginning balance label
that we create and I'm giving it the
text beginning balance which is going to
appear here as beginning balance what's
the color and I'm giving it the color of
gold so it's going to appear like this
and then what's the font size and for
the font size I'm saying whatever the
user has put here that plus one so
whatever the user has put is going to be
this so just to make it a little bit
bigger so I'm saying plus one so this is
how I create this and once we have
created this we have to add this
so we say this meaning within this panel
add this one beginning balance add it
and you do this by saying this and then
when you open it up you say add and then
you have to give it which control to add
and that is the beginning balance we do
exactly the same for the next one which
is going to be bp1 day this one the
beginning balance at the beginning of
today so now we create that and now for
the X and Y value I'm giving it 50 and
30 so it is 50 from the X and 30 from
the Y then we update the value of the
text to today equals and this is what we
will create later so I'll remove it for
now so today equals and then giving
spaces three spaces because we need to
line it up properly but that you can
then play around how many spaces before
the T and how many spaces after the T to
line This equal signs properly then the
the color of the text is going to be
whatever the user selects here and the
font size to whatever the user selects
here I'm going to repeat the same
process for the other four so for the 7
day we say BB uncore 7day and then we
create and give it a level BB 7day and
now I'm keeping this value the x value
the same as 50 so it's going to be x
value Y is the same distance from the X
but from the Y I need to now increase
the value so it's not overlapping but
it's below it so I'm giving it the value
45 so 15 pixels more so it will be 15
pixels
below the today value then the text is
going to be 7 days equal and the rest
Remains the Same and here then we add
that label as BB 7day then the same
thing for 30-day we're going to create
the BB 30day so this one here BB 30-day
label we use that label and create it
giving it the name BB3 days and now
again x value is 50 but now we're
increasing the value as 15 so from 30 to
45 to 60 so from 30 to 45 to 60 in y
I'll remove this for now because we're
going to add that later and then again
the input text color the font size and
then we say add this to the panel this
label and then finally the all time so
we say beginning balance all time again
create and I'm keeping the x value at 50
but then increasing the Y value at 75
just to have that level of distance
between so that there's no overlap we're
going to create the text as all time
High same input of color and then we add
this to the panel so if I compile it now
here and then go back to scalping Prof
form version and compile that as well
and then if we go back to metat
Trader and apply our
EA now I should see the panel here and
these four text in labels that we had
put in today 7 days 30 days and alltime
high they're all appearing here now
let's change the color of the background
first so that we can see it more clearly
I'll remove the E and we go back here
and to do that we're going to go back to
our prop form panel go back up to the
top and here at the very top we're going
to include control/ def. mq So within
the controls this file defines and this
one lets us Define or undefine the
properties of the panel two values that
we're going to undefine are the
background so we say hash un defined and
controls dialog color client background
I mean when you're typing it it's going
to pop up so background and the second
one is the controls font name so that we
can choose whatever font we want to use
and then we're going to define the value
of the controls dialogue as color
midnight blue and we will Define the
controls font name as consolas and
that's the font that we're going to use
it takes exactly the same amount of
space for a character so it's going to
line up everything properly so if I
compile it now I don't have any error
and now I need to go back to the
scalping prop fform version and compile
that as well and now if I go back to
metat Trader and now we apply our
scalping robot prop form version now we
see that the background color has
changed and the font has changed as well
and with this font we able to line up
the dashes exactly in order so this is
the beginning balance section so with
today 7day 30-day and all time and we're
going to get the values of this here
from the prop version but we haven't
defined the variables yet but let's
first complete the panel so we go back
to the panel by the way this needs to be
right at the top even before anything
starts so we're redefining everything
about the panel at the very top so down
here I'll continue adding our labels so
then we put the equity high and now I'm
taking it back to the x value of 10 like
the label here at the beginning and then
on the Y AIS I'm giving it distance of
25 so instead of 15 I'm giving it 25 so
that there is a little bit more space
just to see it in action if I compile
both files now and then we go back to
our metat Trader you see this one is
lined up with the beginning balance and
this is why we had a distance of 10 and
there is a little bit more distance
between all time and Equity because the
distance here is 15 and distance here is
25 so the distance between these were 15
and the distance between this one is 25
then the next one is for 1 day again
going back to 50 and having a distance
of 20 to have a little bit more distance
than 15 I'm going to remove the variable
now and then adding this to the panel
once again if I compile and we go back
to met Trader now we see today as well
this is lined up at 50x so it's more
lined up with this one rather than that
one coming back to prop for panel and
now I'm going to add D3 so now the 7day
again giving it a distance of 15 again
15 again and 15 again 30d and all time
exactly the same way then we're going to
create the draw down so we create and
this one is going back again to the x
value of 10 because that is the yellow
label and I'm giving a distance of 35
just to compile it
now we were missing the closing here if
I compile it now and compile the
scalping prop form version and we go
back to my Trader now we see the draw
down menu appearing here as well now we
need to put today 7day 30-day and
alltime high here we go back to prop
from panel and we create the one day
giving it again the x value of 50 and
then a distance of 30 then the 7day
30-day and all time and again keeping
the value of x at 50 increasing this by
15 once again if I compile and compile
the prop version we see now these four
here as well and then at the bottom now
we create the profit exactly the same
way as before just changing names the
values of the Y the name of the
text and adding this and then we do the
same for 1 day 7 Day 30-day and all time
keeping the distances in the order that
this to this has
35 between these there are there's 15
pixel between the last one and this one
is 25 and then the cycle continues so if
I compile it now and compile the
scalping Prof form version as well we
should now see our entire panel the
values are still not there because we
still haven't assigned them okay now
that we have this panel now we need to
start updating the values here so for
that we need to go back to meta editor
and we need to create these variables
where we're going to store the values
now this file is for the panel this is
where our EA is going to run so all of
the variables and all of the values are
going to come from here so at the top
I'm going to create these variables that
I'm going to need to use and these are
the ones that I'm creating so a double
which is a variable that can store
decimal values and here I'm creating
beginning of day balance beginning of
week balance beginning of month balance
then to populate the draw downs and
profits we're going to go draw down one
day percentage draw down 7-Day
percentage draw down 30-day percentage
alltime percentage and same for the
profit 1 day 7day 30-day and all time so
that we can populate the values here so
this is where we're going to use these
variables and then for the equity I'm
creating also the 1 day 7day 30-day and
all time which are going to be used here
there's beginning balance beginning of
week balance beginning of month balance
that's going to be used here then I need
a start day of the challenge because if
you start the challenge in the middle of
the month then the year needs to know
that and then an mql date time format
mql datetime format is the one where you
can split the day and the day of the
week and hours and months and I'm keep
creating a variable and calling it
challenge start and then let's go down
below at the bottom after where we had
the trading Allowed by day profile
section and let's create a section where
we're going to ask the user to provide
the values for the prop for Challenge
and there I'm creating an input Group by
the name of prop for values prop for
rule settings and here I'm asking the
user now for input by variable initial
balance so what is the initial balance
you're starting with what is the profit
Target
that is a double because it could be in
decimals then what is the start of the
challenge as a date time what is the
challenge length so how many days what's
the maximum draw down allowed per day
per week per month and in total and if I
compile it now and go back to metat
Trader then we see this panel appearing
here as initial balance th000 and here
the user can select which date does he
start the challenge and then all of the
rest of the values then we go to on init
function and here we can start by
putting the value that we got from the
user the start of challenge here which
was in a datetime format and we're going
to put this value Into The Challenge
start variable that we created here in
mql date time so we're basically using
time to structure and taking the date
time variable and putting the value of
that date time variable into the mql
datetime variable so we have the
breakdown by day by hour by month etc
etc and this variable then is string
variable which is the start day of
challenge this is where we're going to
store the value of which day was it when
the challenge started and we do it
exactly the same way as we did it before
so we get the challenges start this
variable in mql date format so we get
the challenges start and then we get the
day of the week which is going to be
either Monday Tuesday Wednesday Thursday
Friday whatever it is is going to come
back as an enum end of the week we need
to convert it into a string so we say
enum to string enum day of the week
challenges start day day of the week and
store that value as Monday or Tuesday
whatever comes back as a string into the
start day of the challenge then we get
the beginning balances at the start of
the challenge or when you are starting
the initialization the beginning of the
day would be the same as the beginning
of the week which will be the same as
the beginning of the month balance so we
get the account balance and we put the
value into beginning of day beginning of
week and beginning of month balance but
they start it's all going to be exactly
the same which is €1,000 or $1,000 that
we start with then we go down to the
bottom and this is where we're going to
update the values on every candle so we
create a function by the name of update
initial balance and let's close the
function here so we we have the initial
balances now but we're going to update
them on every candle because the values
are going to keep changing depending on
the day and the week we start by
creating a variable previous check as an
mql date time static and then we create
a variable of 9 now and then we store
the value of the current time into Now
by saying time current and storing that
value Into the Now variable that we just
created this way we can create a check
that if this is not equal to now that
means that a new candle has opened and
therefore we say if now. day is not
equal to previous check. day so the day
has changed we're going to check it on
every candle and as soon as the now the
day of the now the time current is not
equal to whenever we previously checked
the day of that that means it's a new
day so we're going to update the
beginning of the day balance by getting
the account in double account balance
today we're going to update the value of
the equity high of one day to the
beginning of day balance so the
beginning of the day we're going to take
the beginning of the day balance also
the acity would be the same at that
point in time and then we're going to
reset the value of the draw down of one
day percentage to zero profit one day
percentage to zero and then we're going
to put the value of 9 now into the
previous check so the next time the year
comes back here now. day will be equal
to previous check so it's not going to
do this until the time the day changes
so this is how we Loop through and check
that if it's a new day and if it's a new
day then we update these values then we
update the values at the end of 7day
period so whenever you start it from
there until the end of the week so that
when the new week starts and this is
where we're going to create another
datetime variable as a static so it's
created one and we're going to call it
underscore 7day period in mql you cannot
start a variable by by a numeral and
this is why we start with underscore 7
day period and that's going to be equal
to the start start of the challenge and
then we say if time current is greater
than 7day period so whatever value we
have is stored in it if the time current
is bigger than that then we know it's a
new week because the first time is going
to be a new week as soon as the time
current as soon as the challenge starts
so the time Cur is going to be bigger
than whatever is the start of the
challenge then we update the value of
the beginning of the week balance the
7day high of the equity to the same
amount and then reset the value of the
draw down and the profit for the 70
percentag is to zero and then we change
the value of the 7day period by
increasing it by whatever is the number
of seconds in 7 days and this you do by
looking at okay well how many seconds
are there in one day and then multiply
it by seven so the total amount is going
to be 7 days worth of seconds and that
we add into 7day period so the next time
when the year comes only when the time
current becomes bigger than 7 days after
the last check that's when these sces
are going to be run then using the same
logic we update the value of the 30 days
so we start again with a static datetime
variable of Min of _ 30 days period
starting at the start of the challenge
so the first time is just going to be
whenever the time current is bigger than
that we're going to set the beginning of
the month balance and the equity high
balance both to the starting account
balance have these percentages at zero
and then add to it 30 days worth of
seconds so again seconds within one day
multiply by 30 and add it by saying plus
equals to add it to this variable so the
next time the year comes here the time
current is only going to be bigger than
this variable once 30 days have passed
so this is how we checked for 30 days
let's compile it to see if we have any
errors we don't have any errors so then
we can go on to update the values
because here we're setting up the
beginning balances at the beginning of
the day at the beginning of the 7 days
at the beginning of 30 days and now we
will update the values as we go along on
every candle so we create another
function and call it update prop from
values we start by getting the equity
value of the account and then we say
that if the beginning of the day balance
is not equal to to zero so if it has a
value then profit for one day percentage
is equal to whatever is the equity at
that point in time minus the beginning
of the day balance time 100 divided by
the beginning of the day balance so this
is how we calculate what is the
percentage for today is and then if
Equity is higher than the equity one day
which we had updated in the previous
section if it is higher than the
beginning of the day then we change
Equity high for to B to equity then we
create a double variable call it the
current one day draw down and that will
be equal to wherever is the equity minus
the high Equity whatever is the the new
high times 100 and divided by that
Equity high of one day so that's going
to give us the current draw down if
there is any so on a new candle if you
had a position which was in loss then
your Equity is going to be lower than
you whatever was the high of the equity
for that day and this is why we
calculate current draw down and then if
the current draw down is smaller because
it's a negative number so if the current
draw down is smaller than whatever was
the percentage of that at the start of
the day then we store that value into
the draw down of one day percentage so
that we can use it in the panel to show
then we do the same thing for the
beginning of the week so we start with
if the beginning of the week balance is
not equal to zero then we say that the
profit on every candle in percentage is
equal to whatever is the equity right
right now minus whatever was the balance
at the beginning of the day time 100
divided by the balance at the beginning
of the week will give us whatever is our
profit this week positive or negative
and then if the equity is higher than
the equity value of 7 days which in the
starting is going to be zero but then if
it is if it becomes bigger because we
need to continue updating the value of
the equity on every candle so if it is
higher than the 7-Day Equity High
whatever it was before then store that
value into the equity 7day high and then
check for the current draw down by
saying Equity minus whatever is the high
of the equity time 100 / the 70 Equity
high and if the current draw down is
lower than whatever is the draw down for
the 7day percentage then set the 7day
percentage draw down to current draw
down so as soon as there is a lower draw
down than whatever was before we update
the value to a low draw now then we do
the same for the beginning of the month
so starting with beginning of the month
balance if it's not equal to zero then
the profit percentage is whatever is the
equity right now minus whatever was the
beginning balance of the month divided
by the beginning balance of the month
time 100 and if Equity is higher than
whatever is the equity high of 30-day
then store that value into the equity
high of 30-day so that when the equity
grows we continue to grow our Equity
high value because draw down is always
calculated against whatever is the
highest point of the equity not the
beginning balance then check the current
draw down versus this Equity by saying
whatever is the current Equity minus
whatever is the highest Equity during
the last 30 days divided by the highest
Equity during the last 30 days time 100
and if it is lower than whatever is
stored before then store the new current
draw down value into the 30-day
percentage for draw down and then we do
the same for the all time and this is
where we start with the initial balance
if it is higher than zero because
initial balance is defined by the user
so we're using that value and then do
the same thing so the profit all time
will be equal to whatever is the equity
now minus the initial balance divided by
the initial balance time 100 and then we
check if the equity on this candle is
higher than the equity all time that we
had already stored then replace that
value and then check for the draw down
all time by using the same calculation
as before and then if the current draw
down is smaller than because it's a
negative value if it's smaller than
whatever was stored before then store
the new value into this variable so this
is how we update the value of the
percentage for the profit the value of
the 7day acity high and the value of the
highest draw down versus that Equity so
if I compile it now I don't have any
errors so we can proceed to The Next
Step which is to disable the trading if
the draw down exceeds a certain number
so we're asking the user here what are
the percentages which are allowed for
the draw down for day for week for 30
days and for the entire challenge so
this is where we're going to check for
that having calculated everything here
it becomes very easy because we say if
the draw down one day percentage that we
are calculating here if that becomes
bigger than minus Max draw down because
we're asking the user for the input and
they're going to provide the input as
three but the draw down is a negative
number so it's minus 3 so if it is
smaller than minus 3 then if trading in
aable comment is printed then make the
trading enabl comment as trading
disabled Max draw down for the day and
return the value as false so then the
trading is not allowed because of that
then we do the same for 7 days so
checking the 7day draw down percentage
variable that we have updated here
versus whatever is Max allowed and then
if it is lower than that then we need to
disable the trading so if the trading
enabl common is not equals to printed
and you understand the logic of printed
B from the last time then change the
trading enable common to this and then
false meaning that the trading is not
allowed same for 30 days and same for
alltime percentages and then at the end
we check for the profit percentages by
saying if the profit alltime percentage
is higher than the profit Target then
return the comment of trading enabled as
for the target has been achieved because
that basically means that alltime high
profit here is bigger than whatever was
the profit Target defined by the user so
now we don't want to trade trade anymore
because we've already achieved that
Target and this is why we say disable
the trading return this commment and
return false meaning now trading is not
allowed anymore because we have achieved
the Target and if none of the above then
return true meaning that the trading is
allowed so one day draw down is not less
than whatever is the max 7day draw down
is not lower than whatever is the max
30-day is also not lower than whatever
is the 30-day Max and same for the all
time so now we have that function as
well let's compile to see if there are
any errors I don't have any errors so
now we can go back up to the ontick
function and here after the is new bar
function and after having check if the
trading is allowed for the day before we
do anything else we will update the
initial balances which is going to run
this function to update the values of
the beginning of the day beginning of
the week and beginning of the month
balances then we will update the prop
from values which is going to run this
function to update the percentages and
then we're going to run the function of
is trading allowed so we have updated
the beginning balance for the day 7 days
and 30 days then we have updated the
current draw down percentage profit
percentage Etc and now we can check
whether or not the trading is allowed by
running this function and if trading is
allowed then only the EA is going to run
the code and to ensure that we're going
to bring down this
portion from above to
below so here so once we have checked if
the trading is allowed then we will add
another value here by saying if not is
trading allowed then also run these sces
before we started we had these three
filters then we added the filter ofice
trading is allowed by day and now we are
also adding the if trading is allowed by
the prop form values so when the year
comes here on a new bar it will update
the initial balance it will update the
Prof form values and then it will check
whether or not the trading is allowed by
coming down here and if the value turns
out to be false then this value is going
to be true which is not is trading
allowed so meaning it's false and in
that case close all the order disable
the trading set the chart value to
whatever is the chart color trading off
then the next thing we're going to do is
we're going to simplify these input
variables because here we have crypto
profile gold profile and indicis profile
but they're practically the same because
they're looking at the TP as a
percentage of the price so instead of
having these three we're just going to
go for one so I'll delete these two and
we're going to change this input group
value from crypto input to as a
percentage of price profile then we have
the TPS percentage is stop loss as
percentage then TP and a stop loss as a
percentage TSL and Trigger as a
percentage of the stop
loss and then we're going to add order
distance Point as well as a percentage
of stop- loss and we can move this order
distance point from here which was
related to Forex profile down below here
and make it an input variable as well so
that the user can add values to it and
call it input and we can also move this
these double variables from here again
down below because these are also
related to Forex so I'm going to move
them here and I will add to it order
distance point of without the word input
so we're going to collect the input here
and then we're going to pass on this
input to order distance point from
either from here or from here when we
are into the on on initialization
function pink looks really bad to me so
I'm going to change this to purple the
trading off color and the trading on
color is still black and we can move
this from here as it is not related to
Common to up here just to clean it up
and I'm deleting the integer system
choice because we simply going to use
the system type and then removing the
spaces so this is the start Hour end
hour I'm removing the S choice and end
hour choice because we're simply going
to use the S Type here and I think we're
good to go if I compile now I get all of
these errors because we haven't changed
the
values in the oninit function where we
were assigning these values so this I
don't need anymore so I'll remove it
this we don't need anymore as well so
I'm going to remove that as well because
we don't have the system type 2 and
system type 3 anymore we only have
system type zero and system type 1 Let's
rewrite this to enum system type and
then fix Pips profile and percentage of
price profile so we're not going to use
this anymore we're going to use this one
so I'm going to delete this one and then
let's go down to here we don't need
these system types because we don't have
system type 2 and three and this is
where we were putting the initial
default values but now we're going to
switch between the system type which is
going to be coming from here the system
type and we need to change this to enum
system type because that's the new name
system enum type so the value is going
to be coming from here as either zero or
one so if it is zero which is the fixed
Pips profile then here at the
initialization of the function we're
going to say if the case of the system
type is zero then the TP points are
equal to TP points input which are
coming from the Forex profile here so
it's all going to come from here the
Forex profile so if the system type is
zero then TP points are equal to TP
points input SL points so whatever the
user has provided as input and then also
the order distance point the Forex
profile then TP Point SL Point trigger
point and the TSL Point are all going to
be coming from the Forex inputs same
goes for the order distance point and
then we break because we're using the
case so if that is the case do all of
this and then break from this function
but if it is case one then we say that
the TP points Cel point or the distance
Point are now going to be dependent on
the values provided in the percentage of
price input and here we're collecting
the values as percentages so we need to
do the calculations so the first one
would be PP points is going to be equal
to whatever is the ask in the market
times whatever is the TP as a percentage
and for that we need to have the ask so
we create the variable up above here as
ask and we get the value by using the
function symbol input double sending the
symbol value and asking for the symbol
ask value and then we divide it by 100
because it is a percentage but then
let's say if bitcoin price is 100,000
then
0.4% of that is going to be 100,000 *
0.4% = 400 so that is the stop loss but
if you look at the value of Bitcoin it
has two decimal places after the dot as
well so the actual stop- loss is going
to be
40 dot 0 0 so there needs to be two more
zeros after that as well and this we
achieve by dividing it by the point
value so dividing it by whatever is the
point value so that we're converting
this TP points into points instead of a
number of dollars so then the value is
going to be returned as as because there
are two dots so the value is going to
become 40400 and then two more dots so
40,000 but then when we will actually be
sending the order we're multiplying the
DP points and SL points by the points as
well so we're converting it back into
400 so this is why we will need to
divide it by points here so that these
values are converted into points rather
than just dollar values then because
these are going to be in points so then
we can use this SL point value to
calculate the order distance Point TSL
points and trigger point by multiplying
it by whatever is the user input divided
by 100 because it's a percentage and
then break and then we close the switch
function then the next thing we're going
to do is at the very beginning or
initialization we're going to check what
is the stop level because different
Brokers have different requirements for
how far away from the price the stop-
loss should be so when we're trailing
the stop- loss we need to be careful
that the value provided for the trailing
stop loss by the user is actually bigger
than what is required by the broker
because if it's not then the trailing
stop will never work so we check by
using the symbol info integer sending
the value of the symbol and asking for
what is the trading stop levels and
because it's return as an a long value
and we are storing it into integer so we
use the word integer in front to convert
it into integer and then storing the
value into stop level so now we know
what is the broker's requirement and
let's print that value by using the
print command and saying minimum loss
distance required by the broker on
whatever is the symbol is whatever is
the stop level in points and then we
compare that the TSL points that are
either coming out of this calculation
here or are coming out of the user
provided input for the Forex profile if
those are smaller than what the broker
requires then we PR that the trailing
stoploss value of whatever is the
correct calculated value or the user
provid provided value is smaller than
Allowed by the broker therefore we are
overriding to broker minimum of whatever
is the stop level points accepted by the
broker and then we convert the TSL
points to whatever is the stop level
points accepted by the broker and if our
trailing stop loss points are not less
than the broker's requirement then in
that case everything is fine so we just
say current trailing stop value of
whatever is the TSL value coming out of
the calculation or from user input is
okay so that's the first check that we
do at the beginning then just for the
tester before we check for whether or
not the indicator height is true or not
we start with a default value of tester
hide indicator as false and then if the
user has selected the value as true then
only we convert it into true so let's
start with a default value and then
change it to whether the user has
selected the indicator hiding as true
and now that we have assigned the values
of the TP Point SL Point trigger point
here whether it's fixed Pips or as a
percentage so we don't need to do this
in on tick function so here we don't
have to to check whether it's system
Choice 1 2 or three we have already done
that on the initialization so we can
remove this part and now if I compile I
have these four errors because we remove
these s Choice eh choice and eh choice
so we can replace it with SH input eh
input and eh input which are the
variables here where we're asking the
user to provide when to start the
trading and when to stop the trading so
we remove these two and replace it by
the ones below compile now we still have
one more error and that is the closing
code
expected and this is we didn't have the
closing code compile now we don't have
any errors so this concludes our
creation of the Prof form panel and then
getting the values for those variables
so we can populate these variables but
now we need to go back to the prop panel
and create an update function so that
these variables that we have now
calculated can be populated here so we
go back to prop from panel and we create
a function which is the panel chart
event which is the one that we created
here so we create that we provided the
ID the long parameter double parameter
and the string parameter and we just say
chart event is whatever is the ID passed
on to it whatever is the long parameter
double parameter and the string
parameter that's passed on to it
and then we close the function and then
we create this last function which is
update where we will update the values
in the panel and then we go down to the
bottom and we create another function
for the class C prop form the function
name is update and then we start
updating the values in these levels from
those variables so the first one the
name of this level was bbor 1D so we say
bbor beginning balance 1D do text is it
used to be only
this and now we can add to it the
variable value of beginning of day
balance that we have created here and
populated the value
here so now we're starting to use the
values from the actual EA into the panel
so that's the first one then we have the
7day text the 30-day text and the
alltime text so we start with whatever
is the text before from here and then
just add to it
the value of the values that we're
getting from the variables
here we start populating the panel with
the values because these variables are
going to return a double value and the
text is going to be in a string so we
need to First convert it into a string
before adding it to the labels I'm going
to do it for the rest as well which is
the equity High one day text 7-Day text
30-day text and alltime text and adding
to it the the value of the variables
that we calculated back into the label
by converting them to Strings and then
adding it then the same for draw down
one day text which is going to be again
the initial text which was today 7day
30day and all time but then adding to it
the percentage values that we are going
to get from DD 1 day percentage
variable that we calculate here and here
and here and then the same goes for
profit labels which we calculated here
here and here so we update the values
from those variables back into the panel
labels by adding to whatever text was
before and then adding this value as a
string and then going a string
substructure so that it can be converted
properly and after that we first say
whatever was the color before so input
text colors of the draw down values one
1 day 7day 30-day and all time as
whatever was chosen color by the user
but then in case if the one day draw
down percentage is lower than whatever
is the max allowed so if the max allowed
was 3% so it's minus 3 if it turns out
to be lower than that so it's in a way
it's bigger than 3% draw down then
change the color to Tomato which is the
red color so we can see it very easily
on the panel whenever we have gone above
the Max allowed draw down so this is the
update in the panel to update the values
but because we are getting the values
from this one into this one so we need
to go back up and include
this
file back into this prop form and the
way to do that would be you start with a
dot dot which means from this include
folder where this prop form panel file
that we have created is placed so go up
one folder to here then go to The
Experts folder then to wherever is your
scalping EA these codes are saved this
one so what I can do is I can right
click on it this folder and then open
the folder and then here is my EA so I'm
going to right click on it check for
properties and copy the
location copy this location come back
here here paste it below this is the
part that I need from experts I'll
delete the
rest and then I have to paste it here as
expert YouTube es scalping scalping prop
which is this folder and then within
that folder I have the file as scalping
prop form version so I need to say
scalping prop formore version and this
is why you cannot have spaces here
because then you're not going to be able
able to define the values here in a
simple way so the easiest way is to just
put underscore in the names of the mq5
file that you create so that you can
reference it easier now if you compile
you're going to get a lot of
Errors because now that we are
referencing to this file we can no
longer compile it from within the prop
panel we need to compile it from here
and if you compile it from here then
you're not getting any error so both
these files are compiled into one year
because this EA is already including the
Prof from panel and this Prof from panel
is referencing back to scaling Prof
version mq5 file so you cannot compile
it anymore from here you can only
compile it from here now that we have
created this update function here to
refresh the values from the variables we
now need to go back to the scaling prop
form version come down to the ontick
function and here before we check for is
trading allowed we we going to do the
panel.
update so the panel can then call on
within the prop from panel the update
function that we have just created here
and then the last thing we're going to
do before we start with the trailing
stoploss modifications is to come down
to the bottom and add this one more
function which is the on chart event
function which you can simply copy paste
from here as well if you want to which
is exactly the same function from there
but then we put it here as well now if
we compile we don't have any errors and
now if I go back to metat Trader we can
now see that the opening balance the
beginning balances and everything is
getting updated the equity highs for
today the draw downs and the profit
percentages are all being calculated
within the panel so this concludes our
panel and now we can go back up to the
trailing stop function because that is
the last modification we're going to
make to include Within the trailing the
option to trail by the last candle the
option to trail by fast moving average
and the option to trail by ichimoku
Tenon line go back all the way back up
and here and here after the percentage
of price I'm going to add one more group
and call it trailing stop management and
here we're going to include our trailing
stop management but before that I go
back up here and I create another enum
and let's call it TSL type which is
going to be the default rail which is
the aggressive stop-loss movement like
normal scalping year that we have but
then we're also going to add the option
to select previous candle a fast moving
average or a 10 consent line so now that
we have this enum available we can use
it here and we say that the user needs
to input what trail type does he want to
apply by using this TSL type that we
have just created here so for example
now if I compile and go back to my
Trader then here I should see a new
trailing stop-loss management and here
now the user has the option to select
which one does he want to use and then
in case he wants to use candles to Trail
the stop loss then he needs to Define
how many candles to Trail it on so how
many candles on the left to Trail it on
and in case he chooses fast moving
average then what is the fast moving
average value that he wants to trade it
on 10 consent is 10 consent and the
default Trail is default Trail then that
only need to Define so with these
variables we go down now to
initialization function and then where
we were creating the handles we add two
more handles so if the trailing of the
stop-loss type equals 2 which is the
moving average type then the handle of
the trailing ma equals IMA and handle
ichimoku equals ichimoku now we haven't
created these two variables so I'm going
to go back up here and where we had
created these two hand Les I'm going to
add to it handle of trailing moving
average and handle of ichimoku so that
we can initialize it here and then we
pass on the values of the time frame the
fast moving average period that the user
defines here and in case of ichimoku
then the time frame and the standard
value of ichimoku cloud which is 926 and
52 so now that we have created these
handles as well now we can use these
values so we go to the trailing stoploss
function and start modifying it I'm
going to create two more variables here
the first one is going to be an integer
variable for a stop level so that we can
get from the broker what is the minimum
stop level required and then I'm also
creating an indicator buffer because I'm
going to be copying the values of the
fast moving average and ichimoku now
before we had this function up until
here we're going to keep the function as
it is because what we're doing is we're
running through the positions we're
selecting it by index getting the ticket
number and then we go okay well if it is
in input magic number is our magic
number and its symbol is our symbol then
we know it's our trade then we check
whether it's a buy type and if it's a
buy type then we check whether or not
the price has moved above the trigger of
the trailing stoploss and in that case
we assign the the value of the take
profit to the variable
TP that we created
here but after that we add one more
condition which is if the position is
stop loss currently is below the opening
price which means that it is still the
initial stop- loss and it hasn't moved
because once it has moved with the
aggressive trailing stop loss then it
will be above the opening price so if it
is below the opening price still that
means it is still the original stop loss
and then we say that the stop loss now
is going to be equal to bid minus TSL
point so the new aggressive st stop loss
and then we don't need this condition
and we just say in that case change the
trade modify the position by sending it
the ticket and the stop- loss andp
values that we have just calculated move
it properly so what's happening here is
once we know that this is our trade and
it is a pro type buy and then the price
has moved above the trigger of the TR
the stop- loss
points then we check if the stop loss
the original the the stop loss of the
position currently is below the opening
price which means this is still the
audition stop loss only in that case we
change the stop loss to TSL point
and then change the stop loss to the new
stop loss so above the price meaning
Break Even but once it has moved to
break even then it's going to be above
the price open in which case this is not
going to happen again so once it is
above the break even then we don't want
to do anything and then we're going to
Loop through all of the cases depending
on how the user has defined how he wants
to Trail the stop loss but the first
time the stop loss is going to move is
as soon as it can move to the break even
we move it and then we switch through
the cases and say switch through the
trail type so which Trail type has the
user selected and if it's case one which
means is the normal aggressive trailing
of the stop loss in that case a stop
loss is going to be bid minus dtsl point
just like here exactly the same and in
that case break so don't run anything
below if it is case one then the user
has selected to move it move the stop
loss on the previous candle or whatever
number of candles in that case the stop
loss is going to be the low of whatever
candle number the the user has selected
so if the user has said one then it's
the previous candle if the user has said
two then it's the previous from previous
candle so the low of that will be the
stop- loss and then break because you
don't want to run the rest of rest of
the function if it's case two then we're
looking at fast moving average as the
trailing stoploss in that case we use
the copy buffer function to copy the
value of the moving average main line
for the last candle and paste that value
into the indicator buffer variable that
we have created here set the array as a
series so that it's in order and then
break and then in case it is case number
three then we're going to use the handle
ichimoku and from that we're going to
copy the 10 consent line for the last
candle into the indicator buffer and
then we set the stop loss to be a to be
equal to that indicator buffer so the 10
can line value from the previous candle
and then break so here we now assigning
stop losses based on which Trail type
has been selected by the user and once
we have that now we can say if the stop
loss is above the last stop- loss
because we only want to move the stop
loss upward and the calculated stop-
loss value is not zero because that can
be an error and the stop loss is bigger
than the price open so it is in positive
territory and the stop loss is lower
than the bid because you can have a
situation where on a candle the candle
is bent above but then the price comes
down in which case the price has
actually come below the low of the
candle in which case the stop loss that
we're sending is going to be an invalid
stop because it's going to be above the
bid so we need to check that it is below
the bid and then if those conditions are
met then modify the position by sending
the ticket the stop- loss and the TP
values and the stop loss values are
going to come from here depending on
which case has been selected now if I
compile I don't have any errors which
means that the parentheses are probably
okay and then we go else if if the
position type is sell then we're going
to follow exactly the same logic by
checking if ask price has come down
below the open price minus the trigger
point so it has moved more than the
trigger point below in which case we set
the TP but then for the stop loss we
have to go through exactly the same
logic as before where we say if the
position info of the stop loss is bigger
than the price open meaning it is still
the original stop loss then we do the
aggressive trailing by setting the stop
loss to ask plus the TSL Point like
before and then changing the stop loss
value by providing the ticket number SL
and TP so this is only going to happen
when you still have the original stop
loss and the price has moved more than
the trigger of the stop- loss point in
our favorable Direction so we move it to
break even but after it has moved to the
the break even then we do the same thing
which is switching through the trail
type and then if it's case Zero then the
stop- loss is going to be the aggressive
stop loss which is going to be the same
as here but if it is case one which is
the the last candle or last from last
candle then in that case the trailing
stop is going to move on the high of the
candles whatever number of candles the
user has defined if it's case two then
it's moving on fast moving average in
which case we copy buffer into the
indicator buffer from the handle trail
of ma the main line for the last candle
and then we set the stop loss to that
indicator buffer value which is the fast
moving average and in case if it is case
three the trail type then we are looking
for the jimu and in that case we take
the handle chimu the 10 consent line for
the last candle and copy it into
indicator buffer and then we set the
stop loss to indicate above a zero value
which is going to be the 10 consent line
of the last candle and then we break
so now we have our stop loss calculated
based on the trail type so then we can
go that if the stop loss is lower than
the initial stop loss or whatever is the
current stop loss of the position and
it's not zero so there is no calculation
error and that the stop loss is below
the price open because we only want to
Trail it once it's below the price once
it is in profit and also the stop loss
is greater than ask otherwise the new
stop loss is going to be an an invalid
stop loss so we check for this condition
as well and if those conditions are met
then we modify by sending the ticket
number the SL based on whatever
calculation comes from here and the TP
value and then we don't need this
because we have already instead of just
sending the aggressive stop loss we have
now gone through these cases so we
delete this one if I compile I don't
have any errors put this on the screens
because here the parentheses are
extremely important so you can pause the
video here and copy these codes so this
is page
one and this is page
two and this is Page
Three and from there onwards
here so try to put the parentheses
exactly in the same position where I
have put them and that covers the
trailing stop loss as well and I compile
now and everything seems to be
fine in which case if I go back here now
we have all of the functions available
so you have the width of the panels that
you can change you have the trading type
you have the trading system so fixed is
going to be used for Forex and
percentage of price is going to be used
for other
classes then you can select the lot size
based on fixed percentages of equity
balance or
margin in which case you have to Define
what those values are the time frame and
everything from
before the chart color when the EA is
inactive I like to use it as
purple but you can change it then black
when it is when the trading is
allowed then here you define the Forex
profiles if you're applying it on a
Forex pair and here you apply the
percentage of price method if you're
applying it on bitcoin gold us indices
oil and things like
those then what is the trailing
stop-loss type so default Trail is going
to be the aggressive Trail so as with
the TSL values so with the TSL values
here here and
here but now you also have the
possibility to Trail the stop- loss by
previous candle on fast moving average
or 10 consent line after it has moved to
the break even so the break even move is
still going to be as soon as it
can and then you have the Muse filter
from before you have the RSI filter from
before and you have the moving average
filter from before then we added also
the is trading Allowed by day which day
it is
allowed and then we have the Prof from
settings of what is the initial balance
what is the target profit and what are
the values of the draw Downs allowed and
when do you start the challenge and
these values are going to be updated in
this panel As you move along in case if
we run into draw down more than what is
allowed for today the trading will be
stopped and the chart is going to turn
into purple and once we have reached the
profit Target all time then it's going
to turn into green and the trading will
be stopped as well so this is it for the
ch es and modifications now if I find
any error in the way that I have written
the code or explain them I'll update
that do test it thoroughly before you
decide to apply it because these are
very complex codes so until next time
guys stay safe stay safe
[Music]