we're starting with a balance of ,000 e
we're ending somewhere close to 41,000
92% win on short trades 92% win on Long
trades a relative draw down of only 11%
no running draw Downs the general
performance of the year is just up and
up if you have a computer an internet
connection and 2 hours of time then by
the end of this video you will
practically own this trading robot even
if you know nothing about coding matter
Trader or mql as a coding language we
will go step by step we will look at all
the codings and I will explain
everything so with no motion any let's
start before we get to the coding let's
first look at the year itself so here I
am in the strategy tester I'm going to
run it on USD JPY 5 minutes chart is
starting from 2023 until 2024 we're
running it on every tick and I'm
starting with a balance of
,000 let's look at the input table we
are putting a 3% risk on every trade we
have set our stop loss and take profits
to be 20 Pips and we want our trailing
stop to be triggered once the trade is
in 15 points profit so 1 and a half pip
and we want our trailing stop loss to be
trailed by one pit so 10 points we're
running the year between 700 hours in
the morning until 2100 hours in the
evening so let's start the test so the
EA performs the trading operations only
during the trading hour so we have
defined it to be between 700 hours and
2100 hours so during the night the EA is
not going to do
anything once the trading period starts
the EA will start trading everything
automatically it will then open up the
trades it will Trail the stop losses and
then it will close the trades all
operations done automatically now I will
speed up the
test so the test has finished we started
with a balance of ,000 and we're ending
up with somewhere around
41,800 history wise if you look there
are a lot of Trades which are in profit
there will be some trades which are
going to be in losses as well if we go
back to metat
Trader the first thing you will notice
is that there are no running draw Downs
there are PE of consecutive losses like
here there are periods of stagnation but
if you let the year run for a longer
period of time the general performance
of the year is up and up if you look at
the back test results we're starting
with a balance of ,000 e we're ending
somewhere close to 41,000 92% win on
short trades 92% win on Long trades a
relative draw down of only 11% now this
year requires very tight spreads and
normally on Brokers the years that
you're going to find the tightest
spreads are USD JPY gbpusd and Euro USD
so we're going to run on those three so
USD JPY we have seen let's very quickly
run it on gbpusd as well again five
minutes chart is starting from 2023
until today every tick and 1,000 let's
start the test again you will notice
that there are no running draw Downs
because of a very tight stop loss there
are periods during which the EA does not
do very well so somewhere between August
and December it actually was a stagnant
in fact losing a little bit of money but
overall the performance of the Year
Still Remains up and up over a longer
period of
time looking at the back test results we
started with ,000 we're ending up with
4600 again 92% short trade win and 92%
long PA when a relative draw down of
17% let's quickly run it on Euro
USD and once again no running draw Downs
as I said because of a very tight stop
loss periods of consecutive losses
periods of stagnation but the general
performance of the Year remains up and
up looking at the back test results we
started with a, we're ending up with
4,300 a relative row down of 14% 91% win
on short trade 94% win on Long trades
the year performs really really well now
before we dive in into more details and
start coding the entire stuff let's
start looking at the strategy
first so the strategy is extremely
simple what we're betting on is that if
the price is moving in a certain
direction that it will continue to move
in the same direction by at least one
and a half more bits that's the entire
strategy now you can have different ways
of defining when to take trades the one
that I'm using here is looking at the
last High and the last low so the EA is
going to put orders on the last high and
on the last low and after the trade
comes down to our stop order then we're
basically betting that it was moving in
that direction so it will continue to
move in that direction by another one
and a half pit once it moves in that
direction in our favorable Direction by
more than one and a half pit we start to
Trail our stop loss very aggressively
by One PP only until the time the trade
either goes in the direction of our TP
or it comes back and hits our stop loss
which we are training so that's the
entire strategy now you can use
different methods for example you can
use moving average crossovers once the
fast moving average crosses a slow
moving average you can take the trade in
the general direction of where the
market is moving and then bet that it's
going to move by more than 1 and a half
pip you can use RSI so for example if
the RSI goes from below 70 to above 70
you take the general trade in the
direction of where the price is moving
and then you bet that it's going to move
another 1 and a half pip so you can
start trading the stop loss so entry
criteria can be many the general
strategy is if the price is moving in a
certain direction I will continue to
move in that direction by at least one
and a half more F now this e works
extremely well when the market is
trending so it's going in a general
direction either upward or downward it's
during the stagnant period the chaotic
Market periods and volatile Market
periods that the strategy is going to
suffer now for our friends who are
generally new to the entire coding let's
quickly look at what softwares you're
going to need so the first thing is
you're going to head to Google and
you're going to type metat Trader and
here on the download tab you will find
that metatrader 5 is available for
Windows and for Mac it's also available
for
Linux we're going to download it for
Windows and once you have downloaded it
and installed it when you open it you
will see a screen like this if you head
to the view and you select market watch
that's where you're going to see all of
the currency pairs if you're missing
yours you can add it here so for example
if I wanted to add New
Zealand CHF I type it here and when I
hit it it appears here if I right click
on it and I select chart window we're
going to get the chart in this window
the second thing you're going to open up
in the view is your Navigator and this
is where once you have an account on the
broker you're going to connect it here
you can right click here you can log a
trade account and here you're going to
provide your login details and select
the server which is provided by your
broker to connect the third thing that
we were using again in the view is the
strategy tester and this is what we were
using to run our back test I have
already written the year it's called
scalping robot Forex but we will rewrite
it and I will go line by line and
explain everything if you look at the
input tab this is where we Define all of
the variables for the year so for
example how much risk do I want to take
on every trade as 2% how much is my take
profit or a stop- loss point I'm putting
it as 20 Pips up and down then when does
my trailing stop triggers and I'm
setting it up at 1 and A2 pip and then I
want to Trail my stop- loss by one pit
I'm going to run it on 5 minutes chart
starting from 700 hours until 2100 hours
so these are all the input variables
that we collect information from our
user and we will be coding all of this
step by step and that we do by heading
to the ID which is the development
environment when you will click on it
meta editor 5 will open up and it will
look something like this if you don't
have the Navigator window then it is in
the view you can select the Navigator
window and here in the experts folder
all of our EAS our trading robots
they're going to be coded n store I'm
going to hit
new and I'm creating an expert advisor
and let's call it a scalping
robot and I hit next and then next and
then finish and this is the generic
template that I get to now all of the
stuff that's written after two forward
slashes that's considered by mql 5 to be
Commons I'm going to remove them to
clean up the template and after the
clean up the template looks something
like
this now there are three functions which
come with the expert advisor
automatically the first one is on it
function and these are all event based
so going back to metatrader now the
market is closed so we're not going to
get a tick but whenever there is a new
price that arrives in
metatrader that's what metatrader calls
a tick so it's the arrival of a tick and
then on every tick all the codes which
are written on the on thck functions so
here are going to be run all the the
codes written here under the onit
function which is initialization
function are going to be run when the EA
is initialized so when you attach it to
a chart on the first run of the Year all
the course it in here are going to be
executed the de initialization is the
opposite of initialization so every code
that's written here is going to be run
when the EA is stopped now besides these
three functions we're going to need a
lot of other functions as well and don't
worry about it I will go through every
function line by line and explain the
codee so let's
start I will start creating all of the
functions below this comment line so
that we can separate between the on pick
function initialization function de
initialization function and our general
functions that we are writing ourselves
so the first function we're going to
need is the is new bar function and
that's the function that's going to
check on metatrader that whether a new
candle has opened so all of the ticks
that arrive in between these candles so
that we don't run the EA on every tick
but we only run the EA on the
initialization of a new candle the way
to write this is we're going to call
this a buol function AOL function
Returns the value of either true or
false so we start by creating a variable
previous time and it's a date time
variable I'm assigning it a value zero
so basically leaving it black then what
I'm doing is I'm getting the current
time on the server by using the I time
function function and this function
comes generic with mql so when you will
type I time and open up the bracket it
will ask for three inputs the first one
is with chart and if we write underscore
symbol that basically means whatever
chart that the EA is attached to use
that
symbol then the next one is period
current which is whatever is the period
currently and later on we're going to
Define a variable by the name of time
frame but I will change it already here
by saying this is the variable that I
will send so what's the time frame and
then which bar do I want to check it on
so this is bar zero the last bar this is
bar one bar two bar three and so on and
so forth so I want the value of the
current bar now once I get the current
time which is the time on which the
current bar is started then I can check
whether the previous time is equals to
current time if the previous time is
equal to the current time then it
basically means that no new candle has
opened so the current time is exactly
the same as we had before but if not and
this is the way of writing not if
previous time is not equal to current
time then it's definitely a new bar so
we want to return true but then the next
time the E comes back to check it we
want the current time to be the same as
the previous time until a new candle
opens up this is why we assigned the
current time to the previous time so the
next time the year comes back here the
previous time then is equal to current
time and it doesn't doesn't do anything
it doesn't return a true it returns a
false until the time a next candle arri
and then of course the current time of
the next candle is going to be different
and therefore again the entire procedure
will continue and therefore again the
previous time will not be equal to
current time and then we will have our
true value until the next time so this
is our first
function then the next function we're
going to need is a function to find a
high and a low
so I'm creating a function and I'm
calling it find high and it's a double
function so it will return a value of
decimals now in mql double means a
variable which can store decimal Valu so
100. 333 4 something like that it's a
double variable a variable that cannot
store the decimal will be integer so it
will only store 1 2 3 but it will never
store 1.1 we want to find the high and
normally the prices are in decimals so
we want to create the function to return
value which is going to include decimals
and this is why I'm creting the function
as double visually it is very easy to
find a high so we know that this is a
high we can say that this is a high then
this is a high then this is a high this
is a high this is a high and this is a
low this is a low this is a low this is
a low this is a low this is a low and so
on and so forth so visually it is very
easy and intuitive to find the high and
low how do we tell mql how to find the
highs and lows the way that we're going
to achieve this is we're going to tell
mql that at any point in time look for
five candles to the right and five
candles to the left if all the five
candles on the left and all the five
candles on the right are below the
middle candle that's what we call a high
now it can be 10 candles to the right 10
candles to the left 20 candles to the
right 20 candles to the left but the
logic is the same so as long as X number
of bars on the left and X numbers of
bars on the right are below the middle
handle we call it a high so back again
in meta editor we start by creating a
double variable and we call that
variable highest high and we assign it a
value of zero because we don't have a
highest high yet so that's the starting
point the next thing we do is we create
a loop and this is how you create a loop
in mql by saying for and then for an
integer value is starting at zero and as
long as it's below 200 or 300 400 run
these codes and every time increase the
value of I by one so start at zero run
the code come back make I equal 1 then
run it then I equals 2 then run it until
the time that I hits 200 and that's when
you stop running the loop so all of the
CES which we are going to write here
between these two curly brackets are
going to be run for 200 times we start
by creating another variable and again a
double variable so we can store decimal
in it and we call it high and in that
variable what we're going to check on
every Loop by using the I high function
and the I high function in mql Returns
the highest value of a candle so for
example on this candle this is the
highest point this candle this is the
highest point so that's the point that I
high is going to return so we want to
get the I high meaning the highest point
of the candle we send the value of the
current symbol which when we say
underscore symbol means the current
chart then the time frame variable that
we're going to Define later so that our
user can define whether he wants to run
this on 5 minutes or 10 minutes 15
minutes 20 minutes and then check the
value of the bar number I so if it is
starting then I equals 0 next time I
equals 1 then the next time I equals two
and so on and so forth until 200 so
every time we're going to be looping
we're going to find the high of this
candle then this candle then this candle
then this candle and so on and so forth
200 candles back for and then we say
that if
I is greater than bars n and we're going
to create a variable bars n in which
we're going to store the value of how
many bars to the left and how many bars
to the right you need to look so if I is
greater than Bar N because we don't want
I to be the last candle because we want
to check five candles to the right and
that's not possible so the first time
that five bars on the right are going to
be possible is if the I is greater than
whatever is the number of bars we're
checking on on the right so if I is
greater than Bar's n then check the I
highest and if you use the I highest
function in mql by sending the symbol
value and the time frame value and then
telling mql okay which mode am I looking
for am I looking for high or am I
looking for low and then starting at
which bar and how many bars to
look then mql is going to look back that
many bars and it's going to find the
highest value within that
range so here we are checking so here we
are checking for bars n * 2 so if our
bars n is five so if we checking for
five bars to the right five bars to the
left then bars * 2 is going to be 10 and
then we add one more to it so it's 11 so
we're asking it to check 11 candles
backwards is starting at whatever is the
current IE - 5 so if the current bar is
this one then it start here five bars to
the right look back 11 bars and find the
highest point so for example if we were
starting here and looking back 11
candles the highest point is going to be
on candle number
six and this is what we're going to get
here this function is going to return in
that range of 11 candles which number
candle has the highest value or if the
candle that you find as the highest
candle is the one that
is the I then we know that it is the
high of that range it has five candles
to the left and five candles to the
right so we have found our high and then
if high is greater than highest high so
we started with the value of zero but if
it is greater than that then return the
value of high back because now you have
found the high and the reason why we do
this check is because if the EA has
already found a high let's say here so
we do need to check that the new high
that it has found is actually higher
than the last High it had found so that
we don't go downwards we only go upwards
and then as the last step we say return
the high back and then make the highest
high value equal to whatever is the
higher value between high and highest
high so that the highest high has now
stored the highest value and then if you
cannot find anything just return minus
one so this is how we tell mql how to
find the high now no prizes for guessing
how to find low which is the exact
opposite of finding the high so we're
going to create another function we call
it find low but this time we start the
lowest low value as double Max we cannot
start it as zero because the year is
never going to find a value of a low
below zero so we start with whatever is
the max value available within mql and
then we do the same iterations of
looping finding the low's distance time
and then checking if the I lowest
happens to be right in the middle of the
range that we're looking at the 11
candles and if it does then we return
the low and then we set the lowest low
to whatever is the math minimum between
the low and the lowest low if it cannot
find a low then just return minus one
which is return
nothing now the next thing we're going
to look at is because we are asking the
user to provide how much loss is he
willing to take on one trade
so now we need to do a calculation to
calculate the lot sizes so I'm going to
create a function and I'm going to call
it calculate Lots what we're going to
send to the function is a double
variable by the name of SL points we're
going to send the value to this function
of how big of stop loss is in points
whether below the price in case of a buy
or above the price in case of a sell
we're going to send what's the distance
between the entry price and the stop
loss to this function and then we're
going to ask the function to calculate
for us for the lot size should be so we
start with creating a variable we call
it risk and here we're going to convert
the risk percent variable where we're
going to collect the value from the user
in terms of percentage we're going to
convert it into absolute value by first
converting it into a percent and then
getting the info of what the account
balance is so if the account balance is
1,000 we multiply it by the risk percent
and that gives us our absolute risk then
we need to get the these three values
from mq which is how big is a tick size
so for example for Euro USD The Tick
size value is the fifth decimal so
that's the tick size then we ask for
what's the value of that tick and then
we ask for lot steps so on different
Brokers it can go from 0.01 to 0.02 to
0.03 so these are the steps in which the
lot increases once we have these three
values then we can calculate the Lots we
calculate it by first dividing the SL
points that we have sent by The Tick
size value and lot steps
multiplication and then our lots are
going to be whatever our risk is divided
by whatever is the result of this
formula times the lot step and that's
going to return to us the lot size
that's going to match the risk
percentage depending on the account
balance but as a safety precaution we're
also going to get the minimum volume
Allowed by the broker the max volume
Allowed by the broker and the volume
limit Allowed by the broker and then we
can say if the volume limit is not zero
meaning that there is a limit then set
the lot size to the minimum of lots or
whatever is the volume limit then the
same if there's a maximum volume is not
zero it means there is a limit there is
a max volume then the Lots can be the
math minimum of between our calculation
of the lots and whatever is the max
volume allowed and in case of minimum
volume is also not zero which means
there is is a minimum requirement then
the lot size is going to be the higher
of whatever is that volume minimum and
the lot size that we're calculating here
after that we just normalize our lot
size to two decimal and then we return
the value of the lot
size now before we go with more
functions let's come back to the top and
let's start defining some variables now
the first variable that we're going to
ask our user to provide us is the risk
percent where you can see here and the
way we tell mql that it's a user defined
variable is by starting the command as
input so the mql knows that it is an
input variable it needs to ask the user
and it's a double variable because it
will store decimal values we call it
risk percent and we assign it as an
initial value of two so that's the
default value now risk percent as a
variable itself it's a very unique name
the user might not be able to understand
so if after two slashes you write
something that's going to appear here
for the user in the input tab so we say
risk in percentage on each tra so that's
what the user is going to see as a
description in the input tab then the
next variable we're going to ask is the
time frame we're asking the user to
Define already for us whether he wants
to run it on 5 minutes chart 10 minutes
chart 15 minutes chart and the reason
we're asking here is because in metat
Trader once he has assigned the EA on
the chart the user might actually switch
between 1 minute chart 5 minute chart 15
minute chart but then the EA will get
confused whether it needs to run the
code on 5 minutes chart 15 minutes chart
30 minutes chart so it will depend on
what is currently selected we don't want
that so we ask the user to provide a
value so no matter what the value of the
chart time frame is the EA will always
run it back on whatever the user has
defined the third variable we're going
to ask is the one that we have already
used which is the bars n it's like how
many bars to the right and how many bars
to the left to look for so if I compile
it now
and I don't have any errors so now if I
go back to metat Trader then under the
expert advisors I will find my new
scalping robot if you cannot find it
then just right click and
refresh and it should bring your
scalping robot here now drag this
scalping robot to the
tester and if you can't find the tester
here in the view you click on a strategy
tester and now if you go to input tab
now you can see that these are the three
variables that we have currently defined
in our EA and they are displayed here as
the description which we put after the
two forward slashes so back here four
more inputs that we are going to require
from the user are going to be the TP
points the take profit points the
stop-loss points the the TSL points and
the TSL trigger point these are provided
in points not Pips 10 points equal a pip
the TSL point is going to be how far
from the price do we want our stop- loss
to Trail so we're saying one pip and
then we are also asking the user to
provide when to start trading so how
much the trade needs to be in profit
before you trigger the trading of the
stop- loss and we're setting it to 1 and
1/2 pip so once the trade is in profit
by 1 and 1/2 pip then start trailing the
stop- loss by one tiip then besides the
baren I'm also going to ask the user to
provide an order distance point and an
expiration bar now first the order
distance point so if this this is our
low but the price is here I don't want
to send the order because the price
currently is extremely close to the low
that I have
identified so how much should be the
distance between the lowest point or the
highest
point with current price before we send
the order to so if this was the high I
only want to send the order once there
is a distance between the current price
and that High by more than 10 Pips the
expiration part is once we have sent the
order to the server it's going to stay
there forever until the time that we
either delete it or it expires so when
we're sending the order we will also
send a command to the server saying that
once you have placed the order keep it
valid for a 100 bars but then after the
100 bars expire it so if it's a 5
minutes chart then after 500 minutes
expir it if it's an hour chart then
after 100 hours expire it if I compile
it now and go back to met Trader I will
see that all of my variables that I'm
asking are now defined here and the user
is able to provide the inputs either by
putting the value or by selecting it
from a drop down now the next thing
we're going to collect is the time frame
during which time to trade and for that
we're going to create a variable type
because it doesn't come with mqr we're
going to create a variable type where
we're going to have values of inactive
100 hours 200 hours 300 hours and so
forth and so forth until 2300 hours and
we create a new variable type by saying
enum and then giving it a name and then
putting within the curly brackets what
values it can have so now that I have
this variable type which has these
values to choose from I can ask my user
to now provide an input on a variable
that I'm calling sh input so start our
input and I'm giving this variable the
type a start hour that we have created
in this line so now if I compile and go
back to metat Trader I will see now that
there is a start hour and here is our
drop down and it has the values that we
created in the variable type so now the
user can select what hours it wants or
if it wants it to be
inactive then we do the same thing for
end hour by creating an enum a variable
type calling it and hour putting exactly
the same as here and then we ask for
input and store it into a variable that
we're going to Define as th inputs and
our input and assigning it the variable
tys and hour that we have created here
two more things that we're going to need
from our users are an integer variable
and we're calling it input magic number
and this variable is going to store the
unique identification number for our EA
so that when our EA places its trade on
a server then later on it's able to
identify its own trade from other trades
that are placed on the server and the
last one is I'm asking for a string and
a string is a text variable type and I'm
collecting it in a variable that I'm
defining as trade common and for now
I've put the value as notion an if you
compile now and go back you will see
that our start hour and end hour have
also come here we have our unique EA
number which the user can Define and
user can also write whatever comment
they want and as the last variable
we're going to create two more variables
by the name of asset choice so start our
choice and end our choice where we're
going to store the value of whatever the
user has selected in sh input and eh
input we're going to store it here these
are all the variables that we're going
to use in this
year let's go back to defining our
functions now the next one I'm going to
create is when we find a suitable High
then we will send a Buy order so I'm
creating a function by the name of
execute bu and we will send to this
function the value of the price that we
want to set the order basically the
value of the high for Buys so we start
by collecting the ask value currently in
the market by sending the information of
the symbol for which we're asking the
ask value and asking back the symbol ask
value through the symbol in for double
function once we have the ask value then
the next thing we do is we look that if
the ask value that we're getting here if
it is greater than the entry point that
we're sending the high point minus the
order distance point so where it should
be or below if it is higher than that
then we don't want to send the order so
we basically say return which means
don't do anything further just exit this
function but if it is not then we know
that the price is currently below the
point at which we want to send the
orders and in which case we start
preparing to send the order so the first
thing we do is we create a PP variable
and a stoploss variable our TP variable
is going to be whatever entry price
we're sending which is the
high plus the TP points which we have
collected from the
user how many points to set the TP at
and the SL
points but convert it into the points
Decimal System of whatever the currency
pair is so for example on Euro USD you
have normally five decimal places but on
USD JPY you have three decimals so using
the correct decimal values is important
and that we achieve by multiplying the
points by a generic value that comes
with mql as underscore points and that
converts the value of the TP points into
the correct point system we do the same
for SL but the SL is going to be entry
minus the stop loss points convert it
correctly for the decimal system and
then we start with a standard lot size
of 0.01 as a default value and then we
say that if the risk percent is greater
than zero so if the user has provided a
value in the risk
if it is greater than zero then the user
has provided a value in which case we
don't want the default lot size we want
the lot size to be calculated by sending
the entry minus a stop loss distance to
our calculat loss
function and this entry minus a stop
loss is basically where our entry point
is where our stop loss point is the
distance between the two so we're
sending the distance between the stop
loss point and the entry point point and
not the stop loss
itself the next thing we look at is the
expiration because we need to set the
expiration for the order and this we
calculate by getting the time of the
current Candle by using the I time
function for the zero candle meaning the
current the last candle and then add to
it whatever number of expiration bars
that we have defined so here we have set
100 give it set
100 convert it into whatever is the p
period second of that time frame so if
it is 5 minutes chart then basically it
will be 60 * 5 300 seconds all together
multiply by the number of bars so 300
seconds multiply by 100 bars 3,000
seconds from the current time by adding
it and that is our expiration time once
we also have our expiration time then we
can send the order now in order to do
trading operations in mql we need to
make a reference to an mq file so we
come back to the top and we provide a
reference to a file by saying hash
include and then providing the path
which is going to be here in the include
folder in the trade folder and the file
name is trade. mq now this trade. mq
file comes with mql where mql has
written all of these codes so that we
don't have to write it and we can just
call these functions
to do the trading operations now the
three functions we're going to
use are C trade function C position info
function and c order info function now
the C trade function does trade so all
of the trade operations are going to be
done through Class Type C trade and
we're assigning this class to a variable
that we're creating and we're calling it
trade now if you want to collect
information on the current positions
which are open on the server then we use
the C-Class position info and we're
assigning it to a variable we're going
to call POS and same for order info
we're assigning it to a variable that
we're calling or so now that we have the
trade variable we can go
back to our execute bu function and here
we can write trade as soon as I will hit
the dot all of the trading operations
which are available are going to now be
available to me the one I'm using is the
buy stop because we're sending a buyer
stop on the high value in the market
when you will open up the bracket it
will ask ask for the value of the volume
which in our case is
Lots here that we have calculated or
here then it asks for the price on which
price is set the order and that we will
send as entry then it asks for what is a
symbol and we want to whatever chart it
is attached on then it asks for what's
the stop- loss and we have calculated
the stop loss here then it asks for TP
we have calculated the TP here then it
asks for what type of order are you
sending and we're sending and we say
that we're sending order time specified
so we will specify when to expire it and
then we give it the value of the
expiration time through this variable
that we have created here and calculated
the
expiration and then we finish with a
colon every code in mql finishes with a
colon that's the way of telling mql that
this line has finished and now it needs
to go to the next
instruction if I compile it again I do
not have any any errors so all
good so then we can proceed to creating
no prizes for guessing the execute sell
order which is going to be exactly the
opposite of the buy order so this time
we collect the bid instead of ask then
we check if the bid is smaller than
entry plus distance point so if the
entry is here and this is how much
distance we want if the bid is below
that distance then just exit the
function
otherwise calculate the TP but this time
the TP points are going to be entry
minus because it's a cell so TP is going
to be below the price and the stop loss
is going to be higher than the price
then we start with the lot size and then
we if the risk percentage is greater
than zero then we calculate the lot size
but sending the distance again but this
time we will say SL minus entry here we
said entry minus SL here we will say SL
minus entry because SL for a cell is
going to be above the entry and we want
to send the distance between the two so
this minus
this then we calculate the expiration
bar and this time we use a trade
variable that we have created to send a
sell stop by providing the value that we
have calculated
here then one more function we're going
to require is to close all
orders which is when the trading time
will finish we will close all of the
pending orders and this I Do by going
through a loop so we start for a loop
and and this time I is going to be
equals to orders
total so how many orders are there on
the server get all of them so if there
are five then I want to start the I as 5
minus one because I will go as 4 3 2 1
and zero so if there are five values I
want five iterations so I will start
with a value of four so that it can go
down to zero so I equals whatever the
number of the orders are there on the
server and then
decrease the I by 1 by saying iusus
that's i - one decrease the value of I
by One on every iteration so when we're
going through all of the orders every
time I will become smaller so 4 3 2 1
and zero and then as long as it's bigger
than or equals to zero then run these
codes which is to select the order and
this where we
using the order variable that we created
and assign to class order
info so now we're using that here by
saying order and then select by index so
select this order by its index number so
for example if there five and start as
four get its ticket number by saying.
ticket number and assign it to a
variable by the name of ticket and then
if the symbol of this order is is the
current chart symbol and the magic
number of the order is our magic number
then that basically means it's our trade
placed by thisa and it is on the same
chart so it is the same currency pair as
well and in that case just delete the
order by providing the ticket number so
this is how we will close all the
orders so now that we have written all
the functions that we need let's go back
up all the way to our initialization of
the EA and the first thing we do is we
assign on the initialization of the EA
the magic number by saying set expert
magic number and within there we say
input magic number and then finishing
with the colon so now all of the trading
operations which are going to happen by
this year will have this input magic
number as the magic number assigned the
next thing we do is we assign the value
of what we have collected from the US
as start our input and end our input up
here to these variables that we defined
so let's assign the value of start our
input into start our choice and end our
input into end our choice then we go to
the on tick
function and then on every tick what we
want the EA to do is to check whether
it's a new
bar and we do that by saying if not is
new bar meaning if it's not a new bar
then return so exit the function don't
run the codes below so all the codes
which are going to be written below this
line are only going to be run on every
new candle and not on every tick and
this we do because we don't want the
year to check on every tick all of the
stuff it's good enough to do it on every
new canle then we get the current
time and we create an mql date time
variable and we call it time and you
will understand it in a few seconds and
then we use the function time to
structure and we send to it the current
time and then we assign the value of the
structur time to the variable that we
have defined here by doing this now what
we can do is when we write time and hit
dot then the time can now be split into
day day of the week hour minute second
so for example if it's 20 100 hour now I
can get the value of the hour as 21
rather than the entire
time the thing that we are interested in
is our so we create another variable and
we call it our now and we assign it the
value of time do hours or whatever is
the current time the hour of that
current time now that we have the value
of the current time in hours we can now
compare and we go that if the hour now
this hour now the current time hour is
less than the start hour choice so if
the start hour Choice was 700 in the
morning but the hour now is four then
basically close all the orders and
return meaning exit this function don't
do anything else so don't do any trading
operations before the hour now becomes
bigger than the start
hour and then if the hour now is greater
than or equal to the end hour choice and
the end our choice is not inactive then
in that case close all the orders and
return so BAS basically only run the
codes below during the trading time
defined by the user the next thing we're
going to do is we're going to check if
there are already orders placed by our
EA on the server or if there are already
open positions because then we don't
want to send more orders so we start by
creating two variables buy total and
sell total and we assign it a value of
zero and now we're going to Loop through
all of the positions and all of the
orders so let's first Loop through all
of the orders on the server by exactly
the same way as did is for close all
orders is we creating a loop for Loop we
starting with total number of orders on
the server minus one because it's going
to go down all the way down to zero so 5
= 4 3 2 1 and Zer and as long as I
remains greater than zero then run these
codes and every time decrease the I by
one so go 4 3 2 1 and zero and on every
iteration select by index the order and
the index would be whatever is the I now
so 4 3 2 and then 1 and then zero and
then if the order type equals by stop
and Order symbol is the symbol on the
chart and the magic number of the order
is also equal to our magic number then
it's an order placed by us on the same
currency pair in that case increase the
value of the buy total by one when you
say buy total plus plus it basically
means plus one so now by total will
become one if there is an
order and if the order type equals cell
stop and it is the current chart symbol
and our magic number then we know it's
our trade placed by our year on the same
currency pair so then the cell total
becomes one as well or whatever is the
cell total increased by one exactly the
same way we're going to check if there
are open positions by looping through
all of the open positions on the
server selecting them by index and then
checking if the position type is
position type by is the c chart symbol
and it's our magic number then buy total
increases by one and sell total
increases by one if it is cell type cell
and it's on our chart and using our
magic number so now if bottal is less
than zero or equal to zero that means we
didn't find any order and we didn't find
any open positions in which case we're
going to send the high by finding the
high assigning it to a variable by the
name of high and if there is a value of
I so high is not zero is greater than
zero meaning there is a valid value it's
not a mathematical error then execute
the function that we wrote as execute by
by sending it the entry value as high so
then the E is going to go here and it's
going to run this function and send this
by stop using the value entry which is
the high then exactly the same procedure
for cell total so if Cell total is less
than or equal to zero which means that
we didn't find any cell order we didn't
find cell positions in which case find
the low and then if low is greater than
zero so it's not a mathematical error it
is a valid value then execute the cell
by sending the value low as the entry so
the system will come down
here and execute the cell stop by using
all its
parameters if we compile it now we
hopefully do not have any errors which
basically means our EA is almost
complete and when I say almost complete
the only thing it's missing now is the
trailing stop function but before we
write the trailing stop function let's
check if all of the codes we have
written so far they actually
work so I'm going to head to metat
Trader and here now if I refresh it to
default I have all of these values I'm
going to run it between 700
hours
and
and 2100
hours and I'm going to run it in a
visual mode so I can check that the CES
that I've written are correct so here we
are but it looks horrible with all of
these grid lines so I'm going to stop it
and I'm going to go back to meta editor
on the initialization function I'm going
to remove the grids by using the
function charts at
integer for the current
chart using chart show grid lines and
setting it to false
so I'll compile it
again and now if I run
it it definitely looks
better so now the first thing we're
going to
check is this is the high that our EA
has found it has five bars to the left
and five bars to the right and this is
the first High it could find and then
for the low I don't see so it couldn't
find any low valid low according to our
definition until here so it has sent an
order at this low point with 5 bars to
the left and five bars to the right why
it did not send an order here is because
the price is already below this so it's
not a valid low same goes for this same
goes for this these are not valid lows
because the price is already below them
so this is the one it fun for the buy
order it set the TP 20 points above 20
Pips above and a stop loss 20 Pips below
and if I look above and the DP was set
exactly 20 Pips below so our codes are
working as intended so we can now
proceed to setting the trail stop loss
as
well so I go back to meta editor and
what we're going to do is on every tick
we're going to call a function and we're
going to call that function Trail
stop why we're running it here is
because you would remember that every
code below
this is new bar check is only going to
be run on every new candle but for
trailing of the stop loss we want to
check it on every TI because on every TI
the price can move and we might need to
Trail our stop
loss so the last function that we need
to create is a trail stop
function so I'll come down to the bottom
and I'll
create a void function by the name is
stop we start with two curly brackets
and in between the two curly brackets
we're going to write our fors guys on
this function there are going to be so
many opening of the curly brackets and
closing of the curly brackets that you
really need to follow this pause this
once we have completed the code pause it
and type it exactly the same if you miss
the curly brackets one here or there
you're going to have errors and your
trailing stop is not going to run
properly so pay extra attention to this
one so so we'll start by creating four
variables stop loss and we're going to
call it zero PP we're going to assign it
zero we're going to get the ask price
and the bid price from the market by
using the symol input double sending the
chart value and asking for ask and bid
and then we're going to Loop through all
of the current positions by doing
exactly the same as we have done before
we're going to create a loop for the
total number of positions minus one
because if the total positions are five
then we're going to run it four to 1 and
zero and again decreasing the I every
time by one then we're going to select
the position by index by using whatever
is the I value in that
iteration we're going to get the posos
ticket number assign it to a ticket
variable and then we're going to check
if the magic position if the magic
number of the position that we have
selected here equals our magic number
and the symbol of the position is the
symbol of the current ch
chart then we're going to check if the
position type is position type
by and if it's a buy then we know that
it's our position by this year and it's
a position type buy so if it is a
position type buy then what we're going
to check is that if the bid minus the
opening price of that position has
become bigger than the trigger of the
the trailing stoploss point so we said
that our trading stop will start at 15
if now the price has moved by more than
15% so the bid is even higher than the
opening price by more than 15 then we
need to assign a new stop- loss so we
get the the current take profit of the
position and assign it to the variable
TP but then we redefine the stop loss as
bid minus whatever is the TSL points
whatever the user has said how much to
tra it byy in our case 10 points and
converting it to the right point
system then we go if the stop- loss that
we have now
calculated is above the current position
of stop loss because once we start
trailing the stop loss above we don't
want to come down we only want to go up
so if it is above the current stop- loss
of the position and it's not zero so
there is no mathematical error then we
modify the position by sending the
ticket number of the position and
sending the new stop loss and the Old
takeprofit Point and if it's not a buy
position then we check that if it's a
sell position and then in case if it's a
sell position we have already checked
that it's our input magic number and
current symbol so if it is a sell
position and not a buy position then we
check if the ask plus the trigger point
so whatever is the price if I include in
that the 15 trigger points as well if it
is still below the open price that means
we are in profit by more than 15 points
in that case we are assign the take
profit to TP and we change the stop-
loss by saying ask plus the TSL points
and then if the new stop loss that we
have calculated is below the current
stop- loss again it's a cell position so
if it is below the current stop loss of
the position and it's not zero so there
is no mathematical error then modify the
position by sending the ticket number
the new stop loss and the and the TP for
this function there are so many curly
brackets and all of these brackets need
to be exactly in the correct place for
this to work so I would suggest that you
pause the video here take your time and
code it entirely exactly as it is on the
screen okay let's compile it now and we
don't have any error and this basically
completes our base code for the Forex
and we're going to check now if the
trailing stoploss is also
working now when we will run the normal
test the test is going to be so quick
that we're not going to be able check if
the trailer stop loss works so what
we're going to do is we're going to put
a Mark here by double clicking and I put
a Mark here by double clicking and
thereby we're telling mql to stop if the
code comes to this line and the code
will only come to this line if all of
these conditions are met same for the
cell so if I press the play button now
and our testing has started and as soon
as our sell position is open and I think
the price has moved in our favorable
Direction and this is why the EA has
stopped and it has stopped at this line
because it wants now to modify the stop
loss if I press the play button one more
time and then go back to
metatrader then I will see that the
price has moved below and yes my
trailing stop loss is also moving below
now if I press it again and go back I
see that the price has moved more so in
our favorable Direction so the trail
stop is moving along then I go one more
more time and this time it doesn't stop
because now my stop loss has been hit
and the position has already been closed
now let's let it run until we have a buy
position as
well and here we now have a buy position
and the year has a stopped which
basically means that it's trying to
modify the trailing stop LS if I press
play one more time and go back I see
that now the position is moving in our
favorable Direction and The trailing
stop loss is moving along as well if I
play again it is moving
more it's moving even
further moving even
further it continues to move and the
trailing stop loss is moving along and
I'll press the button a few times and
you can see that the price is moving
upward and the trailing stop loss is
moving moving alongside the price so
this concludes the testing of the year I
will remove this and I will just let it
run a minor correction
guys we go up to where we were finding
the highs and the lows and here we had
defined as I - 5 and I - 5 while what it
should be is IUS bars
n same here IUS bar
n and the reason for that is if we using
the bars n here to calculate our range
which is let's say if bars n is 5 then 5
* 2 + 1 so 11 is our range then we
wanted to start at I minus bars n which
is five bars to the right of the current
candle same here five bars to the right
of current candle but then if the user
defines the bars n to be 10 then it
should be IUS 10 and this is why we are
updating the value here as bars n and as
bars n and not hard coding a number five
so this concludes our coding if I go
ahead and compile I do not have any
errors and this is where our coding
portion is
complete no year is going to make money
every day every week every month and we
saw it in the back test as well that
there were periods when there were
consecutive losses there were periods of
the stagnation for months where the year
did not make any money so if you applied
in a demo account and only base your
judgment on a one we or result you're
doing the year bit of a disservice the
second thing is this year works better
during trending markets It suffers
during the time when the market is
stagnant it's just moving sideways the
third point is it's a scalping robot so
the volume of Trades are going to be
massive so you need very tight spreads
otherwise your broker makes money and
you don't your spreads on an average
need to be below 0.5 Pips for this year
to work better and the last part is your
broker needs to allow scalping which is
basically the ability to Trail the stop-
loss very close to the price we Trail
the stop loss extremely aggressively and
extremely close to the price and many
Brokers do not allow that they have a
requirement of two Pips or three Pips
where you can set the stop loss and
that's not going to work with this year
following this video you should be able
to code this entirely run some demo
tests apply it in a demo account first
for 2 3 months to see how the year
performs what you like about the year
what you don't like about the year
because forward testing is the only
testing in the next video I will come
back with modifications required to
modify this year to trade Bitcoin gold
and US indicis NASDAQ and DOW Johns and
then in the last video I will come back
with some more filters that we will
apply on top of this base code to limit
the trading even further so for example
if the RSI is above a certain number we
don't want to trade if if the price is
way too far away from the moving average
we don't want to trade if there's a big
news event coming up then we not only
don't want to trade we also want to turn
off the year completely so those kind of
filters I will come back with in the
last part in the next part we will look
at gold Bitcoin and US indices and what
modifications are required to this year
in order to run those until next time
guys stay safe St safe
[Music]