we started the series by looking at this
amazing escalin robot with more than 90%
win rate and a very tight stop loss we
applied it on Forex pairs namely USD JPY
gpp USD and Euro USD then in the second
part we looked at all the modifications
required to run the year on bitcoin gold
and US indices and today we're going to
look at additional filters which we can
apply to the EA to tighten the trading
even further and potentially make it
even more
profitable so with no motion arrogance
let's start
for those of you who haven't watched the
first two videos where have you been and
for those who have you know what time it
is it's time to get your laptop and
start coding but just very quickly for
the newcomers a very quick recap in the
first part we coded this EA for Forex
pairs namely usdjpy gbpusd and Euro USD
we ran the back test and found this year
to be performing extremely well with
more than 90% win rate with a very tight
stop loss then in the second video we
did the modifications for gold oil and
Bitcoin we ran the back test and we
again found the EA to be more than 90%
wind weight and with a very tighter stop
loss but that's not enough what we said
in the first two videos is that during
volatile time chaotic time and during
news events especially the important
ones the ca does not do very well and
today what we're going to look at is
additional filters that we can apply to
the year to tighten the trading a little
bit more as we go along you will see
what filters those are now these filters
are not specific to this year these
filters you can apply to any EA that you
already have it just provides you the
filter to turn off the trading when
those conditions exist in the market so
where we ended last time if I look at
the input tab where we were is that we
had the Forex profile the Bitcoin
profile the gold profile and the US
indicis profile we had the time that we
could set for the trading between start
hour and end hour we also had the take
profit stop loss and other settings for
Forex paays and then for crypto gold and
US indices we defined these parameters
as a percentage of the prevailing market
prices instead of hardcoded numbers so
this is where we ended up last time by
the end of this video you will be able
to add three more filters to this EA the
first one a news filter the second one
an RSI filter and the third one a moving
average filter now let's take a look at
each one of them the first one the news
filter now we all know for scalping news
can be very good as well if it goes in
the direction that you are actually
hoping it to go but most of the time the
market becomes so chaotic during big
news events that you have no idea
whether the price is going to Simply
shoot up simply shoot down go sideways
go up and then down and how will it
behave also the second problem during
the news events is slipage normally the
spreads go very high and also the price
moves so quickly that by the time your
order is hit the price already has slit
up or slit down more than I don't know
four or five Pips so then you end up
getting a position that you didn't
really want to get so in order to avoid
those situations we're going to put a
news filter now what we're going to have
in the news filter is you can Define by
a part of the name of the news so for
example you could say NFP jels if I go
to tools and then the toolbox here you
can see the calendar now you can also
write a filter which Goes By Priority
level one two or three so low impact
medium impact and high impact but I
prefer to do it by name because then I
can really specify what news I want to
avoid so for example if I wanted to
avoid this ECB board member I could just
simply use for example the word lane
from this news and then put it into my
EA here as that and then if it is
applicable to that currency so if I have
Euro selected as well then the news
filter will look at that will look at
the combination and will avoid that news
then I also want to limit this news
filter by currency so only applicable to
USD news Euro News GBP news and JPY news
you can add more you can subtract and
then I want to stop the trading 30
minutes before and I only want to resume
the trading 30 minutes after when that
critical period and the crazy period is
over and during that period I not only
want to stop trading but if there are
any pending orders on the server I want
to delete those orders as well in case
of open positions I will let those open
positions run then we go to the RSI
filter and again it will start with the
whether or not this filter is applied so
you will give an option so you will give
an option to the user to either select
it or not select it as true or false now
for the RSI it's a scalping robot I mean
I'm not that concerned when I'm applying
it to a five M whether the RS I is above
80 or below 20 on a 5 minute chart per
se but if on a higher time frame let's
say 1 hour chart or 4 Hour charts if the
RSI is in extremes so for example here
on the RSI when the RSI is extremely low
on even a 1hour chart it's at 12 I do
not want to trade here now this trade is
of course because I have turned off the
RSI filter so this trade is taken but I
actually wouldn't want to take this
trade because already the RSI is so
stretched that on a shorter time frame
it might not be a good idea to take the
trade because it actually might be
reversing from here you could use it on
a 1hour chart you could also use it on a
4-Hour chart in our example we are
putting it on 1 hour chart I'm very
comfortable with 1 hour chart normally
but you can also put it on 4our chart up
to
you then you can Define the RSI levels
on which the trading to stop I normally
prefer to do it above 80 and below 20
then we go on to the moving average
filter what I mean by that is that on a
higher time frame say 4 hours chart if
the price is too far away from the
moving average then it might be due for
a small pullback and that's not a point
where I actually want to place my order
so if this was the high at this point in
time I wouldn't Place Another buy order
here because even if the price comes
back and takes that order because it is
too far away from the moving average
there is a very good chance that the
price might actually take a bit of a
breather and return a little before
going in the same direction so I'm not
debating whether or not it will continue
in the general direction of the trend
but I'm allowing for the market to take
a small breath and take a step back
before continuing in the general
direction of the trend so in these
extreme conditions I would be deleting
the order so I would want to stop and
the way we're going to do it is that one
we're going to Define where to apply
this moving average so I'm applying it
on 4our charts and then I'm going to
Define in percentage of the moving
average price itself so if the moving
average is one then 3% would mean above
1.03
and Below 97 so you will have to
calculate what you feel comfortable with
so for example the price here is around
1.47 so that's around 4 and a
half% which will mean that the 3% would
already be here but is that far enough
already I normally like to Define it as
3% but you will have to take a look on
the chart now on 1 hour chart 3% would
be a lot on a 5 minute chart 3% is going
to be too much and will probably never
even happen so look at the time frame
look at the moving average and then just
eyeball what levels are you comfortable
with and what levels do you think is too
far stretched and you might want to
avoid trading at those levels and back
calculate what those percentages are
that you want to
apply here in this example we're going
to start with 3% and then you can twak
it up or down to see how you like it so
now that we have seen what filters we're
going to apply today on our EA you know
what time it is it's time to get your
laptop sit down get a coffee and let's
start coding
so back in meta editor this is where we
finished our coding in the second part
of the video so the first thing we're
going to do is we're going to go up to
the section where we have the common
trading inputs and there at the bottom
I'm going to start adding a few more
variables that I'm going to require for
one of the filters now the first thing
we're going to do is add two handles for
RSI and moving averages these are the
two filters so we need the indicators
for them the next thing I'm going to add
are two colors so when the trading is
off what do I want the chart to look
like I don't want to see it as black I
want to see it as pink or yellow or
green or whatever fits your eyes so I'm
going to change the color when the
trading is off and I also want to change
the color back again to when the trading
is on then I'm going to create two bu
variables and buol variables are yes or
no variabl so they're going to store the
value whether it's yes or no so when the
trading is enabled I want this variable
to be true and when it's not then I want
it to be false then the next one is to
hide indicators so I want to give the
possibility for to the user so when
they're back testing if they don't want
to show the indicators they can also
hide the indicators in the chart window
and then the last one I'm going to need
is a string variable so it can store
text because when the trading is enabled
or disabled I want to print something
either in the expert tab or as a comment
on the chart something so I'm going to
use this variable for that then we go
down until we come down to the bottom of
our section and this is where we're
going to create our first input group
and we're going to call it news filter
and this is where we're we're going to
keep all of our variables which are
related to news filter so the first one
I'm creating is a bu so it's a yes or a
no variable and I'm calling it news
filter on and for now the value is true
and this is where the user now has the
ability to select whether or not he
wants to apply the filter as a yes or a
no and then if I go back to metat Trader
and now we should have the chart
colors chart when the is active hide the
indicators the three ones that we
applied and also a filter for news
coming back to meta editor the next
variables that I'm going to Define are
one a separated do down so it's an enum
and if you have followed in the first
two videos you know what an enum does so
I'm creating a drop down here and I'm
calling that in numerator separator drop
down and I'm putting two values in it
comma and semicolon because I want to
give my user the ability to select
whether he wants to separate the news
names by comma or
semicolon and then I'm using that enum
that I have created to create a variable
as an input variable and I'm starting
with zero which basically means comma so
now if I compile and go back to
metatrader now I can see that the
separator to separate the key news words
is comma but he can also use semicolons
now that I have that I can now ask for
an input variable and I'm calling it key
news and this is where he can Define
separated by comma or semicolon whatever
he ches here the keywords for the news
is to avoid so if that keyword appears
in the news typle it then the system
will know to avoid that news and I'm
calling it through two forward slashes
keywords in the news to avoid and now if
I compile and go back to metat Trader I
will see that this variable has also
appeared here and the user can type
whatever they want in it the next thing
I want to know from the user is what
currencies in the calendar to look at
because the calendar also has Brazilian
REI Pakistani Rupees Indian rupees and
all sorts of news so we want to avoid
all of that by giving our us user an
ability to specify only what news to
look for then the next thing I'm asking
is for the user to Define how many days
in the calendar to look but the way that
we're going to write the EA is that as
soon as the EA finds the next news it
doesn't look any forward and then we're
asking the user to provide input of how
many minutes before that news event to
stop the trading and how many minutes
after that event to start the trading
again and then I'm creating a bu
variable again and I'm saying trading
disabled news because I also want to
know whether the trading has been
disabled because of the RSI filter
because of the moving average filter or
the news filter so if it is because of
the news filter that the trading is
disabled then I w't to know so I'm going
to store the value yes for the beginning
we're going to create it as false
because the trading is enabled and it's
not disabled and then I also need three
more variables that we will see when we
write the function for the news filter
for now I'm just going to keep it as you
short uh as a separate code variable
name then a string so I can store text
and that's news to avoid and then date
time where I can store the value of date
and time which is last news avoided
which is self-explanatory in the sense
that whenever the last whatever there's
a last news avoided whatever time it was
I want to store that time so that then I
can see how far it has been since that
time so now that we have all of these
inputs we can then go to the bottom of
our EA from last time just below the
trail stop and this is where we're going
to start creating our new functions so
the first function that I'm going to
create whether or not there is an
upcoming news this is a bull function so
it's going to return back true or false
whether or not there is a news coming
yes or no we start this function by
saying if the news filter on if it is
disabled if the user has selected it to
be false then we don't want to do
anything further we just return a false
but if it is enabled then the first
thing I'm going to do is I'm going to
check if there is already a news event
that has recently passed and it hasn't
more than 15 minutes or 30 minutes
whatever the user has defined and I'm
going to check that by saying that if
the trading disabled news equals to true
you can write it like that but if you
just leave it like this because it's a
bull function so it basically is saying
that if trading disabled is true and the
current time minus the last news avoided
the variable that we created where we're
going to store the time of the last news
that we avoided if the time between that
and the current time is less than
however much time the user has defined
as the trading to start after the news
is that if the user has set 15 minutes
before the trading can resume again and
the time difference between now and the
last news is less than 15 minutes then
also return true because the news is
still too recent and we don't want to
resume the trading so in a way the
trading should be disabled now if that
is not the case then we know that the
trading disabled news is false or if it
is not set it to false then we go and we
look at the separator so we create a
separator a string variable and let's
call it SE and remember the separator
that we asked the user to create
here this separator which is either
colon or seic colon now we need to check
which one is selected so I'm using the
switch and switch is basically going
through the separator and seeing which
value is selected so I'm getting switch
and then I'm providing the value of the
variable to check and I'm checking for
in the separator variable and then I say
if the case is zero meaning if is comma
then separator that I'm creating here
is comma and then if it is already found
the case Zero then it doesn't need to
contines to break this function and go
out but if the case is not zero then it
needs to check whether the case is one
which will be the case in case of
semicolon and then in that case the set
variable that have defined here is going
to be storing the value as colon now
that we know that that is comma or colon
now we need to find out what is the code
for that separator because mql uses a
certain code like 05 0252
0357 it doesn't recognize commas and
semicolons it recognizes a code behind
it this is where I'm using this variable
SE code that we created in the beginning
and I'm going at a string get the
character value what is the character
value of what separator whether it's
comma or
semicolon now that we have the separator
code I'm going to use the string split
function to split the key
news this is string that we where we
asking the user to provide us with a
string of how many or what news to avoid
and there are in total
nine and what I'm doing here
now is I'm telling and ql to take that
string and using this separator
code split it and store it into the
variable that we created as news to
avoid here and these two brackets they
basically mean it's an array so it can
store more than one value so it can now
Store Nine values from that string and I
also want to create a variable and I'm
calling it K where I'm going to store
the total number because this function
is string is split it returns a value of
how many when it is when it is split the
string by comma or semicolon how many
values it got so the value of K would
now become nine next I'm going to create
three variables the first one is mql
calendar value and I'm creating the
variable by the name of values and it's
an array variable by putting two
brackets in front of it so it can store
more than one value at a time then I'm
creating two date time variables where
I'm going to store dates and times the
first one is start time which will be
the current time so whatever time it is
right now that's the start time and then
the end time will be whatever is the
start time so whatever is the current
time plus convert into period seconds
using how many seconds in a day so using
period D1 and multiplied by numbers of
news look up days news look up which is
how many days to look up for news so if
it is 10 days then look for 10 days so
the end date is going to be or the end
time is going to be start time plus 10
days then I can fetch the values from
the calendar by using the calendar value
history function and I'm saying store
the values in this variable that I've
just created values starting at the
start time and then ending at the end
time and for now the country code I'm
just leaving as null and the currency
code I'm leaving as null we could Define
it here but I would rather do it
separately then I'm going to go through
a for function so as long as integer I
is starting from zero is less than the
array size of the values that we have
stored here as long as the I is smaller
than that and go by increment of i1
create an event variable and then get
the value of that event so by I'm using
the calendar event by ID and get the
value of the event by using whatever is
the I so if it is 1 2 3 4 5 and get the
event ID and store it into this variable
event that I've just created and then by
using the function calendar country by
ID I'm using the event that I've created
or stored get the event country ID and
store it into this country variable that
I'm creating here and then I'm saying
that if you try to find the string of
this currency because now we have a
country so we can find the country's
currency so for example USD if you find
that events currency to be USD then look
it into the news
currencies a string the ones that we
defined here so whatever is the news
event that you have found look it up and
match it with the currencies that we
want to look up and if the value is less
than zero meaning that you couldn't find
it then just continue meaning
go through the loop again don't do
anything between here and here come down
here and then loop again because if it
is for example Brazilian RI then I don't
want to do anything with that news event
so just circle through until you find a
USD or Euro or GBP whatever has been
defined and then if you do find that the
currency that you have found in the
event is in the list of the currency
that we are looking for then start
another for Loop and here here we're
going to create a current event which is
the news to avoid of J because I've
already used the I here so I need to use
something different so Loop through the
K again so these
values Loop through that however many
you have found here like nine in our
example do the loop again nine times
every time increasing the value of the J
by one is starting at zero and every
time create the current create a
variable called current event and then
whatever news to avoid you have found
put that into the current event and then
the name of the event into current news
and then try to find whether that
current event is in the news so for
example if the total news says us Jools
openings whatever or non Farm payroll
and we have said in our news to avoid
Farm then that matches
and if it doesn't match then continue
meaning go to the next Loop don't do
anything below just run through again
and take the next news item to avoid and
then match that with the news and then
take the next item until you find one
which matches and if it does match then
first of all write a comment saying that
the next news is whatever is the
currency so US dollar and then saying
the event name and the time of
that event by using the value function
that by using the value variable that we
had defined here so that it will appear
here that the next news is on gpp it's I
can hardly read it it's consumer
confidence and it is on the 25th of
October at whatever
time so print it there by using comment
and then if the
Value Stein so whatever is the event if
it's time minus the current
time meaning like if it is at 2:00 and
currently it is: 145 or
146 then it's 14 minutes left and if
that is less than the stop before
minutes the variable that we defined
where we ask the user to provide us the
input of when to stop the trading or how
far in advance to stop the trading so if
it is less than that so if it is 14
minutes while the stop before time is 15
minutes and that again because we
collected the value in minutes from the
user so now we're converting into
seconds by saying period seconds of
period 1
minute so if it is less than that then
we know that this is the time to disable
the trade so we say that the last news
avoided is the values time so we
immediately store the time of the
upcoming event into the last news
avoided so then later on we can then
reference and see how much time has
passed after the news event and then we
also say that the trading disabled news
is now true so that we know that it is
coming out of the news filter and not
from the RSI filter or ma filter okay
and then if the trading enable common
that variable that we defined where we
were going to store the commment if it's
either blank or it's not equal to
printed
then we want to change it to trading is
disabled due to upcoming news and the
name of that news by saying event. n and
then then because we have disabled the
trade so we want the function to exit by
saying return a True Value back for the
entire function otherwise return false
and then at the bottom of the function
we again say return false so that if
nothing has happened then eventually we
want the function to return the value of
false that it couldn't find a news
upcoming let's compile it so now if I go
back to metatrader I can see that my
news filter section is completely done
you can select true or false whether or
not it's active then I would change this
from filters for level three news to
just filter for news and compile it
because what we are actually doing here
is just looking at the key words within
the news and not the importance
levels so whether filter for news true
or false and then here you can provide
by comma separated the the the the
keywords then the the currencies within
the calendar to look at how many days to
look for and so on and so forth now you
cannot run a back test on this so once
you have written the code what you will
have to do is for a couple of days you
need to put it in a demo account attach
the chart select the news which are
upcoming whatever are the upcoming news
maybe like three or four hours separated
and then see whether or not the system
performs perfectly meaning like it
should stop it should stop trading 15
minutes before 15 minutes after it
should start it should print a message
and then it should change to next news
and the next news and the next news that
you have put here so you will have to do
it in live chart in a demo account and
there are ways to do it in a demo test
as well but those are extremely
complicated and it will take forever to
write those codes here
here so let's go up again to the top and
below the news
filter I'll add two more groups the RSI
filter and the moving average filter now
for the RSI filter I'm starting with a
bu again exactly the same way as a news
filter where I'm starting with an RSI
filter on variable and whether it's true
or false then we have the RSI time frame
and I'm setting it to hour one because I
don't want to apply it on a 5 minute
chart 5 minute RSI doesn't mean anything
you can apply to the same chart time
frame as your EA is applied to and then
what's the lower level and the upper
level I normally like to have 80 and 20
but you can also go 30 and 70 up to you
and then when it comes to the the moving
average filter I like to use the moving
average time phrase at 4 hours because
if the price is too far away from the
moving average on a 4 Hour chart that
basically gives me a little bit of a
feeling that maybe the price is going to
take a bit of a breath and might
actually reverse a little bit now that
we have our variables we go down to the
initialization function and the first
thing that we give the user the ability
is to hide the indicator on the chart in
the test environment and because we are
applying the RSI and moving average
indicator in the EA so we need to create
the handles for them now I have two
separate videos which go into details of
how to use handles to get the value of
indicators in mql you can check them out
but this is the way you basically create
a handle and then copy the values of
that indicator into a variable so in the
initialization the handle RSI that we
have created we will assign it the value
of irsi by giving the symbol the time
frame the RSM moving average and the
applied price and for the moving average
we will use the IMA by giving it the
symbol the moving average time frame the
periods 20 150 moving average the mode
and the price once we have created these
two handles then we'll go down to the
bottom under our news filter we will
create another function for the RSI
filter and this is going to feel like a
breeze which is this is the entire
function so we create another bull
function so it's going to return the
value of either a yes or a no and we
start with exactly the same way as the
news filter that if the user has
selected the RSI filter to on to be
false meaning he doesn't want to apply
the filter then just return meaning exit
the RSI filter function by returning the
value false if he has selected the value
as true then we create a variable RSI
and it's an array variable that's why
I'm putting two brackets in front of it
so I can store more than one value in it
even though I'm only going to need one
value and then we use the function copy
buffer to copy the value from the handle
RSI that we have generated in the
initialization we get the value of the
main line starting on the current candle
and we only ask for one value so only go
back one candle or start from the
current candle and only get the value of
the current candle and store it into
this variable that we have created and
then we create create another variable
RSI now and we store the value of the
RSI on the Zero candle which we have
stored here into the RSI now I don't
need this
comment and then we can check for the
condition that if RSI now which is the
RSI on the current candle if it is above
the upper level as the user has defined
or it is below the lower level as the
user has defined for the time frame that
the user has defined then if the trading
Ena commment is blank or it is not
printed then make the trading enabl
commment as trading is disabled due to
RSI filter because we want to
differentiate whether the trading has
been disabled because of RSI moving
average or news filter now we will do
the actual disablement in the ontick
function but here I'm only going to
establish that the trading enabl comment
is no longer what it used to be whether
blank printed or any other value that it
becomes trading is disabled due to RSI
filter so that I can check it in be take
function and then disable the
trading and because this function is
saying well it is either above the upper
level or it is lower than the lower
level therefore the value is true or the
condition has been met so I want to exit
the function and return the value true
back to the wherever I'm calling the
functions wrong and if it doesn't happen
then basically the RSI is within the
range and in that case return the value
of false then we go on to the moving
average function and this is again very
similar to the RSI function we start
with the bull so it's going to return
the value of either true or or false
depending on whether the condition has
been met we start by checking whether or
not the user has enabled this so if the
user has selected false then it
basically means he doesn't want to apply
this filter in this case return and just
return the value of false but if he has
turned it on then we create a variable
moving average exactly the same way as
RSI then we use the copy buffer function
to copy the value of the moving average
from the handle of the main line is
starting at current candle only one
value and store it into this variable
then we create a variable calling it m&
now and we store the value of the
current moving average from this moving
average variable into M&L by using the
index zero and then we also get the
current market price by getting ask
through the symbol input double function
asking for the symbol's ask price and
then we can check the condition so if
ask is greater than whatever is the ma
now times whatever is the upper
threshold so if it's 3% then take the M
now multiply it by 1.03 to create the
upper threshold and then check if it is
if ask is greater than that or if ask is
lower than whatever is the lower
threshold so use the M now and multiply
it by 0.97 which is 1 minus the 3% to
create the lower threshold so now if any
of these two conditions is met that
means that the price is currently above
the threshold of the moving average or
or below the threshold of the lower
moving average and in that case if the
trading enable commment is either empty
or it's printed then make it trading is
disabled due to moving average filter so
we're not disabling the trading within
this function we're only getting the
value or basically getting a a true back
from this m filter check into our ontick
function to see whether or not it is
true and also getting a commment in the
trading enable common variable that we
have created so that we can
differentiate where is the disablement
coming from and if none of this is true
then just return false so that's the end
of our ma filter and now we can go back
up to the ontick function to actually
start testing
this so we come back here now you have
the choice to either write it below that
is new bar check in which case these
conditions are going to be checked on
every new candle or you can check it on
every t for this yeara it wouldn't
really make much of a difference but for
some other EA if you want to check
whether or not to enable or disable the
trading on every take then I would
suggest to do it here let's do it here
above the is new bar so we're checking
it on every take so we say if RSI
filter and you can write as like this
that is if is RSI filter function
returns a True Value but you can also
write it simply like this which
basically means the same thing so we're
checking that if is RSI filter function
returns a true value or if is upcoming
news function returns a true value or if
is ma filter returns of a True Value
then in all of these cases we need to
disable the tra and that we do by saying
close all the orders so all the pending
order which are sitting on the server we
delete them by calling our
function close all orders where it Loops
through all of the orders and closes
them then we say that the trading enabl
is false so the trading is not enabled
anymore so we disable it and and then we
say chart set integer and then we change
the value of the chart color to whatever
is the chart color trading of the user
has selected in the variables above and
then we check if the trading enabled
comment is not equal to printed then
print trading enable commment and this
we are doing because if it is blank that
means that there is no message from one
of those functions and also if we have
already printed which we're going to do
with here once we have printed then we
store the value in trading enable common
as printed so the next time when the EA
comes here the value is printed so it
doesn't keep printing it again and again
on everything and once we have printed
whatever is the value that is coming
back so trading is disabled because of
RSI trading is disabled because of
upcoming news or trading is disabled
because of moving averages we print that
common and then we change the value of
the trading enable comment to print it
so that it doesn't print again and then
we we just exit the function now why do
we exit the function is because we have
already closed all of the orders which
are sitting on the server and because we
are returning here so none of the coures
below are going to be run as long as the
trading is disabled as long as the RSI
filter or the news filter or the ma
filter is R return the value true we're
going to return from here and we're not
going to go below so the system is not
going to do anything it will just close
the orders if there are any orders and
then just
return come back again on the next sck
if the if the values are still true
again return and again return and again
return then we have to wait for when
that condition is not true anymore so
let's say if the RSI was below 20 so
when it comes back above 20 so this will
become false if it was because of news
coming so once that amount of time has
lapsed what the user has defined then
this will become false and once the
price comes back into the range of the
moving averages that we have
provided then we then all of these are
going to be false so the system is not
going to run this it's not going to exit
the function so it's going to come here
and if it comes here then we know that
none of the filters are true and in that
case we start with enable the trading
Again by saying true and then we print
that the trading is enabled again and
then we set the trading enabled comment
to blank so now when we're checking in
the RSI filter or the moving average
filter or the news filter whether or not
the trading enable common is is either
blank or printed it's neither and then
the last thing we do we change back the
the color of the chart back again to
whatever is the color of the chart
selected by the user when the trading is
on so back to black in in our case so
this is it let's compile it and we don't
have any errors so now if I go back to
metatrader what I will see is we have
the entire trading profiles now we have
the chart colors to be selected the user
can select whether or not to hide the
indicators on the chart
then you have down here the news filters
then here the RSI filters and you can
choose whether to apply the RSI filter
on 1 hour chart 4our chart whatever
chart and then for the moving averages
as well the same
thing so now this concludes our entire
journey of writing this EA now there are
many suggestions which have come up in
the comment section by the followers of
the channel I will compile it together
and if there are enough suggestions then
I'll probably make one more video to go
well how do you implement those
suggestions as we said already before
the news filter you cannot test it into
a visual test run you need to apply it
in live environment on a demo account
for a couple of days so that you can see
whether or not the EA is performing how
it is supposed to perform the RSI filter
and the moving average filter you can
test it into the visual mode as well so
leave a comment if there's anything in
the video which was confusing and not
clear and I might make another video to
explain it better we will come back with
a lot more stuff in in the future as
well other EAS and other General stuff
we started on the machine Learning
Journey as well so we'll continue to do
that so until next time guys stay safe
trade safe
[Music]