The stock market runs on two emotions.
Confidence pushes it up and panic pushes
it down. That's how it's always worked,
but something has changed recently. The
S&P drops 2% and nothing. No panic on
the price action, no fear on the tape.
It bounces the next day like nothing
happened. Then it rallies 3% and also
nothing. No euphoria on the price
action, no confidence on the tape. The
emotion has been completely drained out
of the market and I think I know why.
Because most of the market isn't human
anymore. 70 to 90% of daily US equity
trading volume is now driven by
algorithms, not humans, machines. And
these aren't simple bots. They are
sophisticated AI system because as AI
models are getting better, these bots,
these AI agents are also getting better.
You're watching a market where the
majority of the participants don't feel
fear, they don't feel euphoria, they
don't feel greed, and they don't panic
sell at the bottom. Now, I know what
you're thinking. Algos have been trading
the market forever. This isn't new. It's
been happening for the past few decades.
And you're right, but here's what is
new. The barrier to entry just
collapsed. Even a year ago, if you
wanted to build a trading bot, AI
trading bot or AI agent, you were
looking at months of work learning to
code, backtest properly, debug, connect
to broker, learn about API. It was a
serious technical undertaking. I know
this because I tried. I'm an engineer by
training and even for me, algo trading
always felt like completely different
world. But then something changed. In
the past 6 weeks, I went from zero to
running 10 AI agents on a Mac mini that
I got recently start of February. They
are working 24/7 handling my trading
research, my content, my business
operations, and also my personal life.
Out of these 10 AI agents, I have an AI
agent called Flux. It took me one
weekend to build while on vacation. One
weekend, guys. It connects to my broker
via API, pulls the market data, and runs
a backtested strategy on my demo account
right now. I'm going to show you guys
the reasons why. And the wildest part, 6
weeks to learn the architecture, how the
AI agents actually work, one weekend to
build the bot. So, it's a learning
curve, but once you know what you're
doing, a lot easier. That's the new
barrier to entry, one weekend, not
months of backtesting, one weekend. And
if I can do it, a trader with no coding
background, imagine what the hedge funds
and the prop firms who have a lot of
capital are deploying right now, who
they are hiring at the moment. Here's
what the data shows. The market has
become mechanical. Levels hold until
they don't. And when they break, it's
instant. Price absorbs, absorbs, absorbs
at a key level, then teleports through
it. That's not human decision-making,
that's algorithmic execution. Let's now
talk about the strategy. We, me and my
AI agent Flux, tested an extreme
reversion strategy that I personally
noticed in the past 7 years of my
trading journey. We backtested it across
5 years, 423 trades, and it was
profitable every single year. Same
pattern, extreme open, mechanical
reversion to the mean. The market
remembers its range with the machine
precision because bots are trading at
the moment. Humans don't trade like
that. Even the crashes are orderly now.
April 2025 tariff crash, massive move,
but the price action was systematic.
[music] It hit levels, faded. Hit
levels, faded. No capitulation spikes,
no volume climaxes. And our strategy,
the backtested strategy, made 40R in
that single month. The chaos wasn't
chaotic, it was algorithmic. I actually
posted a few reels on my Instagram
recently, so follow me there to stay up
to date of how I am incorporating AI
into my trading. So, our strategy made
40R in April 2025 and now we are in
April 2026.
>> [music]
>> AI models now are way smarter, are 10
times smarter than what we had back in
April 2025. One year is a long duration
when it comes to the smartness of these
AI models. And the best part or the
worst part, depending on how you
incorporate AI into your trading, is
that these AI models are going to keep
on getting better. In the next 6 months,
the models we have at the moment are
going to feel dumb and ancient. So, you
have to stay up to date with what's
happening in this AI universe. Now, the
fun part. I'm going to show you
something, but before I do that, just a
disclaimer that is going to look like
something out of a sci-fi movie, but
trust me, it's not as difficult as you
might think to make this what I'm going
to show you. So, here you go. This is my
mission control of my AI agents. Status
is online because it's been online for
the past 900 hours approximately. I'm
going to get to that. I have 210 active
sessions, 210 chats open with my AI
agents. I have 12 agents in total and
the list keeps on increasing, but at the
moment I'm happy with 12. The list
hasn't increased in the past 2 weeks
approximately. Cron jobs, 39. Uptime,
900 freaking hours approximately. I got
this Mac mini as I mentioned start of
February, first week of February. 900
hours is approximately 40 days divided
by 24. And it's been on. I haven't
restarted it. I haven't shut it down
because my life actually depends on it
now. If it shuts down, even on my
vacation, I had a lot of things in place
that if the power goes out, which
doesn't happen in Dubai, but if in case
the power goes down, it automatically
restarts and I'm able to control it
anywhere in the world. I have a VPN, a
local VPN setup. So, yeah, the security
is in place. You have to consider that
as well, especially if you are running
AI agents.
At the moment, the default model is
Claude Opus 4.6. And as I mentioned, in
the next 6 months, we will most likely
be at five or six, maybe seven. I'm
going to make a follow-up video. And
this 4.6 is going to sound really dumb.
But at the moment, it's the smartest
model out there. If you don't believe
me, if you are into AI, you know Claude
Opus 4.6 is the smartest model at the
moment. 12 agents and you guys can see
Flux is at the bottom. Flux is, I would
say, very popular online now because of
my reels. I posted a few reels recently
on my Instagram regarding AI agents, how
much P&L Flux actually made $1,700
on a demo account as I mentioned. I
posted that reel. So, as I mentioned,
follow me on Instagram. And that reel
has approximately 400 comments and
people commented Flux. So, this is one
of the most popular AI agent, I would
say, online. So, Flux has a soul and the
soul is really happy. Flux is really
happy because I'm promoting him. So, now
here's my team. My chief of staff is
Jarvis. Yes, this is one of the most
popular AI name out there. A lot of
people have their agent called Jarvis. I
just wanted a Jarvis in my life.
Honestly, I would change it, but yeah, I
mean, it's fine for me now because
Jarvis doesn't do a lot of things except
just managing the access of all these
agents. So, all these agents don't have
access to everything. They only have
access to what they need and Jarvis
actually gives the access. So, he's like
the typical chief of staff. Honestly, at
this point of time, I don't have a lot
of chat with Jarvis.
I have a lot of chat with Quill. I have
a lot of chat with Flux because Quill is
the agent she is handling. It's a he in
the Marvel universe, but I it's a she
for me because I don't want it linked to
the Marvel universe. It's just a good
name. Heimdall is another typical Marvel
universe. He's my personal coach. I'm
going to get to it. Quill, he looks
She looks after the main channel and the
encrypted channel. Auger is the
polymarket trader and that's why he's on
Opus. Opus is the smartest model out
there. Flux trading agent again on Opus.
Honestly, I haven't worked on Auger a
lot recently because I have been working
with Flux at the moment, that's why.
Every single day I spend, say, 2 hours,
3 hours with Flux and maybe 2, 3 hours
with Quill. Then all these agents are on
Sonnet. Sonnet is a cheaper version of
what Anthropic offers. But again, Sonnet
is also really smart, but it's way
cheaper than Opus. So, for Opus, I have
like trading, the content and everything
is Opus, the main businesses. And then
we have Sonnet J Junior. He just posts
like on the Discord community, that is
fine. Health coach, Sonnet, we don't
need Opus for health because Sonnet is
also really smart. Is I would say it's
the second or the third smartest. First
is going to be Opus, second is going to
be, I would say, GPD 5.4. Third is going
to be Sonnet. I would say that Sonnet is
also really, really smart. Then we have
Herald who looks after the newsletter.
Then we have Cleo. She is going to be
really important soon. At the moment,
she looks after the Off The Charts
podcast, but this is Vexa business and
Vexa is something that is going to
change the trading industry in the sense
on how you can incorporate AI into
trading. We have been working on this
business since July or September. I
would say September last year. It's been
approximately 8 months. If you guys
watch the Off The Charts podcast, you
guys know what who Arshad is. Arshad is
the CTO. I am the CEO of Vexa. We plan
to launch to beta users in the next 1
week. That is going to be, I would say,
start of April 2026. And then we will be
launching to public most likely in May
or June. So, if you want to know more
about how to incorporate AI into your
trading and Vexa can help you with that
a lot, join the waitlist. I'm going to
put a link in the description box below.
Just fill out the form, put your name,
put your email address, and we will keep
you updated whenever we launch Vexa. And
I'm telling you, if you're interested in
incorporating AI into your trading, Vexa
is going to change the game. There's
nothing like this out there. Then we
have Iris. I haven't worked with Iris a
lot video editing because at the moment,
I don't think so the models are very,
very smart to handle video editing, but
eventually, once the video editing job
that I do every day almost is taken over
by AI agents, then I'm Iris is going to
be of more use to me. And that's why at
the moment, it's just on Sonnet.
Mercury is is someone who just like
posts on X for me. If I release a
YouTube video, it's automatically going
to draft like three or four posts, ask
for my approval. Once I approve it, it's
going to post on X the link of the
YouTube video. Plutus is my job rates
manager. He looks after the Summit
Academy, if the community members are
happy or not. He looks after the
testimonials, gives me a brief overview
of what is happening inside the Summit
Academy because having a good experience
for the Summit Academy members is very
important to me and is very important
for Plutus as well. Freya is personal
assistant, basically. She is on Sonnet,
but she knows everything about my
personal life, my family, my dog, my
wife, my friends, where I'm going, my
vacations, anything I want to plan for
vacations, anything I want to buy, she
knows everything. So, Freya is just a
personal assistant. This was just a
brief overview. I won't go through
everything right here because the one
thing you are interested in because you
follow my channel is how to incorporate
AI into your trading because this is the
first video of the series. I just wanted
to show you guys my setup. I won't go
through everything because it's going to
be a 50 minutes long video. But now
let's jump on to trading now, which is
the most important thing. This trading
category is handled by Flux. Everything
else like this is Jarvis right here.
This is handled by Flux. Jarvis is like,
"Okay, Flux is someone who looks into
trading life of me." He doesn't know a
lot about Flux as well, and Flux doesn't
know
trading right here. You guys can see
this is demo account at the moment. The
demo account had a million dollars. At
the moment, it's approximately Yeah, so
we have made approximately $1,600
already. You guys can see that because
of the AI agents. These are the
positions that it's like if you go on
filled, it does It's not showing all the
history. This is still a work in
progress. So, when the bots are actually
live trading instead of me remoting into
Mac Mini and seeing what's happening on
the Interactive Brokers, it's actually
connected to Interactive Brokers. I can
see my active orders, my open positions,
my P&L on this window, this mission
control right here. We go in dashboard.
So, at the moment, we have all these
strategies in research. We have these
strategies that are archived. I don't
know why they are archived. I still have
to work on these strategies. But extreme
reversion and Tesla opening range break.
So, we all know about opening range
break, but extreme reversion is a
strategy that I have been working on and
that is actually active and that
actually made money recently. So, now we
have two active strategies, eight in
research, 10 tickers tracked. We have
759 R in total backtested R for the past
5 years. Now again, take these numbers
with a grain of salt, but the burst
strategy reward is going to be what is
important. So, let's now click on
strategies. As I mentioned,
active strategy, if you click on active,
research, and archive, right? So, active
at the moment I have this extreme
reversion, which is config B active. We
had a lot of configs. It took me a
while. Yes, it was one weekend thing,
but first you need to get the data. So,
from Interactive Brokers, the workflow
was the first thing first step is going
to be that you connect your bot,
whatever you make, you connect that with
your Interactive Brokers via API. And if
you guys have any issues, just ask the
AI agent, "How should I do it? Give me
step-by-step process. Tell me how to do
it like I'm a 2 years old kid." It's
going to tell you everything
step-by-step. Once it's connected to
Interactive Brokers, if you have data
subscription, you can get the API.
There's a limit for the free version
because I mean, even though you are
paying for the data, but to get 5 years
of data, there will be a limit right
there. So, every 10 minutes you can
proceed. You can have like 50 kind of
API calls. So, it's going to get all the
data. It actually took me a few 8 to 10
hours. I went to sleep. In the morning,
I had the data. One pro tip is that once
you get the data from your broker, I got
it from Interactive Brokers, just get
the 1 minute data because then your AI
agents can actually pass that data and
create the 5 [music] minutes and the
daily and the camera levels, whatever
you want, maybe the hourly chart using
the 1 minute data. I made this mistake.
I got the 5 minutes data first, then the
daily data, and then I actually got the
1 minute data. So, now let me click on
this. It's clickable, which is again a
mission control. And this mission
control is also created by Jarvis and
Flux. As I mentioned, you can just ask
them that, "Okay, I need a mission
control that so that I can keep a track
of my strategies. I want to keep a track
of my agents, what the agents are
doing." My mission control is still If
this looks like a sci-fi movie to you,
you need to search online mission
controls and open claw and AI agents.
You're going to be surprised what's out
there. This is still pretty basic.
Extreme reversion, I won't go through
everything because again, this video is
going to be a 30 minutes long video, but
I have a goal for this series. It's
going to be a series, which I'm going to
talk about a bit later. You guys can
take screenshots, but again, there's no
point taking screenshots. You have to
backtest your own strategy because I
keep tweaking the strategy every day. If
you take a screenshot now, it's going to
change in the next 2 days. So, you can
take a screenshot now, record the
screen, whatever, but we have the entry
rules right here. This is a combination
of camera levels and what spy on the
daily chart is doing. And we have entry
rules. We have the higher time frame
daily context filter. We have a filter
right there. Then we have the exit
rules, which is config B at the moment,
where to take your partials, how long to
hold the positions, and everything like
that. Why config B 189.9 R, 190 R
approximately. Key research findings,
and you guys can see we went through all
these configs, and this was the best R.
You guys can see with V1, this was only
a 28.9 R strategy. With V2, it was a
44.1 R strategy. With V3, third version,
80.9 R. With V3 multi, I don't know what
that is. 136 R. Then V5, finally, config
B was 190 R strategy. Instruments, it
only focuses on spy and QQQ. And if you
ask me, why spy and QQQ? Because this
extreme reversion strategy happens on
something that can't get very extended.
So, spy and QQQ because they track the
overall tech sector and the US stock
market S&P 500, [music] if they get very
extended, they have a tendency to revert
to mean. Whereas, if you apply the
strategy to Tesla or maybe NVDA, most
likely it's going to fail. So, you have
to backtest it based on I have the 1
minute data of Tesla, spy, QQQ, NVDA,
AMD 1 minute data for the past 5 years,
and I have experience with spy and QQQ.
I have been looking and focusing on the
price action of spy and QQQ for the past
7 years. My AI did not come up with the
strategy. I personally realized that
when spy is opening under S4 on the
camera levels, it's very extended, it
usually finds support at S6. And even if
not, the risk-to-reward is insanely high
because your stop loss is right under
S6, and the reward can be R3, R4, R5.
So, the reward can be 10 or 15 R on one
trade. That's why even though I would
say the win rate of the strategy is not
really high, 33% win rate, but still the
R across 5 years is 405 R. So, take it
with a grain of salt the numbers, even
if it's like plus minus 10%, it's pretty
good. It's actually very good.
Then it has the yearly breakdown as
well, 2021, 22, 23, 24, 25, and then
2026. So, that is my extreme reversion
strategy, and there's another strategy I
am working on, which is for a different
video. Because I haven't worked on the
strategy a lot, I don't want to discuss
that in this video because it's only
16.1 R, so it's not worth your time at
the moment, and it's not good on my part
to waste your time on a strategy which
is 16 R, which is barely anything. I'm
going to talk about something really
important after we are done with this
section, but it applies to this section
as well, because it's not about letting
AI do the work for you. Yes, it can do a
lot of things, but if you don't know how
to trade, if you are a shitty trader,
your bot is going to be a shitty trader.
If you don't know how to trade, your bot
is going to suck. So, you need to be a
good trader yourself in order for you to
teach your bot because I tried many
different versions, guys. I'm telling
you. I told the bot, "Do an in-depth
research. Take 30 minutes. Take an hour.
Take 6 hours. Develop a strategy for
me." Wasn't able to do it. This extreme
reversion is my brain. Is what I
realized. Is what I noticed from being a
trader for the past 7 years. This is
what I noticed. I had this idea. Then I
told the bot, "This is my idea. Refine
it. Backtest it and give me the
numbers." And this is the most
profitable strategy of the bot. And this
Tesla 5 minutes opening range break is a
strategy that my bot found based on the
data. And you guys can see the
risk-to-reward. Yes, I can tweak it, but
you need to be a good trader yourself in
order to automate things. And it's not
about automation. You can also use AI to
your advantage. For example, camera
levels.
I trade based on camera level, but
because my bot automatically gets all
the data every night at 11:45, 11:50
p.m. EST, it gets the data of all these
stocks. It automatically calculates the
camera levels for me. And you guys can
see it's awesome because for spy and
QQQ, I want the camera levels without
the extended hours. So, it only shows me
the cam levels of the regular session
right here, spy and QQQ regular session.
For Tesla and all the other stocks
individual names, it's going to be
extended hours, and these are all the
cam levels for the next day calculated
the same day. Otherwise, earlier I had
to wait for the pre-market to open up to
look at the cam levels, but now I have
the cam levels already. So, I am always
eager to look at where the levels are,
how I can I trade for the day. So, this
is something that is helpful for me. I
don't have to wait for the pre-market to
open up so that I can see the cam levels
on TradingView and on my DasTrader Pro.
So, this is just like very convenient
for me, and I use it every day. So, it's
not about AI replacing you as a trader.
You need to know how to incorporate AI
into your trading. Vexa is going to help
you a lot. Develop a mission control.
Just get started. And then the [music]
end goal, maybe in the next few weeks,
in the next few months, you can have a
few strategies that the AI is trading
for you, and then you are trading
yourself because the market keeps on
changing. AI can adjust to the market
conditions because at the moment the AI
models I have a journaling system as
well. It's going to be too much for this
video. I'm pretty sure this video is
already like 15, 20 minutes long, but
that's the plan. The plan is that this
is going to be the first video of a
series of videos, and I'm going to show
you how I am incorporating because this
workflow is changing every day, every
hour for that matter. So, I'm going to
upload a series. I'm going to create a
playlist on my channel. So, if you guys
want to know how I am incorporating AI
into my trading, first of all, subscribe
to this channel. Subscribe to my
Unscripted channel. Subscribe to my
Instagram as well because I'm posting a
lot of reels on my Instagram. And this
idea of making a main channel video came
from Instagram and my business manager,
my social media content strategist,
[music] Quill, she mentioned that you
should dive deep into this because you
have been using AI for the past 6 weeks.
So, you have a lot of knowledge now. A
lot of people are thinking of getting AI
and trading together to incorporate AI
into your trading. You have an edge. Why
not make a video? I made a reel about
it. It got a lot of views. And then I
was like, "Okay, I want to make a main
channel video about it as well." Because
yes, I have been doing it for the past 6
weeks. A lot of people have been doing
it for the past 1 year. But the whole
point of me starting this channel was in
2019, I shared my journey. I was not
making money from trading. I started My
first ever video on this channel was how
I made $90 in 15 minutes. That was my
first video. I did not plan to make
money from trading. I just wanted to
share my journey. And here I am sharing
my journey of how I am incorporating AI
into my trading. By the way, I'm
starting a weekly newsletter breaking
down exactly how I am using AI in my
trading. Every week I will share what
strategies I'm testing because I have a
vision that the AI is journaling and
self-improving itself and then changing
the bots and everything. I have a vision
and what my agents are doing and the
lessons learned. I'm going to send a
weekly newsletter. If you want to follow
along, the sign-up link will be in the
description box below. It's free. I was
the one who was against AI. I used to
say that AI won't take over trading,
humans will be relevant, but the recent
market conditions have raised a few
doubts because the market it's just
range-bound and the price action is not
clean. There is no panic when the market
pushes down. There's no confidence when
the market pushes up. And also with all
these AI models, AI agents getting
smarter every day, every week, it's just
a matter of time that more and more
percent of daily trading volume will be
driven by these AI agents or algos. And
trust me, guys, I have only shown you
the tip of the iceberg. This is just the
mission control. How do I have a chat
with the AI agents? I have a full
Discord community, different channels. I
want to show you guys a lot of things
and that's why I told you guys it's
going to be first video of a series and
that's why subscribe to this channel
because a lot of exciting things are
coming. Flux is my trading partner.
Every morning it actually calculates the
levels across nine tickers and it
actually posts me a game plan on the
Discord group that I have for my own
community, my own AI agents, I mean.
Automatically checks the levels based on
my Notion playbook as well. I have a
playbook on Notion. It automatically
scans that Notion playbook. He knows my
strategy and based on that, Flux is
going to provide me with a pre-market
game plan based on the levels, the
pre-market levels, the volume in the
pre-market and if the stock is holding
near any major Camarilla levels. It's
insane what I'm doing. I want to share a
lot, but it's too much for one video.
Now, I'm not telling you to go build an
AI bot and let it trade for you. That's
how you blow up your account. I have
mentioned that already. The bot doesn't
replace the trader. It helps the trader.
But the AI removes the emotion. The stop
is the stop, the partial is the partial,
no revenge trading and that's how AI
made $1,600 by risking $200 recently on
the demo account. No, I will hold on to
this trade for a bit longer or no, I
want to exit exit exit. That's not what
the AI agents are going to do for you.
The real edge is in speed of execution,
it's speed of research. These agents can
also help you with the research,
backtesting data. We tested 12 different
configuration like I showed you for one
strategy. We had like six different
configuration. That's the kind of
advantage that compounds over time. This
extreme reversion strategy is something
I have been noticing for the past 7
years, like I mentioned, and because of
this backtesting, if you guys see my
Instagram reels, I actually made money
on SPY recently. I never used to trade
SPY, but because of this backtesting, I
actually have the confidence in the
strategy. That's why I have taken like
two or three trades on SPY recently and
I have made $2,000, $3,000 because of my
backtesting of the data with the help of
Flux. So, Flux is not here to replace
me, it's here to supplement me, it's
here to help me. Personally, what I feel
the skill stack of the future for
traders is this. Traditional [music]
trading fundamentals and technicals that
we all have been doing for a while now.
Order flow literacy being able to see
what the algorithms are doing on the
tape because the emotion is lacking, but
you can still see where the algos are
entering and exiting on the tape and
adjusting accordingly. Third thing, very
important thing is AI tooling. Using
these AI models, these AI tools to
accelerate your research and
preparation. All three together, you
have the unfair advantage. So, instead
of taking AI as something you should be
afraid of as a trader, actually learn
how to incorporate AI to help you with
your trading. You yourself have to be a
decent trader first in order to automate
your trading and work on AI agents
yourself. And that's why now is the
perfect time to actually get into
trading because people who have been
trading for 20 years, they will find
that the market is changing, they don't
know why it's changing because they are
too stuck in their own ways, but you as
a new trader, you can learn trading and
then you can also incorporate AI to help
you with your trading. And if you have
been struggling, you can join the Summit
Academy which will actually make you a
better trader yourself so that you can
start building your own AI agent. It's
actually really good, the Summit
Academy. I'm proud of what we have built
together and the testimonials and the
reviews are already coming in. We
launched like 2 months ago and the
reviews already speak for themselves.
Link in the description box below to
check out the reviews and join the
Summit Academy if you're interested.
Now, for people who actually stuck
around until the end of this video, I
have an insane idea. I also plan to
incorporate order flow such as the AI
agent can actually see and interpret the
order flow in real time getting the data
from DX feed or Bookmap. Keep a log of
mistakes and successes and improve as we
trade together, me and my AI agent Flux.
Now, before we end this video, I
understand you guys have a lot more
questions. You guys want to see my
Discord community. How do the AI agents
ping me? They give me the game plan. How
do I have a chat with the AI agents? I
have like 20 different channels. You
guys saw 210 approximately active
sessions. How do I do that? And I
understand because I was at the same
stage as you are at the moment 6 weeks
ago. But I can't fit 6 weeks of
knowledge in one video, unfortunately.
So, the best thing you can do is
subscribe to this channel and stay
up-to-date with AI x trading playlist.
It's going to be a new playlist. This is
the first video of that playlist. Follow
me on Instagram, john_trades. I have
been posting a lot of reels on Instagram
as well regarding how I am incorporating
AI in my trading. Third, most important
thing, it's very easy. Sign up for the
newsletter below because I'm going to be
sending out free weekly AI trading
newsletter before I even make the video
because making the video, recording,
editing, posting takes a while, but
newsletter is going to be pretty
instant. So, if I have a new workflow in
mind and I work on it, I'm going to send
out an email to you. Thank you for
watching. Like, subscribe and I will see
you guys in the next one.