We're building this trading robot. It's
a multi-currency grid management system
with quite a lot of advanced features.
It's been there on MQL marketplace for
quite some time now.
It sells for $2,800.
It boasts a very strong performance,
consecutive months in profit, and it
comes with full documentation including
features, how to install, requirements,
risk settings, the strategy, and all
that good stuff. But, we will build it
ourselves and step-by-step with all the
functionality and this pretty looking
panel. Now, this will be a series of
videos as the trading robot is quite
advanced and we need to build a lot of
functionality. And it seems to have been
very intelligently built. In the first
video, we tried to dissect the
functionality of the EA. We tried to
figure out how does the EA work, how's
the initial trade opened, how are the
grids formed and maintained, how's the
TPs and stop loss calculated, and some
other really cool features like starting
the grid from a certain level, placing
both mark trades in the beginning, a
smart TPs, a smart stop losses, a smart
distancing of the grid depending on the
volatility in the market at that point
in time. And then also looked at some
additional features like news filter,
drawdown controls, additional
restrictions, and a lot more. If you're
joining us from this video, I would
strongly urge you to start from the
first video because building what we are
trying to build without understanding
what it is that we are trying to build
is like getting into calculus without
first understanding arithmetic. I would
not recommend. We don't want trauma of
logging in the end. Now, like always, I
will make the course available in the
store for anybody who wants to download
it for reference, but please understand
this. I am making the code file
available for reference. I am in no way
saying that you're going to make Elon
Musk look like a baker from the 3rd
century by simply downloading and
applying it on the EA. I don't suppose
this is going to make multi-millionaires
overnight. In the same breath, it is a
very good EA as long as you know how to
use it properly. An EA is like a tool,
just like a hammer is a tool. Now, if
you don't know how to use it, evolution
is not going to be happy with its
generosity of blessing us with thumbs.
With that out of the way, let's start
building first the backbone of the EA.
Then we're going to put a skeleton, then
some meat around it, and eventually a
very pretty smooth skin all over. video,
we're going to write the fundamental
structure on which the entire EA is
going to be built. And we're going to
get to a position where we open up the
first trade. Then in the later videos,
we will open up grids, we will do the
smart distancing, then we're going to do
all the lot sizing methods, different
types of calculations for the lot sizes
for the grid based on various different
ways that you can manage the grid. Then
we're going to look at TPs and stop
losses, and also additional
functionalities like not sending the TPs
and a stop loss to the broker, but
managing it internally. Then we're going
to put some really cool flavors and
colors on the EA in terms of drawdown
controls, FTMO stuff, news filters,
other sorts of restrictions, margins,
safety measures, and this extremely
pretty looking panel. Once again, I'm
not going to build it with a green
Pac-Man, I'm going to build it with a
yellow Pac-Man because I just couldn't
find a green Pac-Man. And in the end,
it's going to be a journey, so buckle
up. And for the faint of heart, use of
discretion is advised. Now, with no more
shenanigans, let's start. Okay, so we
start here and in the YouTube folder,
I'm going to create another folder.
And let's call it Waka
Waka by Mr. Caffrey.
Now, copy the name.
And then within this folder, we're going
to create
a new MQL5 file, Waka Waka by Mr.
Caffrey. Next, next, and next. And here
we have the opening template.
I'll clean it up.
Okay, so here we are with the clean
template. We have the on initialization
function, which is going to be run on
every time the EA is initialized.
Then the deinitialization, which is the
opposite. So, when the EA is
deinitialized or it's removed from the
chart, that's what all the codes here
are going to be run at.
And then you have the on tick function,
which is every time there is a price
change or a new price data arrives.
All the codes which we are going to
write here are going to be triggered
then.
So, we're going to start at the top and
we're going to add a few properties.
So, we're going to add a strict property
and a description property. The
description property is
self-explanatory. The strict property
basically asks when we compile, we ask
the MQL to do a very strict compilation.
So, go through the codes and properly uh
look through for any errors or
warnings and stuff like that.
Then we are going to include a trade.mqh
file, which is the file that you have
here in the include folder. Trade
trade.mqh.
And these are all the codes which are
which come pre-written with MQL,
which help us with all the trading
operations.
So, in in terms of opening trades,
modifying trades, getting information on
the positions, getting information on
the order, and things like those.
So, for trading operations, we're going
to use the class CTrade and we are
linking it to a variable trade.
For position information, we're going to
create we're we're linking this class to
a variable by the name position info.
So, we're going to use position info to
get all the position related
information.
And then COrderInfo class, which we're
linking to order information variable,
which I think we are not going to use
within this EA, but this is just my
general practice to create this so I
have all the trading operations in
trade, all the position information in
position, and all the order information
which are the sell stop, buy stop, limit
sell limit, and those kind of things in
in this variable.
And then we're going to create a few
enums.
So, the first enum that we're going to
create is the lot sizing enum. And enums
are basically if, for example, I go back
to my scalping EA
and I'll put and I pull down here, if I
go to my scalping EA and go to the
input, what you can see is, for example,
here the trading system applied,
you can select from this drop down of
fixed pips or percentage. So, that's an
enum that we're using. Or here, for
example, you can choose fixed lots,
percentage of balance, equity, or free
margin, but that's only because to this
variable I have assigned an enum which
has these four values.
So, that's what we're doing here. We're
going to create we're creating an enum
which is going to have these members.
So, low risk, 20% mid risk, significant
risk, high risk, dynamic lots based on
equity, dynamic lot based on balance,
lots based on deposit load, and fixed
lots. So, these are the options that
we're going to give to our user.
We're creating the enum by the name lot
sizing enum and we're going to assign
this enum to a variable which then in
turn will make all of this available in
the drop down.
So, that's the first enum. Then I'm
going to create three more enums, which
is allow buy sell enum, where we're
going to give the user the ability to
select only sell,
only buy, or allow both buy and sell.
And then in case the drawdown is hit,
it's triggered, what action do we want?
So, we're giving four different
possibilities to the user. So, to
prohibit the new grid until restart,
prohibit opening up a new grid,
close all the trades and stop trading
until restart, and close the trade and
stop trading for 24 hours. So, these are
the options that we are giving.
And then, how are we going to calculate
the drawdown? Is it going to be only for
this strategy? So, not calculate the
drawdown for the entire account, but
only for trades which are opened by this
strategy because you can also have
somebody who applies this
in the charts,
but then also open manual trades, or on
the same account there are multiple EAs.
So, do we want to calculate the drawdown
for the entire account or only for the
strategy? So, these are the enums I'm
creating. And then I'm going to create a
structure.
And we're creating a structure by the
name symbol information so we can assign
the symbol information is structure to a
variable.
And then within that variable, you will
have all of these sub variable
available. So, you can, for example, if
we create a variable by the name array
size,
and then we assign to it this, then we
can use array size.symbol name, array
size.last
main time frame update, array size.
uh OPO time frame update. So, all of
these then become available as a dot
later on,
which we can use to assign different
properties of that variable.
I'm not going to go through all of them,
but just a few main ones. For example,
the main time frame, the last time frame
updating this. So, what is the time?
Then can buy and can sell as a bool,
which is true or false.
And this is going to use to see whether
or not we buy or we place a sell order.
And then various properties like has the
grid opened, has the OPO been triggered,
what's the smart multiplier, what is the
Bollinger bandwidth on this symbol,
other things like days of the week,
average price, last buy average price,
last sell average price, last buy TP,
last sell TP.
Uh last time the grid was open on buy,
last time the grid was open on sell, and
those kind of properties we can store in
one variable then using a dot and using
all of these sub members of the those
variables. So, we create this.
And now we can go ahead and actually
create variables,
which are going to be available for the
user to select from. So, these are all
input variables.
We start by saying input group so as a
header, select the risk setting. And
here we are creating all of these
variables.
So, for example, if I compile now
and hit the play button,
stop.
Then I can see here now
our EA has been created.
Waka Waka by Mr. Caffrey. And within
that EA now we have the select the risk
setting
and all of these. And now because we
assigned
this lot size enum to lot sizing method,
this enum,
therefore,
now we have this drop down available to
select the lowest setting, medium,
significant, high, dynamic lots, fixed
lots, and those kind of things.
And here we allowed the allowed to buy
and sell
this enum.
So, allowed to buy sell has now sell
only,
buy only, or buy and sell. So, these
enums are also populated. So, we
ask the user if we can allow opening a
new grid,
true or false.
And then the lot sizing, depending on
what method is chosen. Now, if it is
fixed lots, then what is the value of
the fixed lots? If he has chosen dynamic
value based on equity or balance, then
what is that on dynamic lot size?
Then if he has chosen load percentage of
deposit load, then what is that
percentage? Then the fixed initial
deposit,
which is only for tester, because what
can happen with the grid, if I mean, one
way to use the grid strategies is you
start with a 5,000 balance,
and as it makes profit, you take that
profit out. So, you always keep the
initial balance at 5,000.
Because one day I mean, it's not a
question of when It's not a question of
if, it's a question of when the grid is
going to
like bite the dust and the strategy is
going to blow.
So, what you're banking on is that you
make enough profit and take it out
before the account is blown.
So, if you have a starting balance of
1,000 euros and you're constantly taking
the profit out, keeping the initial
balance at 1,000,
so that is all what that 1,000 is all
that you're risking
on the strategy.
And if you want to test it like this,
then the user can select here a true,
and in that case we will keep the fixed
initial deposit for lot size
calculation, and instead of using
the equity or the current balance after
the profit, we're always going to revert
back to fixed initial deposit.
Then what's the maximum lot?
Do we allow auto split?
Which basically means and on larger
accounts, let's suppose
if the lot size calculation is giving us
200 lots,
but the broker is only allowing 100 lot
size.
So, in that case, do we allow auto split
so that 200 calculation is then auto is
split into two trades and we open two
trades instead of one?
Or do we revert back to if it is false,
then we revert back to whatever is the
maximum allowed by the broker? So, even
though our calculation is giving us 200
lot size, we still go with the 100
instead of dividing it into two.
Then the max is spread and slippage, and
then how many symbols the user is
allowing the grids to open at. So, even
though there might be four currencies
that you're applying it on, but as soon
as there are two grids on two
currencies, you don't allow
opening of the grids on more currencies.
So, how many maximum symbols at one time
can have grids?
Then allow hedging, meaning if there is
a buy grid open, do you allow a sell
grid
to open as well? Or if there is a buy
grid, then you don't allow a sell grid.
Do you allow trading on holidays? And
holidays here basically mean between the
25th of December and the 3rd of January.
So, do you allow trading during that
time?
Then allow to best buy sells like Well,
we have already seen buy only, sell
only, and both. Minimum free margin in
percentage,
uh zero is disabled.
Maximum drawdown
in percentage,
and maximum drawdown in money.
So, that we trigger the drawdown once
that level of maximum drawdown is hit.
And then what's the action, which is out
of these four?
And then how do we calculate based on
strategy or on account?
Then we go to the strategy settings,
which is how many symbols, what are the
symbols separated by comma,
the time to start trading, time to stop
trading.
What's the hour?
Then Bollinger Band period, as we saw in
this in in the strategy testing, the
Bollinger bands are going to be used
primarily for TP setting,
but we need to create the Bollinger
bands.
So, what's the period for Bollinger
band?
And then the RSI period and the RSI
value. And as we saw in the actual EA,
the RSI value is what determines from
50, the middle RSI,
how much higher and lower do we place
the buy and the sell order?
So, the default position is 15, so
that's going to give you 65 and 35 as
the ranges for RSI where the trades are
going to open. And then you have the TP
settings. So, what's the initial TP?
Which is the TP that's initiated on the
first trade.
Then do you use weighted TP? And by
weighted TP I will mean that once there
is a grid
and it's going to open at different lot
sizes,
do we weigh
uh the lot sizes as well from the
average price? Then the grid TP, meaning
initial TP was 10,
but for the grid TP, do you want to set
a different value? Break even after
this, so ignore all the TP settings of
how much TP do we want
after a certain level. So, grid opens
level one grid trade, then the level two
grid trade, and maybe you say that after
level three, enough is enough. Let's set
it to break even so that at least we can
get out. Hide TP, which is like a lot of
people want to like, "No, I don't want
to send the TP to the broker because
there's going to be a TP or stop loss
hunt."
So, no, I'm going to just calculate it
and keep it inside. So, that's the hide
TP.
Use the OPO method, which is
as If you have sent the TP to the
broker, then it doesn't really matter
because as soon as the price gets there,
the TP is going to be triggered.
But if you have chosen the hide TP, then
you're keeping the TPs and the stop
losses internally.
In which case, we can have the OPO
method, which is on only on open price
only,
which means that we're only going to
close the trade once a full candle has
closed above the TP.
I don't know why you would want to do
that,
because if the TP is hit, the TP is hit.
I mean, on the stop loss I understand,
but on the TP to use the OPO method,
uh for me just doesn't make any sense.
But because this is part of the EA, so
I'll I'll build it and will I'll explain
it.
But I'll not spend too much time on
that.
Then the OPO time frame, which can be
different,
because you want to see a candle closing
above the TP in order to close the
position.
Then do we
want to do it on the 15-minute chart
itself, which the EA is going to run at,
or do you want to use a 5-minute chart
or a
10-minute chart or become, you know,
like be fancy about it?
Then a smart TP is going to be based on
Bollinger bands instead of these initial
TP situation. We're going to calculate
TP based on Bollinger band because that
gives us a dynamic TP. So, when the
Bollinger bands expand, our TP also
expand
because the market is volatile and then
we want to have a higher TP. But when
the market is ranging and is very dull,
then the Bollinger band is going to
shrink,
and so our TP also shrinks down and
comes closer to
to the actual trade
uh to give us more chances of hitting
the TP
in a less volatile market as well.
>> [clears throat]
>> Do not change or adjust the TP unless
there is a new grid level that opens,
and only when a new grid level opens,
then you do the calculation of the TP
and then adjust the TP.
Then you have the stop loss setting.
Again, hide and grid stop loss is like,
do you want to set a stop loss? If
nothing, then we're going to use a 1,000
pips.
Then we look at the grid settings and
multiplier. So, what is the distance
between the grids? So, it's 35 points or
35 pips.
So, if the initial trade is here, and
the next trade is going to open at a
distance of 35 pips.
But because we're going to be opening
trades only on new candles, so it might
not be exactly 35 pips, but it's a
minimum of 35 pips.
Then a smart distance, and then the lot
multiplier.
So, the first lot is going to be
whatever the lot size calculation gives
based on
the risk that we have chosen here, lot
sizing method.
But then the third one
the second one is going to be the same,
for example, multiplied by one. But then
for the third to fifth trade, you might
want to apply a different multiplier.
So, like we start increasing and
martingaling.
If you set it to one,
then it's not a martingale, it's just a
grid. If you set it to a value higher
than one, then you're martingaling, so
you're increasing the size every time by
a factor of two. And then from the sixth
trade onward,
you apply a 1.5. These are the default
values.
And then what are the maximum number of
trades?
And then the question is grid level to
start. And this is These two are the
complex settings,
which basically means that the first
trade is going to open here, for
example.
But do you want to open it already? I
mean, if you're expecting that the price
is going to go against you
and then you're going to open the first
level
and then it's going to go against you
again and you're going to open the
second level and the third level
then if you're already expecting that,
why not
start from the level three? So, in that
case, you place a very small minimum
0.01 trade at the base level at the one
zero level at the second level at the
first level
and then only from level two, we start
to go if like, okay, now we actually
enter the full lot size then. Let's
place a marker so that we can actually
calculate the lot sizing, but let's just
put minimum lot, minimum lot, minimum
lot and then go from level three
the actual lot sizing. And then we have
the last one which is the trade comment
and a UID which is a unique identifier
for this particular instance of the EA
because we're going to create magic
numbers based on a base magic number
that we're going to not ask the user
for.
Um
and then we're going to create we're
going to
and then we're going to change that
magic number or base magic number add to
it
a direction so it can tell us whether
it's a buy or a sell and then also the
levels at the end which is well, is it
the first trade? Is it the second trade?
Is it the third trade? Is it the fourth
trade within the grid?
So, we're going to create a separate
magic number for every trade.
But then if the user wants to apply the
same
EA
on the same account twice
that's where the UID comes into place
which is a different instance so that
you're going to change this if you're
going to change
if you're going to apply more than one
instance on the same account.
So, these are our input variables. If I
compile now
and we go back, now we have all of this
appearing in the input step. These are
all the variables which we are asking
the user to provide us information on.
And then come global variables. So,
we're going to create a tick counter
variable. What is the main time frame
that we're going to apply this EA on?
We're not giving this to the user to
decide. It is fixed within the EA.
And this is a symbol array
variable. So, it's an array because it's
going to have more than one currency.
You could call it currency array.
I'm calling it symbols array.
So, symbols array
so, it's going to store all these
symbols one, two, three.
And this is the symbol where we are
using the structure. So, this symbol
array is going to have the sub members
by clicking by using the dot and then
you can choose one of these properties
within that.
So, this is a very dynamic variable that
we're creating. Not only that it can
have
these three currencies so, it can be
Australian New Zealand, Australian
Canadian dollar, New Zealand Canadian
dollar. But within within that currency
with the dot then you can access all of
these members of the variable as well.
And then the magic number base. So, this
is the actual magic number but we're
going to be using this base to convert
it into a different magic number for
every single trade so we can find the
direction of the trade
and also the level of the trade within
that grid.
Then epsilon is just a value 0.0001
which is just above of the zeros and
this we're going to use throughout the
year to check whether or not the value
is a valid value so, it's bigger than
one.
And then you have the current hour. I
mean, we're just creating these
variables and we're setting it to an
initial value
whether or not there is a symbol error
list, whether or not the drawdown has
been triggered so, it's false, whether
we want to stop trading until restart is
false, how many cool down hours in case
the drawdown has triggered zero
initial balance zero
and initialize as true.
So, these are the global variables that
we're going to use. And then the
indicators that we're going to use
within the EA are the moving average and
the standard deviation which we're going
to use to create the Bollinger Band
calculation.
And we're going to do manual
calculations of Bollinger Band because
on multi-currency EAs
MQL struggles with updating the
Bollinger Band values for every currency
so, we're going to manually calculate
it.
And then RSI because our EA grading is
based on RSI. And then the ATR 96 and
which we're going to use to determine
whether there is more volatility in the
market by dividing faster ATR
divided by
the slower ATR to see whether or not
there is more volatility in the market
right now
because then the value is going to be
above one. Then we go to initialization
and here we're going to start by
printing
trade comment initializing. So, when the
EA is loaded, we're going to get a
message.
Then I'm going to set the chart integer
the grid to false
because I like to see no grid on my this
just looks cleaner.
If you want to see the grid like this
then
then you can skip this
or set it to true.
Then tester hide indicator. I want to
hide all the indicators. I don't want to
see it on the chart
in the tester.
And then a comment which is going to be
printed here.
And then as a start we set the drawdown
cool down hour is zero.
Stop trading until we start is false and
drawdown trigger is false so, there is
no drawdown
at the initialization of the EA.
I mean, hopefully.
And then we're going to be using the on
timer function so, unless so, if not MQL
tester and not optimization so, it's not
a tester
and it's not we're not in the
optimization mode or testing mode back
testing.
So, we are in the real live environment
in which case the events at timer is 5
seconds because we're going to be using
the on timer to refresh the data every 5
seconds. And then we're going to set the
last check timer check to current time
so, initial initializing this variable.
And then we get to our first function.
So, we're going to call this function
and if this function fails
then in that case we say, well, we
failed to initialize the symbols
and in that case the entire
initialization fails. We're going to
write this function but here we're
calling that function and using if not,
then print.
Then we created these five handles so,
we need to resize them.
And we're going to resize them to the
array size in the parsing and
initialization of the symbol, we will
create the symbol arrays for these
currencies so, it's going to be one,
two, and three.
So, then now we can resize the array to
the number of members within the symbols
array which is going to happen here in
this function.
So, it's going to be three because there
are three currencies.
And then we initialize all of the
handles
but for every single currency in the
symbol array. So, we're going to loop
through all the currencies starting at
zero
going through zero, one, and two
because there are three currencies and
for every one of them we're going to
create an instant of instance of the MA,
standard deviation, RSI 96 ATR, and 672
ATR for that particular symbol index.
So, there are going to be three handles
of MA, three handles of the standard
deviation, three standards of RSI, and
so on and so forth. Now, because we're
going to be using the MA standard
deviation to to create or calculate the
Bollinger Bands and this is why we're
sending here the Bollinger Band period
to get the standard deviation and MA.
Now guys, I have to go a little bit
quicker because if I explain every
single line in detail, this video is
probably going to be like 7 hours long
and nobody's going to watch it then.
So, that kills the entire purpose. If
you have written the other EAs with me,
then you probably are at a level where
you can understand these.
Now, we're going to check if the RSI
handle fails or the standard deviation
handle fails. If any of them fail, then
we just print that we failed to create
the indicator for this symbol.
And the initialization fails then. So,
now we have
called this function so, let's go and
create this one. I'm going to create a
few sections. So, the first section is
I'm going to call it symbol related
functions.
Then let's have another section
which we're going to be using for let's
say lot size functions.
Then let's have one for
grid related
functions.
Then let's have one for
TP
and SL
related
functions.
One for
closing
the grids
and trades
slash drawdowns.
And then at the end
some general
helping functions.
So, that we have
sort of a structure.
So, now this parse and
initialize symbol, we're going to put it
here under under symbol related
functions. So, we create it here.
Okay, so let's first create a sim
a variable by the name symbols and it's
an array.
And then we're going to get the symbols
from this symbols variable that we
created here.
Symbols, so there are three of them.
So we're going to take that and we're
going to split it by using the character
comma
and store these values into this symbol
array that we have created.
So there are going to be three members
here.
And that's going to return the count of
three which we're going to store in
this variable symbol count. And then we
say if the symbol count turns out to be
greater than zero, so there is a value
which is coming back and it is not the
tester,
then in that case we resize the array of
the symbol array to symbol count. The
symbol array, remember the variable
which has all the
sub members from the structure, we
resize that here to the symbol count and
this is why
in our initialization, after doing the
parsing, we could resize the moving
average, standard deviation, RSI arrays
to the symbol arrays because here we
have already
resized the symbols array
to the number of symbols which are
available or what the user has inputted
in the symbols variable.
And then we're going to loop through all
of the symbol counts. So starting at
zero, going all the way up to two. So
three, zero, one, two.
And then we say symbol name is equal to
whatever is the symbols I get the value
of the index from because this is where
we stored all the symbols.
So we take this, we loop through it, and
for every index we create the symbol
name.
And then we trim it left and right
because somebody might have put a blank
like
a space.
So in that case, we need to to to trim
it.
So we trim it left and we trim it light
right.
And then if it is if it comes back to be
blank, then we print that the symbols is
incorrect, check for extra commas and
like that. And the symbol error
list is true.
And we return false that we're not able
to parse it.
Otherwise, we run a function by the name
initialize symbol data
for this index in the symbol
and send to it the symbol name which is
coming out of here.
And then we close this if.
That if the count was greater than zero
and it wasn't the tester. Well,
otherwise, if if it wasn't tester here,
then we are in a tester and in that case
the tester is only going to run it on
whatever pair is selected here. So it's
the single currency then.
So in that case
the symbol array becomes one.
The symbol name becomes symbol, so
whatever is the symbol
selected here.
And then initialize the symbol data that
what we're doing here as well, but here
we're sending the index in the symbol
name, but here we said just zero as the
index and the symbol name which is the
symbol which is selected here.
And for now, I'm deleting this and we're
going to come back to this.
So only this and then we just return
true. So we have initialized the
symbols, we have parsed it. We have put
them into this array.
We have populated the array of the
symbols array. So now the symbols array
variable has all of the the currencies
and therefore all of these
are now available to be updated by
currency as well.
Let's compile
and we have two one two errors.
Which is the unexpected end of program
and unbalanced parentheses.
Let's check here.
Did we close yeah properly?
Let's go back on initialization.
We're not closing it properly
because we did not close this for loop.
So we need to close this for loop.
So if I close it
and now if I compile
still a error.
Oh, because we said
because we have created Oh, we we wrote
this function symbol initialize symbol
data here and here, but we haven't still
created this.
So now we are in this symbol data
function, so let's create this function.
So we're going to create this function.
And to this, we're going to be sending
the index and the symbol name to
initialize the data.
Let's hit compile
and now we are okay. It was just missing
the initialization of the symbol data.
So let's just initialize
all of the values
that we have created in the structure
in this structure.
So what we're doing here is in the
parsing, we're going through the symbol
count
and for every one of them we're getting
the symbol name and then we're passing
that symbol name index and the symbol
name here, so it's going to be done
three times
for each of the currencies.
Which is going to store the symbol name
the last time frame. I mean, currently
we're just storing zero zero zeros and
falses and trues.
But now we are able to
for example, for can buy and can sell
for every individual currency
within the symbol array, the three
currencies, we can set the can buy, can
sell and other parameters separately for
all three of them.
So all of these variables are available
three times because there are three
currencies.
Compile once again, no issues. Okay, so
let's go back up and on the
initialization I want to make one change
which is here.
Instead of printing that command
failed to indicator, I'm going to add
this part as well which is check that
all the input currencies are visible
within the market watch window
because the most common reason
that this these handles can fail
for different currencies
is that you have here these three
currencies input
but these are not available here. So if
AUDCAD wasn't here, MQL is not going to
be able to load load the indicators. If
Australian New Zealand and New Zealand
CAD are not here in the market watch,
you will get the error message that it
failed because it's not going to be able
to load the indicators. This is the most
common reason that these can fail, so
let's say that check all the input
currencies are available in the market
watch window.
Let's hit compile once again, no issues
and then we go to the on tick function.
Here we're going to start by creating a
a bool variable where we're going to
check if it's a a new bar on the main
time frame.
And then we're going to loop through
all of the symbol arrays, so all three
currencies, starting at zero, then going
one and then two. So loop through the
three currencies. And then we're going
to check that if we sent the symbol
array symbol name
once again, we're using these
sub members
of the currencies. So if I'm sending the
first currency,
the zero index currency, and dot symbol
name, it is getting the value from that
structure.
For the main time frame current candle,
get the I time.
And if the I time is lower
than or equal to whatever we had updated
before in that currency symbol array as
last main time frame update time, then
in that case
the time it's it's not a new candle.
So we set the new time frame new bar for
the main time frame variable to false.
Otherwise, it's a new candle and then we
set this variable
to
the time
of the current candle opening time
and we set it to true. So the next time
it's going to come, then unless there is
a new candle,
this is going to fail and then it's
going to be false. And then if it is
true, the new time frame, then we're
going to update symbol information. We
initialized the symbols and now we're
going to update the symbol information.
And then we close the for loop
and this is our on tick function for
now. Now if I compile, I'm going to get
an error because I haven't created the
update symbol information sending it the
index value. So let's go down here and
create this function.
So this function, we're going to send
the symbol index from this looping
on on tick
because we're looping through, so we're
going to send the index value to this
update symbol info. And if I close
and compile
everything is fine so far. So let's
start updating it. We get the value of
the symbol name and store it into the
symbol.
And then we go for that symbol array,
update the counter plus plus, so
increase it by one. So we're increasing
the value which we initiated here as
zero will now become one. So now this is
keeping track of how many times
uh the counter has updated. And then
we're going to create an MQL datetime
variable
by the name TM current and within the TM
current we're going to store the value
of the current time
by using the time current. So we're
storing the value of the current time
into the TM current. And what the TM
current basically does is now with TM
current you can hit the dot and for the
time current that you have stored here,
you can get the value of the day, the
day of the week, the day of the year,
hour. So it creates a full structure.
And this is why we are
putting the current time into this is
structured time variable, so we can get
the value of the current hour and the
current minute. And then we're going to
store the value of the time into the
current bar time and also into the
previous bar time.
We update this
and then we update the value of the
current bar time into the previous bar
time.
And this is on update of the symbol
information. And then we create a bool
variable by the name can trade
and we're going to check if the trading
is allowed and if the user has allowed
opening new grids.
And we're going to store the value into
can trade. So, if trading is allowed and
the user has allowed the opening of the
new grid, then can trade becomes
true, otherwise it's false.
And then we apply this value to can buy
and can sell. So, if it is allowed, then
can buy is true and can sell is also
true. Now, let's go down to our
general helping function and here we're
going to write this function is trading
allowed.
And here we're basically going to be
checking four things.
First of all, if it's MQL tester or it's
MQL optimization, then return true
because in tester and optimization,
trading is always allowed.
Otherwise, if it's live environment, we
create a variable allowed
and we store in this the value of the
terminal trade allowed, meaning here is
that turned on
or is that turned off. If it is not
allowed,
if allowed is zero, so if it's not
allowed, then return false for the
trading allowed.
Otherwise, check account trade expert is
allowed. And if it's not allowed, then
return false,
which is here.
Check if this is allowed.
If it's not allowed,
then return false because the trading is
not allowed.
And then the third thing is check that
the broker side trading is allowed. So,
the broker is allowing trade.
And then if it's not allowed, then
return false.
And if none of them,
then just return true.
Compile and we're fine.
So, let's go go back up. So, here we're
checking that everything is allowed and
the grid opening is allowed.
So, this is allowed and then can buy is
allowed and can sell is true as well.
And now we're going to run through a lot
of different conditions.
So, we're going to check
if the main time frame has less than
1,000 symbols,
then in that case not enough historical
data
and can buy and can sell are both false.
So, we were true here, but if this
happens, then set it to false. Let's put
a comment.
Check historical data.
And then we're going to check the
account balance or free margin, which is
we go over get the free margin and if
it's less than 10, then in that case
we say it's low margin.
Print the uh margin value
and we
uh because we don't want to print the
message is many like every single tick,
so we're going to start with last
message as a date time variable
zero
and then here we're going to print and
then we're going to set the last print
message to time current.
And then the next time we're going to
check that the time current minus at
last time message is greater than 60
minutes. So, we're only printing it
every 60 minutes.
This 3,600 is in seconds.
So, we only print this message every 60
minutes and because the margin was
lower, so we set the can buy and can
sell to false.
So, if this is true, then can false. If
this happens, can false. And then we're
going to check the UID.
Remember, the user can select the UID
between zero and nine.
So, we check here that if the UID is
less than zero or greater than nine, so
it's not in between,
then in that case again we print this
message and we only print it once. So,
we start with a false value for UID
printed
and then if it's false, then we print,
but then we set it to true, in which
case the message is not going to be
printed again because it's never going
to be false again once we have printed.
And then can buy and can sell becomes
false.
So, we're not allowed to sell or buy.
And then we don't want to start trading
on the very first bar when the
initialization happens, so we're going
to go through if the symbol array update
counter is less than two.
Remember, we were updating the counter,
the update counter plus plus. So,
starting from zero, it's going to get
updated, but it's happening on every new
bar. So, at least two bars
after the initialization before we can
start to trade. And this is why if it is
less than two, then can buy and can sell
becomes false. And then we're going to
check at the broker level by getting the
trade mode for this symbol and asking
for trade mode.
And trade mode is whether or not the
trading is allowed.
Now, if the trade mode comes back to be
disabled,
then we're going to say can buy and can
sell are both false.
If the trade mode comes back that long
only are allowed, then can sell becomes
false. And if short only is allowed on
the broker for this symbol, then can buy
is false.
After checking at the broker level, we
are going to check user level because
remember we had the possibility to
select
allow buy, allow sell or buy both or
allow both.
So, we're going to check if
the allow to buy sell is one, then only
buy is allowed, so can sell is false.
And if it is two, then only can sell is
allowed,
then can buy is false. If it is zero,
then both are allowed, so we don't need
to do anything. And then we're going to
get bar times after doing all of these
checks.
So, we'll start by creating a variable
date bar time and we're going to get the
current bar time from the symbol index
which we just updated
with the current bar.
And then we create a variable by the
name TM bar
and then we put this time which is in
the regular time format into this MQL
date time format TM bar, so that now we
can get the dot hour, dot minute, dot
day, dot month and dot year and assign
it to hour, minute, day, month and the
year for the bar.
And now we can check the trading hours
check, which is
we're going to first get the
bar minute and bar hour and multiply it
by 100. So, for example, 14:30
becomes
14:30 like this.
And then we can take the start hour
multiplied by 100, so
if the user has selected one, that
becomes 100.
And it's top trading
uh which becomes So, for example,
if the user has selected 23, then that
is going to become
because we take 23 multiplied by 100 and
then add 20 and 59. And if the user, for
example, had selected one, so one will
become
100. So, one
hour becomes 100.
So, now we can check.
We start with the time okay bool
variable creating it.
And then we check if the stop time is
greater than the start time, then it's a
normal day. So, because this is greater
than this, so the trading is starts
earlier and finishes later.
So, in that case, we're going to check
that if the current time
here is greater than or equal to the
start time
and the current time is smaller than or
equal to the end time.
So, in that case,
time is okay.
But if
this is not true, meaning the time is
start time is bigger than the stop time,
which means the user is starting at 1700
hours in the evening and finishing at
600 hours in the morning.
In that case, we need to check that the
start time that the current time is
bigger than the start time
or
the current time is smaller than
uh the stop time because we're starting
at 1700 and going until 6:00 in the
morning,
so we cannot check for the end, we check
for the or.
So, we get the time okay and then we do
a holiday check, which is to say if
the month is 12 and the day is greater
than 25
or the month is one, January, and the
day bar is equal to or less than three,
so it's
from 25th of December until the 23rd, in
that case time okay is false. So, even
though if it was okay here, it becomes
false. And then we do one more
validation check for the 15-minute
boundaries because our main time frame
is 15 minutes and time okay and the bar
minute is either zero or 20 or 15 or 30
or 45. That's just an additional check
that we have the correct bar minute
coming back from this current bar time.
And then we can integrate the can buy
and can sell by saying if can buy was
true and can time is true, then can buy
stays true. But if any if can buy was
true, but the time okay is false, then
also can buy becomes false. And same for
the can sell. So, we combine these two
together to see
whether or not both are true, in which
case can buy is true, otherwise
if either of them is false, then can buy
becomes false. We're not allowed to buy
or sell. Then we're going to update the
value of within that symbol array for
whatever is the current index, the
closing price and we
assign to it the I close for the current
symbol because that is the index symbol
for the main time frame last candle.
Okay, that done, now we can go ahead
with the indicators.
So, we're going to calculate the
indicators. We create two buffer
variables with size one because we're
only going to store one value in them.
Then we get from the moving average for
the current index symbol index. So,
whether three currencies, so it's the
zero currency or the one currency or the
or the second currency.
Get the moving average, the main line
zero
because it's moving average, so main
line is starting position one meaning
the previous candle
and only get one value.
And then the same for the standard
deviation as well and copy these values
into these buffers that we have created.
So, get from these and copy into these.
Once we have this populated and it's
only one value, so we can now take that
value and assign it to a variable by the
name Bollinger Band Moving Average and
then Bollinger Band and Standard
Deviation assigning this value here.
Zero index because there is only one
value.
And offers on the way to start with 0 1
2. So, if it's only one value, then it's
going to be at index zero.
And then we can calculate the Bollinger
Band upper, which is going to be the
moving average plus
two times the standard deviation.
That's the Bollinger Band upper
and minus two times the standard
deviation is going to be the Bollinger
Band lower.
If you understand the Bollinger Band,
you understand this logic as well. And
then we have the highest bar check.
Let's first get the count of the highest
bar. Where is it?
By getting the highest function sending
it the symbol mean time frame mode high
for the Bollinger Band period.
And the lowest bar. So, now the EA is
going to go back like 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8
and then for example, if this was the
high, it will go like 5 10 whatever 15
that Let's say this is bar number 19.
And this is the lowest, which is bar
number I don't know, 23.
So, it's going to return the value of 19
and 23 here. And then using that we can
get the value of the actual high in
price by using the iHigh function and
iLow function by sending to it the value
19 and 23
to get the recent high price value of
this candle
and this candle.
So, we get the recent high and recent
low and then we create a digits variable
where we store the value of the digits
for the current symbol.
And then we say we up date the value of
the Bollinger Band width
for the symbols, all three of them, one
after the other
by saying BB upper minus BB lower
and normalizing it to the level number
of digits for the symbol. So, we update
this value
for all three symbols.
So, these members are going to be
updated. And then we're going to use the
RSI filter to see whether or not we
should place the trade.
So, if RSI period is greater than zero
and RSI value is greater than zero, so
the user has input proper values, then
we create a buffer for RSI and then we
copy from RSI handle for the current
symbol index
only one value and put it into this
buffer.
And then take that value from the index
zero and assign it to an RSI
variable
so that we have the RSI value for the
last bar.
And then we say if can buy
whatever was the can buy, so if it was
true now you need to also check that the
RSI is less than
50 minus the RSI value because for our
buy, we want to have the value of the
RSI below
35 or below 40.
So, if the user has selected 15, then
it's 50 minus that 15 and for the sell
is the opposite, so it's 50 plus the RSI
value. Whatever the user has input
here, the RSI value. So, if he puts 20,
then it's 30 and 70. If it's If he puts
15, then it's 35 and 65 and that is what
we are checking here.
That for the can buy, RSI needs to be
lower than 35 and for the sell, it needs
to be higher than 65. And then we create
a variable by the name close and we
update the value of the close price from
the symbol index. Again, remember that
array and then that is structure, so we
get the value for the current array
member
but for the sub member close period
price that we updated up here.
We get the close price and then we're
going to do the at the close, I mean, if
the can buy is still true, then check
that if
close is below the recent low
and the recent low has a value.
And for get sell, the close is above the
recent high
and the recent high high has a value, so
it's not a an invalid recent high. So,
we check that again and update the can
buy and can sell. And then we're going
to do a maximum symbol check.
So, we're going to start with active
symbol as zero.
And then we're going to check
by looping through the symbol arrays,
all three symbols that we have in the
currencies
looping through all of them and we're
going to check whether or not a grid
exists. And if the grid exist, we need
to write this function. And if the grid
exist then we're going to
make the active symbol increase it by
one, so there is a grid on one symbol or
two symbol or three symbol.
And if the active symbols become more
than the maximum symbols that the user
has allowed, then in that case the can
buy and can sell becomes false as well.
Remember here we had this
maximum symbols.
So, how many symbols can have active
grid at one point in time?
We're going to write this function.
But for now
let's go down to grid related functions
and we're just going to stop it.
So, we're just going to say for now
just return false.
And what we're going to be sending to to
this grid is the symbol
the level and the direction because what
we might want to check
So, you can you can use this
uh function in different ways.
So, you can send it
for
buy direction, does a grid exist
for buy
does a sell grid exist
or does any grid exist? So, this is what
we're going to control from here.
And then we can say level, so
we can also check has this grid now
gotten to level two or has this grid now
gotten to level three?
So, we can differentiate.
And the third one is of course symbol.
So, for which symbol are we checking?
So, these are the three values we're
going to send to this grid exist.
What we are checking here is send the
symbol
of whatever is the current symbol in
this iteration
by sending the name, but then zero and
zero meaning we don't care about levels
and we don't care
about the direction, the buy and sell.
So, if it's buy or sell, we don't care.
If it's level if if the grid has opened
up to level two or three or four or
five, don't care.
As long as the grid exist
we say that the active symbol goes up by
one. And then based on the ATR values,
we're going to apply a smart distance,
which is basically
we're going to get the ATR buffer.
Again, from the ATR handles, we're going
to copy the values into ATR buffer 96
and ATR 672, so we can assign it to the
variables ATR 96 and ATR 672.
And then if it is a valid value, so ATR
672 is greater than epsilon
if it is a valid value
then we're going to update the symbols
smart distance multiplier
with ATR 96 divide by ATR 672.
Which means that if the current
volatility is bigger than the longer
term volatility
then in that case the value of this is
going to turn out to be more than one
and we store that into smart distance
multiplier so that even though the
user has said the distance of the grid
is to be 35 but if he selects a smart
distance then that 35 is now going to be
multiplied by this volatility factor as
well.
Now, this is a question mark. I mean,
you might want to write it, you might
not want to write it, which is the
clamping of that multiplier between one
and 1.5. So, if this turns out to be a
less than one value meaning it's more
volatile in 672 than in
in that case we don't really want to do
a smaller multiplier. We don't want to
reduce the grid size from 35 downwards.
So, we
clamp it to one
by saying choose between whichever is
the higher, one
or the multiplier, which is here
which we have stored here.
So, if the if the multiplier turns out
to be 0.9 for example, then which one is
bigger, one or 0.9? One is bigger. So,
use one.
But if this is bigger than one, if it is
1.3, then use 1.3. So, using math max
we have clamped the lower value down to
one.
And then this is
the value which is going to come here.
So, for example, it might come back to
For example, if this was 1.8
then the math max is going to be 1.8.
And then we use math min to say choose
between 1.5 and if this turns out to be
higher, 1.8, then it's math minimum, so
take 1.5. In this way we are clamping
the value of this smart distance
multiplier between one and 1.5. So, it
never becomes like 2.3. Because we don't
want to increase the distance of the
grid to like ridiculous levels.
So, here we had calculated it.
And here we're clamping it by updating
the value of the smart distance
multiplier by of whatever turns out to
be.
If it is between
1 and 1.5, then the smart distance
multiplier will become or will it stay
that value. But if it is bigger than
1.5,
then it's going to become 1.5. And if it
turns out to be less than 1.5, then it's
going to become 1. So, we're clamping.
And then we're going to do a day
tracking,
which is we're going to get the day of
the week from the TM bar variable that
we had created before.
The TM bar.
So, we get the day of the week.
And then if
day of the week is not equal to the last
day of the week,
so we check again.
And the symbol there is not zero, so
it's not a first update.
Then in that case, we
change the trading day allowed today to
whatever was the previous day. So, if it
was allowed to trade yesterday, we allow
it to to
to today, so we roll it over.
And then we change the previous day to
true as well. So, we're basically
rolling over
uh
the period allowed
from one day to another day. So, if it
is can So, later on if can buy was true
on one day, then it is can true on the
next day as well.
And then can buy becomes whatever is
whatever in the end comes out to be
trading day allowed today versus this.
So, if it is allowed today and can buy
is also true from all the previous
conditions, then it remains true. If it
wasn't allowed today, then can buy even
though all the previous conditions were
true,
but because of the drawdown, for
example, if this becomes false,
then this becomes false as well.
Then we do a margin level check. That if
the minimum free margin that the user
has set is greater than epsilon, so
there is a value
that the user has selected here
is minimum free margin
is greater than epsilon. And remember
the epsilon value is 0.000, so it's
greater than that, so it is a valid
value.
And the account margin level is less
than whatever the user has put.
So, the margin level has dropped below.
So, in that [clears throat] case, we
will also set the can buy and can sell
to false.
But before that, we print this message
once every 60 minutes or
I don't know, 180 seconds.
So, we say this is zero.
First time because it's a static
variable, so the first time when we're
creating it is zero.
Then if the current time minus this is
greater than 1800 seconds, then print
this.
And then set this
to time current. So, the next time when
we come back, unless the time current
has now become again greater by 1800,
we don't print it again.
And then we're going to check for the
maximum drawdowns, and we're going to
create that function.
But let's suppose if the drawdown is
triggered,
then we say if drawdown is triggered
or the stop trading until restart has
triggered
or cool down hours is greater than zero,
then we're going to print a message and
we're going to loop through the reason.
So, if the if the drawdown is triggered,
then the reason is drawdown triggered.
If this is true,
then the reason is drawdown restart
required. And if this is true, then
drawdown cool down period these many
number of hours.
And then we print this that the trading
is blocked and the reason is
whatever one of these three.
And then again, we set this in a way
like before so that this message is only
printed every 60 minutes.
And then the can buy and can sell
becomes false.
So, this is the drawdown check.
And we're actually going to create this
separately. But for now, let's go down
to drawdowns
greater trades and drawdowns section,
and I'm going to just a stub it for now.
So, for now
I don't know, return false.
Well, in fact, it's a void, so it
doesn't have to return anything. So, I'm
just going to stub it for now.
We come back and we are going to look at
the last process hour. If the last
process hour is less than the current
hour,
then the cool down hours, which once it
has been triggered, we drop it down by
one.
And then if the cool down hour become
less than zero,
because once it gets to zero on the next
turn by saying minus one, it's going to
become minus one. In that case, we reset
it back to zero.
And then if the drawdown was triggered,
but now
when we're looping through the array
size and getting the total lots
in the grid,
and that turns out to be zero, so less
than epsilon,
then in that case, drawdown trigger
becomes false again. So, this is just
resetting that, and we're going to write
this function.
There Well, well, but what we're
basically doing here is that if the
drawdown was triggered during the check
of the max drawdown,
then we are rechecking or because in the
next one in the next one in the next
loop,
we're going to get the total lots
on the current by looping through all
the currencies,
the total lots in grids. And then if the
total lots come back as a smaller than
epsilon, so it's zero,
then in that case, well, there is no
position, so there is no drawdown.
And this can happen because we close all
the position or something like this. And
because we will be calling this
function, so let's go down to the grid
related function, and for now I'm just
going to stub it. We can get the total
lots in a grid for only buy, for only
sell, or both,
for levels above two or above three, or
all the levels.
And use original lot size that we're
going to come back to when
when I'm going to explain to you
this setting of grid level to start.
Cuz I don't know if you remember grid
level to start meaning like we put dummy
trades 0.01 minimum loss until a certain
level, and then we go proper lotting.
So, do we use original, and that this is
related to that one.
But you will understand this as we go
down through the the functions
and write this function. But let's come
back here to
where we were.
And now we can actually update the
symbol array for this currency.
The sub member can buy to whatever now
is the value of the coin can buy after
all of these checks. If it is still
true, then it's true, otherwise false.
And for the can sell, and then we set
the value of the grid open for the
currency
as false.
We update the tick counter.
We These are the global variables
which we created here.
Last update minute, last time we
checked, and those kind of things.
So, we update it by one.
And the last process hour becomes
current hour.
And then we send the initial order.
And we're sending the initial order, not
the grid levels, the initial order
by sending the symbol index.
Because if can buy is true
and can sell is true,
then we send the initial order.
If I compile now,
I have this send initial order. Okay,
let's remove this line for now.
And if I compile, everything is fine.
And because now we're calling this
function, which we're going to write
next,
uh this is why we got this error. So,
everything is fine for now.
We compile.
And now we're going to go ahead and try
and send the initial order. So, let's
create it.
And it's a void, so it's not going to
return any value.
And then what we're going to be sending
to it is just a symbol index. So, that's
the only thing we send to it. Now, from
that symbol index, we can get the name
of the symbol by using symbol array
symbol index dot, so the member sub
members,
and assign it to symbol.
And then we're going to do a very quick
check if trading is allowed. That is the
function we wrote here.
And then we're going to also check this
condition, which is can buy is false.
Because we're checking for not
and can sell is also false, which
basically means that you cannot buy, you
cannot sell, so what the are we
doing here? So, we just return, we exit
the function.
And if not trading allowed, then also
return because if trading is not
allowed, then
what's the point of continuing forward?
But if trading is allowed and either can
buy is true or can sell is true or both
are true,
then we're going to check
the
total number of active symbols,
which we also did here. I know
just like before coming here, we did
this.
But by the time we come here, it might
also be that you have another symbol
which opens up the trade.
And in that case, the maximum the active
number of active symbols might change.
So, we do a check quick check here as
well. Then we do a check for the
spreads. So, let's get the spread as
symbol is spread.
And then if if the spread is greater
than the maximum spread that the user
has provided, but the user has provided
the spread in pips,
while the spreads here are in points.
So, we need to get a multiplier for the
symbol so that we can convert it into
we can convert both into the same apple
to apple comparison.
And then if the maximum spread is
bigger than epsilon, so the user has
provided a value, then if the spread is
bigger
current spreads, then we basically
spreads are too high, so we're not going
to open up a trade.
And we're going to write this function.
So let's go down to the bottom where we
have the helper functions and here
let's just write get pip multiplier and
it's a very simple one. You get the
digits
from the broker and if the digit is five
or three, then return 10.
Because five basically means let's say
US Euro USD, GBP USD, they have five
decimals.
And the last decimal is a point and the
pip value is actually 10.
10 points. So this is why we're
returning 10 in case of five and three.
And three because of the JPY pairs. So
you have USD JPY, GBP JPY and they have
three digits.
But in all other cases, return one
because on all other in all other cases,
your pip and your points are exactly the
same.
So that's our pip multiplier. So we
check the spread.
So we try to open the buy order.
We check the symbol array can buy. So
whatever is the symbol array symbol
index can buy.
Meaning on the current currency, if the
can buy is true, so we can buy, so all
of the conditions that we wrote are are
basically all of them are met. Then
we're going to check very quickly allow
hedging and we're going to create a bool
variable, so true or false and we're
going to check for allow hedging. If the
user has selected allow hedging as true,
which means you can trade both buy and
sell direction at the same time.
Then if it is true, then we're going to
check if the grid exist by sending the
value of one, which is the value of the
buy. We're going to write this function,
but what we're going to write in this
function is three things. Symbol, level
and direction, so we can specify what
we're checking.
So we're checking for buys then. And
minus one basically here for the level
means we don't care. We don't care about
levels. But we do care about buy, so if
hedging is allowed, then we check if
there is already a buy grid existing and
if
hedging is not allowed, then we check if
there is any grid at all for the hash
position that if hedging is allowed,
then check that the grid doesn't exist
for buys because we're saying not grid
exist.
And if the grid doesn't exist for buy,
that means hash position is true.
And if hedging is not allowed, then we
are going to look for anything at all.
Then in that case, we check if no grid
is available because we're saying not
grid exist. So if no grid exist at all,
either buy or sell, then hash position
becomes true.
And if hash position becomes hash
position comes out to be true, then we
send the order by using the function
open market order, which we will write,
sending it again the symbol index so
that it knows which symbol and then
telling it that we're going to open the
buy order. And then we say try to open
the sell order, which is the reverse
logic, so hash position if allow
hedging, but now we're going to check
for sell grids.
And all of the grids.
So if hedging is allowed, then we check
that the sell doesn't exist. If the sell
doesn't exist, then hash position is
true.
And if hedging is not allowed, then any
grid at all,
if it exist, then it's false.
And if it doesn't exist, then it's true.
And then we're going to open the market
order by sending it the order type sell.
And now we're going to go to open the
market order. So what we are sending to
the open market order is symbol index
and order type
as enum order type. And then once again,
we convert the index into the name of
the symbol.
And then we start with the max attempt
of 10. So this is for every order, we're
only going to try it 10 times and if it
fails after 10 times, we give up. And
then what we're going to do is we're
going to start at attempt zero going all
the way to as long as attempt is less
than max attempts and attempt plus plus.
So 10 times we're going to do this loop.
We're going to start by saying well, the
lot size is going to be calculate lot
size. And then if lot size from here
turns out to be less than epsilon, so
it's less than 0.0001, so then it's too
small, so we print this.
And then we're going to check for
margins.
So we're going to start by saying double
margin, creating a variable, assigning
it the value zero.
And then we're going to check a few
things.
The first one is run the order calculate
margin, sending the order type, which we
know from here,
the symbol, the lot size, which we're
going to calculate here.
And then we're going to say if it's
order buy, order type buy, then use ask,
otherwise use bid.
And copy paste the value into this
margin
variable.
Now if this function fails, and this is
what we're saying, if not, if this
function fails
or if the margin that we stored here
comes out to be less than or equal to
zero,
or if the margin that comes out here is
bigger than what is available as free
margin, then in that case, we say not
enough money.
And then if the order type was order
type buy, then we change the can buy to
false and can sell to false, otherwise
for the symbol index
that we have currently sent here.
So for that currency, we change the can
buy and can sell to false because
there's not enough money.
By the way, we are here calling this
function, so let's go down and for now,
we're just going to stub it
to return 0.01.
Coming back,
we're going to calculate the unique
magic number for that particular trade.
And this is what we are going to do here
is we're going to start with the base
magic number,
which is 84570 in our case, which is
hardcoded in the EA. We don't ask the
user to provide it. 84570.
And then let's suppose the user has
selected the UID as zero.
So it's the very first instance that
he's running.
So this is going to become
plus zero,
so it will remain as 84570.
Then what we're going to do is we're
going to get the number of digits in
this magic base.
So 1 2 3 4 5, so it has five digits. And
then we're going to say if the order
type is buy, then one, otherwise two. So
let's say in case of buy, it's going to
be one. In case of sell,
it's going to be two.
And then we create the magic number by
saying take
10 raised to the power digits plus two,
so 10 raised to the power
seven.
Five digits plus two, so raised to the
power seven, which is going to be equal
to 10 million.
Well, without the commas, so 10 million.
Then
multiply it with the direction. So for
buy, it's going to be one.
And then add to it the magic number
84570,
but multiplied by 100.
So it's actually going to be 8457000.
So for the sell for the buy, it's going
to turn out to be 184570
and then 00.
And this is where this is the magic
number for the EA.
This one is the direction.
And this 00 is the grid. So this is the
00 level, so base level, then level one,
level two, level three, level four,
level five.
And in the same breath, for the sell
order, because for the sell order, the
direction equals two, so when we
multiply it by two, it will become this
value is going to be multiplied by two
instead of one.
So in that case,
the value which is going to come out to
be is 2457000.
So our buy is going to be one
and our sell is going to be two.
So this is going to be the unique ID for
that trade, which has the magic number,
which has the direction and which has
the level.
So this is how we will create the magic
numbers.
And this is how we will read them as
well. And here we are doing the base
trade and not opening up a grid yet. And
then let's prepare a comment. So we say
comment equals to trade comment and then
we print that we are sending a buy or
the sell order and attempt number,
whatever is the attempt number.
Plus one because the loop is starts at
zero. And then we're going to set the
trade expert magic number to the magic
number that we have just created.
And set the standard deviation to
whatever is the max slippage, get the
multiplier, so get the max slippage that
the user has provided and use our get
pip multiplier at the bottom
to do the multiplication, get it at the
right pip value for that symbol. And
then we actually send the trade. So we
create a success variable bool.
And then we send if the order type,
check if the order type is buy. If it is
buy, then trade.buy, send the lot size,
symbol, no TP, no SL and comment.
And if the trade is sell, then
trade.sell, lot size, symbol, well, no
price, no stop loss
and no TP.
Current price, no stop loss, no TP and
the comment. And then we're going to
check if success, meaning like if the
order went through,
then in that case, we print the comment
that this order has opened. And in that
case, we update the status
that if the order type was buy,
then the for the current in symbol
index, can buy becomes false because we
have already bought.
And the last grid time becomes current
time so that we are updating when was
the last trade taken.
Otherwise,
can sell. So this was for order type
buy, so this is for order type sell. So,
we change the can sell to false because
we have already sold, and we update the
last sell grid time to time current,
meaning this is when the last trade in
the grid for this symbol was taken. And
then we change the grid open value to
true because now there is a grid open,
and O P O trigger is also true. And O P
O trigger is open price only, and this
we're going to use in the closing when
when we when we're going to look at the
closing.
So, here we close this function of if.
If it's successful, then do this.
But if the trade was not successful, so
if it was successful, do this, but if it
was not successful, then we print that
failed to open this,
get the description and the result code.
But remember we were going to do this 10
times,
this entire thing we're going to do 10
attempts.
But in case if it's a fatal error,
meaning if the red code is invalid,
or invalid volume, or no money, or
market closed, or trade disabled, if one
of these come back from the broker, then
there is no point in doing a retry.
So, in that case we just set the can buy
to false and can sell to false, and
return, meaning exit the function. And
then just sleep for 5,000 seconds.
And here we close this else because this
So, if it failed,
sleep for 5,000 before attempting again,
and then we close this entire for loop
as well.
And then we close the function.
Okay, if we compile,
I don't have any errors.
Now, there are some stub functions.
So, we're going to get a 0.01 calculate
lot size, so things like those.
But at least now we have a working EA.
Let's go back
to the top initialization function, and
here we're going to remove or we're
going to comment out the tester.
So, don't hide the Don't hide the
indicators.
And then if I run,
now we're going to see the indicators as
well.
So, when we get our first trade,
here
we get our first trade, and we can see
the value of the RSI has gone up to 65,
I think.
Uh let's run it a little bit more.
Yeah.
So, here the value of RSI went above 65,
and this is why the first trade was
opened here. Now, we still haven't built
the grid logic, so it's just going to
continue to open trades after trades
after trades
on every new candle,
every time the RSI is greater than 70.
But at least this is working.
So, we have a working EA now
on the lot size 0.01.
And now we can start to work on the
volume or lot sizes, and then we're
going to work on the grading system.
This is all the rationale of opening the
trades, and now we come down to lot
sizing functions.
>> [music]
[music]