with a 90% win rate and a very tight
stop loss this is an amazing scalping
robot in the first two videos we did the
coding for Forex pairs USD JPY Euro USD
and gpp USD today we're going to look at
the modifications required to run this
EA on bitcoin gold and US indices namely
NASDAQ and DOW johs so with no motion
any guns let's
start before we get to the coding of the
modifications let's run a quick back
test to have a bit of an indication of
what the EA is all about so I'm going to
start with PTC USD on a 5 minutes chart
is starting from 2023 until 2024 today
I'm going to run it on every take with
,000 Euro balance to start with now I
know there is a lot of discussion
between real take and every take and
which one is better these are just two
data sets provided by your broker I
don't believe in either the only real
test is actually forward testing where
you apply the EA in a demo account and
see over the next 2 three months how the
EA performs you will like some things
you will not like some things you will
like some periods you will not like some
periods and that will give you a bit of
feeling of when to apply the year and
when not to apply it more importantly
when to turn it off so those are the
kind of things you will only learn
during real testing not in a back test
anyways we're going to run it on every
tick and let's look at the inputs we're
running it on bitcoin profile we're
running it on 5 minutes chart starting
at 7:00 in the
morning and until 2100 hours in the
evening these are the Bitcoin related
crypto related inputs that I'm providing
and we're going to go through this a
little bit more in details so let's run
the test now the first thing you're
going to notice is that there are no
running draw downs and that is because
of a very TI of stop loss that we put in
place the second thing to note is that
there are periods where there are
consecutive losses there are periods
when the EA is stagnant so for example
between here and here but overall if you
let the EA run for a longer period of
time it does have more good perod than
bad period now this EA performs very
well when the market is trending it's
going in One Direction by the up or down
when the market is choppy and it's going
sideways with no clear Direction up or
down that's when the year struggles a
little bit if you look at the back test
results we started with a balance of
€1,000 we're ending up with €
433,000 we have 90% win rate on short
trades we have 90% win rate on Long
trades we have a relative draw down of
10% Now is it going to be the same in
the real world don't know I mean I only
know through the back test that there
are indications that this year can
perform if you look at the hourly where
you will see is that during the overlap
of New York session and the London
session is when the EA makes most of the
money but it is quite profitable during
the London session alone as as well you
can try it during the Asian session as
well but I have not had good experience
with the Asian session because of the
liquidity crash during that
time now let's look at
gold again 5 minutes chart is starting
2023 until 2024 on input stab we're
going to select the profile
gold and thereby we're applying these
inputs and not the Bitcoin inputs let's
start once again you see that there are
no running draw Downs there are periods
of stagnation there are periods of
consecutive losses and draw down as well
here for example between June and
September it is completely stagnant but
if you let it be the overall performance
of the EA is up and up if you look at
the back test results what you will see
is we started with a balance of ,000
we're ending with a balance of €
24,000 10% draw down 93% win on short
trades and 92% win on Long trades again
on the timing you will see that during
the overlap between London session and
New York session is when the year
perform better it makes more more profit
during that period but it is quite
decent during the London session as well
now let's look at
NASDAQ and I will just run NASDAQ but
you can also apply it on us30 as well
Dow
Jones on the input tab we're going to go
up and we're going to select us indices
as the profile and now these inputs are
going to be used and not the Bitcoin
ones or the gold ones let's start the
test once again no relative draw Downs
because of the tighest stop losses
periods of stagnation periods of
consecutive losses but overall the
performance of the EA is up and up
during the trending periods the e is
going to perform very very well during
sideways Market chaotic markets sudden
volatile markets where it goes up and
down very very quickly the EA will
startle if you look at the back test
results we started with a balance of
,000 we're ending up with around
24,000 almost 9% relative draw down 92%
win on short trades and 91% win on Long
trades as well timing wise on NASDAQ as
you would imagine it's Norm during the
US session when the year is going to
perform better because it is a US index
but it does do okay during the London
session as well but do your testing see
it in a demo account whether you like
the New York session alone do you like
the overlap of the London and New York
session better or do you like to run it
overall between New York session and
London session up to
you now that we've seen the back test
results we can start with the coding of
the modifications So today we're going
to start looking at the modifications re
wired in order to run it on bitcoin gold
and US indicis starting from the
previous video the first thing we're
going to do is we're going to arrange
our variables into groups so what I've
done from the last video is that I've
created two of these sections and I have
put the variables which are common like
Risk percentage time frame magic number
start Hour end hour total number of bars
expiration bar because this is going to
be common variables across all of the
profiles so I've grouped them together
here and then all of the Forex Trading
input related like the TP Point SL Point
trigger point and the TSL points that I
have put against another section now
after this we're going to get to the top
and what we're going to do is we're
going to create one more section and
we're going to call it trading profiles
and we'll start with an enum because
we're going to create a dropdown menu
for our users to select from so I'm
creating an enum I'm calling it system
type that's the variable type which will
be assigned later on to a variable and
I'm giving four inputs in within that
Forex Bitcoin gold and US indices and
I'm giving them 0 1 2 and three as
respective
identifiers now for gold because mql
already has somewhere in their coding
gold used so we cannot give it the name
gold as a profile so I'm giving it
underscore gold you can give it gold
underscore just gold is going to give
you an error the next thing we're going
to do is we're going to create a
variable and we're going to call that
variable
system type we're asking the user to
provide the input and this is why we're
going to start with input system type by
assigning this variable type so that
these drop downs are available we're
going to create the variable ass system
type and the default value that we are
assigning to it is zero which is Forex
and after two slashes we give it a
description trading system applied Forex
crypto gold or indices and then I'm
creating another integer variable system
choice where I will store the value
whatever the user selects then we come
back up here and and I'm going to create
another section and I'm calling it
crypto related input which are effective
only on the Bitcoin profile and there
like the Forex we're going to store
these values but for Bitcoin we're going
to have the values stored as percentages
of the price now one thing which is
different from Forex into Bitcoin gold
and US indices is that the prices can
fluctuate a lot so Bitcoin can be 10,000
one day 15,000 and another month 60,000
70,000 the prices keep changing a lot so
we cannot assign a static stop loss we
need to have it as a percentage of
whatever is the price in the market and
so we are asking the user to provide an
input of pp as a percentage of the price
SL as a percentage of the price and then
we're going to use that TP and assign
the trigger of the stop loss and the
stop- loss itself or the trailing stop-
loss itself as a percentage of that PP
so as an example if the price is 60,000
and we say
1% of the price is our TP then 600
points is going to be our TP 600 price
up from the price and 600 points below
from the price will be our stop loss and
then out of the 600 if we said 10% is
our trailing stop loss then 60 points
are going to be our training stop loss
we're going to do exactly the same for
gold and for indices as well now the
reason I'm creating these different
profiles you can keep it under one
because the logic is exactly the same so
you can keep it under one but I'm
creating it separately because I like to
keep a track of what the percentages are
and if I want to change and once I have
found something which works on gold or
which works on indices or which works on
crypto I don't want to have to remember
it and change it every time that I apply
it so I'm creating three different
profiles so now that we have the
profiles then we can go ahead and we can
assign the vales in the initialization
and I say here that if the S type is
zero which is
here if the user has selected S type as
zero which is Forex then this variable
system choice is going to be zero if
user has selected one which is Bitcoin
then system choice is one if user has
selected S type as two then system choic
is two and if they have selected S type
as three which is indices then the
system choices three which is indexes
now one of the difficulties we're going
to face is that here we have all of
these points we're collecting the input
from the user and if you're collecting
an input from the user then you cannot
change the value of that variable during
the operations so we need to create four
more variables and I'm coming back up
here into the common trading input and
I'm putting here these variables as
double and I'm calling them the TP point
the SL point the TSL trigger point and
the TSL point now if you would remember
from the Forex video and if you have
coded along using that video is that
these are the variables that we use in
the EA itself to send orders to modify
positions and do all sorts of operations
so I'm creating them separately and
these will have zero values at the start
of the E now if you would remember from
the Forex coding video these these
variables were called TP points SL Point
TSL trigger point and TSL point but I've
added the word input at the end of all
of them so that when once we collect the
value on the Forex from the user these
are input variables but these are not
assigned yet to these variables and
these are the variable that we're going
to use in the year so while we collect
the input we keep it into the user
provided input variables and not assign
it to anything at this point in time
same goes for crypto same goes for gold
same goes for indices all of these are
collected from the users but these are
not assigned anywhere so now on
initialization what we're going to do is
we're going to start assigning now for
the default what I'm going to do is I
will assign to these variables the
values that I have collected from the
user under the Forex profile so these
variables are not empty they have by
default the Forex values into it then we
go to the ontick function so this is our
new bar section everything written
underneath is going to be run on opening
of every new candle and every code above
this is going to be triggered on every
tick because the system is going to come
here on every tick it will do whatever
is here then it's going to check whether
it's a new bar and if it's not a new bar
it's going to exit so nothing is going
to be run only on a new bar everything
below this code line this code line is
going to be run so when we come down
here once we have assigned the trading
hours then what we can do is we can just
simply go that if the system choice is
one which is our Bitcoin profile then
let's get the ask value
by using the function symbol in for
double sending the value of the current
chart symbol and asking for the ask
price and then we'll use that ask price
as the market price and then we can go
then the DP point is going to be ask
price multipli by whatever TP as
percentage the user has
defined here for
Bitcoin then for the stop- loss we're
going to use again the market price in
terms of ask variable that we have
stored the ask value in and then we're
going to multiply it by whatever is the
stop loss defined as percentage under
the crypto here is the variable so
assign that value and so on and so forth
we assigned the order distance point now
for the order distance point the logic
in the Forex was if the SL points were
200 points 20 Pips then we were putting
the order distant Point as 100 which is
10 Pips which is half and I'm using the
same logic here here by saying that
whatever is the TP now or whatever is
the SL now put the order distance Point
as divided by two then for the TSL Point
what we're going to do is we have the TP
points now so we're going to multiply it
by the TSL as a percentage of TP we're
using this so if the user has said that
5% of the TP is going to be my trailing
stoploss and 7% of my TP is going to be
my trigger of the the stop loss then we
come down here
and we say multiply that as a percentage
so first converting into a percent and
then multiplying it by the TP point so
the TP points were I don't know 600 and
TSL as a percentage of TP is 10 then
it's basically 60
points then we go to the next line and
we repeat the same process for Gold by
saying if system Choice equals two and
if you put two equal signs that's a
condition check so if system Choice
equals 2 then get the ask price then
multiply the T or get the TP points by
multiplying the ask price which is the
market price by whatever is the TP as a
percentage gold so use this variable
instead and then the same for SL then
the same for trigger point following
exactly the same logic we go then the SL
Point equals this variable multiply by
price and then the TSL points and the
TSL trigger points are going to be
whatever is the TP points multiply it by
whatever is the trigger of the stop loss
as a percentage of pp
gold then if the choice is indicis then
exactly the same process get the ask
value by sending the symbol value and
asking for ask and this time around we
multiply the ask value with the TP as a
percentage or stop- loss as a
percentage but this time indicis section
now these are the values that I have
used in the back test that I've shown
you but by creating these separate
profile files that gets you the
flexibility of creating different
scenarios optimizing differently and
remembering and putting that value and
hardcoding it so that you don't have to
remember it all the time so this is it
Guys these are all the modifications
that you're going to use to convert the
Forex EA that we created in the previous
video to apply it on bitcoin gold and US
indices now this is not limited to this
because once you follow the logic that
now we're using TPS stoploss trigger
points and stop L coins as a percentage
of the price now you can check this on
other things as well like don't know oil
whatever else you trade you can try this
percentage method and see what values
work and what values do not
work before I go just a few very
important points number one no EA makes
money every day every week every month
there will be times when the will make
money and then there will be times when
the will not make money or even lose
money we just hope that the periods in
which the year makes money far outweigh
and are more frequent than the times
when the year loses money or is stagnant
the second point is this this year at
least in my experience works better when
the market is trending either up or down
when the market is chaotic volatile or
is stagnant that's when the year
struggles the third point is because
it's a scalping robot the volume of the
trade is going to be massive so you
require really tight spreads so if your
broker does not have very tight spreads
offered
then I would suggest you to try it on
different Brokers and see which ones it
works on which ones it doesn't work on
Fourth important point is that your
broker needs to allow es scalloping and
by that I mean setting the trailing a
stop loss extremely close to the price I
know some Brokers do not allow setting
the stop loss very close to the price
and if that is the case then the trailer
stop loss is not going to work and if
the trail stop loss is not going to work
then this strategy is not going to work
because this strategy completely banks
on the idea that as the price moves in
our favorable Direction then we start to
Trail the stop loss extremely
aggressively so since the entire year is
based on that there is no getting around
it so when you run the test and you get
60% or 50% win rate the first thing to
check is whether or not your trailing a
stop loss is working and if it's not
working well after checking the codes
that the codes are correct what you need
to check is that your broker actually
allows the trailing stop loss to be
Trail very very aggressively now further
points again I will keep talking about
them in the frequently ask questions run
it on every take run it on real take see
what you like see you don't what you
don't like the real test is forward
testing because that's the only time
when you're actually applying the EA
into the real market conditions and
that's the only way to know whether or
not you like it and even if you like it
which parts of it you like and which
parts of it you want to twe so back
testing is good but back testing is not
real
testing now in the next video I will
come back with a few filters which we're
going to apply on this year to tighten
the trading even further so for example
if the price is too far away from the
moving average we don't want to trade if
the RSI is above 75 below 25 we don't
want to trade if there is a major news
event upcoming then we not only want to
not trade but we also want to turn off
the EA and we want to delete any order
which is sitting so those kind of
filters I will come back in the next
video leave me a comment if there's
something that I didn't explain well or
if there are any questions frequently
asked questions I will continue to put
them together into a frequently Asked
question segment and we will continue to
come back with more and more stuff uh so
stay tuned and until next time guys stay
safe fade safe
[Music]