over the years I've developed 14
different years that I use in my own
portfolio in the summer of last year I
started sharing them one by one with
full explanations of the code on YouTube
the scalping year that I shared as the
first year I thought it was a very
simple year to understand and the inputs
and the rules are very simple to follow
and set but I've learned from all the
comments in the YouTube section that it
wasn't that obvious what surprised me is
when people started to share with me
their results following the settings
that I use and those results were
extremely different I realized answering
some of the questions that there are
some fundamental settings that are
probably not clear and that is what's
driving the differences in result so
today we're going to look at the most
important settings of the EA and if you
change them up or down how does that
change the behavior of the EA we will
also look at the fundamental
requirements of this EA and lastly I
will speak about the use of this
scalloping robot on Prop forms and what
can we do to make it more suitable to
prop form challenges so with no motion
enam let's
[Music]
start let's start with the results so I
created this account on the 18th of
December last year specifically because
when people are sharing their results
with me then at least I have something
to compare with so if we look around we
do have a few losses where the initial
stop- loss was hit most of the time the
EA starts trailing the stop loss very
aggressively once we are in the
profitable territory so therefore you
see that all those trades are closed
upon hitting the stop loss but in profit
and occasionally the year also hits a TP
here or there when the market Moves In
One Direction quite quickly especially
on bitcoin that happens a lot more
overall the EM made about 30 18% profit
in 1 month on a € 5,000 deposit now if
you look symol by symbol Bitcoin made
around 7% €350 in total on bitcoin you
will also have a few times the TP is hit
despite aggressive trailing of the stop-
loss as Bitcoin when it goes fast it
really goes fast in One Direction then
on Euro USD we have about 3% return €150
which is break even in my Bulls because
if the next trade goes into lws that's
going to hit 3% negative so it's going
to come back to zero gold made around 2
and 1.2% in profit a bit below the break
even as one stop loss hit of 3% will
wipe that out but it is so far without
any loss gbpusd took two losses so
around 1 and a half% in negative NASDAQ
also a very similar story one loss trade
of 3% almost covered by five profit
trades now banking on the 90% win rate
it is heading in the right direction and
lastly the usdjpy which is also around
3% in profit so far no losing trade so
in my book it is at break even because
if the next trade goes to hit the stop-
loss all of this profit is going to be
wiped out so non Forex payers are sort
of doing okay carrying their own weight
Bitcoin doing quite well because it has
recently been a very strong trend on
another account that I set up only for
Bitcoin gold and NASDAQ as a trial now
here one of the key settings which is
different than the other account is how
many number of bars are used to
determine the highs and lows so on the
previous account that we saw it was 100
bars n and here we're using only five
and overall we have 15% return return
return in the month which is quite
similar but the number of Trades taken
are very different and the behavior of
the EA is also very different which goes
to show how one setting change can
completely change the behavior of the E
now on gold we have 7% return on bitcoin
around 11% and NASDAQ is doing poorly
here as well with ative -2% return so
these settings have made similar
percentage returns even though no Forex
pair was applied and the trading
patterns and the style are also very
different between the two years with
just one setting change okay these are
only one month of results so take them
with a grain of salt but the main thing
is that one setting can change the
behavior of the E quite dramatically and
therefore I want to go over the most
important settings within this EA and
explain what to expect if you change one
of those settings up or down and you
will need to change those settings from
time to time because the market keeps
changing so with the €5,000 account I
have set it up on Euro USD gbpusd usdjpy
NASDAQ gold and Bitcoin for the settings
I'm using the same settings that I've
shared in the videos so 200 2 20 and 10
for the Forex paays and 0.4 0.45 and 10
for the non Forex pair which corresponds
to the Forex settings in terms of price
now I'm using the news filter and I'm
avoiding NFP JS non-farm and interest
rate but only for the USD currency
because that is what moves the market
suddenly and is prone to slip pages and
I normally do not like to trade in those
kind of conditions I'm using the RSI
filter on 4our chart with 20 and 80 so
when the price is an extreme on 4our
chart I don't want to be trading I'm
currently not using the moving average
filter but depending on how markets turn
out to be in the future I might be using
it in the coming months now one big
setting that I've changed here from
default is the number of bars to
identify the highs and lows and I moved
it to 100 from five that I shared in the
videos now let's go through what every
setting does and what impact it will
have on the behavior of the EA if you
change those
settings most of the settings are
self-explanatory for example time frames
lot sizes trading hours and those kind
of things but there are two settings
which are most likely causing a little
bit of confusion the first one is the
number of bars to Define highs and lows
if you remember from the very first
video in the series we said that if
there are five candles on the right and
the five candles on the left all below
the middle candle that's a valid High
and the reverse is true for the low but
what if you were to set that setting to
50 or 100 then there will need to be a
100 candles to the left and 100 candles
to the right all below the middle candle
for it to be a valid high so what
difference does it make with five bars
on the left and five bars on the right
that's going to happen quite a lot so
every time the market breaks a previous
high and goes up and then comes back
down you will have a new high to trade
but with a 100 candle now the EA not
only has to find the 100 candles to the
left but also 100 candles to the right
and that's quite rare and therefore the
highs and lows established are going to
be on more established prices so when
the markets have a very strong Trend I
tend to move the bars end value lower
because I want to trade every new high
that's forming in the market Market but
if the markets are less Dynamic I do not
want to trade every single small low
that's forming because if the market is
zigzagging it's going to come back and
hit my stop loss so for example between
December and January I know normally the
markets have lower liquidity and
therefore I crank the value up all the
way to 100 because I didn't want to
trade every single high and low only the
most established ones now if a pair will
start showing me strong Trend again or
if there is a news or interest rate
decision or something that changes the
market on the fundamental level then I
might the value down back again to maybe
50 25 20 or 5 even but that will all
depend on how strong the markets are
trending I hope that this clarifies it
but if it's still confusing leave me
comments and then I might make one video
entirely explaining the bar's n function
and the second confusion is normally
coming from setting stop losses take
profits the trigger of the stop- loss
and the trailing stop loss as a
percentage of price rather than fixed
values the idea basically came from
Bitcoin was $20,000 and it was $40,000
and $50,000 and $100,000
so fixed values do not mean much and
therefore we link everything to the
current prices in the market say if
Bitcoin is trading at $100,000 and we
set the value as TP and stop loss at
0.4% of the price and triggered of the
stop loss as 10% of the stop loss and
trailing stop loss as 5% of the stop
loss then if a trade is taken on bitcoin
at 100,000 Mark exactly our TP and it
stop loss is going to be set at 0.4% of
100,000 so 400 points away from the
price so at 100, 1400 and 96,6 00 10% of
that is the trigger of our stop loss so
once the market moves in our favorable
Direction by that much points that's
when the trailing of the stop loss will
start so price will need to be above
10040 Mark before the trading stop loss
will trigger and the trading stop loss
itself is 5% of 400 so it's 20 so at any
point in time once it has been triggered
it will Trail the current prices in the
market by 20 points I hope this
clarifies it now that we understand
these two confusing settings of the EA
let's look at some of the requirements
of the year as well this year will work
on any pair as long as the spreads are
tight and this is true for every
scalping year because of the number of
Trades so if the spreads are not tight
then you're paying the broker a lot of
money so the broker is getting rich then
best to use a standard account because
the EA starts trailing the stop loss
once you are in profit and if you're
using a commission based account I
haven't written the code in a way so the
EA doesn't know about the commission so
it will start trailing the stop loss
even though you are still in negative
now if you have to use a commission
based account then at least increase the
trigger of the stop- loss setting by at
least 5 Points more to compensate for
that commission and as we already spoke
this year is a trend based year low
zigzagging currencies like Australian
dollar New Zealand dollar Swiss frank or
Canadian dollar are not that conducive
for this year and the last one is the
ability to Trail the stop loss very very
close many Brokers do not allow a
trailing stop- loss very close to the
price they might have a requirement of
two or three tips away from the price
and this is very true for prop firms as
well and this is why the year is not
going to work on those and this brings
us to our last point of discussion which
is about prop Firs now most of the prop
FS as far as I understand them do not
allow for a trailing stop loss very
close to the price or they might have a
requirement on how frequently you can
update the stop loss and in that case
this e is not going to Trail the stop
loss and that kills the entire strategy
so over the last few weeks I've been
thinking and I've come up with some
ideas on how to circumvent these
requirements and use a different method
for the trailing of the stop- loss while
still keeping the win rate close to our
current setup I'm finishing the final
touches on that and hopefully within the
next two weeks I will be releasing
another version of this scalping robot
but with a different trailing mechanism
that suits the prop forms better or the
Brokers that do not allow aggressive
trailing Cas being xes and OCTA FX for
example remember an EA is just to it's
like a helicopter it can take you places
but you need to know how to fly it so
take the time to understand and get to
know this EA properly and its settings
so you can fly this helicopter without
crashing it into the side Hill so until
next time guys stay safe trade safe