Welcome to the video. So, I'm going to
be doing a breakdown of my strategy
today.
Give you an insight. I'm sure we'll take
some trades, show you the data I've
already collected.
And we'll go from there. End of year
video to kind of break things down. So,
let's have a look.
>> [gasps]
>> So,
as far as things stand, let's just take
a quick look at analytics before
we dig into more potential setups. Okay?
So, we've overall I've tested October,
November, and just coming into December
now. Just so I'm
kind of keeping that flow state coming
into 2026. Now, I've had an insane
October and November, so just keeping
momentum going
and using it as a
nice tool
to look at.
Okay. So, strategy breakdown and
analytics.
You can see for the most part in
October, it was incredible.
I will potentially be cutting out
Monday coming in 2026. The PA's not the
best, of course I'll be monitoring it.
Here, the data shows otherwise. But of
course, I've noticed in live trading
it's just not as great on a Monday, so I
will be factoring that in. But you can
see October very positive, two minor
days. We have also had days as well
we've taken losses. For example, here
you can see 57.7
59 59.7% strike rate. 86. So, there's a
few losses in there as well, but for the
most part
very green, which is what we want to
see. November
is
a lot more.
We can still see clear profitability
overall, but there was a few break
evens, a few losses in there.
These two are loss uh break evens, and
of course a few losses, okay? And then
December so far
one positive day
and one negative day.
So, we're going to continue. There's a
couple days left to back test before we
are at the current date.
So, I'm going to walk you through, see
what price action actually folds. And
I'm done this year for trading wise
anyway, so I'm just staying in flow.
Trading by hour. So, what's important
for me is 2026, my plan is just to trade
London open.
You can broaden your horizon from London
open or New York open. For me, I'd
rather keep that window tight between
8:00 a.m. 9:30 a.m. UK time, because
when I'm in the UK, it suits me very
well with routine.
In terms of daily cycle and what I'm
looking at in London session, it's
amazing, especially when it comes to
gold, pound yen, euro dollar, etc.
New York, there's a few different
variations in there, and it's later in
the day in the UK. And here when I'm in
Singapore, it's late at night, so it
doesn't really make as much sense.
So, I'm going to be progressing with
London open. But you can see most of my
winning trades
here
between those hours. This is This is 1
hour ahead.
So, between 9:00 a.m. and 11:00, which
is 8:00 a.m. and 10:00. So, you can see
that's the window of time I want to
trade in.
Okay. So, with 33 trades taken, 22 out
of 33 winning trades, which gives me a
66.67%
strike rate. Pretty solid.
Here's some tips.
Okay. So, after 30 trades, what I'm
going to get is
a breakdown
of what's should be suggested to me
going forward.
So, you can see here
it says, "Try stopping for the day after
two consecutive losses to improve
profits." Now, personally, I do this
anyway. I say max two bullets a day, and
then after that, I'm done. I'll just
forget about it. Whatever happened,
whether I've taken a win, break even,
loss, move into the next day.
That alone will save a lot of traders
and get them into profitability. What's
sometimes most important is just not
giving the profits back once you've made
them.
So, this is a good tip for you.
And then here it says, "Try avoiding
very low risk trades." I don't do that
anyway.
And then consider cautiously increasing
position size after winning streaks.
Which would have equated to a plus 90k,
which is obviously huge,
but it's not something at the stage I
want to I want to be doing. But let's
take a look. I want to dig into the
trades.
Let's dig into the charts. Okay.
So, here currently
I'm on
gold.
We're currently digging into
this current day, and the bias is long.
So, how I formulate my narrative always
starts with the daily bias, okay? I'm
starting with the daily time frame, and
I'm looking at a few things.
Market structure. Are we formulating
higher highs and higher lows? That's one
aspect. The other aspect is is there
draws on the liquidity to support price?
And then thirdly, has price tapped into
PD arrays, rejected with momentum? Are
we a point of interest where price is
likely to reject from? Those are my
three foundations. Then we move into H1
order flow, do the same thing. H1 order
flow and daily bias will sometimes
contradict, so H1 order flow can
sometimes lag behind, which is fine,
which is why I put more
weight on the daily time frame. But
usually you'll find they do enter into
line quite well. And then the lower time
frames is purely playing a daily cycle,
playing it very well, and capitalize on
the move.
So, here what we have is we just play
price out a little bit more, okay? Now,
this indicator on the right
you can download that from this
platform, okay?
This is a custom indicator built into
the platform. It's easy to download, and
it's available for pro package, okay?
So, I've got it, and it's very much like
the TradingView one, which is nice to
have. Just to track price, because when
I'm on the lower time frames, I want to
be seeing what the 1 hour is doing.
Okay? Cuz a lot of my
not a lot of my strategy, a lot of my
entry is based off the precision of the
1 hour.
Okay? So, let's just play this out. Now,
remember I said
this data is just an hour
in front of London.
So, I'm just going to play this out, but
I'm observing
how Asia is formulating.
Okay. So, we're about to tap into
Frankfurt here.
Okay, perfect. Let's start marking out
territories.
So, 8:30 is 7:30, so I'll do 8:30.
9:00.
9:30.
And we'll leave it at 10:00, okay?
So, what I'm noticing here straight off
the bat,
which is great for us,
on this particular day,
is we've taken this swing low.
Which for me is great,
because what this means is that this is
a previous daily low, okay?
Which for me is what I want to see.
Previous daily low has been taken.
You can see how did we take it? We took
it with a clear flush down. We then
bought back very aggressively, and since
then, we've actually had this.
Now, we're still not in London just yet,
but we can already see how this is
setting up.
Just going to change the color of this a
little bit.
Internal shift.
Which is solid.
Price so far is respecting these lows.
All I want to monitor now coming into
London, are these lows respected? Cuz
it's my job to determine is Asia acting
as accumulation or manipulation, okay?
And because that then builds into the
bias of what I'm expecting London to do.
Okay. So, this is 7:30.
Okay. Just coming into London now. So, I
want you to start to watch
the 1 hour candle and how it starts to
shape up, okay?
So, what I'm seeing
so far at the back is we can see
that the market is already protecting
these lows, which is good to see. We're
starting to break above, and we have
liquidity above
resting above Asia highs
for potential
expansion.
So, let's continue to play this out.
Okay. Straight off the bat, there is a
potential entry here.
I'm not going to take it.
But there is an entry here. How I
[music] take that? Just off the
rejection.
Taking that to higher prices, targeting
Asia highs, and then we'll get into it
in a minute. But just trailing stops as
we go along, okay? But what I'm noticing
here
is if we just look at the time aspect of
things here.
What time is that? 8:30, [music] 7:30.
Let's just drop some text on here.
7:30 7:30
7:35.
Okay. So, all I'm formulating here is
that the market is shaping up for longs
nicely. First potential trade here.
But I'm not taking it yet, because I
want to see a bit more movement to the
upside. Remember, as soon as price
starts to gravitate more towards Asia
highs, I have more conviction that this
high is going to be taken, okay? This is
quite early into the move. Still an
opportunity.
All right. So, that confirms what I
already know.
Which is great.
Perfect. That's a trade.
So, all I'm doing
is obviously a lot of people just look
at the first OB, right? So, the first OB
will be shifting market structure,
inducement. You You all know that simple
model, okay?
But, it's all about following order flow
as we go along as well. It's not just
taking the first entry. It's
understanding how to play price when it
reacts to a certain daily cycle. So,
this looks clean.
I'd be happy to take this. I'm going to
take this.
And I'm going to do it with a safe stop
below structure. I'm not a trader that
wants to does the smaller stops ever.
It's not how I do things.
I'd rather have a decent size stop and
allow myself time.
Allow myself a bit of a gauge
to make sure that I'm safe, basically.
Okay, so Asia highs is the main target.
Been doing 2% of risk per trade
on this. And we're now in.
Okay, and then if we do get close to
Asia highs, then I'll just monitor how
price
forms. Usually, if I just set my draw at
Asia highs or let's say a a draw on
liquidity,
price will often expand depending on
that speed. So, I like to be a little
bit diverse in my approach.
All right, so we're in here.
This is good. Good signs.
Especially the candle here.
The timing aspect of things.
Okay, so right before that pop, notice
what we had
is we had equal highs starting to form.
Price pauses temporarily to pull back,
and then we go.
So, there was actually an additional
entry here.
I'm obviously not going to take cuz I'm
already in the trade.
But, as soon as we get that first pop,
trailing stops.
Okay.
Trailing stops now on gold.
What time is this? Coming into 9:00 a.m.
So, new hour. Watch what takes place in
this new hour.
Watch the candle.
Okay.
It's going to start to trail a little
bit more.
Boom.
Break even.
Now,
like I said before, there's a lot of
speed here.
So, what I'm going to do
is
extend my TP
to the next draw. And I'm just going to
focus on trailing.
Trailing stops.
Okay.
Something I like to do as well, the more
price moves,
the more aggressive I will become with
trailing stops. Reason being, if price
is running heavy in profit,
and the the sooner we get to that draw,
I want to be aggressive. I don't want to
be giving back profits to the market.
So, just getting a bit more aggressive
here.
If we get one more push, there we go.
Trail again.
Now, notice how I'm being a lot more
aggressive the further we move.
There we go. Getting towards the draw.
Trailing a lot more aggressively now.
We're coming out of session two, so
we're likely to
start slowing down,
pulling back. This is where price
facilitates
a pullback around this time.
Okay.
Boom.
>> [sighs]
>> Solid.
Beautiful trade. You can see what took
place.
Asia in this instance acting as
accumulation, manipulation coming into
London, taking previous daily low, which
is beautiful. That's all I need to know.
And then as soon as we start to see the
signature of price to move higher, at
this point, as soon as we start to
protect this low,
all I'm looking for is the rejection to
show protection of this low following
the shift. And then as we start to
gravitate more towards this high,
which is here,
as we start to gravitate more towards
this high, we will get pauses in price.
This is what I want to see in order to
then take more trades. Now, this is
quite early for me, but as soon as we
start to step into time, you can see I'm
very much on side taking the trades.
Beautiful. So, that is
the first one.
Now, what I'm going to do is just speed
things up to the next day cuz I'm done
at this point. I'm not going to hold
around into New York.
It's not what I'm
looking at.
And
to save you efficiency of watching this,
I'm not going to switch too much between
time frames, but just know that I'm
looking at higher time frames. I'm
looking at the 1-hour to shape my bias
and narrative for the day.
Okay.
That's what I'm looking at.
Now, here, just going to watch what
shapes up.
So far, we have a bearish
signature price.
Just going to do the same thing again.
Half eight, nine.
Okay. The great thing about this, and a
tip I will give to you
if you trade very similar to me in 2026,
is
trade one session if you can. Minimize
the amount of pairs you can trade as
long as you have a bit of
diversification in there, and you
understand how price [music] moves in
different market cycles,
you'll be flying, and you'll focus on
mastery of one or two pairs.
This is shaping up for a bearish day,
not a bullish day.
Time is this? Half seven. Okay. Play
this out a bit.
Okay, did we take that low?
We didn't take that low. Interesting.
So, what's taking place now is what I
call the coil, which is another setup
for me to take. So, what I'm observing
right off the bat,
price
is
Oops.
Price is formulating
lows,
protection of the highs.
So, we have liquidity above the highs,
but I'm not expecting that to be taken
based on how the daily cycle is shaping
up here, and the timing of certain
things as well.
So, Asia is putting the high.
Frankfurt is also starting to put in a
high.
And I'm looking for more downside
pressure, okay?
So, I'm just going to start to notice
[music] how price
reacts from here.
Okay.
Here.
Safe stop.
Quite a big target. Quite corrective day
so far.
Want to be aware of this low as well.
Okay, draw's been taken.
Don't want any risk on the table now.
Break even.
Break even taken.
Half eight.
It's a half eight, 8:25.
Okay. Just trying to stay in flow while
I
talk to you.
But if this was live, I'm looking at
this as well.
Re-entry fits the model. I'm expecting
this low to be taken. Reason being, this
low that formed, you can see we did push
to the upside for a temporary amount of
time, swept this liquidity, pushed the
downside. The overall daily bias is
setting up for more downside as London
distribution lower.
So, now that that low's been taken, my
next low is
here just to see how price reacts. And
you can see all price is doing is
pausing here
and pausing here.
So, I'm going to want to take a trade
here.
And I'm going to do
Notice how I'm going above the highs
quite often in a selling market.
Where's that previous low?
Just grab that again. Let's just delete.
Okay.
Beautiful.
Exactly what I wanted to see.
So, now that low's been taken,
again, reduce Well, remove risk.
Notice how quick I am to remove risk.
Break even.
So be it.
See how the narrative played out. I'm
done now.
Yeah, quite a corrective session.
Narrative was bearish, as you can see.
It is what it is.
It's a one win, two break evens.
Let's go to
the next day.
We start to catch up to real time here.
So, I'm going to do one more trading
day.
Need to refresh it.
Okay. Coming to the end of the data
because I'm getting so close to live
time now. Give You need to do 24 hours
beyond 24 hours for you to test it. But
let's just take a look at analytics. So,
you've seen how I'm taking trades.
And like I said, it's a combination of
daily directional bias, H1 order flow.
For the past 5 years, the there was
always my fundamentals.
Then there's just a few layers to add in
when it comes to understanding how the
sessions interact
with,
you know, accumulation, manipulation,
distribution.
And then being able to play that in the
moment as well. It's one thing talking
about it. Being able to do it live is
obviously different different ball game
that you have to practice.
But I just want to see the analytics
now.
Okay.
So, sweet. So, end of December so far.
The next 2 weeks are obviously low
volume. There's no need to really test
that. You can go back to previous years
if you want to. We can see one winning
day, one losing day, another winning
day,
and a break even day.
Okay.
Just the stats as well.
You can see heavy amount of profit. It's
2% risk per trade, so it's going to
start to stack up quite quick,
especially if you've got an edge. And
based on how October went,
it went very well.
Okay.
Max drawdown
is good. Return is heavy. Profit factor
is extremely good.
Just having a look at some stats here.
69% win rate. Very happy with that.
For the most part,
two to ones,
couple three to ones,
and a couple five to ones.
Just on gold. I'll give you a bit of
advice as well. When you're back
testing, instead of back testing the
whole day,
I would recommend back testing with
intention, which means if you're back
testing an asset class, let's say like
gold, and you want to first test London,
just do purely London.
See how the data interacts.
Then move into doing New York. Separate
out the sessions a little bit. Run a
data collection period on that and see
which is your best
time frame to actually trade and your
time period. Through that data alone,
you'll see what your winning periods
are. And I'd recommend
don't just sit around the charts all the
time every day.
You know, I've had it when I've
uh had an office before and in the years
prior where all you want to do is just
sit by the charts and trade. It's
probably one of the worst things you can
do. You are better showing up in a set
window of time, call it London kill
zone, New York kill zone where the
volume's at its highest.
As long as you understand what that
session's likely to do,
and it formulates with your strategy
like it does with mine,
then you're you're good to go. But once
trading's done, log off, come back
tomorrow. That's the way it should work.
Okay. So, overall,
this is that. With the indicator, just I
just want to go back.
Like I said, you can download this
indicator.
Uh it's disappeared now, but you can
download the indicator. It's called ICT
higher time frame candles version 2.1.
You'll be able to import. So, all you
would do, let's say you wanted to
download the indicator, you go to
indicators. There's a few on here you
can use. I've also used the sessions as
well.
So, you can see sessions.
Formulate them now.
You can see mine. So, if we just go in
here,
trading sessions, style,
uh sessions here.
I wasn't a fan of the timings or the
colors here, so I just changed it. Put
in my custom ones
along with the right timing.
Good to go.
And then here, you can customize it how
you want it.
Which means
I didn't want any of the values in
there. I only wanted one time frame to
show, which was the hour. You can, of
course, add any time frame you want.
And then ob- obviously just change the
colors.
And everything else. If you want fair
value gaps or volume imbalances to show
as well, you can obviously have that as
well. I don't, so I don't need that. And
then, of course, apply.
So, very happy with that. So, all you do
is you need to go on the pro plan. And
then with the pro plan, that comes free
to use, which just makes back testing so
much easier.
And yeah, I've been, you know, I don't
back test as much anymore. It tends to
be with a purpose.
But when I do, it's to stay in flow,
build confidence, and just
especially in Christmas period. There's
a few things that I want to sharpen up
on and refresh. So, I'll be doing that.
I would highly recommend if you're new
to a strategy or you're formulating your
own,
back test over the Christmas period.
Okay? Feel free to use the platform that
I am, which is FTO.
Code Bamber, b a m b e r, for 10% off.
And you can use this whenever you want
to.
And it's a solid platform to be able to
use and [music] test some data. And then
I really like the analytics platform at
the back end of it because you getting
more than enough data to formulate
everything, tweak certain things, and
get some pattern recognition on what
you're looking at. Okay?
>> [gasps]
>> So, overall, hope you enjoyed this
video. Hope you enjoyed me running
through a bit of my strategy, what I'd
be looking for in live time.
And uh hopefully you got some value from
this.
Speak to you in the next video.