Very good morning everyone. This is
Rajendran here joining from Open Algo.
So today's session right it's going to
be a very interesting session I would
say.
We're going to talk about an uh evolving
topic a very hot topic in uh the AI
world called auto research.
So this is from uh Andra Karpati I mean
Andre Karpati he is a very well-known uh
person in the AI field right so Andre
Karpati one of the core member of openAI
right and then he also uh worked as a
Tesla director as well right so you his
videos in YouTube is quite famous for
explaining the LLMs a lot more things
right so we can say like he's the goat
of uh the LLM models
now very recently right so probably an
around a month back probably 3 to four
weeks from here before to that so he
released an uh very interesting uh AI
workflow called auto research
so what he had done uh he had an um he
built an model called nanohat some time
back.
So he was doing hyper tuning using H. So
basically instead of he doing the hyper
tuning he allowed the model to do the
hyper tuning iteratively. Right? So this
is something like an ML model doing the
hyperparameter tuning. So initially he
used H00 GPUs. Right?
and uh he
set the goal for the AI to do the
tuning. So you see that the numbers keep
reducing over here. So what does that
means is every single time
every dot here represents a new
experiment which is conducted by AI. He
haven't said what to do but he had uh
said only what should be the end goal of
the model. So maybe he was talking about
getting a better model, getting a better
hyperparameter optimization.
So the AI has been continuously
iteratively doing various experiments.
Whichever the experiments are
successful, it is recording it.
Whichever the whichever the experiments
are not successful, it is discarding
those experiments. So over a period of
time after multiple experiments probably
you can even run hundreds of experiments
also which I'm going to show you very
shortly
you can see that the numbers has been
keep on getting down and down and down
so lower the score better the model is
going to be right.
So in this he used three important files
one is prepare.py
and then train.py Pi and also the
instructions how to run the program
right how to run the experiments so that
has been run uh using the auto research
so this this programm contains the
instructions how to run the experiment
how to conduct the experimentation all
those details in a in a markdown format
so then I got like I mean not I'm not
the only one who's thinking about it
many people probably would have already
thought about is
many people
try to use this workflow in their own
domain to improve its something. So
whatever they want to improve
iteratively
without a human thinking an AI can kind
of think through that and then uh
improve the models.
So that what I had done um I had
probably the code which however the
experiment which I had conducted is like
uh probably if you go to market calls
github.com/market calls if you go to the
repositories you'll be finding this back
testing auto research.
I had given a simple EMA crossover
strategy and I asked the model to come
up with an iterative experiment. I
haven't said what should be the model
should do right or what the model should
do
but I just given couple of goals so I'll
show you if you go to the auto back test
branch so there is an April 85 is there
you can see various commits over here
all each and every commit is a
experiment successful experiment
conducted by AI Okay. So, initially the
back testing results was something like
this. Initially I I used a simple State
Bank of India
and the goal is to uh probably can you
can see like
where I can get the details.
So if you do a simple back testing right
you would have got something like an 10%
CAGGR
sharp ratio was like 0.52 and max draw
was 46.51 this is the initial simple 10
and 30 MA crossover right so I just want
to know like how things are performing
or how the experiments are conducted
right so I thought like I I'll try to do
always I'll I'll start with something
simple right and then later on we can
always extend so just to get an idea how
things works
So I said like I want to improve the
CAGR. I want to improve the sharp ratio
of the buck testing and the max draw
down. So basically I want to increase my
reward and reduce my risk and improve
the reliability of the uh smooth equity
curve. So that's what three things I
want to perform by the model.
So by default the model values as I said
like 10% caggr and 0.52 and 100.
So I want the model to conduct the
experiments. So I have to write these
three files again. So if you could see
in this code right
um I would like to show you something
like if you go to this folder you'll be
finding this program. MD. So this will
be containing the instructions
how to conduct various u details. So it
has a back test.py it has a fixed
harness like it has how to load the data
portfolio simulation how to do the
scoring output right which it cannot
modify it and then there is something
called strategy.py Pi this is where the
file it can modify it can generate the
signal logic right so the programm
is the one right now that we are
watching out over here it contains a
goal so the goal is to do what the goal
is to
improve the caggr improve the sharp
ratio improve the max draw down so how
we had done is like we had taken a
weighted score of it
so means 40%age caggr and 30%age option
cap ratio and 30%age of max draw down
I'll be getting a number so initially
the number was something like 28 or
something if you combine everything
that is a number you would have seen in
the read me section also right now what
it can do every time it can conduct a
new experiment on top of EMA it can add
some filters maybe it can add another
200 EMA as a filter or it can use an RSA
as a filter or a combination of RSA and
volume I don't say what the model has to
do I just have to say right so what the
end goal is that that's what I have to
say over here and then I have to start
the application probably we'll we'll run
a similar experiment right so that we
can get an idea
so that it comes up with various
experiments so some of the experiments
I'll show you if you go to the readme
section you can see some of the
experiments conducted
so here are some of the experiments
different multiple experiments conducted
almost 24 experiments conducted. Some
experiments passed through, some
experiment failed.
So it added ADX as an experiment,
momentum filter as an experiment, exit
strategies. It was using how to exit ATR
based exits. It was using volume
filters. It was trying to use it was not
only trying to optimize the entry, it is
also trying to optimize exit also,
right? It is also trying to use some
sort of an ML as well, but it it haven't
worked well. So I tried with random
forex and it got discarded. Right? Of
course I haven't given very clearcut
rules for ML but it tried with a little
bit of ML and then it failed. That
doesn't means like ML doesn't works but
I haven't given any deeper instructions.
I thought like okay let it just a simple
experiment. So I just have to discard
it.
So here are some of the discarded
experiments. What experiments failed?
Which experiments gone through? Right?
Over a period of time it was slowly
improving the results. You can see like
the improve the results has been
improved. Not in many cases. Some cases
the overall score improved. You can see
that this is the initial score. The
score has been keep on improvising over
a period of time. So if the score is
improving what does that means is your
CG is improving. Your sharp ratio is
improving. Your max draw down is
reducing that that's what it means
right. So something similar experiment
is what I'm going to show you right now.
So I'm going to use open algo for it.
Right?
So I I'll try to explain for for the
people who are very new to what we are
going to do over here. Right? So what
we're going to do is we're going to have
a strategy, right?
Say an EMA crossover strategy. EMA
crossover strategy.
So with this EMA crossover strategy, we
will be getting three different metrics.
So one of the metrics that we're going
to get is like CAGR, right? We'll be
getting an CAGR. Oh, C AGR.
And we will be getting another metric
which is sharp ratio
which says how much smoother your equity
curve is. And then there is a third
third metric which is max draw down. So
these are like very important metrics in
any trend following systems. So max DD
right.
So what we do is like we combine these
things and we try to create a collective
composite metric composite score
let's say the composite score initially
is like 28 because the C is like
something like a 10
C is 10 and sharp ratio is like some 14
and then max do is four so you put
everything together and you put the
formula for that which is nothing but
CGR multiplied by the C. I mean the
let's say we'll be giving weightage to
that. I'll give 40% weightage to that
because C is very important. Sharp ratio
is also important. How much important is
like I I'll give 30% weightage to that
30% weightage to that. Right? So it is
who is giving me the who is giving the
weightage is like I'm the one who is
allocating weightage to that because
yes net profit is more important.
Equally what is also important is like
max draw is also important. Sharp ratio
is also important. So I'll give equal
weightage to sharp ratio on max. So 30
30 percentage is what the weightage I'm
going to give right. So whatever the
number that we are getting over here it
will be get multiplied by the percentage
and everything will be get summed up and
we'll get this composite score right.
There are different ways you can do the
uh composite score. You need to come up
with some sort of composite score. The
whole idea is to increase you increase
the composite score.
So as long as the composite score is
less than your threshold. Let's say your
composite score you want to improve
drastically. You are setting a goal. So
the goal is to
improve
the composite score CS. CS is nothing
but composite score to something like
40.
So we try to check in every experiment
we try to check is the goal is improved.
If it is yes
uh if it is no
again the experiments will be conducted.
So maybe we'll be adding more filters.
We'll be adding more uh uh context.
Of course,
let's say
what we'll be do trying to do is like
we'll be uh
conducting
unlimited experiments. We cannot say
unlimited experiments but multiple
experiments. It can be like hundreds of
experiments
running without any human intervention.
Right? So there's no human to intervene
over here. We keep on running those
experiments
by adding
various filters.
So every time the experiment is
conducted, the composite score will be
calculated. If the composite score is
increasing, it's well and good. It will
continue. It will keep those strategies.
If the score is not good, it's going to
discard those things. And every time it
is going to do the score, it's going to
commit to the git, right? So locally,
it's going to commit, not to the remote.
Locally, it's going to commit.
So in order to do this, I hope you're
able to understand this so that we can
proceed. If you have any questions, you
can also ask me. There is a
hand button is there. You can ask me. I
can unmute you and you can speak back as
well.
If you guys [clears throat] are clear,
just type clear.
Or is it too complex?
Vishnu says clear. Crypto info says
clear.
How about others?
Adwin,
Arun, DH, Karthik, Lucky, Ansari, Rajes.
Yeah, Karthik says clear. D says where
to find historical data. I mean you can
download that from Yahoo Finance or from
open go via the broker. Right.
So Rajes says clear and crisp and clear.
That's what Johan is saying.
All right, great. So let's move little
forward. So what I had done is like I'm
running open algo over here, right? It's
running in an analyzer mode. So what I'm
going to do, I'll go to histoy. I'm
going to download the historical data.
Right? So I'll go to histoy.
From here I'm going to take the same
state bank of India. I'll try to
download locally. So if I try to
download, it'll get downloaded
via duct DB, right? So I'll add the
symbol. I select the symbol and I ensure
that daily data. I want to download for
the last let's say since 200. I don't
know how far the data is there, but let
me try to download the data from 2000 to
2026. Let me download the data.
Hopefully it should get downloaded.
Yeah, I think it is throwing some
errors. Why is it so?
If it is throwing error then we can try
with it says too many request
to give one more try. Maybe
I try with only last 15 10 15 years
maybe.
2015 onwards. Otherwise there is another
way is like directly use Yahoo Finance.
I think this got succeeded last I think
some 2000 onwards it's not able to
download but 2015 onwards we are able to
download. It's also go and check it out
like I'll go to the charts. Yeah the
data is there right? So statement of
India the data is there. So we're going
to conduct experiments.
We're going to do the back testing. So
for the back testing, what we are going
to do is this is the process that we're
going to follow, right? We're going to
use a vector BT is what we're going to
follow. So most likely this is what
we're going to do here. So we're going
to have an historical data. We're going
to render it in a pandas data frame
format from duck db. It's stored in duct
db inside open algo. And we're going to
generate the signals using strategy.py.
As you remember the strategy.py Pi is
the one which we're going to modify it.
What it cannot modify is like the
vectorbd back testing engine like back
test.py. It'll be loading the data.
It'll be back testing. This is the one
which will be back testing it. Apply the
entry and exit signals. This file we
cannot modify. Right? The the AI cannot
modify this file. Why? So that the AI
cannot mix up the results. AI cannot say
hey I improved the results. Right? So
this is a standard template which is the
one which will be evaluating which will
be applying the realistic commission
slippages everything it'll be
calculating the equity metrics and
vector BD and all those things it's
going to do right and then this is a
file it'll be calculating the score as
well. So it will be calculating the
score on every signal generation it will
be every experiment which is conducted
it will be calculating the score and as
long we compare with the metrics as long
as the metric is not done it'll be
running in a very iterative loop right
this will be keep on going on every now
and then so that's how the pipeline
works so we need to we're going to set
up the pipeline from the scratch so far
I just installed only open algo I
downloaded the data but that is Not more
than enough but we need to go and set up
from the skills. If you remember we have
skills right? So skills.sh. If you go
here and then search for vector BT
vector BT you can also find the same
thing the vectorb expert market calls
this one. You can also find this in our
uh documentation as well. You can also
find this skills. It's called skills. We
already done some couple of videos about
it. Right? Right? I'm not going to
explain what a skill is all about. So
here are the skills. Right? So for back
testing, we have skills for back
testing. You just have to just copy this
and you have to install it. So I'm going
to open an new
one. I'm going to paste it. Oops. I'm
sorry.
This is Mac Mini. I'm using a Windows
keyboard. It's it's a mixed up one.
So
go back, right click probably copy and
the the keyboards are a little different
here. I hope I'm Yeah, I got it now.
Yes, I'm going to install the skill. So
the skill what it does is like it's an
expert in back testing. You don't need
to write any Python codes. We just have
to tell hey this is my strategy and I'm
going to back implement all this setups
right enter and cla code is what I'm
going to use. So the AI tool what I'm
going to use is like claudic code.
However you can also consider using uh
um
anti-gravity or cursor or maybe you can
also consider using codex as well. So
codex codeex and uh cla code is what I
would highly recommend right. So I use
cladic code a lot and as a backup I use
codex right
however probably the next version uh it
can be like you can consider using
client or codex or anti-gravity. So
these are the one which many people are
using it. So I'm going to first of all
I'm going to fire up cla code and in the
meantime what I'm going to do I'll try
to pull up my
uh this we need some examples about
Andra Karpati's
let's go to Andre Karpati
auto research
So, I'm just going to copy this link.
I'm going to clone it. So, a lot of
cloning that we're going to do here.
Now, one good thing these LLMs are
really it can do is like it can imitate
things. So, we also going to do a lot of
imitation today. So, I'm going to clone
the andra. Oh, come on. It's not copied
yet.
We're just going to clone Andesh
Karpati's research.
Right. I'm going to uh fire up Claude.
And then first thing I'm going to do is
like I'm going to do a setup, right? So
that's what I'm going to do here. I'll
say like / setup. That will be setting
up the
vectorbt environment with open algo and
everything.
So what this does is like it'll analyze
my what version of Python which is
installed, what operating system I had
used. So it'll try to create a virtual
environment. It create an back testing
folder. So a lot of things it'll be
doing
and I'm going to enable something called
sandbox mode and this sandbox mode is
available only in Linux or uh Mac
machine. So that I don't need to provide
yes yes every single time. So it auto
allows
and this process will take anywhere
around maybe we can say like 2 to 3
minutes
maybe for time being I'll disable the
sandbox because is facing some issues.
I'll just disable the sandbox.
Maybe I may have to provide couple of
yes yes yes yes sort of stuff.
What I'm thinking is like uh the way the
AI is going to conduct experiments and
it's going to make your strategy better
maybe the creativity
of the strategy itself going to become
much better in the next couple of years
right probably I think I would say like
this is the starting point of
how to build an very interesting and
meaningful strategies like even an how
an reasonable strategy which is having a
reasonable edge
can be made even more much better right
so it is creating an back testing folder
as you could see this is a folder I'm
going to commit not right now so I'm
going to say like I'm going to use uh
Indian markets like I I'll use Indian
markets is what I'm going to use I'm
going to use open algo I'm going to use
duck DB [clears throat] uh and then I'm
going to submit it's going to ask me it
is asking me a couple of uh details like
which market I'm going to back test
and then uh yeah I'm going to use open
I'll go for it submit the answers
maybe if you're using codeex you may not
be asked this kind of questions
enter your open algo API key so I'm
going to enter the key here
and it's also asking for a path as well.
So the path we can get it from here. So
the path is where my duck db is there.
So my duck db lies inside open algo
inside duck db I mean db that is an
histoy duck db is there. So that's the
one uh I'm going to right click and copy
that
and I'm going to paste it.
What happened?
Copy path right? copy part and then
paste it. That's my DB path.
So what it does is like inside the back
testing folder it will be creating an
env file. So I have to enter my uh key.
So the key I have to enter is
let me go and get the key from open
alyso.
Here's
the AP key. Copy it
and paste it over here.
All right.
So, there are a couple of questions
here. Manu is saying like, I'm late to
this live show. Is there a chance to get
a recorded session? Yes, the session
entire session is getting recorded,
right? and it'll be available in YouTube
as well.
So in the meantime what I'm going to do
is like I'm going to say like I want to
build a simple uh I'm going to reconduct
the same experiments itself right maybe
this time the experiments might be a
little different but I'm going to say
like I want to uh back test or we can
use slashback test over here slback test
I'm going to say like I'm just going to
say what strategy I want to implement I
want to uh back test statement of India
for the last let's say like uh 11 years
uh that that's a data that we are having
from the last 10 years
on a daily time frame
a simple 10 and 20 MA crossover is what
I want to do right uh simple 10 and 20
30 MA crossover
strategy
is what I want to back test is what I
want to back test.
So you can see that lot of things has
been already installed right. So these
are the packages which has been already
installed uh inside everything is
available uh in as an virtual
environment. So here all the libraries
has been installed. So we having an back
testing right now there is nothing
inside back testing. So I'm going to
create my very first strategy. So I'll
say like /back test followed by that I'm
just saying what strategy that I want to
back test. a simple 10 and 20 MA
crossover for the last 10 years. We know
that the data is already there in duct
DB. So it should not be taking much of a
time. Now what it does is the moment I
say it will start writing the code
and it'll try to fetch the data from
Doug DB or if Doug DB is not available
it'll try to fetch the data from uh the
directly from the API itself. Right?
So it is trying to load the vector BD
skill. So the back test itself will be
invoking the back testing skills inside
vector BD. Vector BD has lot of skills.
It can do back testing. It can do
optimization. It can do a lot of other
things right. And uh among that we are
just simply using 10 and 30 MA crossover
strategy. So we just first of all we are
just simply building this uh strategy.
So it is trying to use duct DB with
source equal to DB or what it does is
like it will be automatically
able to
create a strategy. It creates a folder
name called EMA crossover inside the MA
crossover it will be writing the Python
code. Not just that it will execute the
code also and it'll give you the summary
of out of it as well. Right
now like 3 weeks back we had conducted a
lot of experiments in our live sessions.
We built uh strategies like uh portfolio
level strategies complex uh uh
strategies right so combination of
multiple strategies like four five
strategies combined together you'll be
able to build an equity curve. So a lot
of things we built using this.
So I'm going to say like uh run the
strategy right I just want to get an uh
result right so what is the result I'm
getting for the last 10 years it's a
simple long only strategy
you can also see the source code over
here right so how the strategy is
everything is written in Python
what is the reliability of the strategy
if you ask me like very very high right
so because it follows the best
principles
from the the skills itself. So we have
like a lot of skills for back testing
optimization with a lot of examples, a
lot of working examples we had built and
we converted that into a strategy set.
Of course, what I forget to do is uh
just give me a sec. I'll say like no uh
because I forget to download for uh
Nifty index because Nifty will be used
as a benchmark. So I forgot to download
for Nifty index. So I'll go and select
index and type nifty.
I'll add it and for nifty also I'll
download the same uh last set 2015
onwards. I'll try to download
for nifty.
I ensure that the interval is daily. You
can also download 1 minute as well. So
brokers like zeroda provide for like 10
years and five years of done and of
stocks like they are providing like five
plus years of uh historical data they
are providing. I'll download for nifty
as well
and hopefully that also should be get
downloaded. Yeah got downloaded. So let
me also verify whether the data is there
or not. Yeah the data is there up to
date right. So um I'll just say like
yeah
can you try now I just added
nifty oh db
it was not there so I was trying a
different method to try to download from
yahoo finance. Yeah that would have
worked but better I try to keep
everything in one place itself.
So now it is trying to run the code and
we're going to get a very basic back
testing results. So this is a back
testing results that we got right. So um
and if you could see the
this is a benchmark that we are getting
right. So this is a strategy.
This is a plain vanilla strategy, right?
So there no filters, nothing. Uh plain
vanilla returns for the last 10 years.
Sharp ratio, sautino ratio, max draw
down, right? Whereas nifty if you could
have seen that the the returns has been
pretty much bigger and sharp ratio is
going to be like 93 again bigger sino
ratio. Yes, pretty much good. uh max
draw down comparatively for the strategy
it is minus 24 percentage here it is
like minus 38.44 44. Now this time what
I'm going to do is like I'm going to u
implement an uh uh similar metric but
slightly a different uh experiment is
what I'm going to conduct over here.
Right? [clears throat]
So I'll say like uh I'm know I want to
understand this auto research right. So
can you understand
the auto research stuff which is from
Andra Karpati because I'm going to
create something similar. I I want
something similar for that.
Yeah. So it had understand what is what
right? So I'm going to say like now I
want to
um conduct similar uh automated
workflow
for uh uh we can we can say like uh now
even before doing this right I would
like to commit this to GitHub.
So whatever that back testing that we
had I'm going to commit this to GitHub.
So I'll say like add
uh readme.
So we want readme, we want g ignore
and MIT license
from it calls GitHub link,
right? Um to the
EMA crossover folder.
First we'll push it to GitHub.
Once this is pushed up to GitHub, uh
then we will add the experimentation
loop.
Push this to get up.
I don't know what what is trying to do.
So I just want to say like I want to uh
push only the EMA crossover strategy
into a new uh GitHub uh
project.
If not, we'll try to do it manually.
That's not a big deal.
So, what should be the GitHub repository
name should be? So, I'll say like EMA
crossover-
auto research. That's the name I want to
give.
It's going to be a public one. I'll
submit.
Hopefully, it'll be adding more controls
to it
saying like I should authenticate first.
walking with the web browser.
Oh man.
Enter the code display in the app and go
and get the app.
Okay. The details will be provided over
here. Yeah.
Right.
Again, one more layer of confirmation.
Yes.
So that should be pushing it to GitHub,
right? That is done,
right? So which means
um yes, you can uh try now. So what I'm
going to say so now it can push it
automatically to GitHub. So whatever the
code is there it gets
it's checking whether I'm connected or
not. Yes, I'm logged in. So it should be
pushing it to the GitHub.
So all these are like boring one time
setup but once you're done with the
setup right next time it's not going to
happen. It's going to happen seamlessly
for you.
reading all the files.
It's kind of annoying to approve every
single time. That's why it's better to
use a sandbox.
So I guess it created the GitHub link.
So let's go to this link, right?
So here is the link. I just
So what we done is like we just simply
published this uh state bank of India
simple moving average crossover. There
is no auto research nothing as of now we
haven't added but that's what we're
going to do now. We're going to add auto
research to that.
So
once again what I'm going to do I'll ask
it to read the auto research. Let's say
like understand
understand
auto research right I want to um
auto
improve my uh trading strategy my EMA
crossover strategy crossover strategy
want to apply the auto research workflow
workflow
uh to my EMA crossover project
where I want to enhance the I'm just
setting the goal uh enhance the CAGGR to
let's say like 15%age at least because
if you remember the previous CAGR was
how much
CAGR was like we we don't get to know
the CAGGR but let's say like strategy
was like having a return of like 171%
percentage maybe I can set an total
return of a different numbers right or
we'll say like we have a total return
rate right so I'll say like total
return of
250%age
and let's say I want to draw use a draw
down so here I'm going to use only
three things total return uh we don't
have a CG metric over here. So I instead
I use a total return and then sharp
ratio it was like8 I would like to go
with like something like 1 1.2. So I'll
say like sharp ratio
to at least 1
uh two which is little greedy.
And then the last one is like uh we want
to improve the max draw down. Let's say
something like around like less than 18
percentage
and max draw down
less than 18%age
right this is the target this is the
goal I am setting to the AI model. So
the AI model have to figure out it has
to conduct various experiments. Right?
So these are the three goals I'm setting
over here for my the simple AMA
crossover. Your strategy can be anything
right? Your strategy can be anything.
Your goals can be anything
and your uh goals can go as deep as uh
possible but in order to make you to
understand I'm just taking with simple
examples.
So it is preparing the prepare.py Pi
which is fixet which is the where the
back testing evaluation happens
strategy.py P. This is where the
experiment is going to happen. It's
going to have like indicators, entry
exit logic, filters, parameters. Going
to change the parameters. It's going to
try with different filters. It's going
to try with entry different entry exit
logics, right? And uh it's going to add
couple of more indicators as well. And
programm this is like where the we set
the goals, we set the agent
instructions, how it should run the
experiments.
Since it should run the experiment,
right? I'll also enable the sandbox
mode. Now it's a time to enable the
sandbox mode so that I I don't need to
press the yes multiple times. And there
is something called Ralph loop. I don't
know how many of you guys had heard
about it. Ralph loop is like kind of an
infinite loop.
You don't need to give any instruction.
The AI model itself will be keep on
conducting multiple experiments. So you
run it overnight.
uh during the night you'll be conducting
hundreds of experiments. So you wake up
in the morning the end goal would have
been more or less it tried to achieve
it. It would have tell you like what
happened whether the model has been
succeeded or not.
So as you can see that it is writing the
strategy.py. So this is where the uh
strategy it is going to conduct various
experiments.
So it's here like strategy.py file. This
file is going to likely to get changed,
right? So you can see like this file is
likely to get changed
and in this case we are putting in 75%
allocation is what we are making over
here.
This particular strategy uses 75%
allocation.
Likewise, it is also likely to write the
program.m MD as well. So, let's go and
read the programm.
This is a program.md instruction.
Going to open up the preview.
In the meantime, I'll say yes. So, let's
go and read it. So, it says like this is
an experiment. This is the main
instruction file like the program.md
EMA crossover auto research. This is an
experiment to have the LLM autonomously
improve a trading strategy. So to set up
a new experiment workflow with a user to
agree on a running tag. So propose a tag
based on today's date and create the
branch. So all these things are later to
GitHub and read in the scope files. The
repo is small. Read these files for full
context. You have to read the readme.md
prepare.py
where the fixed data loading back
testing execution and evaluation scoring
everything will be happening. You should
not modify that and strategy is where
the file you can modify indicators entry
and exit logic filters and parameters
right and then uh initialize the
results. You'll be getting the results
in results.tsv files and then uh confirm
step looks good. So once you're uh get
confirmation kick off the
experimentation once uh you have to get
the confirmation from the human. I'm the
one uh who's going to give the
confirmation over here. Once I give the
confirmation the experimentation should
start. So here are the experimentation
instruction. Right? And uh here is the
goal which I had provided. So total
return should be like 250%age. Sharp
ratio should be greater than 1.2. Max
draw down should be less than 1.8%age.
So it should build a score out of it.
Right? So I don't know how it is it's
here is what it comes out with the
composite score. So the composite score
lower is better. So in this case lower
the value is going to be better like
combined distance from all these three
targets score equal to 0.00 means all
targets has been met like how closer are
we to this numbers I mean these numbers
how closer are we to the sharp ratio.
How closer are we to the targets? So it
is going to derive a score. Maybe by
reducing these numbers we'll get a
number right. If that number is bigger
that means we are not still far away
from the targets.
If the numbers are closer to zero
that means your target is achieved.
Right? So means your total return
percentage what you expect has been
achieved or sharp ratio has been
achieved or maxed drawn has been
achieved then the experiment will stop
until then the iteration will be keep on
happening.
So Karthik is asking what is the data
setup for the back testing here like was
it downloaded by cloud? It's not
downloaded by cloud. We are taking it
from histo. We are taking state bank of
India and benchmark nifty both we are
getting it from the uh open algo duck db
itself. It'll be automatically getting
from there. Right.
So DH is asking is the auto research
itself running in your locally u is
there a need for a GPU? So there is no
need for a GPU here because we are not
doing any ML experiments. It is going to
be uh done by the LLMs. Yes, AI is used
but are we using GPUs? Not in my local
machine, right? So probably I am using
cloud code and cla uh it'll be called so
cloud code will be using uh GPUs at the
anthropic data centers. I'm not running
any GPUs over here. Even though my
machine has some GPUs,
right? I guess that clarifies the next
question.
So you understand the score. The score
is a little different from what I showed
you an example, right? So now let's go
and run the experiment. Right? So all
these files has been ready. The program
files has been ready and lot of other
things are there. What has get logged?
What details the AI will be looking into
that. So this is how it'll be running
those experiments. any experiment each
and every line is experiment over here
the sample code how the report should be
prepared every single line it measures
the score so if the score is improved
it'll keep if the score is lesser it is
going to discard over here right so
that's how it is so it's going to
conduct a lot of experiments so let's
run that
I'll say Yes,
that's preparing the prepare.py as well.
That's the main thing.
The max draw is trying to take it as an
absolute number because max will be
always in a negative number but in our
case we want positive number so it's we
are taking the absolute value of that
order number
so that the score will be always
we try to achieve the score close to
zero
so means I'll try to uh explain you see
that it's trying to add an
get commit
it's not committing but it's just adding
it to that
and it's also committed to that as well
automatically it's committing right and
I'm pushing it to the origin so that we
can uh get the link to this file
right now I'm going to say like I'm
going to start the experiment right so
let's say like uh this is The current
value this is our current value then
this is what we want to achieve right
the sharp ratio this is a one and we
want to achieve at least 1.2 and greater
draw down we want to reduce it to 18%
okay the score current score is like
0.98 we want to bring it to 0.0 zero if
all the things are met. Right? So let's
say like I'll say like start the
experiment.
It's kicking off the experiment. I'm
going to say it's asking me for a human
confirmation.
It's going to create a new branch. It's
going to create a new branch called like
auto research with April 5 today's date.
And I just type yes.
So means uh we are already having an
main commit along with that a main
branch along with that a new branch is
getting created and that is where we're
going to run the experiments
and now it will be keep on running in a
loop right so now it is doing the first
set of uh
experiment
still not started yet but it it's
getting the results so now it's
conducting the second experiment it's
combining you can see that's using EMA
821 and SMA 200 trend filter.
It's changing the strategy.py. So you
can see like it is changing the
strategy.py, right? So because
strategy.py is where we can it can
automatically modify the code.
So score is going to 1.95 means it has
to discard.
Let me keep this.
It's running experiment number three.
How many experiments it can run? I think
Andrah Karpati right in his one uh every
5 minutes one experiment will be
conducted in our case every 30 seconds
an experiment will be conducted a new
experiment so we don't need to wait for
a very long time because data is there
it's not going to take much of a time so
within every 30 seconds a new experiment
will be conducted
again now it is checking with like EMA 9
and 36 with an allocation 0.90.
So it says like draw down exploded to
37.9. It is discarding. So it is
discarding if any experiment which is
failing by the draw down is increasing.
It is discarding those experiments.
Now it is trying with EMA plus RSI 75
with overbought levels.
Sharp return reduced sharp ratio is good
max on reduced so still the score is not
good enough it's discarding
so it's it's coming with different ideas
as you can see like right even though
some of the experiments are not going
good so far
this is [clears throat] experiment
number 5
1030 plus ATR trailing with an
allocation of like 0.95 percentage.
So 190.86
is sharp ratio. Max draw down is 30.96.
Again the return went up slightly but
draw down jumped to 30.95. So the
rolling window trailing stop isn't
working well. So it is discarding again.
So multiple experiments are getting
discarded.
Now how it's going with experiment
number six. It's using ADX as an entry
filter.
So far none of the experiments is going
good so far.
37.81k 81. Totally terrible experiment
and this time it is adding like EMA 1025
with 8% stop-loss exit and uh allocation
is like 9 90 means 90% of the money is
part in that strategy
every single time.
As you can see like every experiment
right it is committing and if it is not
working it is also discarding the those
as well.
So 177
so it is thinking like things are not
working good. So the real problem during
draw periods the AMA crossover stays in
the losing period. So it's trying to
think slightly in a different way.
I think so far not even a single success
yet
the model is struggling a bit. I think
now the return is much better 203%age
return jumped. So what it says like
return jumped button also went from 24
to 27 but slight score slightly worse
right. Um yeah so let's see slight
improvement but still not enough which
means again it is discarded right. So
the numbers are not improving the
overall number has to improve.
I don't know why it is asking yes every
single time it says unandboxed
but I already enabled sandbox right
it's already sandbox is enabled
almost like eight experiments so far. Uh
no improvements at all. Everywhere the
draw is somewhat increasing.
Next time total returns are not that
great.
That is also failing.
It was using uh EMA 13 with wider
separation.
Now experiment number 11. EMA 825 plus
MC histogram greater than zero. Entry
condition. It's adding some filters.
I think when I tried in the morning with
15 years of data in state bank of India
um I was using a different uh goal right
in the morning. So there
probably out of 10 experiments three
failed and seven passed right but here
everything is failing.
We'll see in which experiment it's going
to conduct which is going to pass
it is having an entry with a different
EMA and exit with a different EMA
like first time the score improved right
so you can see like from this is the old
score the new score is like 939 return
jumped from 172 to 194 draw down was
almost similar and we still have 29
trades. This is the first improvement.
Keep this commit. So it's going to keep
the commit over here. Rest all the
commits would have been ignored.
So where all these commits are there?
All these commits are still locally
only. It is not pushed to the GitHub
yet. Unless we want to push it, it's
still visiting in your local commit
only.
Maybe one more improvement. I think
it's a higher return but draw on went
higher. So draw on is something which is
is not getting down. So so far we got
only one little success.
Let's keep trying with different
numbers, different allocations.
Yeah, we could have done the
optimization but it is not only changing
the values, it is also changing
different filters,
different uh uh different indicators
it's trying to bring as a filter Okay.
Or you can also give diverse set of uh
indicators which are the indicators you
can consider using as a filter. More
instructions, more powerful instructions
you're going to give uh more improvement
it can do. So now it is trying to use
Ballinger band with expanding entry
filter.
Total return is 5.95. I think it's going
to get discarded. It's a terrible one.
entry filters consistently hurt. So it
says like what it says it's now it says
let me focus purely on asymmetric EMA
tuning and allocation. The winning combo
was 10 30 and 50 at 80. Let me try
slightly different exits
again. A little bit improvement in the
returns
but EMA 60 exit is too slow
so far. Only one positive commit is what
we got.
So where I can see the commits you can
go and see over here. Right? So this is
what the auto research asymmetric EMA
and every one every yellow one what
you're going to see is like a positive
commits
improved strategy still the strategy
same 10 30 MA crossover only but
slightly an enhanced strategy
now I'm not interfering anything like
it's keep on conducting experiments it
keeps on going in a loop right so let's
say if it is sandboxed as of now it is
not sandboxed yet I don't know why it
says unsandboxed if it sandbox it will
not even ask for this yes kind of thing
it keeps on running in a loop. We'll be
keep on running like conducting hundreds
of experiments.
Identical score to the base symmetric.
The second entry didn't fire. So this is
also almost similar score. So it's going
to discard that as well.
So we want the overall value to go down.
again it's going to discard I think
yeah I know EMA crossover is a pathetic
strategy but
on a daily scale it makes it's okay to
have such kind of strategies
I'm not trying to justify you should use
EMA crossover but just consider this as
an experiment right
I just little curious like how the AI
models are trying to figure out on its
own like what works what doesn't works
rather than we trying to break our heads
the AI will be breaking the heads for
you
experiment number 21 right
I don't know how long this is going to
keep going on.
So when is the loop expected to end?
Until the goal is not met, right? It
keeps on going in a loop.
So so far uh not much.
Yeah, it it got a first new best score.
Slight improvement return dropped like
from
here the return dropped but draw down
improved significantly like from 24 it
went to like 22 right so the moment of
exit is protecting capital during draw
downs I'm going to keep this that's what
it's going to say it is also learning
from the past experiment as well which
worked which doesn't work so it'll try
to figure out like from there it'll try
to enhance it by increasing the
allocation or something like that of
course if you increase allocation rate
automatically draw also increase that's
the problem
return increases but raon also increases
parallel
so that's what I said like return
increases but ra also goes higher so
that's not a great idea by the way
it cannot touch the allocation
It's trying to reduce the momentum look
back.
It can even conduct thousands of
experiments also.
And that's what a Ralph loop is all
about. Let me try to get you what a
Ralph loop is all about.
Probably we can go to CLA.
What is a Ralph loop?
So the Ralph loop also called as Ralph
vigum technique is an autonomous
iterative development methodology for
claudia code name after persistent never
give up character from the Simpsons
right
so as it is simplest as Joffrey Huntley
describes is Ralph is a bash loop a
simple while loop while true so that
keeps on repeating feeds an AI agent a
prom file allowing it to iteratively
improve its working work until
completion so how long it's going to go
on it's going to keep on going on until
the target is achieved or unless you say
like boss stop right you just press an
escape key. It's going to keep going in
a loop. So means it's going to consume a
lot of tokens.
In my case, it's fine.
So far only we have like two successful
experiments.
It's trying with a different momentum
look back. Maybe we should have said
like you should you should use optimize
to figure out the fastest way rather
than changing the values one by one
and now the return improved I think yeah
huge improvement you see that there is a
huge improvement in the score like from
0.93 7.99 means return jumped sharp
ratio also jumped draw down to 26.66 66
draw down was worse but overall score is
getting better right um yes so overall
score is coming down means we're getting
very closer to zero it's a great
progress
so we have like three successful
experiments so let me keep pushing it
just trying to uh
see whether it is able to reduce further
or
You see that it's adding the commit
again one more improvement score now
gone down to like 228 that's a massive
improvement return jump to 292 one of
the target is met sharp ratio 1.04 04
second target is also met. Only the draw
down is not met, right? So like
this is crazy. I don't know what changes
it had done but let's see like this is a
very close
it's trying small variation in the
momentum look back to see like so it
knows how much to adjust depends upon
the strategy right so it's seeing like
whether if I can change the momentum
look back to like nine or maybe it might
try to come back to seven and see like
will there be any drastic improvement or
not even a better score one more
enhanced score right so your draw down
gone from like 20 to 19 very close to
the 18% Say target
very close again 290 sharp ratio is
like.996 draw down is like 19.
So it is trying to work very closer
using this
can end here but let's see like whether
it's able to achieve all the three
targets or not. Almost two has been met.
So score went up. So now the score is
going up. So that means uh look back 10
is loose. So it's going to discard it
obviously
because we already had a better score
ratio still 1.2 need to be achieved that
is also that is one more thing is there
right but it's able to maybe 1.2 two is
too big number. I should have maybe I I
should have set to like one.
Let's see
allocation. It should not increase
because it's going to increase the draw
down. That's a bad idea. Return is
jumping but at the same time your draw
down also will be jumping higher.
Yeah, it's the same thing like return
jumped but uh draw on goes to like 20
sharp ratio barely moved right it's one
now score is worse so it's going to
discard it yeah even I will discard just
because return went up but the other
parameters are not going up it's not a
good idea
so the sharp ratio and drawon are the
remaining gaps I need to reduce volat
it's trying to see like what if I try to
reduce the volatility of the equity
curve. Let me try.
So
it's trying a different methodology.
It says like I I can't do dynamic
allocation since prepare.py uses a fixed
allocation float. So I cannot change the
prepare.py.
Let me focus on what I can change. It
can change only the signals, right? You
cannot change uh fixed allocation
allocation fixed over here. Means uh you
can either use an 70% allocation or 80%
allocation. You cannot keep on changing
the allocation every single time
dynamically.
Of course it if it have been that it
could have been a better one.
Again returns are going down. The new
experiment is failing
but it's this time draw down is less
than 16%. we are able to achieve but
returns are dropping right so now it's
need to find a middle ground the
strategy has to find a middle ground
somewhere in between
experiment number 30 right so 3day
so it's it's checking whether 3day if it
is rising uh whether the signals are are
we able to reduce unwanted bad trades or
something like that it's adding couple
of more filters that way 3day rising
slope entry
total returns are 211
still not enough we need 250 is the
number I given right
better returns higher allocation but
draw down went back to 18.93 sharp ratio
still at84
score is 050 50.
The current best score is 212. return to
90%age.
This time score is 27 return is good
but maybe other values could be not good
enough.
again it's trying a different approach
again once again return is good
very close so current best is 212 but we
got like 215 draw down dropped to 18.44
44 almost at 18.8 target and return is
like 264 but sharp ratio is like 96 very
slightly lower
I know getting into 1.2 two is very
tough I would say somewhere we may need
to stop
because getting an ratio on a trend
following model that two with an EMA
crossover that is very difficult I know
that
but let's see if at all the model is
able to figure out maybe if I run
throughout the day the model somewhere
it'll be able to figure out but all
these are very simple experiments only
nothing
It's ready trying to reduce allocation.
Yeah, that's a good idea. Trying to
reduce an allocation is a good idea
because your RON gets reduced. your uh
return will reduce a little bit but
that's fine but your radon also get
controlled
and draw on is below uh below 18%age but
return dropped sharp ratio is like 987
it's getting middle ground right 75 it's
trying to adjust so that uh returns also
able to pass and draw down is also able
to get around like 18
the total return is 262%age
I think new best score like.169 right
you can see that um the new best score
is a.169 that means almost target is met
sharp ratio 1.2 2 as I said it's very
difficult max draw down we are able to
get like 18% so I'm going to stop here
right so I'll say like I'll say no to
that
or maybe I'll say
um yes and I'll say like let it commit
and then I'll stop here because I know
right the sharp ratio is not going to
happen from 1.2 two it need to push
sharp ratio it's it's going to figure
out but uh
um it says like shen ratio is 1.52 it's
but I'm going to say first let's let it
add and then I'm going to say like let's
stop here and uh tell me what is the
strategy last experiment that you had
conducted
it it's coming with more uh it's it got
one more best score so sharp ratio is
now jumping but ra is like 18.26 26 it's
going to keep it up but because it's a
new best score numbers are still keep
reducing more lesser the number better
the strategy is going to be slightly
changing the variation in allocation so
that we can bring down the draw down we
can bring down best score I mean we can
we can produce more best scores
so new best score yeah so as I said like
new best score is there draw down is
17.82 82 and return is 273. Sharp ratio
improved to one. So I'll say like I I'll
escape here right I'll say an escape.
So I want to say like uh
u can we use the sharp ratio target to
one
um cuz it is a trend following system.
My bad
that score I mean my bad that
I should never said 1.2
So it's adjusting the sharp ratio
because I said so otherwise it cannot
adjust unless I I'm the one who is
modifying the targets.
Now once again it is trying to conduct
the experiments. All targets are met.
So,
so we'll we'll say like uh what is the
last score
I mean last uh strategy
where all the targets are met
37 experiments out of that only eight
successful one where we They're slowly
able to reduce lot of failed one.
So you can see that. So what was the
strategy is all about is
same instead of 10 and 30 EMA crossover
we using 12 and 30 the standard EMA
crossover that's the entry but exit. So
we have two conditions. EMA 12 crosses
below EMA 50
and uh EMA 12 has been declining for
nine consecutive days and closes below
EMA 12. That's a momentum exit cut
losses before they become big draw
downs.
Allocation 73% of the capital per trade
nothing much right. So there's a the
exit is little different and allocation
initially it was like 75 allocation we
are just reducing it to 73%age so that
all the three targets are getting met
right [clears throat] so what is the
effect
holding winning trades 40% longer
compared to the previous one it was here
in this case it was holding the winning
trades boosting total returns
earlier it was having an uh 9-day
momentum exit it is happening. So if it
is declining for nine consecutive day
the EMA is declining it going to cut
down the positions pretty much faster
and uh allocation also fine- tuned
that's what the final result is this was
the baseline what we had earlier and
after conducting multiple experiments
what was the improvement so improvement
is done across the scale there has been
an improvement is here minor improvement
in the win rate profit factor huge
improvement max draw down yes definitely
a huge improvement
total return a huge improvement sharp
ratio reasonable improvement even 8 to1
is like it's a decent improvement so I'm
going to say like can you provide the
equity curve
and tier sheets point tier sheets
because vectorb right it's not just only
do the back test it also provides you
various metrics as well I can provide
you the equity curve and the quanter
sheets so all those things you can find
inside
um you can you can find inside
the vector BT skills.
Now what is likely to go away is like
people going and doing a manual back
testing that is going to be gone.
So these are you can see these are the
list of experiments succeeded
experiments. It was discarding all the
unsuccessful experiment it was
discarding.
So that any strategy each and everyone
is every commit is a strategy over here.
Now all these are still holding locally
and this is a final enhanced equity
curve and draw down around like
17.66%age
max draw down. You can also get the
quant tier sheets as well. So let's go
and get the quant sheets.
So inside crossover
we have here. Yeah. So here is the
quantity sheets final.
Come on
reveal in the finder. I'll try to open
up the quantity sheets. Right. you'll
get very comprehensive metrics including
the benchmark results. Right?
So what I'm going to do I'm going to
commit um
commit the experiment
to
GitHub.
So it will be committed as a separate
branch as I said right it'll be pushed
So you may have to install GitHub CLA
for this right. So you have to install
GitHub CLA, you have to have NodeJS for
installing the vectorBD skills. You need
to have Python
and you need to have open algo or even
if you don't have open algo you can
consider using Yahoo Finance right
because the vector BT skills supports Y
finance if you don't have open algo.
All right. So the link has been pushed
over here. Let me controlclick.
So we have an separate branch. It has
been pushed to separate branch. We have
two branches over here. main branch
which contains what our uh simple EMA
crossover and we have three files
prepare.py strategy.py Pi and programm
explain what is what right and then we
have the final experiment which has been
conducted all the 17 experiment this
doesn't contains any experiments you can
see there is only two commits this
doesn't contains any experiments all the
experiments are in the auto research APR
5 branch right so here almost each and
every commit is a successful
improvement in the results right finally
um we are able to bring down because uh
I should have said sharp ratio as one
itself it's my bad like I have to change
it to from 1.2 to 1 so that all targets
are met otherwise
I don't know maybe uh after a long maybe
another 1 hour or 2 hour later that 1.2
into target also would have met somehow
right but it it would have been doing a
lot of iterative search without any
human intervention right this is a basic
example but I'm sure like you you guys
know how to enhance it with your own
strategy you want to enhance your
strategy maybe you can say like what to
use what not to use you don't want to
use a simple RSI simple EMA as a filter
you can just simply say that so that
your preparepy will be or programm will
we return the rules accordingly right so
or how what kind of filters that you
want to use what kind of experiment that
you want to conduct what experiment you
don't want to conduct if you give such
kind of things you'll be getting an
complete enhanced output probably you'll
get wide variety of ideas that's what
you can get mostly
so are you guys clear about what we had
done so
Is there a way to ensure you don't burn
out lot of tokens?
Maybe you have to monitor it if it is um
it's better to go with codeex or cloud
code so that you go with an a fixed
plans. So if you are don't try to use
directly the APIs API key don't directly
use use codex GPT plan or maybe
anti-gravity ensure that you're in a
fixed plan trying to use in cursor um
maybe it could be a good idea because a
single thread conversation
I'm I'm still not sure like how cursor
will be conducting because your tokens
will your your each and every
conversation will be consumed so you'll
be running out of credits. it's very
faster but something like cloud code and
codeex where you have unlimited access
not exactly unlimited access but kind of
an unlimited access um still they'll be
having a rate limit
so as long as that is uh not hit yes you
can go and try this out right
but don't try this loop experiment if
with an real uh direct APIs I'm not
using direct API here I'm having a Mac
subscription So uh even I can run like
this this kind of experiments I can run
another 100 experiments also I'll be
able to run for the day.
So again Ganesh is asking when the loop
is expected to end
infinite experiments as long as the
target is not met they'll be keep on
running in a loop no matter what.
So be aware of those things. So try to
set reasonable targets. Don't try to set
miracles in your back testing report.
You may get but that will be super
overoptimized. Not necessarily it has to
work. So try to set some some reasonable
goals right. So what is possible? What
is not possible? You might have an idea
about it. So based on that you set the
target goals and the AI should be able
to conduct various experiment and it
should be able to met.
Any other questions before we calling it
a day?
Are you guys able to understand the uh
EMA crossover and auto research?
If yes, please type yes so that I get an
idea that you guys are able to
understand the context and what is going
behind the scenes.
All right. Arun said yes and Ganesh says
yes.
Mun says yes.
All right, great. So, let me pause here.
We'll come back in yet another session
and we'll talk more about it. Thank you.