in the summer of last year I shared my
scalloping robot and then there were a
lot of requests if I could add
additional features to the EA to make it
more suitable for Prof fform so 2 weeks
ago I shared a video which includes
those additional features that make it
more suitable for Prof fform challenges
including a panel so you can track all
of the stats in one go in one place and
all the quotes shared in the videos and
fully explained in details and now there
are a lot of requests if the same
scalping year written in metat trater 5
language can be converted into metat
trater 4 so here we go in this video we
will take the scalping robot script that
we wrote from metat Trader 5 and we will
convert it into metat Trader 4 and this
method is universal so if you follow the
video and learn it you will be able to
take any metat Trader 5 script and
convert it into metat Trader 4 following
the same logic with no more Shenanigans
let's
start now I will not go through the full
back testing of the EA because I've
already shared the back testing in
several videos that I've made before but
let's do take a look at the actual
performance of the EO over the last two
months I have used this EA in my
portfolio over many many years which for
NDA reasons I cannot show but to compare
my results with the results that people
were sending to me after I released this
EA I created a small account and applied
the EA with the setting that I have
shared so that when people are sending
their results to me I at least have a
comparative base to compare it against
so let's log on to the VPS and here we
have our results for the last 2
months so if I go currencies by
currencies so starting with Bitcoin we
have made about 7 % profit we've had a
few TPS hit because when Bitcoin moves
fast it moves really fast if I go to
Euro USD a similar story we had one loss
in the beginning and since then the EA
has been performing quite decent there
are a couple of pp hits one this one and
this one very close probably as well and
we have about 9% profit on Euro USD so
Euro USD has also been performing really
really well then go to Gold so far we
have not had any loss one TP hit the
rest are aggressive trailing of the stop
losses so small profits overall
amounting to about 8% profit as well
then going to
gbpusd this one has had two different
losses and one near TP hit and all
together about
1.6% of profit then we look at us Tech
and this one has had two different
losses and it's slightly negative but
very close to break even depending on I
mean it's not too many trades so far and
then to USD JPY which is around 6% in
profit one is stop- loss hit versus all
of these are aggressive trailing of the
stop losses so resulting in either small
profits or a very small loss because of
slippage probably all together 32%
profit in the last 2 months if we look
at the report we can see the EA has made
about €3,000 in profit and have lost
about half of it looking at the symbol
Euro USD has been doing the best
followed by by gold Bitcoin and USD JPY
now the last time when I shared the
result Bitcoin was doing amazingly well
and was here so probably Bitcoin has
taken a few yeah Bitcoin has taken a
loss and came down here if we look at
month by month we started in the middle
of December but I shut off the EA during
the Christmas period and over the new
year so nothing major in December
January we had about ,000 or 20% profit
approximately and this month in February
in the first 22 days we're about 8% in
profit now coming back to the settings
I'll not go through them in very much
detail but yeah it's 3% with 100 bars in
this for the Forex profile and this for
the crypto profile gold profile and US
indices news filter is true avoiding
these news for USD currency only RSI
filter is on I'm not using the moving
average filter currently and the last
thing that I want to say is up until now
I had been uploading my code files into
the store as well I've seen way too many
times my codes appearing on Telegram
Channel where people are trying to sell
it for five times the price 10 times the
price I don't have any problem with
people selling my code under their name
but then at least put an effort and take
an evening or two to actually sit down
and actually follow the video and code
it for yourself before you start to call
it your own and try to sell it so going
forward I will be uploading the working
EA EX file so the people who do not
either have time to sit down and Cote
for themselves or do not have
understanding enough or they just want
to use the EA and not want to learn
learn the algorithm behind it they can
still download it but I'm not putting up
my code file for people to download and
try and sell it and of course I will
still share all of the codes in the
videos so if anybody wants to actually
take the time to learn all of the codes
with full details will still be
available for free so if you're one of
those people fill up a flask with coffee
get something to eat sit down and let's
start
coding we start in the metat trader 4
terminal and I'll start by going to the
meta course language editor which is
here if if you click on that this screen
should open up for you so this is a
blank screen now I've already created a
folder YouTube shared where I'm going to
create these files So within meta editor
4 we're going to create a new year and
it's an expert advisor and I'm just
going to call I'm going to call this
regular disc scalping
PA and then if I press next next and
finish we get this opening template now
we have all these codes from the time
that we wrote the scalping robot
including the gold Bitcoin and us
indicis with news filter RSI filter and
Ma so I'm basically talking about this
video here so we're going to start from
that so this is the mq5 file which is
valid for metat Trader 5 I'm just simply
going to copy everything and go to meta
editor 4 select everything delete and
paste everything from mq5 file so our
starting point for the conversion is
starting from an mq5 written code and
then we're only going to make the
changes required to convert it into mt4
so even though today we're converting
the scalping robot from mt5 to mt4 but
you can follow the same process to
convert any metat Trader 5 file into a
metat Trader 4 now the first thing which
I'm going to do is I'm going to delete
all of this the reference to the trade.
mq file and within that we had the C
trade C position info and c order info
because metat Trader 4 does not work
like that so I'm going to delete all of
that and now if I compile I should get a
lot of Errors so I'll go up to the top
and I'll start from what are the issues
and I'm going to continue to solve them
until the time that we have our year
perfectly running so I'll start with the
first one which is the group declaration
is without type which is basically this
and to remove this you basically Define
a property which is is strict so if you
define that property then all of this
messages should be gone so if I compile
again and go up now I don't have those
Errors By the name group so that one is
taken care of then the next one I see is
that this identifier has already been
defined which is I am defining the start
hour and end hour separately and then
assigning it to start our sh input and
eh input even though the number of hours
are practically the same so I can
combine it together and this is what I'm
getting here as well that this has
already been defined underscore 100
toore 100 one way you can resolve this
is by putting an underscore after
instead of before but what we're going
to do is we don't need two different
enums we're happy with just one so I'm
going to delete this one and I'm just
going to call this
one enum
hour and then if this is enum hour then
I'm assigning enum hour
to these two
variables and this should now take care
of all of these error messages so if I
compile I have 94 errors remaining so I
go up but all of those are gone now now
the next one is that the trade is an
Undeclared identifier and that is
because we deleted the reference to the
trade. mq file so this we're going to
correct later next I go to set expert
magic number that function doesn't work
because we don't have the trade variable
anymore so I'm just going to delete this
and we're going to assign the magic
number to the trade when we're opening
or closing the trade manually this is
all fine I don't need the S Choice
equals s input so I'm going to remove
them and because I don't need them so
I'm going to go up here and I'm also
going to remove the variable definitions
I'm changing the bars end to 100 because
that's what I'm currently using now if I
compile again I still have 94 errors
let's go up to the top and now I see
that irsi wrong parameter mq5 deals with
indicators through handles and those are
defined in the onit function but mt4
does not do it that way I can't use
these anymore but I can still copy paste
this formula and I'll go down where the
RSI filter function is and here instead
of using the copy buffer method which is
particular to
md5 and I can't use this in
md4 I'm going to just simply Define
RSI as irsi which is Prov by providing
the symbol value RSI time frame
everything else remains exactly the same
the only thing is here it asks for a
shift in mt4 as well so I need to put a
shift I can give it the last candle or I
can give it the current candle I'm going
to give it the current candle and then
I'm going to remove this double colon
and then because now I'm calling this
RSI either I can change the name to RSI
now because here we're checking RSI now
is above RSI level up and RSI now I'm
going to change the name of the variable
from RSI to RSI now the rest of the
function remains okay to me so I can go
back up and then the second one was the
IMA and we cannot use it through a
handle method because that is particular
to mt5 so I'm going to copy this formula
and then I'm going to delete both of
these because I don't need them and then
I go down to ma function is ma filter
and here again I cannot use these mt5
functions so I'm just going to remove
them and I'm going to call this variable
as moving average now because that is
the variable that we're going to be
testing here and I can assign it the
value by pasting now the formula that we
copied from above providing the symbol
the time frame everything else Remains
the Same the only thing I now need to
provide additionally is the integer
shift like which candle are we copying
are we copying the current candle or the
previous candle or I'm just going to
copy the current candle I'm going to
make it a little bit bigger so you guys
can see now if I compile I should have
fewer errors so now I have 91 errors so
let's go up and now this s choice we
deleted the asset Choice before we were
assigning the value of the sh input and
eh
input to S choice and eh choice but now
we can directly use them we don't need
to assign them so I'm just going to go
here and instead of s Choice I'm going
to type sh input and here I'm going to
go eh input and eh input so we basic
Bally directly assigning that if the
hours now is less than the sh input so
whatever hour has been selected then
close all the orders and if the hours
now is greater than eh input and is not
zero meaning it's not inactive then
close all the orders so then we can only
trade during the trading period allowed
if I compile now these two should also
disappear and now I have 89
errors I go up and now these two are
also gone now I go to O
issue and this has to do with the way
that metatrader 5 Loops through all the
positions and all the orders is
different from metatrader 4 in metat
Trader 5 you have orders total and
positions total but in MP4 you only have
orders total and then you have the order
type which is either op buy or op sell
so we're going to have to change the way
that we we Loop through these to find
the total number of buys and sell which
are currently open I'm going to delete
all of this and I'm going to write the
code for metatrader 4 where you still
have the four function but now you're
only going through the orders total
exactly the same way which is orders
total minus
one but then you order select by index I
whichever is the I index that is looping
through and then you go select by
position and then you provide more
trades and then you go if it's op buy or
it's op buy stop so if it's a open
position by or if it's a pending by stop
order in both cases if the order symbol
equals symbol and Order magic number
equals input magic number in that case
our byy total is by total + one
otherwise if the order type is open
position cell or it's a cell stop order
and the symbol is our symbol and the
input magic number is our input magic
number in that case we say that the cell
total is increased by one so is exactly
the the same thing that we did in
metadata 5 but doing it in a different
way and orders in mt4 include open
positions as well now if I compile again
now I have 70 errors left now the bul of
the errors I can very simply remove
because metat Trader 4 does not have a
built-in calendar so I'm going to go
down to the is upcoming news and I can
either delete the entire function or I
can just put a forward SL
asterisk and then at the end and asteris
forward slash so md4 is going to treat
all of the codes written here as Commons
thereby we're basically disabling this
entire function of is upcoming news and
if I'm disabling it here then up here
where we were checking for is upcoming
news I'm also going to have to remove
that or I can do the same thing as
this and then here as that so I'm making
this this portion here as a comment now
if I file now I am only left with 36
errors so let's go back up to the top
once again there is somewhere we're
using the trade function and that trade
function cannot be used because we don't
really have the reference to the the the
trade. mq file it doesn't work in
metatrader 4 so I'm going to have to
write the the order send command to send
the bias stop to in metat tra 4 I'm
going to write it below first so that
you guys can see what is happen
happening in in metadata 4 we send we
use the order send command instead of
using the trade. mq files C trade class
so we order send by sending the symbol
and this you can check as well so if you
say order
send and this is case sensitive so if
you say order s is small you're not
going to get anything so you have to
know well you can write a start writing
order but then you can select by going
down to order send but this is very case
sensitive so it is s as a capital and
then SC and d and then when I open the
bracket it asks me for the symbol which
is the symbol then it asks me what kind
of order am I sending so I am sending an
OP buy stop because we're sending a buy
order a buy a stop order so I say buy
stop and then I provide the values of
lots and
entry and then if there is a slipage
factor but that's useless so just put
zero and then the stop loss then the
take profit what is the a string that I
want to put I'll say
Mr cap
free then input magic number which is
the input magic number that be sending
and this is where it's also different
between metat data 5 and metat data 4 in
metad data 5 you already in
initialization assign a magic number to
the trade class by saying trade. set
magic number but here you have to send
it with the order I'm sending the magic
number as the variable input magic
number and then what is the expiration
and then what color Arrow to put on the
chart so I'm going to delete this and
now we can delete the old mty 5 function
and the reason I'm doing this if is
because if you remove
this then you're going to get a warning
that the order send should be
checked the return value of order send
should be checked so you should check
whether or not it has s be successful
and this is why I'm saying that if it is
successful that if order send happens
then just return meaning exit this
function so this this is how I'm
checking now when I'm changing the buy
function then I also need to change the
sell function because here again this is
using the trade. mq file the trade class
so I'm going to write the function as it
is written in metat Trader 4 which is
order send providing the symbol and now
it is a sell stop type again entry LS
sltp let's call it Mr
Cape input magic number expiration and
the green color and then I'm checking it
and this Mr Caffrey is because I'm
trying to move my channel from no
shanigan which is a faceless channel to
a channel where I also show my face
because YouTube has been giving me a lot
of issues with the with the faceless
Channel motion anigan I will be slowly
transitioning so for a while I will put
all of the videos that I put on Mr cfre
also here in noan andigan but I would
suggest to already start using the Mr
cafrey channel uh because slowly and
gradually I will transition everything
there okay I can remove this because
this is MP5 related
and let's check here as well on the top
now in metatrader 5 you get the asked
value by using the symbol info double
and asking for the symbol ask value in
metat Trader five ask and bid prices are
automatically given so I can remove that
and just change this
to Capital ask and now you can see that
it changed to Pink which basically means
that it is an assigned metat trator 4
variable which which is a predefined
variable so this is the ask the TP and
SL I don't need to change anything like
now double Lots so we start with the
whatever is the broker's minimum value
so as a matter of fact instead of
putting a 0.01 I can say get the symbol
through simple info double get the
symbol's volume minimum so whatever is
the minimum volume for that we start
with that and then if the risk
percentage is greater than Z then we use
the function calculate Lots as in metad
data 5 now I'm going to do the same
thing here as well in the cell we don't
need to get the bid value it comes
automatically as a bid variable with a
capital
B I don't need to change the tpnl
setting and again here I'm going to copy
paste from
here that lets start as a
default with the symbol info double
getting the symbol volume minimum and if
you are using the metat trader 5 version
as well then you can potentially change
that as well because say for Bitcoin the
minimum value is
0.001 on many Brokers so maybe it's a
better idea to start the lot size as
default from a 0.01 on bitcoin and not
0.01
hardcore the rest seems fine to me so
let's compile and see how many errors do
we have now and we have 30 errors left
so let's go back up once again there is
somewhere we have used the OD function
which is to get the order information so
here on close all orders what we were
doing was we were going through all of
the orders total which is an mt5
terminology now we need to write in
metat Trader 4 format so I'll write it
above and then I'll delete the the one
at the bottom and this is the method for
checking the same
thing in metat Trader 4 orders total in
metat Trader 4 in includes both open
positions and orders in metat trat five
they are different positions total and
orders total so when we are going
through the total orders exactly the way
that we are going
here and the selection method is
different it's not or select by index it
is order select providing the index
value then select by position and more
trade but now we need to check that it
is a buy stop and it's a sell stop
because it can also be a position open
and in case the trading period has
finished so it's 9:00 in the night and
the trading period has finished we don't
want to close the open positions so this
is the additional thing that we add on
top of because here we check for the
symbol is our symbol and magic number is
our magic number we're checking this
here as well that the order magic number
is input magic number and Order symbol
is symbol in metat Trader 4 language but
now we are adding one more condition
which is it needs to be buy a stop or
sell stop because if it is an OP
buy just this then it's a position which
is open and we don't want to close and
open position we only want to delete the
orders which are pending on the server
once the trading period is finished so
we check for that as well then we get
the ticket number exactly the same way
as here but not using the or ticket but
like I showed before you start typing
order and then you get order ticket so
this is the way it works in matter Traer
four so we get that put it into ticket
and then we use the order delete command
by sending the ticket number and giving
it a color for the arrow because you
need to give a color for the arrow as
well which you don't need to do for
matter
file and then again I'm checking if this
was successful otherwise I'm going to
get a warning message here that this
should be checked so I'm just checking
if it is successful then just exit the
function return so I can now delete the
metat trader five part which is this
part so now this function has been
converted into metat Trader 4 as well
now if I compile before I had 30 errors
and now if I compile I have 23 errors
left let's go back up and somewhere we
have the same issue with the positions
total because somewhere we were checking
for position total which is in the
trailing stop and positions total does
not exist in metat Trader 4 it's orders
to total and then sub selection through
op sell and op buy as order type so we
will have to change that but I'm going
to come back to the trailing stop later
let's see if there was something else
that we can potentially take care of
before I don't know what this
is and it's coming from here so
somewhere something is wrong here yeah
there is an
additional closing bracket that I
mistakenly typed here so I'm going to
remove that and if I
compile now we only have these 20 errors
and these are between line number
350 and line number
367 so they are definitely only related
to the trailing stop because it starts
at 350 so the errors start
here and they go all the way to
367 which is here so all of these errors
are definitely coming from trailing stop
which then tells me that the rest of the
EA has been converted into metat TR 4
and now we need to convert the trailing
stop uh this one is going to take a
little bit of care so follow it properly
now once again we don't need to to get
the ask and bid value it comes in mt4 as
ask and bid so I can delete
that then we know that we don't use the
loop as positions total in metadata 4 we
use orders total so I'll start with that
by replacing this with with this and I
need to have an opening
bracket so instead of positions total
now I'm going orders total well that's
the way metat Trader rules then we
cannot select position by select by
using the C-Class position from trade.
mq so now we need to change that as well
and the way to do that in metat Trader
is to say if order select index I
whatever is the index currently select
by position and more trades once that is
selected in metad data 4 you don't
really need the ticket number because
that's not how metat trator rolls so I
delete this and then if position magic
number equals input magic number and
position symbol equal symbol that we
will need to change as if order Magic
number equals input magic
number and Order symbol equals
symbol then if position type equals
position type by we need to then change
it into metatrader 4 language is
order type equals
op
by then if bid is less than position
price open well this again position that
function doesn't exist in meta 4 so we
need to get the price open so order open
price is greater than trigger stop- loss
so this is fine then PP equals order
take
profit SL equals bid and bid is now with
that Capital so it's a pink value so
it's the generic
MP4 variable so SL equals this the rest
is fine if a stop loss is bigger than
the current stop loss so again we now
need to find to get
order a stop
loss and the stop loss is not equal to
zero so that is fine and in that case
modify the position and you modify the
position in meta Trader 4 not by
referencing to the trade trade C class
but by sending a direct order saying
order
modify sending it the order ticket
number and this is why we didn't have to
get it here Order open price so you need
to send the order ticket number which is
again whatever is the selected order
order ticket from there and then the
open price then the stop loss that we
have calculated here then you can either
write the TP down here or you can just
simply send the order take profit which
is the value that we're assigning here
anyways then no expiration and then
color none because we don't want to
really assign an arrow every time there
is a modification otherwise you're going
to get too many too many arrows and
because we're sending the order take
profit directly so we also don't need
this DP here and once again why I'm
checking this if is because if I don't
check this if then I'm going to get a
warning down below that the auto
modifier should be checked now it should
be checked properly but I'm I'm happy
with just checking it and if it is okay
then saying continue like continue
meaning go
next to the rest of of the code I'm not
saying return because return will mean
exit the
function continue means continue the
same thing I'm going to have to do here
so instead of
position position type I'm going to have
to say order
type and instead of position type cell
I'm going to have to say op
cell and then ask is with a capital so
it's the generic mql4 variable this
looks fine to me now position open we
need to get in metat Trader differently
so it's order open price and we're not
going to need the TP so I can delete it
this again is going to be ask and did we
here change because this is this
ask is also here as bid so I need to
change this as well to bid okay and then
stoploss is order stop loss and then I'm
going to modify the position by using
the order modif if and once again
sending the order ticket number order
open price the new SL because that's the
only change which is practically going
to change and then returning back
whatever was the original order take
profit keep it no change to expiry and
then color none meaning I don't want to
see an arrow and then I'm checking it
just so that I don't get a warning and
then I say
continue so this should take care of
everything okay I'm missing a few
parentheses es so I'm going to put them
here so this parenthesis is
fine and this is this
one so I'm going to line it up with
four then this one I open the
parenthesis here and then it should
close all the way down here so what we
can do is we can potentially move this
up here and this one back so this one
becomes for four
and then this one becomes for if then
here I have an open is fine because it
should close here because all of these
codes are checked within this so this is
this one that one is okay I'm just going
to line it up properly so that I don't
conf get confused later then this if is
if it is aut type bu then it is
correctly ending up here because then we
go if it is aut type cell then this one
is if it is this one then this is also
closing correctly and this
if is this one and that is fine as well
and then if it is order type cell then
all of these codes so fine this should
be closing here and this one is opening
here and then all of these codes so yeah
this one is closing correctly as well
and then this one is closing here
correctly as well so I think now we have
all of the parenthesis correctly formed
so if I compile and I really hope that
there are no errors remaining and voila
we don't have any errors remaining so
now this metad data 5 code has been
converted into metadata 4 for the part
which we wrote in these three First
videos now that we have finished the
basic year now let's start looking at
the two additional modifications I a to
the e in this video which has two parts
two additional filters and then the
entire prop for modification so let's
first finish the additional features
which were to have different ways of
putting the lot sizes and then we will
add the trading is allowed on certain
week days and not allowed on certain
week days or over the weekend so these
two modifications now so if you have
written the mq5 E with me that one is
this with the additional features
where we added is trading Allowed by day
function so I'll start by copying this
function so I'll copy this function and
I'll go to met tra 4 go down to the
bottom and I'll add this function here
and let's see if we have any errors by
compiling and I think the only errors
I'm getting is that these fun these
variables are not declared so I go back
to meta editor 5 and go back up to the
top and this is where we defined all of
these functions for the trading Allowed
by days section so I'll copy this go
back to meta editor 4 and here at the
bottom I'm going to add this section so
all of these are now variables also
defined here so if I compile now there
are no errors so basically we have added
this function and convert it we didn't
have to convert anything for meta editor
4 here then going back to meta editor 5
for the lot sizes we change the lot size
we Chang the stuff around here where we
added another enum for lot type whether
it we want fixed Lots percentage of
balance percentage of equity or
percentage of free margin so I'm going
to copy that enum go to meta editor 4
and then up here at the top I'm going to
add this enum and what we had also done
was we moved all the enums in one place
I'm going to take all of the
enums and put
them and put them in one place as well I
don't think I have any other enum well
the news filter we're not going to be
using the news filter in metadata for
anyways because it's not available I
mean there are ways to put news filters
as well but there is no generic calendar
in metat trator 4 so you can't really
use that as a generic function so these
are all the enums so now that we have
enum lot type as well I go back to to
meta Trader 5 and now we need these
three variables so I copy them and then
here I will put here these three
variables but now I don't need the risk
percentage twice so I'm going to remove
one so now what we're going to have is a
drop- down button which is the enum lot
type so you can select whether it's
fixed lot balance Equity or free margin
and if it is fixed lot then you have
have to Define here or the user has to
Define here what is the fixed loss and
if it is part of the percentage of
balance or Equity or free margin then
we're going to use the risk percentage
method so now that we have these trading
inputs we go down to the calculate Lots
part because this is where we're going
to decide whether what the lot size is
going to be and there again as a
precaution we will start
with a default value of whatever is the
the minimum symbol volume which comes
from the broker so we start with that
and because I'm defining the Lots
variable here so I cannot redefine it
here so I remove the part double in
front of it and then I will exactly the
same way as we have in meta Trader 5 I
will have these three the account
balance the equity balance and the free
margin I think if it is blue it probably
is a default variable anyway so it will
get the value from metat Trader anyway
but doesn't hurt to get the value as in
account in for double account balance
account equity and account free margin
we get those Valu in here and then we
say the risk in the beginning is zero as
a default value and then switch through
the lot type the variable that we
created
here this lot type which is fixed slots
as zero balance as one Equity as two and
margin as three so switch through them
and if you find that the case is zero
which is the fixed Lots then in that
case simply Lots is going to be equal to
fixed Lots the variable that we are
asking the user to provide their input
in and if it is not and if it is case
one then it is based on account balance
so then account balance time the risk
percent divided by 100 if it is case two
then it is equity balance and then if
it's case three then it's free margin so
we assign the risk based on account
balance Equity or free margin based on
what's selected divide it by 100 because
it's a percentage and then we say break
so that if it if if it finds if it finds
that the case is zero then assign the
fixed loss and just return with the Lots
meaning exit the function you don't need
to do anything else but if it is not
zero then you look for one and in that
case break if it's not one then two and
if you find the two then break break
meaning break this function but go here
and then if it's three then break
meaning break the switch function and
then come down here so now the risk has
been defined and the rest of the
function is basically the same function
as metat 4 there is no language
difference between metadata 4 and
metadata 5 here so this should be okay
if I compile I'm getting
this as I'm I already defined it here so
I cannot redefine it I'm just going to
remove the word double in front and now
we should be good to go now one thing
which I forgot to do and which wasn't
which wasn't caught by metat Trader in
the errors is because once again metat
Trader only looks for syntax error it
doesn't look for logical errors so we
Define this is trading Allowed by day
function and we put all of the variables
here but we didn't use that function
anywhere but a metat is not going to
force us to use it so there are no
errors but there is a logical error
and for that we go to the ontick
function and here where we were checking
is RSI filter is upcoming news filter is
ma filter now we also need to check that
is trading allowed does not return a
true value and this is why I'm saying
not is trading allowed so as long as the
value coming here is
false then run these codes and if it
comes back as true then don't run these
codes so this is why we're saying not so
only run these codes course if is
trading allowed returns are false and
that is because if it is allowed on
Monday and today is Monday then return
true and trading is allowed on Monday
and and today is Monday so in that case
trading is allowed and this is why we're
seeing here if it's not meaning if it
returns a false then close all the
orders disable the trading and
everything else so if I compile now I
don't have any syntax error and I
hopefully do not have a logical error as
well so this completes our regular
version of the scalping e including the
ma filter the RSI filter the different
modifications required for Bitcoin gold
and US indices and also the new features
that I added which are the lot types and
also defining whether or not trading is
allowed on a certain day and now we can
move on to the prop F part so we go back
to meta editor 5 and now I'm going to
open up the prop firm version that we
had written and also we have had written
an include file by the name of prop from
panel now this prop from panel file is
written in a language which is allowed
by both met trater 5 and met trater 4 so
we don't really need to change anything
here except for when we will be
referencing where is the file located
for our mq4 so I can copy this go back
here and then I can select new and this
time I'm going to say I want an include
file file by the name mq and then I can
call it prop fir panel and then if I
finish it the file is going to open but
the file is not going to open here
because I have already written this file
as include here as prop from panel but
the file would open what you will do is
it will open with the default value you
can just simply select the entire thing
and delete and then just paste what you
have copied from metatrader 5
because it's the same mq file you can
also copy the file by going to the
folder open the folder in the include
folder you can copy this prop from panel
close then go to meta editor 4 and here
also open up the include folder and just
paste it here or you can create the file
and copy paste the stuff but here we're
not going to be changing anything except
the reference back to our meta mq4 file
you look for where this file is saved so
my file is saved in YouTube shared this
is where this EA is currently saved
regular scalping year if I open this
folder I can get
the value from expert onwards so I copy
this part come back to meta editor 4 in
the prop form go up to the top and I'm
going to write it here but you can see
what happen so you start start with
include and then dot dot means whichever
folder I am in in the include folder so
here is the include folder dot dot means
go up one folder so come out of this
folder then go into the experts folder
and within the expert folders go to
YouTube shared folder and then here is
the name of my file and I should
have and this is what I'm going to do
now I'm going to close this because I'm
going to change the
name and put underscores here because
metat Trader for some stupid reason
cannot deal with spaces so now this is
the file name with underscore so I can
open it again so this is my file metat
tror 4 and then I copy the name of the
EA put it here and then
mq4 and then close this so this is where
my metat Trader four file is saved and
I'm referencing it here in the mq folder
because when it will come to update
these it will be looking for the
beginning of day balance beginning of
week balance the all of these variable
values are going to come from the
scalping EA so I need to reference it
back by providing this here now one
thing which I'm going to do is because
this is the regular scalping e which we
have written so far let's compile it
again and it is all fine and now I'm
going to save a copy by going to file
save as in the same folder now I'm going
to call it prop
formore scalping here and I'm going to
copy this name as well so we're creating
a copy here and now our prop from panel
needs to be linked to the prop form
version so I'm keeping these two
versions separate from each other now if
I compile I will get thousands of Errors
because we still haven't created all of
the stuff which is prop firm related in
our nq4 file so let's start on that I'll
compile and I will have a lot of Errors
which is funny uh because we are still
not calling any yeah because we're still
not calling anything from the perform
panel and this is why we don't have any
error so
far also I think because up here now we
need to
reference to the prop file so I'm going
to say include and within the include
folder it is prop from panel file which
is this one so I'm referencing to it now
and within that I'm going to reference
to cop from Panel class and I'm
referencing it to a variable by the name
of panel now if I compile I should have
a lot of errors and that is because all
of these variables which this prop fun
panel is trying to use in the update
function all of these variables are not
really defined anywhere so let's go back
to the mq4 file the actual EA and let's
start adding these variables so these
variables we created in meta data 5 and
now we can copy paste
them into meta data 4 as well I don't
need this integer system choice because
we are using the system system type
directly or if we not then we're going
to get an error but I'm deleting it for
now and if I get the error then I'm
going to solve it later and then from
metat Trader 5 file at the end we had
this input group where we had all of the
Prof from Rules settings variables so
I'm going to copy
them and at the bottom here I'm going to
add all of them then on the
initialization function we had the panel
initialization
so let's copy
that and I'll come down here and after
the chart set integer I'm going to
create I'm going to copy paste or I'm
going to paste the panel
initialization then you would remember
in the profor metatrader 5 variation we
got rid of all of the shabang about
these profiles as crypto gold and
indices because they're practically the
same profile it's all percentage as a
percentage of price so why not combine
all of these so what I did in metat
Trader 5 and I'll do it here as well
which is I got rid of all of these
profiles and we replaced it with one
profile which is as a percentage of
profile
input and we don't need
this so I'm going to take this and then
copy
paste to meta Trader four so now we have
two profiles the Forex
profile and the percentage profile
exactly the same way as we have it here
the other thing was we had added an
order distance Point input here as well
and an order distance Point variable
here so I'm going to copy
this and paste this
here and then all of these
variables I'm going to paste them below
as
well in metadata 4 okay if I compile
now I have 20 errors left because it is
still looking for all of the gold and
indices and shabang like this and system
choices that we need to
change
so first of all this TP Point trigger
point is an order distance point this is
already defined somewhere else so let's
take a
look and it is defined here here so I'm
going to remove them from here so
they're only defined
here if you see these are exactly the
same variables but I just moved them
from here down to here and added the
order distance points as well because
these are all related to Forex Trading
input so I'm going to combine them
here if I compile again I have 16 errors
to fight with and the first one is order
distance Point variable is already
defined where is that one
defined see previous
declaration and it is defined here so uh
this we put this here as order distance
Point input in the Forex so we can't
have it double so let's move this down
here and if I compile now I don't have
that and now I have the system Choice
issue because here on initialization
what we were doing was if you select
Forex or Bitcoin or gold or us indices
then we have system choices so we
assigned it to a variable but now we
have gotten rid of all of that shebang
so I'm just simply going to delete
this then we go back to metat Trader 5
and instead of these we're going to
switch through the cases of what system
type has the user
selected so we
say we select this and then we paste it
here which is switch to the system type
what has the user selected here
as system type which is either he has
selected and we need to change this as
well because it's still the old stuff
so I'm going to go back to metat Trader
5 and system
type enum system type is this one now so
fix Pips profile or percentage of price
profile so I select that back to metat
trater
4 and paste it here so now we have these
two types instead of the previous ones
where we had four different profiles so
now user can s here as enum system type
the type whether it's fixed or
percentage of price and depending on
whether it's fixed or percentage of
price we're going to Loop through if
it's case Zero it's fixed Pips in that
case TP points become normal input by
the user and in case if it is as a
percentage then we need to calculate it
and we calculate it based on ask and in
metadata 4 you don't get the value of
ask by using the symbol in for double
method you basically simply get it as
calling the function calling the
variable ask then we don't need this
because we have already assigned these
here I'm going to delete them and then
if I go back to metat Trader we wrote
all of these codes for prop form
functions I'm going to copy
them and I'm going to paste them here as
well which are all
fine no need for any changes
because of metat Trader
4 and these ones as well we can just
simply copy paste them from metat Trader
5 into metat Trader 4 no need for any
conversion because it works exactly the
same way in metat Trader 4 as well then
these functions we already replaced the
RSI and moving
average and these two trailing type ones
are the ones that we're going to have to
write later so I'm going to leave them
for
now and then we created the panel up
here and on De initialization we're
going to destroy the panel so in metat
Trader 4 as well I will do exactly the
same thing which is destroy the panel
later then here one of the things which
I Chang was I move the is new bar to
after trailing the stop- loss because I
don't want to do all of this I don't
want to run all of these codes on every
tick I only want to run them on every
new candle except for the trailing stop
which should be run on every tick so I'm
going to move this here then in
metatrader 5 we had on the onti function
before the is new before checking for
all these filters we
added these four functions which is
initialization update the initial
initial balances update the prop form
values update the panel and if trading
allow prop form values these four
functions which we're going to create
now so let's go down to the bottom and
this is where we're going to create
those four
functions if I come back to metat Trader
5 I can just simply copy paste these
four
functions which is after the is trading
allowed all of the functions that we
wrote for meta Trader
5 I can just simply copy paste them here
and now if I
compile I have these 11 errors
left so the first one is system choice
because here
on onti because here on onti we are
still going through the system choices
which we don't need to anymore because
we have already put the system choices
by looping through the system type
whether it's fixed Pips or as a
percentage of price already here on
initialization so now we don't need to
do that again so all of these
scores I'll just simply delete
them compile again and voila I don't
have any errors I think when we will run
the test we will see if there are some
errors still which we need to figure out
because not having an error here means
that there are no syntax errors
but there can still be logical errors
because one for example one of the
things is we also had the is trading
Allowed by prop form values we created
this function to check but we didn't
update it up here we didn't use it
anywhere we have to use that up here so
I'll go back to metat Trader 5 and here
you can see is RSI filter news filter ma
filter trading allow filter as a knot
and then I need to add this as a knot
again and is trading allowed prop form
values as well so this is another
condition that we're going to check for
which is if the value returned from is
prop form function we have just created
if it is
false meaning that the trading is not
allowed because of the prop form values
then in that case close all the orders
and do all of these things now one more
thing which we will add here is that if
the per the profit alltime percentage is
greater than the profit
Target which is the profit Target we are
asking the user to Define what the
profit Target is if it's 10% then as
soon as the overall profit becomes
greater than this 10% then set the chart
to Green so we know that the target has
been achieved and if you go down to the
bottom where you will see here is that
if it is bigger than profit Target the
trading comment is hoay the target has
been achieved so coming back up here
where we're checking the
values if any of that returns as false
meaning the trading is disabled then the
color is going to change to purple but
then only in case if the The Profit
overall has exceeded the target profit
then we change it to Green so you're
going to get a green screen if the
profit has been if the profit target has
been achieved I'm going to compile it
again and we don't have any errors so
there seems to be no syntax error but we
need to run some test to see whether or
not the EA is working as we intended it
to work and if it is not then we need to
come back and see where it went wrong
but before we start doing that in the
prop firm we also added for trailing
stop a lot of other functions as well we
created a separate section for trailing
stop management which is you need to to
select which trailing type it is based
on a drop- down which is going to come
from what is the type which is the
default which is the aggressive one or
on previous candle or on fast moving
average or on ten
conson so I'm going to take this enum go
back and paste this enum here as well
then I'm going to come down here and
take this entire input section below the
percentage of price profile and paste it
in the same place here so we are asking
what is the trail type and in case if
the user selects previous candle or the
fast moving average then he needs to say
okay well how many candles to Trail it
on and in case of fast moving average
trailing what is the fast moving average
period so that is five in case of 10
consent line we know it's a 10 consent
line so we don't need to use we don't
need to ask the user for anything and
then we go to the trailing stoploss
function now this function is going to
become very comp liated because now we
need to add many different types of
trading stop losses depending on uh
which one the user has selected so I'm
going to try and go one by one if I
compare
it so if I put this side by side this is
my metat Trad 4 this is my metat Trader
five and I go to the trailing stop loss
now we can see we started with stop loss
equals 0 tpals 0 fine we don't need to
get the ask price but we do need to get
the stop levels here because that's what
we're going to check on the
initialization that what is the minimum
stop-loss distance Allowed by your
broker between the stop level between
where you're putting the stop loss and
the price we don't need the indicator
buffer because we're going to use direct
because metat Trader 4 uses the
indicators directly and not going
through a buffer mechanism then we have
this line is corresponding to this line
then we have selection which is fine
here then we have the magic number and
the symbol that we get here then we have
the open when then we have the position
type which we getting here then we say
if bid is bigger than this trigger stop
loss which is this
line then we
set then we get the TP but you remember
in metad data 4 you can use the
order you can use the order take Prof it
as a command so we don't really need
this
line and then comes the part which is if
position
info is bigger than this then in that
case set this so this is what we need to
add
now so we're going to take these
lines and from here I'm starting and I'm
going all the way down to where the
switching is finishing
and then also these two so all the way
down to
here which is within this if
function you see this one which
is where we getting whether it's bigger
than the trigger stoploss so it's bigger
than this and below that we need this
these functions so I'm going to copy
them and then I'm going to come back
here and I'm going to
paste the this here and I'm going to
indent
it so that we can see more
clearly So within the function of
trigger stoploss point within the
function of trigger stop-loss point
we're copying this entire section which
is if the stop loss is less than the
open price because they're in the buy
that means that it's the initial stop
loss in which case we aggressively Trail
it as soon as we are in profit but then
if that is not the case then in that
case we switch through the trailing type
which is 0 equals aggressive one equals
on previous candle two equals on on
moving average and three equals on 10
consent so we have these and
then depending on what is the SL that
comes out of here then we go if SL is
bigger than the current stop loss then
modify the stop loss so now we have
copied this this
logic but now we need to change the way
that the logic is written because met
tror 4 has a different language so now
position info is stoploss is order
stoploss and open
price is called order open
price then bid is with a capital and the
way to modify the trade
in metad data 4 is through order modify
function sending it the order ticket
number order open price the new SL then
order take
profit no change in the expiration and
color none because we don't want to see
the arrow and then we continue meaning
exit the fun exit this small snippet of
the function and move to the next and
then through the switch Trail type again
this is going to be bid
the rest is fine so in case the user has
selected aggressive trailing type then
SL is just going to be bid minus the TSL
so we are continuing to to aggressively
Trail the stop loss at a distance of
whatever the user has defined in the
trailing stop- loss points then in case
it's one which is the user wants to
Trail it on the low of the last candle
it is it Remains the Same no changes
required so on the previous candle using
the iow function and then when we come
to the moving average we cannot use the
copy buffer function because that is
particular to metatrader 5 so we delete
this part and then the stop loss is just
going to be whatever is the moving
average by getting the moving average
value through the IMA function providing
the symbol value time frame fast moving
average period that the user has
defined the ma mode the ma applied price
which the user has selected and then
providing a shift of zero so it's
basically the current candle and then
the same is true for 10 consent line so
we delete the copy buffer way and we set
the value of the stop-loss by using the
IH muku function providing the symol
time frame the default settings of the
Juku cloud and then saying get the mode
10 consent get the 10 consent line for
the shift zero so on the current candle
and then break so what will happen is
that when the EA is going through once
the bid has gone above the trigger of
the stop-loss point then the first thing
it will do is it will set the stop loss
to break even or add the TSL points once
it has moved to break even that's when
we start looking at case 0 1 2 and three
and depending on which case the user has
selected for the method of the stoploss
trailing we assign the stop-loss value
and then we go that if SL is bigger than
the profit in for stop loss and now we
change this to order stop- loss in MP4
language and that the stop loss is
bigger than the the open price so order
open price and stop loss is is smaller
than the bid meaning that it's still
below the bid so it is a valid stop loss
in that case we will modify the position
again so I can copy the modification
function from here and paste it here
which is modify the order by sending the
order ticket number open price stop loss
take profit no change to the expiration
and color none and then continue so this
is how we will go through four different
methods of trailing the stop- loss based
on what the user has selected and then
we go on to the next part which is else
if the order type is op cell then once
again once we have checked that this
trigger stop loss Point once we have
checked that the that the that the trade
has moved in profit more than the
trigger stoploss Point by checking if
the ask plus trigger stop- loss point is
lower than the open price that's when we
will do exactly the same thing as we did
in the function before so I'm copying
the entire thing up until here so within
the trailing stop-loss trigger portion
of the if I'm copying the entire thing
and I'm coming back here and if and
within this if function everything that
is within this if function I'm going to
delete it and then replace it with what
we have just
copied and I'm going to indent it so we
can read it more easily and again the
same thing so stop loss becomes order
stop loss position info price open
becomes order open price ask becomes ask
with a capital this is fine and then
again we modify the trade by using the
Met Trader 4
method so order modify sending it all of
the
information this is where we bring the
stop loss to break even and then once it
is break even then we switch through the
trailing type once again this is fine
this is also fine now it's on I high
instead of I low because it's a sell
trade so we are trailing the stop loss
on the high of the previous candles we
cannot use the copy buffer so I'm going
to delete it and I'm going to pay paste
the IMA value I can actually copy it
from here as
well and then come
below and paste it we are now changing
the stop loss to fast moving average
once it is above break even in case the
user has selected that method and then
once again we need to delete this part
and we can copy the
ichimoku function from above as well so
in case the user has selected ichimoku
then we are assigning the stop loss to
whatever is the 10 consent of the
ichimoku and then again we check that if
the stop loss or that if the new stop
loss is a smaller now
then whatever is the stop loss currently
on this position because we only want to
Trail the stop loss downwards and the
stop loss is not equal to zero because
that means that the calculations have
gone wrong and that the stop loss is
below the open
price because we only want to Trail it
when we are in profit and that the stop
loss is bigger than ask so changing it
to Capital a then again we modify the
position I can copy it from here and
then just paste it here I'll make it
bigger again and I'll show you the
function from top to the bottom once so
that if you want to actually type it you
can so this is the first
page this is the second
page and this is the end of the function
so if I compile
now I have one error which is somewhere
the ask is still without the capital so
I'm going to double click on it and here
I forgot to
change it to a capital ask if I compile
it now we don't have any error and this
brings us to to the end of the entire
modification remember to have this
reference exactly to where this file is
saved and once you have made this
reference now you cannot compile it from
here anymore you need to compile
everything from the mq4 file so this is
it I'll apply the EA ones I'll open up
the Euro USD
chart because you cannot apply it to a
visual chart the one that says visual
you cannot apply to it because that's
coming out of a back test so you need to
open a fresh chart and then if I apply
the
year these are all of the
inputs now one thing you will notice in
metad data 4 you don't have the sections
anymore so these are the benefits of
using met data 5 but all of the
variables are here now please do
remember to put this initial balance to
whatever you are putting in your testing
or whatever is the balance of your
account and then set the profit Target
correctly as
well if I click okay here is my
panel and once the once the candle is
going to change the values here are also
going to appear let's run a back
test so let's run a few tests in meta
Trader 4 just to see that our CES are
working properly so I have loaded the
prop from scalping EA from the YouTube
shared folder where we saved it I'm
going to run it on gold from 1st of June
last year until today if I go to
properties and this is where metat
Trader fold looks horrible because you
don't have the sections anymore one what
one thing we can do is here in instead
of using the input group what we could
potentially do is we say input a string
and call it a v
variable by the same name as this and
then if I
compile and I need to put an a colon
here and then if I compile now this
should appear as trading profile into a
bit of a separator here so if I go back
here all of a sudden I see trading
profiles and then with this dash dash
dash so this is one way to do it it
doesn't look as neat as it looks in
mattera 5 but if this is the best we can
have then that's the best we can have
let's put a lot of dashes and then I'm
going to do this here as a string common
inputs equals and then put a lot of
dashes and then the next one is input
again as a string let's call it
Forex inputs equals
let's make it more
prominent same for this the
string call it percentage profile
equals I'm making this prominent through
the dashes then the string
trailing stop
equals and the News fil we can just
simply
delete or I'll put
asterisk
and asterisk backs slash to make it not
available and then his string again as
RSI filter
string
prop form or prop
rules settings
equals this is some this is where we can
somehow all these errors because we
needed a colon after all of them because
these are now variables definition
r
r I think it should be okay now yeah and
now it is okay so if I go back to meta
Trader and now if we go to expert
properties at least we have some
semblance of sections so it is not as
chaotic as it used to
be okay so I'm going to choose the
percentage of price profile because it's
gold I'm using the percentage of balance
to start with with 2% I'm going to go
with bars number 10 because I'd want to
see some trades if I put 100 then there
will be very few trades this is fine
this is
fine starting with default
Trail and then RSI and moving every
filter as false trading allowed on every
day and then 10,000 because my initial
deposit here in the test is 10,000 so I
need to put 10,000 here as well and have
the same date as the tester so this is
fine let's run it visually so we can see
so here the first trade is placed if I
go here I see that the stop loss is
about
$10 and $10 TP which makes sense because
we put as 0.4% of the price so if you do
the calculation it should be around $9
$10 so the trade is placed correctly
there is a sell trade as well so we can
pause and go and check what the sell
trade is and I think one of them is
already triggered but the sell is stop
was also with this price about
$10 stop loss and about $10 TP which
sounds about right for 0.4% off the
price then we had a buy here and it
started trailing very aggressively I can
see
that here and then let's also see if the
the aggressive trailing also happens for
a sell trade yeah here as well so I can
pause it and here we had the cell trade
which aggressively was trailed and close
down here same here and I think here as
well now one thing which we need to see
still is a loss trade and if we go to
the graph so far we have only wins I'm
waiting for a loss trade and this one
was a uh a stop loss hit so if I go back
I should see a loss trade as well now at
the bottom down down down yeah here is
the loss trade and it is about 2% of the
balance so the calculation of the lot
size is also working
correctly so I'll go back I'll stop this
test now the next thing I'm going to
check is changing it from percentage of
balance to fixed loss to see that we
should get
0.01 and at the same time I'm also going
to check for the RSI filter so we turn
this to
true I'm going to change this to 5
minutes so we can see it on the screen
and I'm going to change it to
40 and 60 so we don't have to wait a lot
as soon as it is 40 and
60 we get the pink chart if I start now
yeah I'm getting the pink very very
quickly and I'm getting some trades as
well in between and the value is 0.01
and the pink basically means that it is
changing to
uh that the trading is being disabled
and we should be getting this error of
trading is disabled because the RSI is
below 40 above 60 so RSI portion is
working as well and I'll quickly
check I'll turn this off and then turn
the moving average filter as true and
once again on 5 minutes and I'll change
this to only 0
5 or even 0.3 just to quickly check that
once the price has moved
above the moving average by more than
0.3% that we get a pinky screen and a
disabled Journal yeah so we are getting
that as well so price is as a percentage
of ma is outside of our range and this
is why it's turning it off so I'll stop
the test we go again to
experts I'll turn this to false as
well and then the last thing I want to
check is let's say on a
Tuesday the trading is not
allowed so let's start so on Tuesday it
should become Pink as well so today is
whatever day trading is allowed and I
think now it's Tuesday so it's pink and
then when it comes Wednesday it could
start trading again so on Tuesday it was
disabled and then back again on
Wednesday it starts trading again so
that portion is working as well so this
is it for our testing uh do your own
thorough testing of the stuff as well
and then in case there are any errors do
send a comment and I will update it into
the comment section in a pinned comment
if there are any modifications that need
to be made so until next time guys stay
safe and trade safe
[Music]
oh