70% 64% 66% 82% 84% Today, I'm going to
show you four different bots and I'm
going to help you automate your trading.
So, I'm going to help you get your
trading bots live. 144%
here on Polymarket. I'm going over four
tutorials today. Plus, I'm going to show
you my actual framework for building
bots. So, 133% on women's tennis. Are
you kidding me? Pakistan Super League.
So, things that I I don't even
understand like how many tweets are Elon
Is he going to tweet this month? All of
these things are tradable on Polymarket.
This is just a new venue. You know, I
build bots for crypto, stocks, futures.
And now we're also building for
Polymarket. So, today I'm going to show
you how to become a fully automated
trader even if you've never coded a day
in your life. I'm giving you
step-by-step
instructions. I'm giving you my exact
framework and I'm giving you four full
bots. But, you have to lock in for this
video and just clear the the next hour
or two so you can watch everything. If
you can't watch it right now, save it or
subscribe. Do what you need to do
because I literally give you the whole
plan and I give you four different bots.
So, let's dive in. You already saw some
of the results. Let's go ahead.
All right. So, today I'm going to be
going over a couple different Polymarket
ideas I had. So, I'm just going to get
you caught up to speed with those so you
can see everything even if you would
never code in a day in your life. I'm
going to show you a few things here
today. Uh first off, I'm going to show
you exactly how to
uh build these Polymarket bots out so
you have some ideas of things that you
can build yourself.
Um Polymarket. And this is all
transferable to other markets as well.
So, I believe code is a great equalizer.
That's why I show everything here every
single day. And um at the end of the
day, this is what you're going to learn
because
I think it's extremely important that
you step away from the charts. Step away
from the charts. Step away from the
charts. It's hard to predict these
prices. They go up and then down and
then up and then down. Nobody knows
which way the price is going to go.
Uh you have opportunities here to build
bots that that you can see if they
actually worked in the past. If they
work in the past, they're much more
likely to work in the future. But,
they're not guaranteed. So, I have a
framework that I'll be going over here
today showing you how to build
everything that you need. But, what I
want to start with is
>> [clears throat]
>> I want to get you some ideas here
of things that you can build.
So,
Okay. So, I built a few new bots this
week.
And I want to go over them step-by-step.
But, it wasn't allergies unfortunately.
It wasn't allergies. So, much love to
you 777. Let me get the key in the chat
here.
So, first things first is let me get
that key in the chat.
So, let's go SSH.
SSHHL node. Okay.
Okay. And then we're going to say
get into Moon Dog.
That's dash Moon Dog. Okay.
We're going to say C. Okay, beautiful.
Beautiful. Yes, I confirm. So, I will
show you all the secrets that I know
about how to automate your trading here
today and then I'm going to have a few
tutorials throughout so you can actually
have actionable stuff that you can leave
with. But, um
There's really It comes down to three
things when it comes to automated
trading and I explain this in the road
map. So, I want to get you that road map
ASAP.
So, let's go ahead and get you the new
API key along with the road map. The
road map will show you
how to
get started.
So, the road map is like my
book essentially because it gets better
and better every single day. You can see
I have a bunch of bots running down
here.
Uh I've got this bot here that is
on um Solana and then I also have
a few Polymarket bots here. This is a
cricket bot which is crazy because I
don't even know how to play cricket. So,
you know, that's pretty cool if you ask
me.
I built a tennis bot. I'll show you how
to build. I'll build I show I built an
NBA bot. I built a call sheet scanner as
well.
A lot of people are asking for that call
sheet scanner. So, what I'm going to do
here is I'm going to try to
teach you how to automate your trading
but also give you some straight
tutorials. So, some of them might be
beginner. Some of them might be
advanced.
And you're going to have to lock in to
see the whole thing.
And um anything I know I'm I'm willing
to share all live here
because I believe code is a great
equalizer and I think I'm here for a
much bigger reason than just run up a
big bag for myself. I'm chasing Jim
Simons. Yes.
But, I don't need $31 billion.
I just don't.
So,
you know,
I might as well just share some.
Not saying that I have 30 I don't have
$31 billion.
I don't even have a billion. So, I'm
embarrassed.
I'm embarrassed and I'm going to keep
chasing until I do. New key activated
here. Unlock. Boom.
So, this is the Moon Dog app you do get
access to.
You do get access to here.
Okay. So,
Let me go ahead and get that key in the
chat.
Sometimes I give away a free key here
for the
live zooms.
Okay.
Let me get it in the chat.
777, good to see everybody. Dixie, good
to see you.
Um can we do an ETH arena?
Uh maybe.
Maybe. Maybe. Maybe. Let's Let's see how
the arena's doing. So, we have this
arena that you can compete in. This is
the robot by the way.
So, I'll be going over things from here.
Today, we'll be teaching you as three
secrets. Pretty much Pretty much my RBI
system.
And then you can see the live
leaderboard. This is for our Moon Dog
arena. You can sign up and
um compete in order to win prizes which
is pretty awesome. Essentially, what
you're predicting is the next 5 minutes
price. And if you can predict the next 5
minute price or the 1 hour price better
than anybody else, you win.
So, feel free to join the arena now.
There's a leaderboard here.
You can see Root Killer is up top.
Plus nine. There's a day left.
The dev is number two. Shy crypto is
number three.
Where's Warshaws key?
Where's Remble?
Okay. So, somebody just won this one.
And now Root Killer's in in the lead.
So, we just This one just ended. We can
go to history here.
Root Killer two wins. Who won this?
24 BTC won this one. So, congrats to
him. He got a free appoo.
It's $50-ish. So,
you know, nice little daily win as well.
Nice little daily win as well.
But, long story short here, dude.
What is this, dude?
What is this?
What is this code you just put in there?
PID two box size? Kill cat?
Seems sketch.
It seems sketch whatever you put in
there.
Seems super sketch.
Before I get too deep into teaching this
stuff, I'm going to show you all the
three three steps and the three secrets
in order to automate your trading. I am.
I'm also going to give you a couple
tutorials here today. So, make sure to
lock in all the way. Clear your
schedules.
Clear your schedules. I'm going to show
you three different Polymarket bots here
today.
And um
Before we get too deep, I got to give
you a little bit background how I got
here.
So, I won't I won't be long on this but
Essentially, in order for you to
understand how I even got here, you got
to understand my background. So, I grew
up a hooper actually. So,
uh competing
my entire life.
Long story short, I made it really far
in basketball. I got paid. It's awesome.
But, uh along the way, I had to stop
through college and in college they made
you do an internship and I was like, "No
way."
I watched a webinar and the guy was
showing me how to build apps without
knowing how to code.
I was like, "Yeah. Okay."
But, then in the end, he offered me
something for $2,000. I didn't have
$2,000, dude.
I put it on the credit card because I
knew that that was the way.
Then I went ahead and built this app
out. I was telling my teammates the
entire time how sick my app was going to
be. It's going to be the next Temple Run
cuz we were all playing Temple Run
competing against each other all the
time. I got this next the next Temple
Run coming out, gang. It's going to be
fire.
Long story short, I spent 2K I didn't
have and I spent 15K on a developer to
develop that game. My next game. And
I brought it to my teammates six six
months after like talking about it and
they're like, "This is trash, bro."
Trash game. I was heartbroken.
But, it pushed me into this business
model that I I created pretty much and
it made a bunch of money over the next
10 years.
So, what do I do?
Of course,
you start buying crypto.
And you start trading crypto.
And then you start losing money.
Cuz you're trading by hand with
emotions, just like you, dude. I'm sure
you traded with emotions, right?
I'm no different than you. I'm just
locked. We saw trading the vehicle, but
then we realized this is way harder than
we thought, so
thank God I spent two racks to buy that
course because that was the thing that
got me to build my initial bag and got
me into tech really in general.
Somebody knew something I didn't know,
and I purchased his knowledge, and then
I got caught up to speed with him, and
then I went ahead and build my own
thing. So, out of
out of all of that difficulty and
embarrassment and spending of money I
didn't have on credit cards, I was able
to build a million-dollar app business
that also led me to some e-commerce
businesses and ads businesses that led
me to having a bag that I was trading
with too much size, with too much
leverage, and that led me to meeting
some dude that was trading a billion
dollars per day algorithmically, and I
had been scared to learn how to code
this entire time. That's why I was
hiring developers.
I spent probably a million dollars on
developers on Upwork.
But I knew once I got inspired, dude,
to actually do this myself, I knew I had
to had to actually learn how to code, so
I locked in for 4 hours a day, every
single day.
That's 5 years ago.
Maybe even six.
Six years ago now.
But I only knew that I needed to do this
by myself because I had worked with
developers for so many years, and I knew
that if I had if I build my edge out, I
would have to keep it close to my
my chest.
Have you been liquidated before? Because
that's what got me to stop. I got
liquidated way too many times. I had to
stop trading by hand.
I had to.
So, how do you even get into this
industry, dude? Well, I went ahead and
made this much easier than it was for
me. I took 15 courses,
and only one of them was about
algorithmic trading because nobody
shares this information.
So, I do have a roadmap here for you
somewhere. Yeah.
So, the first step in order to get in
this industry is find a mentor.
It's hard to find, but
might be a couple others out there.
But it comes down to researching great
ideas. You have to have great ideas in
order to then even think about
automating them. So, if you don't have
great ideas, then you're cooked. But if
you have great ideas, then
you can build for the rest of your life,
as long as you have the courage
to use this AI all day like I do.
Where do you find good ideas? Well,
there's plenty of books. There's Google
Scholar.
Here's a bunch of books on that book
list that I just shared with you in the
chat.
Read any of these books, and you'll come
up with ideas, trading ideas.
You can then automate those trading
ideas
after you see if they actually work.
But I'll get into all that later. First
thing I want to do here is I want to go
over one of those bots that I built this
week.
Cuz I think it's fairly interesting
to open up
new markets, and I've been opening up
new markets here with Polymarket cuz
Polymarket is something Jim Simons, my
idol, didn't have.
He traded He built up a net worth of 31
billion dollars, Jim Simons, if you
don't know of him.
Algorithmic trading, and that's who I've
been following for multiple years now.
He's just a regular dude, just like you
and I.
So, why can't I do that, too?
So, I'm going to keep chasing him.
31 billion, I'm not there yet. No, I'm
not even at a billion yet. But
I do have automated trading systems that
are trading for me 24/7 365 when just 5,
6 years ago I thought that was not real.
I thought it was only for Jim Simons and
the big guys.
But I met that dude. I met that dude
that was trading a billion dollars per
day. That inspired me. Okay, great.
Let's get it.
I've been building bots for
I started with futures, stocks, quickly
went into crypto. I had more fun in
crypto.
So, that's where I build, but recently
I've been building Polymarket bots, so I
want to go ahead and show you one of
those first Polymarket bots here
that
um it's not one of my first ones. It's
probably my 15th, but
we've been working on new ones
pretty much every week.
So, right now what I want to do is go
over one of those ideas. Get you the
code, show you everything.
And then I'm going to put it in my
Discord for everybody that's already,
you know, a member and
part of the crew cuz at the end of the
day it's all PvP.
Player versus player.
It's all PvP.
Okay.
So, if it's PvP, player versus player,
how are you going to have
this shown to so many people?
I don't know.
It's a good question.
Well, my thesis
was, hey,
nobody showed this to me.
And Jim Simons literally says every
single day
to do what others
are not doing.
If everybody is doing something one way,
don't do that.
So, I've just followed that advice
for years now.
Everybody is being secretive about this
industry. Nobody wants to share
anything.
Don't do that.
So, right now I want to be unsecretive
about things. I want to show you exactly
step by step how to build the bot that
we literally just built yesterday, okay?
So, on Polymarket there's unlimited
things you can trade. That's why this is
so exciting. Jim Simons did not have
access to all these unlimited things
that you can trade.
But we do. He also didn't have six
different AIs that can work for him
24/7.
Let's go ahead and explain the idea
first, okay? Let's go ahead and explain
it. Can you go ahead and shortly and
concisely explain my tennis bot idea so
the audience can understand it?
So, what I did is I was going through
Polymarket the other day, and I was
looking through sports. I actually built
an NBA bot. As I said, I was a a
basketball player in the past, so of
course I'm going to
build an NBA bot first. But I saw this
video a few weeks ago, and they were
talking about tennis and why tennis is
appealing to trade. And the reason it's
appealing to trade is because there's so
many matches, and it's year year round.
Essentially, there's two different
tennis leagues,
uh male tennis and female tennis, and um
a lot of them overlap with three games.
So, there's three games in each or three
matches or something
in each to in order to win the actual
tennis game. Now, as you can tell, I'm
not well-versed in tennis, but I do have
um
profits already from this tennis bot,
and I built it 24 hours ago. So, I want
to get it to you. I want to show you how
to build this as well.
But the two differences here are this,
and I think this is alpha to understand
before you get started with any type of
tennis bot or any type of bot um in any
sports, right? The thing to understand
with tennis is
some games are of three. So, you have to
win a best out of three, and some are
best out of five. I think it's only the
male games that some of them are best
out of five. But WTA is what I zoned in
on for this first one, and the reason is
because those are all women's matches,
and I'd rather watch women play tennis.
No, for real. I would The reason is
because they have three matches. It's
best out of three, so they're actually
more more volatile.
And I think that's exciting, but you
could also take the other side of that.
If you want things to be less volatile,
you would take the ATPs that have five
matches. I haven't been able to figure
out which ATPs have five matches and
which um don't.
But the way I looked at it is first off,
I would rather bet on women.
Second off, I want volatility. But if
you want less volatility, if you think
about it, if it's best out of three,
there's going to be more volatility.
There's going to be more upsets, right?
So, if there's more upsets, there's
going to be more volatility. But if it's
a best out of five, it's going to be the
best player actually wins more often.
So, that's how I looked at it. So, I
went ahead with the volatility route.
Let's go ahead and see what she said.
She went ahead and explained it for us.
The WTA tennis stink bid bot. So, this
is pretty cool, and this is might not be
something you thought about. Back in the
day when you would trade or I'm sorry,
bet, sports bet, you kind of just trade
with the casino, right?
You don't get to pick the price. You
don't get to get to say, "Hey, I'll buy
this if it's a 30% discount or
whatever."
But that's what I do for this bot. So, I
hope this is enlightening to you. And
I'll I'll put all the code inside the
Discord after this at the end. But
essentially, we place low ball bids, 30%
below market price, on the favorite to
win
the WTA tennis match. If a whale panic
sells during the match and dumps the
price, we scoop those shares up cheaply.
If we get filled, we just hold to
expiration. The The favorite usually
wins, right? So, you collect the full
dollar. So, if you buy it at 30 cents,
you get a dollar. That's a good little
return. You saw the results here at the
start.
The bot refreshes every 15 minutes, a
very basic idea, but this is a new
paradigm.
And I love new paradigms. I mean, that's
why I'm in crypto, dude. That's why I
got into crypto in 2014. It's a new
paradigm. It's we never seen before.
Again, Polymarket is something we never
seen before. You weren't able to go to
the sports book back in the day and say,
"Hey, I'll buy this this player's win if
you give me a 30% discount." And that's
exactly what I'm doing here.
So, let's go ahead and look through the
code a bit so you can understand it a
bit better.
I've already explained the idea. It's a
stink bid. A stink bid is when you're
saying, "Hey, give me this.
I want this, but only if
it drops that low." So, let's go through
here
and go through some of the code, some of
the highlights of the code. And like I
said, I'll drop all this code inside the
Discord.
So, if we go to sports here, we'll go
over here. And if you want me to go over
any of these other ones as well, just
put them in the chat.
I got a cricket bot. I built something
for cricket. I built something for
baseball. That's crazy. I built
something for NBA.
I got the NHL scanner and the soccer
scanner and the UFC scanner as well. WTA
stink bot. So, I think this is what's
important to understand. It places stink
bids on the favored player. Now, is that
right or wrong? I'm not sure yet.
But I don't think
you've thought about this idea of, "Hey,
go to the sports book and say, 'Hey, I
want a 30% discount.'" They're going to
be like, "Okay, no."
But on Polymarket you can do that cuz
it's peer-to-peer.
So, find all today's WTA matches on
Polymarket.
For each match, pick the side with the
higher yes price. That's how I picked
the favorite.
Place the stink bid at 30% discount.
Cancel all orders before refreshing. And
that's important. A lot of people will
miss that. And if we go back to the road
map here, remember, this is how you
automate your trading, whether it's
stocks, futures, whatever.
If you look back at the road map, let's
go ahead and see if we can find it.
This is very important when you're
building out the back and I know I just
skipped the back back testing part. It's
a little hard to back test on
Polymarket, but I'll talk about back
testing for regular
stocks, futures, crypto, whatever. And
it's important. But you can see here's a
checklist. Add risk controls to the bot.
One of those risk controls is, "Hey,
make sure you don't over order." I've
seen and done too many times where it's
like I'm building a bot, I'm excited
about it, and I put in the order, and
then it doesn't check to see if there's
already order in there. So, it just puts
in another order and another order and
another order and you just drain your
whole account. So, check to see if
there's already a position. And make
sure to cancel all orders before opening
a new one.
I've got some other things here on the
checklist as well. Always start with
tiny size because at the end of the day,
this is the process I'm teaching you
today. It's the process of automating
your trading.
It starts with research of trading
strategies. So, how do you find great
ideas? Well, you got books, you got
Google Scholar, you got podcasts, you
got YouTube. It really comes down to
coming up with ideas, ideas, ideas.
That's research.
Then you back test those ideas. See if
they actually work in the past. Now,
with these Polymarket bots, it's a
little harder to back test, sure.
But you can still incubate small size.
So, you saw earlier, I'm running $5 size
here.
Nothing crazy.
And nothing is too hard here. You can
see I have the configuration here, bet
size of $5.
Refreshing every 15 minutes. I've got a
multi-account system set up because I
want to be testing multiple different
ideas across multiple accounts, and they
don't have sub accounts yet. So, how do
you do that? Well, I set it up this way.
So, I have
my OG account private key ENV, and then
I can just say account two, account
three, account four. You can see these
are the APIs that you're going to have
to get connected with here on Polymarket
in order to get this going. Got to
validate your credentials.
I'm using the ESPN WTA API in order to
get the women's prices. So, you can see
it's super easy, it's free. I'm going to
put all of this code as like you What
are we going to just copy all this code
down? I'm going to put all of this code
here right now inside of the Discord.
So, I'll go ahead and show you that
really quickly. Let's go here to that
Discord. So, our Discord is
hundreds of us all chasing Jim Simons
together and all sharing and helping
each other with ideas all day long. And
then I go ahead and we also put
strategies here in this Discord. So,
quant strategies, there's years and
years of strategies here. But this is
just for members. And then in this quant
elite section, for the last few years,
my team and I have been posting back
test, bots, etc. What I'm going to do
now is say this is the women's
tennis Polymarket
Polymarket trading bot.
And every week I just try to pick one of
my favorite bots, dude. And I just paste
it in here. Because then if I work on
this, like this took me
a day and a half to build.
And now that you get it for
like in a few minutes. Now, you don't
want to just go run somebody else's bot.
Polymarket
tennis
.py. But you have something that I
didn't have
when I got started.
You have somebody to break this all down
in short concise videos. You can see now
it's
in the GitHub in the quant elite code
section. You've got somebody to break
down all these
these strategies for you, somebody to
give you code. Now, don't plug and play,
of course. You got back test for days.
All these videos are in short concise
videos here, day one through day 15.
And by the time you see this, if you go
to moondev.com,
moondev.com/easter,
by the time you watch this, you see it's
not available right now. But we're going
to have a Easter special. So, go to
moondev.com/easter
if you want to get this code, you want
to learn short concise videos. There's a
90-day no questions asked money-back
guarantee. But this will not be here for
long. So,
I got to set that page up, I guess.
So, you saw like I literally just came
up with a random idea yesterday.
You saw the research process.
It was just me scrolling through
Polymarket, figuring out what markets
trade a lot.
And I found this market. So, I built a
bot for it.
That's it.
That's it, dude.
Every day I'm just coming up with ideas.
That's the research, remember? You have
the road map here.
I come up with ideas, I research ideas.
Whether it's from books, podcasts,
whatever, dude. That doesn't matter.
There's unlimited ideas out there.
There's unlimited ideas out there, dude.
Now, a lot of people want to trade on
Colosseum as well. So,
I was thinking about it.
I was thinking about it, dude. I was
thinking about it.
But I was just tired. I was tired and
tired tired. Tired of trading by hand,
dude.
Do you ever felt like they can see your
positions? They actually can. I can see
your positions, too.
Do you go over here to trade?
I can see everybody's positions, exactly
when they're going to get liquidated.
1.3 million
liquidation and 0.8%.
1.6 million and 0.7%.
Wall Street can see this. If I can see
it, you can they can definitely see it.
And you can see this as well. 11.2
million liquidation and 1.2% on
Ethereum. You have the keys and
everything in the chat. And I'll go
ahead and make sure that those keys are
in there again.
So, I'm going to drop them again here.
Let's go ahead and find that chat.
PGA bot. Okay, that's a good idea. Thank
you.
I'm going to put that on the list.
Tennis here.
Just wanted to show you that tennis bot
and put it in the
quant elite section.
>> I feel like this secret right here is
what changed my life. So, I hope this
hits.
Process of automating your trading
starts with the research of trading
strategies.
Not running towards the to a bot right
away. I learned to code. I spent like a
year trying to learn how to code. I
built a bot and I lost all my money.
Cuz I didn't have a system. I didn't
have a robust system like this.
I was like, okay, I know how to code
now. Let me just go ahead and build
that.
I didn't even test it. I didn't even
test ideas. I didn't incubate. I just
put 10K in and just went to zero.
Strategy of trading by hand didn't work
and I was trading by hand.
>> [laughter]
>> But out of that struggle, you get you
get the actual
framework that has helped me
be able to do this for 6 years.
And I'll be here for 60. So, I'm just
getting started. We're only 10% through.
I'll be here for 60 years. Can you
imagine how much you're going to learn
over time?
Can you come up to speed with me
everything you need?
Everything you need. So, a lot of people
want to trade on Kalshi as well. Let's
see what I have going on with this
Kalshi stuff.
Let's go to that Kalshi
bot here. Electron
cursor
Kalshi scanner
Kalshi Kalshi Kalshi
I got the Elon tweet bot, too. Damn.
Oh, no, no, no. Kalshi Kalshi Kalshi
Kalshi's right here.
I'll also have her start working on
this.
Let's say SSH Moon Dev.
Moon Dev, okay. SSH Moon Dev.
Okay.
SU Moon Dev
See.
Okay, yes, I trust this folder.
Go ahead and look at moondev.com/go.
Also, go ahead and look at moondev.com/
lucky.
So, moondev.com/lucky, we're going to
take that offer and make a new page,
moondev.com/easter.
It's going to be the same offer as the
lucky one,
which is closed now, but it's going to
be for Easter. So, you have all the
links for everything there.
Make this a Easter theme, but don't make
it like it's too lame, you know?
It's a male audience, so don't make it
like too pink and, you know what I'm
saying?
So, go ahead and make that page for me
with the \slash} lucky offer, and this
one will be open, but it'll be
moondev.com/easter.
I'll get that prepared, so
she'll cook that up for me. So, I just
use Cloud Code all day for everything.
Front end, back end, side end, whatever.
My brain, dude, come on.
Come on.
We got AI all the AI in the world. We
can build anything for the rest of our
lives.
So, I hope you're using AI all day.
I hope you're using AI all day.
Let's go ahead and see this Kalshi
market here.
Damn, they're using Verse Cell for
Kalshi. Cooked.
They're paying a lot.
Moon, are you using the open-source
Cloud? No, I'm just using the regular
one. What's up, Deep? How are you doing?
PGA bot is a good idea.
So, I know everybody wants to trade on
Kalshi. Everybody's seen my videos.
People are taking my videos. My name is
Moon Dev and they're sharing all the
Polymarket results.
It's interesting to see that everybody's
sharing my results
and not theirs.
But anyways, they're going to keep
ripping my videos. So, I wanted to show
you guys cuz I'm getting a lot of demand
for this, how to build on Kalshi. So, if
you want to build anything on Kalshi,
you've seen all the results of my
Polymarket stuff. I'm absolutely cooking
over there.
But now, it's time to start building
for Kalshi. So, what's the first thing
you need to do when you build for
Kalshi? Let's go ahead and explain it
here and also show you. Can you go and
explain short and concisely what my
Kalshi Kalshi scanner does? Thank you.
So, I'll have Cloud Code go ahead and
explain it for you here, but I'll also
just go ahead and run it. And this code
I'm going to go ahead and go over as
well. I'll go ahead and put it inside
the Discord in case you're not inside
the Discord. I'll make sure that there's
a link for you here at the end.
I don't see anything for Kalshi. Okay,
well, look at the Kalshi folder. It's k
a l s h i. Silly girl. But let's go
ahead and get the scanner running first
off because in order to
trade on Kalshi, you must be able to get
every single trade that's happening.
Right? Because I want to see only people
that are trading big size.
And you can see it's scanning here.
8:43, a whale just came in. Will Belinda
bank it, whatever.
In New Mexico at Tulsa winner, Barcelona
at Real Madrid winner. So, you can see
these guys are putting real cash up.
These are the This is how I started all
of my Polymarket stuff. That's why I
want to start this Kalshi series with
the thing that helped me build
everything. It's a scanner. It's got to
show you exactly what are people buying.
If I can see that people are spending
1,000, 3,000, 4,000 dollars on a
different market, then that gives me an
idea. Just like I've built out my uh
tennis bot, just like I built out my
Elon bot, just like I built out all of
my bots, they all come from this scanner
here that I want to get you and explain
it to you right now. Essentially, what
I'm doing is I'm looking at the Kalshi
API and I'm scanning through all of the
trades that are coming in and anything
over a thousand dollars, I put here
because at the end of the day, I can
then click these and see what's the
actual market here.
What's the Kalshi market that they're
trading? I can see I can see the actual
name, more tech layoffs in 2026. It's a
little nicer down here. New Mexico at
Tulsa winner. Okay, but I can also open
them up. So, just open them up into the
actual page and this is how I do
discovery. I don't know about you, but I
only want to trade markets that are
liquid, meaning a lot of people are
trading. So, in this Kalshi scanner, I'm
just having it run all day collecting
all of the biggest traders, following
all the whales. And I'll make sure that
all of this code is inside the Discord,
but you can see I've only ran it for a
few minutes and I've already found 25
whales.
Now, I know it's only a thousand dollars
or more. You can change that to however
you want it to be. The longer you run
it, the more markets you're going to
find that are actually liquid. People
are actually trading.
And that's the important thing. Like I
said, I built an Elon bot. I've built a
weather bot. I've built a uh Twitter
bot. Sorry, not a Twitter, a tennis bot.
I've built a cricket bot, a baseball
bot. All of these ideas come from me
just watching this scanner. I've got
something similar to this here on my
website, moondev.com/polymarket,
that just watches all of the Polymarket
trades come in. You can see that it just
sits here and whenever a trade comes in,
I see it and I'm able to just
pretty much just stock all of the big
traders because these give me ideas.
Like, okay, Dota 2. I've started
building out an e-sports bot as well.
But how did I build these? It's it's
simple. I just watch the big trades and
the big trades that come through, okay,
that's a highly liquid market.
So, what I want to do now is I want to
go through all this code so you have
something to leave with today. If you
want to get started with Kalshi, this is
the number one thing you have to have.
You must have a scanner like this. As
you can see, the base URL here is very
simple to input and then you can see the
trades endpoint, the market endpoint,
the events endpoint. Now, some of this
was tricky. So, I want you to lock in
here and see all of this code. And if
you do want to just copy the code, like
I said, I'll put it inside the Discord
because this is a scanner. This one's
not just like running somebody else's
bot. I'm not a believer in running
somebody else's bot. There's something
called alpha decay, but I can give you
the pieces to a scanner that you can run
and then come up with your own ideas
based off of it. You know my process of
automated trading by now, right? I just
explained it. It comes down to coming up
with great ideas.
Research, backtest, and then incubate in
the small size. So, Polymarket's a
little harder to backtest on, but you
can still do the research. How am I
doing research? I'm watching everybody's
big trades. If you're trading something
big on Polymarket or Kalshi, I see you.
That's already an edge. I see every
single trade.
And a couple of these things, putting
the actual link together so it's
clickable, was a little harder. So,
check into this build link function
here.
This is how you actually build a link.
The format is kalshi.com/markets,
and then series
lower case, and then the title slug, and
then the event lower. So, that's how you
build it. And then I also save all the
markets to the CSV, so I can let this
run for 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7 days.
And then just come back and see all of
the whales that have traded. And that is
research. That's giving me ideas. So,
I'm scrolling through all the codes
slowly, purposely, so you can go ahead
and get all this code if you'd like it.
I'll also go ahead and put it in the
members-only Discord, of course. By the
end of this video, we're almost there,
you're going to have a full scanner for
Kalshi, and this is step one for
building out any bot, and this is legit
the exact same thing I did with
Polymarket. I ran the scanner, I saw
where people are actually trading on
Polymarket, and then I started building
ideas off of it. I showed you some of
the the results here at the start, but
at the end of the day it comes down to
researching great ideas,
backtesting to see if they actually work
in the past. And for Polymarket, really
I'm not backtesting much.
But for hyperliquid stocks, futures,
forex, backtesting is awesome because
you have a ton of data. Polymarket's
new. There's some things you can
backtest, and I've definitely done
backtests with Polymarket. But for
Polymarket, it's really you come up with
great ideas, and then incubate with
small size. So, you just saw the
complete code here of how to
get the scanner. Now, if you want me to
just post it inside the Discord, I've
got this Discord with a bunch of us
quants here
that are all working together to
optimize and help each other out. You
can see the members area here, but
inside of the quant code elite code
section, I just went ahead and posted
something crazy. I posted a Polymarket
trading bot, it's a tennis bot, but I'm
just going to keep posting here today.
So, I'm going to have this Kalshi
scanner here next. So, I'm going to say
Kalshi scanner, Kalshi Kalshi whale
scanner.
And I'm just going to post this here
today, save it. So, this is the Kalshi
whale scanner. So, now
you not only have it inside of this
video, I explained the important things
about it, but you also have the code
inside of the Discord. Let's see if this
page is ready yet. I sent my AI off to
do it. moondev.com/easter.
If you do want to become a member, this
should be live by the time you watch
this video, but we're going ahead, let's
say this.
Let's see if she can figure it out.
Done. Created this. Let's go ahead and
push it live. You are the server that
it's running on. So, just get this live,
and then anybody who joins can have all
that code they just saw. And the thing
about this, dude, is I've been here for
5 years
pushing 6 years doing this exact
process.
Coming up with ideas,
and then testing them to see if they
worked in the past. And then if they
work in the past, I build bots and I
incubate them. And I've just been
uploading this code week after week for
years, and you can see there's three
other quants in here with me. And we're
all just working together to chase the
$31 billion man. His name is Jim Simons,
but the thing Jim Simons didn't have
that we do have
is AI. Yes, of course he was using
machine learning, but he didn't have six
Claude codes sitting there helping him
code his ideas out all day long. But you
and I do.
So, while I'm chasing the $31 billion
man,
I mean,
let's be honest, $31 billion is going to
be an L. We're in a whole different
time. I've got 50 more years of this
game.
So, I don't need that much money.
So, what I do is I just share everything
with people that are actually eager to
do this. Now, if you're actually eager,
go to moondev.com/easter.
There's a massive discount going on.
It's all purple. I'm going to change all
that color.
I don't like the purple, so let's come
up with a different Easter color, drop
all purple. But you know where to get
everything, dude.
I showed you the Kalshi scanner. If you
want to cook on Kalshi, you can do that.
If you want to cook on Polymarket, you
can do that.
We all have expendable income.
We all know we have bad habits. If you
just clean up a couple of those bad
habits, we all know that money just
continuously replenishes.
At the end of the day,
you have two options.
Say, "Oh, dude, this is cool. I want to
get my own Kalshi and Polymarket bot set
up," and then just go do nothing, or you
can just join up right now, join the
Discord, and we'll step on the gas
together.
All right, I want to change all that
purple. Hate the purple.
I'm leaking, bro. I'm leaking.
Absolute I'm absolutely leaking today,
dude.
Absolutely leaking.
This is no joke. Critical emergency.
MoonDev down. MoonDev is down, down,
down.
But that don't matter, dude. Still lock
in. Do it anyways.
Do it anyways, dude. Do it anyways. Lock
in.
Just do it anyways, dude. Just do it
anyways.
I can't believe I have a cricket bot
that is live.
Like, does anybody know how to play
cricket?
Anybody in the chat know how to play
By the way, now that you've been here
for a bit and you've seen me explain the
process to automated trading, you know
what it takes now.
So, I don't want you to embarrass
yourself anymore. Um you don't have to
join this if you don't want to, that's
fine.
But now you are not a hand trader
anymore. You don't have to be like, "Oh,
what do you do What do people ask what
you do?" You don't have to be all
embarrassed and bashful about I'm a
trader because you know they're about to
roast you. They'll be like, "You're a
gambler. You good? You good, bro? Are
you good?" You're not a You're not a
gambler anymore. You're approaching
these markets quantitatively. So, from
here on out, go change your Twitter
profile, your LinkedIn, etc. Because
you're a quant now.
You're going to get much more respect on
your name, as you deserve. Cuz that's
the thing is I know we're all ambitious,
dude.
We're all getting after it.
And we're all used to working harder and
getting more results, right?
The harder I work, the better results I
get, but the last few years you've been
trading by hand, you know that's not the
case.
You work harder at trading, you lose
more money. It's sad.
It's the biggest waste of energy for
ambitious people in the
in the world, in my opinion.
So, if you're a trader right now, you
got two options. Stop trading
cuz you're losing all your money,
or take me up on the offer and say
you're a quant now.
Cuz you are a quant now. You found me
somehow, so big ups to you, dude.
Introducing yourself as a quant sounds
way better than, "Hey, I'm a a degen.
I'm a trader," right?
You deserve that. You've been working
hard your entire life.
And look, dude, I'm nothing different
than you. Actually, you're probably well
ahead of me. You probably didn't get
held back in seventh grade. You probably
didn't get called in by your homeroom
teacher, and she said to me, she said,
"Moon,
you're not going to make it around
here." I'm like, "What the hell do you
What do you mean make it around here?
We're in middle school."
Yes, she said the only way I could stay
is if I do seventh grade again.
I've been told my entire life I can't do
this, I can't do that. You look at
Twitter, YouTube comments right now.
Moon, you don't know what you're talking
about. You can't do this, you can't do
that. But that's the point.
That's the point.
I will always attack industries that I
don't know how to do, or I don't know
what I'm doing. Because everything in
your life
is behind that wall of fear. I was
scared to learn how to code for 10
years. I spent near a million dollars
paying developers to code for me. Are
you kidding me?
I got held back in seventh grade.
Who gets held back in seventh grade?
If another man can do something, I can
do it, too.
And I believe in you, dude.
Cuz you found me somehow.
You're the ambitious one. Yes, I'm
ambitious, too. Every time you log on to
YouTube, the internet, you see MoonDev
here. Okay, that's great.
I believe in myself, but I also believe
in you, and it's so sad. I see people
come through all the time.
They're just dabblers. There's doers and
dabblers. The dabblers are like, "Oh, I
can't do this because I don't have a
science degree or I'm not a math Me
neither, dude. Me neither.
I've been rejected by everybody my
entire life. And to this day, look
around, dude. People drag me down every
single day. You can't do this or that
because you didn't go to Harvard. Okay,
I don't care.
I'm cooking.
You guys are watching me cook. You see
the results every single day. I'm not
here to brag. I'm not.
I'm not.
I'm here to encourage you if you have
the will to spend the last couple years
trading by hand just to lose all your
money,
no, dude. There's a better way. Look
around. Jim Simons, $31 billion.
Look around. Citadel, Jane Jane Street.
Look around, dude. The only people
getting off in trading are automated
traders. So, you're an automated trader
now.
You're an automated trader now, dude.
You're a quant. You're not just a degen,
okay? I'm going to keep showing you
these bots that I built this last week
or two, but this is just a small small
sample. Remember that. I've been here
for 5 to 6 years. People on the
leaderboard that are competing in this
arena, a lot of them have learned from
me. Warshawsky, he's smoking everybody
on this 1 hour and 5 minute leaderboard.
He's smoking everybody.
He learned it all from me.
He's taking it to the next level.
That's amazing, dude. Nobody was here to
show me this stuff. I had to go figure
it out on my own, but then I make it
easy for you.
It's not easy. It's not easy, but it's
going to be easier.
You don't have to fiddle around for the
next 5 years. Just keep locking in. It's
free on YouTube, dude.
You can watch everything.
Yeah, you're going to have ads on
YouTube, of course. You're not going to
get the massive bonuses on YouTube, of
course.
If you want to chat with me, of course
I'm not going to just chat with people
on random people on the internet.
But I do believe if you found me somehow
some way that you're a good researcher.
And if you're a good researcher, you
should be researching, not trading.
No, dude.
Research. Spend your time researching.
Find great ideas. I gave you all of
these places to find
great ideas. Google Scholar,
books, podcasts, videos.
You're a good researcher. I don't even
need to teach you this stuff. Here, take
a snapshot of these trading books. These
helped me figure out systems that work.
You got Market Wizards. That's an
essential series of books to read. You
have to read those.
Chat With Traders podcast, you can
listen to those all day. And every
single one of them have been verified.
They're verified good traders and you
have unlimited ideas. And I know you
have the ambition to compete in this
industry. I know it because I'm
literally a random dude on the internet
that you're watching and you're like,
"Ooh, this is fascinating."
I didn't ask you to show up here.
Shoot, I didn't even send you an email.
I never ran a ad. None of that, dude.
You're here somehow some way, so much
love to you.
Much love to you.
So, now you know how to research great
ideas.
There is something called backtesting
where you can get data from the past and
you have the app now. So, if you want
data for the last 50
50 504 weeks, 15 minute data, you can
get that as well.
It's all right here on the app, the
MoonDev app that you have access to if
you're in the Zoom call.
Or if you're in the members area, you
have access to that as well. You can
backtest for days. Backtesting is the
process of seeing if a strategy worked
in the past.
Click run backtest and see if it worked
in the past. You can see this is a MACD
histogram reversal strategy. If the
strategy works in the past, it's a much
better indicator than putting some MACD
on the chart and saying, "Okay, let me
try to trade this by hand." You can see
this lost 88% of its money. Probably a
trash strategy. On BTC, it did okay.
I built all this in to make this process
easier for you.
Cuz it was not easy for me.
It was not easy to figure all this out.
But now I've helped hundreds of people
figure it out. So, if you go to
moondev.com/testimonials,
you can see those hundreds of people and
what they've had to say.
This just scrolls forever.
So, I want to go ahead here and give you
another little tutorial of something I
built here this week. And remember, this
is just a small snapshot. I've been here
for multiple years.
And I was just like you. I thought that
this stuff was going to be too hard. I
thought I had to go to school for it. I
thought I had to go to Harvard.
The closest thing I got to Harvard,
dude, was sitting on my couch watching a
Stanford professor talk about one thing
that made my mind absolutely go upside
down. He talked about this. When you're
in an emotional state, which you always
are when you're trading, when you're in
an emotional state, it's impossible to
think logically.
It's impossible to think logically
because it's just a shorter route to
your emotions. I'll go ahead and have AI
explain it, but essentially the route to
your emotions
is shorter than the route in your brain
to your logical brain. So, if you're
always trading by hand, your emotional
brain will always take over. Let's go
ahead and have AI explain this because
she's better at everything than I am.
But that's the that's the good thing for
you, right? I had to learn all this
stuff by hand. I had to start from
absolute scratch. I took 15 courses and
only one of them touched on algorithmic
trading because nobody in their right
mind shares this stuff. I'm just taking
a different bet, dude. I'm taking the
other side. Jim Simons told me, "If
everybody's doing something one way, do
it the other way."
So, everybody is being secretive about
this stuff, so I'm doing it the other
way and I've been doing it for the other
way for 5 years live.
And I found some crazy things and I've
built a community that has returned well
over what I could ever do by myself.
So, everybody's doing it one way, I'm
going to do it a different way. And
guess what? Then I'm going to give all
my secrets away. And then I'm going to
start paying people who win this
leaderboard. This is a different
approach to algorithmic trading. This is
a community approach. So, if you want to
be a part of a community instead of that
little hobbit in a hole by yourself for
the rest of your life, you can actually
lock in with us
and learn from these people as well.
They learn A lot of these people learned
from me. Not saying all of them did,
but now they're competing for real cash.
And what's going to get hap what's going
to get what's going to happen, dude?
Everybody's going to get better and
better, right?
Because if I'm competing for cash
against you
and we're trying to be at the top of the
leaderboard, well, that pushes me and
you.
So, again, you might be questioning,
"Why would you share all this stuff?"
Cuz Jim Simons told me to.
That's how I interpreted it as well, at
least.
Just like he said, "If everybody's doing
something one way,"
and he's the best in the world at this.
Jim Simons ran up a net worth of $31
billion. He comes up on my screen all
the time. He says, "If everybody's doing
it one way, do not do that."
Even himself, you watch all his videos,
he didn't share anything. He's not
telling secrets. So, he told me a secret
and he didn't even intend to tell it
this way. He says, "If everybody is
doing one thing one way, don't do that."
Even himself is secretive about all of
his his secrets, his algorithmic trading
secrets. But he's also slipped up to say
multiple times, "It's actually not that
hard.
It's not that like you don't need to be
that smart to do this stuff." So, he
said that on one hand. On the other
hand, he said, "Don't do what
everybody's doing." And on the other
hand, he hasn't shared any like secrets
with us.
So, what I
put together is, "Hey,
if everybody is being so secretive and
scarcely led in this industry of
finance, I'm going to do the exact
opposite and it's going to piss people
off, but I'm going to build the best
community in the world.
And look at how hard people are cooking.
17 correct, eight wrong. That's a
profitable trading system. 28 correct,
20 wrong. That's a profitable trading
system. That's on the hourly. On the 5
minute, this just started an hour ago.
Eight correct, three wrong. Eight
correct, four wrong. History here.
If I show everybody absolutely
everything, what's going to happen?
Well, everybody's going to know what I
know and it took me 5, 6 years to figure
all that out. I'll teach you in a couple
weeks. Perfect. I'll teach you in a
short video. Let me get into the next
vid, dude. I want to give you another
tutorial here because then
I've already given you two full
tutorials plus explained my framework.
The framework that I follow every single
day.
I show you how to find great ideas.
Literally steal them from your
competitors. That Chat With Traders
podcast is literally your competition
showing exactly how
they trade.
The Market Wizards, literally
those are your competition
showing you how they they trade.
And then I showed you a cool little app
here on on my app that you can backtest
with. You can just backtest with a click
of a button. Have AI backtest for you.
It's fire, dude.
And I want to build more backtests. I
just tell AI, "Okay, let's go ahead here
and just tell AI to backtest some more
new backtests for me."
Click here. Backtest. Okay, perfect.
I want you to look at
our last five backtests and then I want
you to build
use what's good in them and then do a
capitulation type strategy. So, you're
looking for a volume spike with open
high low close volume data. Build five.
Use five agents. Thanks.
So, I'm watching five agents here.
And I didn't have access to this when I
got started. I had to do all this hard
stuff by myself. But now I make it so
easy for you especially since you have
AI. So she's going to go ahead and
backtest some new ideas for me. And I
want to get into this new bot that I
want to show you that we built this week
as well. I built a bunch of stuff this
week.
And we have all these shoes in the
world, dude. I should be cuddled up in
bed right now. I'm going through it. I'm
sick as a dog.
But that's the difference between me and
the dabblers. I know you're a doer and
you'd be standing up here, too.
Doesn't matter if I'm up, down,
whatever. I'm sick as a dog, dude.
I'm sick as a dog, dude. And I'm still
here. I'm still like do it anyways. I
don't care. We got one opportunity at
this life, dude. I might die today.
I'm going to get it in till the end.
Much love to you. Thanks for locking in
with me.
I'll continue to show you absolutely
everything. I want to get into this
cricket bot because I think cricket's
interesting.
Okay, so this is [clears throat] this is
just insane. I'm just mind-blown here.
Honestly, I'm just mind-blown that I
have a cricket bot that's running 24/7
365. I've never played the game of
cricket before. So you can see here's
there's multiple games going on. The
Kolkata Knight Riders.
You got the Pindids versus the Karachi
Kings. I think that's Pakistan. So
you've got a game that I've never
personally played before. I barely know
the rules. I actually don't know the
rules. All I do know is I figured out
yesterday that the rules are one team
goes one half and then the other team
goes the second half. Now, why does this
important? If we go over here to
Polymarket, you can see I have a bunch
of bots. You've seen all of the results
of my bots in the past. You see
everybody's stealing Moondev's videos.
I'm Moondev. I believe code's a great
equalizer. I'm not your Chinese cousin,
dude. Everybody's saying I'm their
Chinese cousin. But what does that tell
you? If everybody's stealing my videos
showing my results.
Don't you want to go to the source?
Well, the source is here.
I've been looking for new markets to
trade on Polymarket cuz I want to get my
hands wet in every single market because
that's how you come up with great ideas
and great systems. Trade places that
other people aren't trading. And you can
see I have a position here on this game,
the Kolkata Knight Riders.
I I don't even know what country that's
in. I barely even know the sport. But
the sport is cricket and the reason I
got interested in it is because look at
this. There's 24 markets here, 109
markets here, 16 markets here, 28
markets here. And what I want to do here
in this short video is I want to explain
the entire idea. So you can have the
idea of this bot that I'm running on the
cricket markets on Polymarket. You can
take that idea and take it to the next
level. You know, it's one thing to to
feed a man a fish, it's another thing to
show a man how to fish for the rest of
their life. So you know, the process
that I show is this. It's it's simple.
I'm always doing one of these three
things. I'm always following my RBI
system, Moondev's RBI system. Just in
case somebody's saying I'm their Chinese
cousin cuz I'm not even Chinese, but I I
foot the Chinese heavy. The process of
automating your trading starts with the
research of trading strategies. Then you
backtest those strategies to see if they
actually work in the past. If they do,
they're not guaranteed, but they're much
more likely to work in the future.
So that's the simple framework that I
follow. And I've been explaining it
today. I've shown you a bunch of ways to
find great ideas. But one of the ways to
find a good idea, you know, you got
books, you've got YouTube videos, you
got podcasts. I've given you all of
those different sources. If you want to
screenshot them, this is where I got my
initial ideas.
I also go ahead and give you on this
roadmap a ton of ideas straight from my
note sheet. So if you're lacking ideas,
don't be one of those excuse makers. We
all got excuses, dude. Like I said, I
got held back seventh grade. Like I
said, I'm sick as a dog right now. I
should be in bed cuddled up. I should
have somebody taking care of me. But no,
dude. I believe code's a great
equalizer. I believe if I show you
absolutely everything about all of these
bots that I'm building, whether they're
whether it is a brand new idea or
something I got from my note sheet in
the past.
You'll be able to see that for the rest
of your life you can have automated
trading bots trading for you.
I want to explain this to you.
Can you go ahead and quickly, shortly,
and concisely explain my cricket bot and
the actual strategy behind it? Because I
think that's the important part. I've
already shown a lot of the code and I'll
put the code inside the Discord for
people. But explaining the actual idea
behind it is the interesting part to me.
Because I can you know, obviously give
you bots, but I'm not going to do that.
I don't believe in that. There's
something called alpha decay. If you
want to look that up, I'll just tell you
about it. What is alpha decay short and
concise?
Essentially, if there's a million
dollars in the corner and I tell 50,000
people there's a million dollars in the
corner, how long is that million dollars
going to be there?
When it comes to algorithmic trading,
alpha decay. Jesus, dude.
Anyways, here's the idea that I'm going
to be showing you the code for it. I'll
drop the code inside of the Discord at
the end of this. So it's the same core
idea as the tennis and the NBA, place
lowball bids. So I call them stink bids
at 30% below market
on the favorite in the IPL and PSL
cricket matches. The twist is the
timing. Cricket T20 matches have two
innings, okay? So if you're
an American like myself, you probably
don't know that. We don't have cricket
out here.
We only bid during the first inning. So
team one batting. I don't know if that's
right or wrong. That's just what I did.
So again, I want to explain this idea so
you have it and then you can take it to
the next level. Once the second inning
starts,
which is called the chase, we cancel
everything. The logic is
that first innings is where the
uncertainty is highest.
And a whale that panic sells can dump
the the favorite.
It can dump their price and that's where
I get filled. And then I hold to
expiration. It's $5 because I I truly
believe like again, I just built this
this week. I truly believe this is the
best approach to automated trading. You
come up with the idea, backtest it if
you can, and then incubate it with small
size, something that's not going to keep
me up at night.
No, I'm I'm testing these ideas and I'm
showing them live. And the great thing
is it might take me four to six hours to
build it, but then I can explain it in
10 minutes and give you all the code so
then you can test your ideas. Because
you haven't walked in my shoes. I
haven't walked in your shoes.
That's the beauty of this. And Jim
Simons tells me every day. He says, "If
everybody's doing it one way, don't do
that."
And everybody in finance is such a
scared little [\h__\h] about sharing their
ideas. I'm not going to do that. I'm
going to share every idea, every word,
every line of code every single day.
Jim Simons told me to and he's the goat.
He's the goat.
So going back to alpha decay here, in
algorithmic trading, alpha decay is the
the the
the deterioration of trading strategies
edge over time. A signal that once
generated excess returns gradually
becomes less profitable and eventually
stops working. Common causes, crowding.
Other traders discover and exploit the
same signal, arbitraging it away.
Market regime changes, volatility, data
snooping, structural changes. So the
number one thing here and the thing the
reason why everybody's so scared of
sharing their stuff is because of
crowding.
If other traders discover your exploit,
your edge, then they can go ahead and
trade that, too. And then it will go to
zero. That's why I'm not here to just
say, "Hey, plug and play this exact
stink cricket bot that I built yesterday
and it has shown some profits." Sure,
but I know for a fact that this is not
going to be the exact iteration that I
scale. We all have to come up with our
own ideas. But Jim Simons told me, he
said, "If everybody's doing it one way,
don't do that." So everybody's hiding
this stuff from you. Nobody wants to
share. Everybody's saying that you have
to go to
Harvard or some stuff to do this. But
dude, I got held back in the seventh
grade. Come on. I'll tell you that over
and over again because you have so many
excuses like I do. We all have excuses.
Here is the cricket stink bot. I want to
go through some of these pieces, but
I'll go ahead and drop the full code
inside of Discord. Don't just go run it,
of course. It places a stink bid on the
favored side. So what is the favored
side? It's pretty much the side, if you
go to cricket, that has a higher price
cuz they're the favorite, right? So you
can see 44 cents versus 57 cents. This
would be the favorite. I think this game
might be going. I'm not sure, but it
doesn't matter. I I don't care if it's
going or not because the bot's handling
it. I've already built it.
You can see it's the Indian Premier
League and the Pakistan Super League,
okay? Cancels all bids after the halfway
point. So I already explained that part.
There's two innings and first first team
bats first and then the second team
chases it. So this is another cool thing
about Polymarket is you're going to
expand your your rollodex rollodex of
knowledge at the end of the day because
I'm building for sports that I don't
even understand or politics I don't even
understand. It's so cool, man. It's so
cool. And the only reason I'm here is
because I was here.
Trading emotionally,
losing money, getting liquidated just
like you. You think they they can see
your positions? You're 100% right. They
can see your positions. They are moving
towards your stop loss and take profit.
I can see your positions, too. And
everybody in this Zoom chat can also see
your positions. You can see this guy
gets liquidated at 1.1%.
This guy in 1.4% he loses $11 million.
So yes, you're getting you're getting
hunted, dude. You're getting hunted.
You're getting hunted by us. Let's be
real. So, let me get you some more of
this code because you have the full
idea. You can start building right now.
I'll scroll through some of this, but
I'm also just going to drop it in there.
You can see these are the important
parts. I'm using the ESPN API here
in order to get the actual score and
figure out what time it is.
I'm using a multi-account setup here, so
I can switch to other accounts here. I
don't want this video to be over 10
minutes. So, what I'm going to do is I'm
just going to go ahead and drop all this
code here
inside of Discord. I've explained the
majority of this or the entire idea.
Here's my cricket
cricket polymarket polymarket cricket
bot and we'll call it cricket.py here. I
know everybody wants shorter videos, so
shorter videos just comes down to like,
okay, I have to take something out. So,
I want to explain the idea because I
think that's the most important thing.
You can see here I have posted the
videos or I mean, sorry, the code for so
many things over the years. My team has
as well. I just uploaded three fire
ideas, the cricket bot, the polymarket
cricket bot, the call sheet whale
scanner, and the women's trading bot.
This is all in the quant elite section.
We do have an Easter special going on
right now. If you do want to grab that,
it's moondev.com/easter.
But, damn, I just went over 10 minutes
and people are want shorter and shorter
videos. You save 300 bucks, but you can
see that if you want.
Damn, dude. It's so hard to make under
10 minutes, dude. I just yap too much
and I apologize. I'm trying I'm really
trying.
I'm really, really trying.
I'm really, really trying, dude. I'm
really, really trying.
Okay, so I do want to make some changes
here while this is up.
So,
when it's over 24 hours,
I want it to show days as well. When
it's under 24 hours, it will only show
hours.
Thank you.
Also, moondev.com/win,
we need to adjust that pricing.
Don't make it any taller.
Just say Easter special and you'll it's
new pricing there. So, go ahead and
update that moondev.com/win.
And for the 24-hour thing I was saying
above, you know, that will be for
moondev.com/easter.
Schedule that to close on Monday at
midnight Pacific time.
So, today is Thursday, April 2nd, and
Monday was a few days from now.
I think Moon Dev was held back in the
7th grade. I was.
Wish I could take care of you. Thank
you, Dixie. Appreciate you. Your
teaching, sir. Not yet, but I appreciate
I appreciate you.
>> [laughter]
>> You thought that was my stink bot
producing output,
but it was actually Moon Dev blowing his
nose. I'm so
I'm so sorry about that. That's so
funny.
Yeah, that probably sounds like a big
old fart.
You guys are like, this guy is nasty.
I'm doing good, Deep Sight. How you
been, bro? Good to see you. Much love.
All right, there is one more bot I want
to show you guys here today. Um but
before we get there, like, okay, so
dude, this stuff is scary. Like I said,
uh I don't know if I've told you this
guys guys, I don't know if I've told you
this, but I was held back in 7th grade.
And I'm just kidding. But, uh
I was, but
>> [clears throat]
>> even as a grown ass man, dude. Like I
told you I spent 2K on a course in order
to learn how to code or not code, learn
how to build apps without knowing how to
code. I was like, that's awesome because
I'm scared of coding. Okay, perfect. I
actually ran up a great career off that.
So, that's how I made my initial bag is
I hired developers that built apps for
me and like I said, my first one failed.
Everybody laughed at me.
I spent I was 17K in the hole. 2K for
the course, 15K for the app.
But then I built a business model based
off of what that guy taught me. So,
that's what's great about this world is
you can find somebody that knows
something you don't know.
Pay them, get everything they know, and
then you build your own stuff, but you
just accelerated by 5 years or whatever.
In this case, I only accelerated by 2
years. He was it was the app store was
new. It was like 2011.
It was only out since 2008. People were
really only building for a couple years.
He got in early, taught me everything,
and then I cooked for the next decade.
I was using developers off Upwork,
though, and I was paying, paying,
paying.
And
once I got into trading, it was just
like it got bad quick, you know? Trading
by hand with just spot is one thing.
Like, of course, I've been doing that
for a long, long time.
But, it's when I started getting on
BitMEX and Phemex and all of these
exchanges that gave you 38 40X leverage.
That's when I started getting cooked, so
it's too easy to rail that leverage up,
dude. It's too easy. And I had heard
about the automated traders before, but
it it was one day my realtor was showing
me a place. She's like, I got this
special client here and he doesn't want
to see many people, so seems like you're
really interested, so I'll show you. I
walk in, dude, and he has the windows
wide open. Beach view, wide open.
[\h__\h] magical. Looks so sick. You can
see the whole beach.
He's sitting on the couch, though. First
off, what are you doing here, buddy?
He's on his computer. I see all these
flashing lights. That's what inspired
all this that you see on my screen. All
inspired by this guy. Flashing lights
like this. I walk in like
trying to listen to the realtor. I'm I'm
wondering why this mother Why does he
have the air conditioning on
with the windows open? You must be
balling. She's she's yapping. He's over
here
on the couch, on his computer. I
couldn't pay attention, so
eventually I'm like, what is that, bro?
And he's like, oh,
I'm an algo trader.
I push a billion dollars per day.
He's trading a billion dollars per day.
Talked to him some more and he's just
like a bro. He's just a bro, dude. Just
like you and I.
No different.
And that's when it clicked cuz I was
I was living that trader's life, but
trading with leverage just just wasn't
working. It was too much time, too much
stress, too much lost money,
too much anxiety.
So, once I shook that man's hand, I I
realized that he's just a regular dude,
but he's trading a billion dollars per
day. I don't need to trade a billion
dollars per day. I just need to automate
my trading.
That inspired me. So, for the next year
I locked in 4 hours every single day.
Every single day to learn how to code by
hand.
This was 5 6 years ago. We didn't have
AI. 2 years in,
ChatGPT dropped. And since that day,
people have been making fun of me for
being an AI coder. But now, like now in
2026, late 2025,
now everybody's like, oh bro, have you
heard heard of Claude code? Yeah, we
have our whole team using Claude code to
code. Dude, I'm I'm a pioneer.
Pioneer in the app store. Pioneer in
drop shipping. Pioneer e-commerce
Shopify. Pioneer in Facebook ads.
It's just I'm always early to these
things.
And I always try to help my friends get
caught to speed, but my friends don't
care. They don't care about this stuff.
I'm sure you can relate, right? You try
you get excited about opportunity and
then you try to tell your friends and
they're like, what okay.
I don't care.
It's like, come on, bro. I'm trying to
get out the trenches. I'm trying to help
you out the trenches as well.
They don't care. They don't care.
There's doers and dabblers, but that's
why I'm so impressed with the people
that come through here. It's because you
guys actually care. I didn't ask you to
come here. You're just literally
watching over the shoulder of some
random dude on the internet building
bots chasing Jim Simons.
That is extremely confident because I
have the data.
I have the data. I get to things early.
I build. People think I'm crazy. They
were saying I'm an idiot. I'm crazy in
2020 in 2022 when ChatGPT dropped. I
started using AI for everything because
remember, I learned how to code, but I
was only like 2 years into coding.
So, I was blessed with AI.
And the thing is, you probably think
you're too late right now, but we have
just started to get into this AI era.
Everybody's using AI now. You're not
silly if you're using AI anymore. Like,
I I used to call it, oh, he can he can
only code cuz he uses AI, but it doesn't
matter. Code is code. It's the output
that matters. I have the ideas and I
show you how to get the ideas. Anybody
can do this. LA says, my friends don't
even like AI. Exactly. They think it's
going to like ruin the world and things
like that.
You're ahead of the curve. You're ahead
of your friend. You're ahead of your
family. So, you can't listen to them
when it comes to how to build the
future. And I think that's the point.
It's like I I saw all this rhetoric
about trading bots and stuff,
but it was hard to believe it like that
I could do that until I met homeboy. He
was sitting there smoking a joint
when I walked in, dude. He put out his
joint. It's like, what the hell? You got
somebody looking at your place? You
don't give a
It doesn't give a He had a few money. He
was trading a billion dollars a day.
And his tank top on.
That dude, it's just it was like, oh
yeah. Okay, you can do this, I can do
this, too. Let's get it.
Locked in. Couple years took me to
figure out a code. A year took me to
figure out a code. Got my first bot
live. Lost all my money on my first bot
cuz I didn't have a framework. I just
set it live thinking, "Hey, I know how
to code now. I'm I'm going to be a
billionaire." But, that's not it. And
that's why I I do preach this so hard. I
go here and I show you this because this
framework
changed the game for me. Now, I don't
just go run and build bots. I go ahead
and research great ideas. I have a stack
of ideas. I actually share a lot of
these ideas here.
And then I back test to see if they
actually work in the past. If they work
in the past,
then they're much more likely to work in
the future. My system before this was,
"Hey,
I have a I have an idea I want to trade.
I think that Apple's going up today or I
think Bitcoin's going up today or I
think it's going down today. So, I'm
going to use 30 40X leverage." But, now
I have the data that using 34 40X
leverage, you won't win ever. You'll
never win. You'll never ever ever win.
He says, "Just got my first bot set up.
It's still in testing, but very
promising." It's much more promising way
to approach the markets, and I think we
all know that. Just like it's much safer
to have AI drive for us in these Teslas
than it is for me to drink a couple
beers and then drive down the road,
right? Like, it's it's obvious. And I
lost my best friend to drinking and
driving. So, that [\h__\h] hit that [\h__\h]
hurts. That hurts.
And I What was I doing when he was doing
that? I was staring at the charts. My
other friend hit me up like, "Bro, call
me back." I'm like, "No.
I'm in a trade."
That [\h__\h] stings, dude.
We literally have AI driving for us.
But, we still are manual trading.
If AI was driving that night,
he would still be here.
But, I was over here manual trading.
Like, I know there's there's no
correlation. It's not my fault. I get
that. But, how many times did I not go
home? How many times did I not kick it?
I didn't even answer the I didn't even
answer the phone call in the emergency,
you know?
Cuz I'm over here wasting my life
trading thinking I'm a a trader. No,
dude. There's a better approach to these
markets, and it's been proven over and
over and over and over again. You look
around right now, who's everybody
talking about? Jane Street.
How do they trade?
Fully automated.
There's no reason to waste your life,
waste your time.
Please, please, please.
I hope this inspires you, dude. I hope
it does. I hope you can see that I'm
just a regular dude
just like you.
You're probably ahead of me. I don't
know if I've told you this before, but I
got held back in seventh grade.
Oh my god. I want to show you one more
tutorial here because I think it's
important that you, you know, I'm not
just yapping.
I hope this is helpful to have this
framework. Like I said, I thought that
just because I learned how to code, I
could just build a profitable bot, and
this is not true. Don't go spend $10,000
on your first bot. Start with small
size. You can see this entire time I've
had bots incubating all day cuz I
actually follow what I I preach because
I built this framework for myself.
Because some days you wake up and you're
like, "What the hell am I going to do
today?"
Oh, well, I get three I have three
options. I'm either researching, I'm
back testing, or I'm incubating. That's
that's my my framework
that I've spent real money to develop,
and now you have it.
So, you know, you don't have to pay me
anything. You already have the
framework.
You can go do this on your own.
But, let's be honest. Information alone
isn't going to help you that much.
You're going to need a team. You're
going to need
step-by-step instructional videos.
Or you're going to need to spend 5 years
like I did. So, that's a decision you'll
make.
But, I want to show you this NBA bot
now. Cuz I showed you the tennis bot. I
showed you the Calshi scanner. I've
shown you the cricket bot.
But, I don't know
about you, dude. I'm a hoops guy. I grew
up playing basketball.
I'm a basketball player.
I'm just a dumb jock.
Yes. Yes, the same people that are
picking on me today were picking on me
back in the day about me being a dumb
jock. Like, okay.
>> [laughter]
>> The thing is is like the tides have
turned, right? Like,
okay. Okay. Okay. Okay. Nowadays, you
actually have a point. I didn't go to
Stanford. I didn't go to Harvard. I
don't have a math degree. I'm not a
scientist. Once you get out of school,
it's not cool to be a jock anymore. It's
not.
While you're on the team,
okay, it's kind of cool. But, it's not
Once you're grown up, it's not.
I should have spent my time studying
more.
But, I hope it encourages you that like
if some dumb jock held back can figure
this out, you can, too. And I've made it
much easier for you. I have On that road
map that I gave you, it has frequently
asked questions. You probably have a ton
of questions here.
Ton of questions here.
And I have a ton of answers here.
Got a ton of answers. Do I have a
community? Yes, I have a Discord.
Do you have videos that show me how to
do this? Yes.
This road map is thick. It's better than
a book, in my opinion. But, there's also
a bunch of books in it
that you can learn from. So, now you
have successfully learned exactly how to
find great ideas, literally steal them
from your competitors.
Do you know how to get data
to back test yet? Cuz if you don't,
data's very very expensive, and it's
very hard to get. But, you get it for
free on this road map. Or you can go to
moondab.com/data, or you can go to the
app here and just download data here so
you can back test. So, come up with
great ideas, back test, see if they
actually work in the past. If they do,
then go ahead and automate them.
Now, like I said, a lot of this
Polymarket stuff is hard to back test,
but this alone will be helpful for you.
Instead of running a bot with full size,
incubate it. So, with Polymarket, where
I can't go ahead and
back test very well, I just incubate
with small size. And you've seen these
bots running all week, all month, all
year.
I'm always incubating on screen, and
then I scale up here on
I scale up
on servers.
And these die because they're on
Polymarket, and I have to switch on and
off something special in order to trade
on Polymarket.
But, I've got hyperliquid bots. I've got
Polymarket bots always always
incubating.
And then I just scale on a server. It's
super easy, and I I know it's
intimidating to think about servers, but
rest assured, it is as simple as
watching a 10-minute tutorial that I
show you how to build your server up so
you can deploy your bots on the cloud so
you don't have to run them on the
computer. I like to run them on the
computer to start
because then I can see errors like you
just saw. Like, these will die. If you
get on a VPN, get off of it,
they sometimes die. You got to restart
them.
But, I've got what? Probably 15
different bots I'm always incubating on
screen.
But, back to that NBA bot, I want to go
ahead and I want to show you that. I
understand this is intimidating, dude. I
understand that.
I consider myself dumb as well. So, if
you feel dumb, you feel behind, if you
feel like it's too late, I didn't start
until I was 30 years old.
I didn't start until I was 30 years old.
I spent the first 10 years in tech
scared to learn how to code.
Let me get the keys and everything that
you get when you join the call here
today. Let me get all of that inside of
the Zoom chat, and then I'm going to
spend another 10 minutes to go over
this next tutorial here that will show
you exactly how to build the NBA bot.
So, the last one I showed you was the
cricket bot tutorial.
I showed you the Calshi bot tutorial
today. I showed you how to build a
women's tennis Polymarket bot. And I've
given you my actual framework. So,
if you're still here, you are a quant. I
want you to realize that, and I don't
want you to ever say you're just a
trader because I look at my friends when
I tell them I'm a I'm a trader, and they
literally they they smirk. They're like,
"Moon, are you okay?
Are you good?
You're just gambling for a living now?"
But, once I changed
into automated trader, I tell them I'm a
quant, they're like introducing me to
their friends like, "Oh, you got to meet
my friend. He's a quant."
So, I think that's life-changing that
literally you qualify for now because
you understand the system in order to be
a quant.
You understand that you don't have to go
to Harvard. I feel cooked, bro. I feel
like I'm not smart at all.
I'm just persistent. And I think you're
persistent as well. Actually, I know
that
because you're still here.
You're still here, and you found me
somehow.
So, much love to you.
Let me go ahead and
show you this this NBA bot real quick.
Aw, he's so
girl.
Oh my god.
She found my clean clothes and then
she's laying on them.
I don't even care.
It looks comfy as as hell.
So, let's go ahead here and just explain
this real quick. So, let's go to
Cricket. Let's go to NBA. So,
this is crazy that Polymarket unlocked
something that you haven't thought about
yet. And I want you to think about this
clearly. Okay, before when you used to
sports bet, I don't know if you ever
did, but essentially you're gambling
against the casino. The casino's not
going to let you win, period.
We know that.
Okay.
But,
trading on Polymarket is different. And
here's why. And I'm going to show you
the full idea today. I'll get you all
the code,
but I think the important part is the
idea cuz you can teach a man to fish,
feed him so for the rest of his life, or
you can just give him a fish and feed
him for the night.
I'm going to teach you for the rest of
your life.
Before,
I was not convinced on sports trading on
Polymarket cuz I looked at it the exact
same way as I looked at betting at the
casino.
You're not going to win.
But, this one concept right here should
open your mind up
to the fact that there's actually a
paradigm shift happening here.
And it's because, remember, you take 50
bucks up to the casino sports book and
you say, "Hey, I want to bet on the
Lakers." Okay, you pay what they say
you're going to pay, right?
There's some spread or whatever.
But, you don't get to make the rules.
Now, this is the regime shift, the
paradigm shift. I can go over here
instead of saying, "Okay, casino, I want
to take Minnesota for 40 cents or
whatever the spread is."
Now, I can go in here and say, "Hey, I
want to take Minnesota,
but only if I can buy it for a 30%
discount." That is game-changing.
Because you don't have to trade every
single game. Now, if you're like a
gambler and you're just like doing this
for fun where you want to bet on the
Hornets cuz you're a Hornets guy, that's
one thing.
I'm an algorithmic trader. I'm looking
for edge. I'm looking for
bots that can run 24/7 and make money
for me.
That's what I'm looking for. So, until
to this week, really, I haven't been
trading on Polymarket sports because my
thought was everybody's too emotional,
yada yada. But, I hadn't thought about
this strategy that I pulled from another
strategy that I was building on
Polymarket. I've built probably 15
different ideas on Polymarket, and I
brought this stink bid strategy over to
sports, and so far, so good, dude. So,
now we're building it for NBA games.
I'll go ahead and give you all the code.
I'll show you it, and if I don't have
time, then I'll at least explain the
idea and put all the code inside the
Discord. But, does that make sense to
you? When you go to a sports book, say,
"Hey, I want to bet on bet on the Suns."
They're like, "Okay, it's going to cost
this much."
You can't go to the sports book and say,
"Hey, I want to place this bet if the
the market moves 30% down."
And this happens a lot because there's
whales in here, and there's not a lot of
liquidity.
So, if somebody wanted to sell more than
$6,000 worth, well, it's going to jump
down to the next price. And more than
that, it's next price. So, what I've
been doing is I just set my bids really
low, and I'm not going to get in every
game. I'm going to get into a very few
amount of games, actually. But, when I
do get into a game,
it's going to be at a price that I got
to pick.
You can't pick prices at the sports
book. You can pick prices on Polymarket,
and that is the paradigm shift that I
hope changes the world for you. So,
let's go ahead and have her explain it.
I'm using six cloud codes at all times.
Go ahead and explain my NBA bot here so
everybody understands it.
So, we'll have her explain it.
But, I want to start going through some
of the code here because I think it's
important that you see part of this
code. So,
essentially, it's the same playbook. I
built a cricket bot based off of this
idea. I built a tennis bot based off of
off this idea, and I've built a bunch of
other bots, just like 5-minute bots
based off of this idea. Hey, I will buy
any market if you give me a mad
discount.
Now, nobody else is going to share that
even idea with you.
But, essentially, it places a lowball
bid 30% below market
on the favorite in every NBA game. We
only bid during the first half,
quarter one and quarter two. Is that
right or wrong? I don't know. Again, I'm
just getting started here, and I think
it's important, since I do believe code
is a great equalizer, to share the idea
with you so I can teach a man how to
fish for the rest of our lives.
Once the second half starts, Q3, we
cancel everything.
Is that right? I don't know. The idea is
in the first half, it's the most
volatile, and panic people panic.
If a favorite goes down early, someone
dumps their shares cheap, we scoop them
at a discount. If we get filled, I hold
it to expiration.
The favorite usually wins, and we
collect the $1 per share. So, if I get
filled at 30 cents, beautiful.
Do you go to the sports book, you got to
get filled at 55 cents. Refreshes every
15 minutes, and we use ESPN for quarter
status. Now, that's important to know
because people are always asking, "How
much are the APIs? How much are the
APIs?" Well, ESPN API is free.
So, let me get you some of this code,
and like I said, I'll go ahead and make
sure that we get the um
all this code loaded into the Discord by
the end of this. But, essentially, it
places what I call a stink bid on the
favored side
of the NBA games.
You can see right here, the bet size I
use $5.
And the discount is 30 cents. Why do I
use such a small size? It's because I
wasn't able to backtest this. So, I
don't know if it's going to work. So,
you're cooked if you think you're just
going to go run this and make a million
dollars.
But, the process I follow is start with
research. I kind of did some research
based on my other bots, and I see that
the stink bids are doing well, so I
brought it over to sports, and I was
scared of trading sports cuz I thought
everybody was emotional. But, like I
said, you can't just go up to the sports
book and say, "Hey, let me get 30%
discount on this game." You can't do
that, but you can do that on Polymarket,
and that's a paradigm shift. Just like
the paradigm shift I went through from
web to mobile. Everybody started
building apps and making millions of
dollars on apps.
Nobody knew how to build apps. Somebody
taught me. I spent $2,000 to
learn how to build an app, dude. And I
didn't know how to code. That was the
whole premise. I hired a developer,
spent 15k building an app, it flopped,
but it put me into a business model that
I was able to run up millions of dollars
in cuz that was a paradigm shift.
Polymarket is a paradigm shift. The old
way of trading,
or betting sports betting, you're
trading against the casino. Now, you're
trading against people.
So, there's ideas like this, and this is
just an idea. I'm always researching.
You catch me every single day. I'm
always researching, backtesting, or
incubating a bot. So, since it's kind of
hard to backtest this idea, I skipped
it, and I incubate with small size.
And that is alpha for you because I got
into this, I spent a year learning how
to code, and I just launched a bot with
10k size. I didn't backtest or research.
I lost that money.
But, out of this, I've built a robust
framework that I don't lose money like
that anymore because the most I'll lose
is that $5 size, $10 size. If this
doesn't do well over time,
then I just don't scale it.
And if it does do well, I put it in the
cloud, and I never look at it. I just
let it run so I don't tinker. But, you
can see, these are the APIs that you're
going to need. This is the ESPN API. If
you're an advanced coder, you already
know how to use that. You can send in
the AI even if you're not an advanced
coder. I did not know how to code before
any of this.
So, validating credentials. This is
because I have a multi-account system,
obviously, right?
Everybody sees my account. They see the
returns. They see the ups and the downs.
Whatever, it doesn't matter to me.
I got to scale elsewhere.
I have to test five to six to seven
different ideas a day.
So, with Polymarket, there is no
sub-account, unfortunately.
So, I have a multi-account system here,
and I'm just running this on one
account. You can see, this is how we
find today's games on Polymarket.
So, every single day, there's new games,
and that's what I was looking for,
really.
I was looking for markets that trade a
lot. You know, the 5-minute markets are
fun, but they almost trade too much.
So, I was looking for things that turn
over each day. That's why today I've
actually gone ahead inside the members
area,
I've gone ahead and dropped three
different bots, and I've been doing this
for years, and I have a team that's
doing the same thing.
I spend 4, 8, 12 hours figuring
something out, and then I try to make
these videos under 10 minutes.
And I give all the code to everybody
inside of the Discord. So, I'm running
up on that 10 minutes, and I don't want
this to be longer than 10 minutes
because, guess what? Everybody tries to
juice their videos to be over 10 minutes
so they can get more ad money. I don't
want your ad money, dude. I want your
mind.
So, if you're actually interested in
this stuff, join the Discord.
And I'm putting this code in here before
this 10 minutes is up. NBA
Polymarket
bot. But, I explained the main idea
already. So, you have the main idea, NBA
Polymarket
bot. If you want all of these bots plus
5 years backtesting bots,
then take me up on the Easter special.
It's moondev.com/easter.
There's $300 off. You can find the link
for that below. But, like I said, you
get paid more ad money if you're over 10
minutes, so I want to make sure this
video is not over 10 minutes, peace.
All right, dude. I know I threw four
different bots at you today.
I know [snorts] you're probably a little
overwhelmed.
I get that.
Uh throw one in the chat if you want me
to go over that Easter special.
I put together the Easter special for
you guys. Throw one in the chat. Like I
said, I'm actually dying today. I need
to go to bed.
Um but I will spend 10 minutes going
over that here. Let me go ahead and see
if it's updated here.
moondev.com/win
Okay, so this is everything you're going
to get for that Easter special. It is
live now. moondev.com/easter
But essentially, I'm going to show you
step-by-step how to get your trading
bots live. Now, like I said, I got held
back in 7th grade, dude.
If I can do this, you can do this.
I'll show you in short concise videos
over the next 6 weeks
exactly
how to get your trading bots live.
No BS.
I'll show you every single step of the
way.
I'll answer any questions that you have.
We have that members area that you saw.
We're all here helping each other.
We're in the members chat all day long.
You got questions, we got answers.
We got a code help section as well. So,
this is a full hold your hand to success
algo trade camp step-by-step tutorials.
You can see there's 6 weeks of videos
here.
Day 1 through 15, you're going to learn
how to get your bots live, but I'm not
your guru.
I'm in the trenches with you. I'm
chasing Jim Simons. He's the $31 million
man.
This is serious stuff to me. So, every
time I find something new, I just add
another day. So, it's a 15-day boot
camp, but now it's 6 weeks cuz again,
I'm not like I'm not your guru, dude.
I'm in the trenches with you.
So, in the algo trade camp, you can
Google it. See all the reviews. Algo
trade camp reviews.
See what people have to say about it.
16 hours ago. Just simply amazing.
These are real people just like you that
found me, so
big ups to you, really. You also get the
AI masterclasses. This is a course that
shows you exactly how to use AI to do
all the coding for you, so you don't
have to worry about all the hard stuff.
Like I didn't know how to code either.
I'll show you step-by-step how to use AI
to do all of the heavy lifting. So, not
only am I going to help you get your
trading bots live, I'm going to make you
the best in the world at using AI to
code. For the rest of your life, you're
going to be able to cook up anything,
any day, anywhere, anytime.
On top of that, I'll show you how to
build on Solana. Two different courses
for that. On top of that, you saw a
bunch of Polymarket bots today.
I showed you four tutorials of how to
build a Polymarket bot. I showed you my
framework of exactly how you can go from
non-coder,
emotional trader to fully automated
trader.
And I'm going to show you step-by-step
in this course
how to build for Polymarket.
Plus, you get unlimited Zoom calls. So,
all of these Zoom calls that we have,
you get for life.
And you saw me drop those four bots here
in the Quantalyt today.
Well,
Quantalyt code,
you get access to the Quantalyt, which
other people are paying $300 a month
for.
So, you get access to that for the
Easter special that is starting, I
guess, right now.
I meant for it to start tomorrow, but it
is what it is. I don't I don't know if
I'll make it tomorrow.
I don't know if I'll make it tomorrow.
I'm going to make it. I'm going to make
it. I'm going to make it every day, but
I am sick as a dog here today, so I
appreciate you guys locking in. This is
everything you're going to get.
Actually, there's a little bit more.
Quantalyt is crazy though cuz people are
paying $300 a month for that. It's a
$3,500 value. You get lifetime access to
it including everything in the past.
But on top of that, you get a bunch of
bonuses. The Moondev vault is pretty
cool. It has all of my videos that have
been taken down from YouTube. There's 2
terabytes of videos, stream things that
nobody else has access to except you.
If you join as well today, you get the
Moondev API key. It's $10,000 value
because if you go to CoinGlass and try
to buy liquidation data alone, not to
mention all of the hyper liquid data,
not to mention the AI,
they would charge you $900 a month for
12 days of data. I give you 18 months of
data.
It's a free bonus. The API key is sick.
You can go to moondev.com/docs
if you want to learn more about it. You
also get my trading bot GitHub. This is
another huge bonus here.
I'm going to show you exactly all of the
code that I've been building, all the
bots, all the backtests, 100 plus
backtests, a bunch of templates. If you
want to trade for futures, stocks,
forex, whatever. If you want AI agents
to help you out with building out
systems or you want my swarm agent, you
also get this GitHub. This was the
fastest growing GitHub in the world. I
took it down
because this is war. And if you want to
go to war with me on my team, then jump
in, get caught up to speed. You're
getting everything you see on the screen
plus more. You also get the Moondev app.
So, the app that I use all day in order
to code,
in order to see everybody's positions
here. I can see everybody's positions,
dude.
How much better of a trader are you
going to be when you're able to see
everybody's positions?
It's a crazy advantage. It's crazy
advantage, but you get that as a bonus.
So, you get the algo trade camp where I
show you step-by-step how to get your
trading bots live. These are short
concise videos. You also get the members
area.
You get the AI masterclasses. You get
the Solana copy bot and sniper course,
the Polymarket trading bot course. It's
all everything all forever. It's
lifetime access to everything. You never
have to pay me a dime again.
And you can see the results from other
people. Like you saw the testimonials
earlier.
See, this just scrolls for hours. This
just scrolls for hours and hours and
hours. These are just more and more
people that found me just like you
organically through the internet because
you are a data dog and you research.
So, if they can do it, why can't you?
That's the question.
Now, it's a $48,000 value. I'm not even
going to charge you half that. I'm not
even going to charge you 75%
of it, 25% of that, dude. I'm not.
And like I said, there's a Easter
special. So, you don't have to get on a
call with me. You can get started today.
This is real world stuff, not just a
classroom environment. I paid him a year
in advance. The boot camp is the best
value I've ever received. It changed my
life.
Moondev's course is amazing. I honestly
don't want more people to join.
Huh.
Come on, dude.
It's time.
For Easter, we're having a crazy
discount, $300 off.
It's $14.95 instead of the regular
$17.95. It's one-time payment, lifetime
access. You never pay me again.
moondev.com/easter.
If you want to take me up on that here
and now, don't worry, there is a 90-day
no questions asked money-back guarantee.
So, we all know money replenishes, but
time does not. So, if you want to spend
5 years trying to get caught up to speed
with me, you'll never catch up,
unfortunately,
because I have so many intelligent
quants around me all day long helping me
out.
So, you can see this is the Easter
special here. You got a few days if you
want to decide, but really, you have 90
full days if you truly want to decide as
there's a 90-day no questions asked
money-back guarantee. You can see that
everything that you get here, you get
the algo trade camp that's going to help
you get your trading bots live. You get
the AI masterclasses that's going to
help you master AI and build for the
rest of your life
anything you want, anything you can
imagine. So,
ask yourself this. Is 1,500 bucks worth
being able to build trading bots for the
rest of your life? And not only that,
build whatever you want. You saw me spin
up this website on the side. Just AI
just did it for me. So,
you can join now, save 300 bucks for
Easter. Super simple to do. Just click
the join now button.
You'll be able to scroll here and you'll
see it's all connected via Stripe.
And I'm in Mexico right now. Not
actually, but you know how that goes.
You can see you can pay with credit,
debit, cash, whatever.
Crypto, or you can break it down to two
payments. Two payments of 777. Much love
to you.
You get the Polymarket course. You get
the Solana course. You get unlimited
Zoom calls. Everything I've ever had,
ever released, and everything in the
future. This is a lifetime all access
pass. Quantalyt, 5 years of bots and
backtests, and new code added every
single week. I dropped four
bots in there today.
That's insane.
Four on a Thursday. On a sick day.
You get the Moondev vault. You get the
API key for life. You get your own API
key forever.
You get the trading bot GitHub. You get
the AI agents GitHub. You get the
Moondev app access. And these are real
people that came through here just like
yourself. And there's a 90-day no
questions asked money-back guarantee.
I'm nobody special.
I don't know if I told you this today,
but I got held back in 7th grade.
>> [laughter]
>> Uh I I just want you to know that like
anybody can do this. I want you to know
that whatever situation you're in,
however cooked you feel, however far
behind you feel, dude, I feel that, too.
But this is a perfect time.
Remember, I didn't have AI and you do.
Plus, you have a mentor that actually
cares about your success. I'm in the
chat with you. If you got questions,
we're here to help.
If you get stuck, we're here to help.
The videos are so straightforward and
packed with so much information. The
boot camp is lit.
Just wanted to personally thank you for
making the boot camp. Like you could
have sold it for 10x that.
The course should be perfect for you.
I'm also a dev and it got me caught up
to speed with crypto and algo trading.
It's actually really cheap considering
what you get. Most of it can be pieced
together from MoonDev's YouTube videos,
but it would require constantly
screenshotting and copying code. And
those YouTube videos that he was talking
about are now not even on YouTube. They
made me take them down. I took down a
thousand videos.
Cuz I got strikes. They don't want me to
share this stuff. I'm telling you, dude.
So I put it all into the vault. It's all
in the vault. You still can have access
to those videos.
I went from not knowing Python to
learning the fundamental building blocks
with the help of MoonDev's boot camp.
Algo trade camp is is great with a
genuine teacher.
He delivers time after time.
You won't be disappointed.
It's not a get-rich-quick scheme.
Even after you pay, you still come to
the streams. That's the thing is maybe
these streams don't make too much sense.
That's cuz I'm on year six, dude.
Sandlin says, "My bot is making money.
So get to coding and stop losing. I was
classic get stopped out daily and it
pissed me off, hence why I'm here making
money."
Been a member, it's great. Would highly
suggest it. That's cool. One of my bots
I set up with watching you is pretty
profitable, thanks to you.
So if you're ready to get started, just
go to moondev.com/easter
and join the $300 off. Either way, two
payments or one payment. It's a 90-day
money-back guarantee. That's the thing,
dude. You can be an informed buyer. I
went to Costco last year and I didn't
know if I wanted the PS5. We went up
there. I was eating my hot dog. She said
uh we asked what the money what the
refund policy is. She said,
"We take back a half-eaten hot dog." So
I was like, "Yeah, I'm I'm implementing
that." 90 days, no questions asked. Be
an informed buyer. Check it out. If it's
not for you, it's not for you. No
questions asked. 90-day money-back
guarantee. And you know I'm here. You
know I'm going to be here for the next
90 days, too, because I'm obsessed with
chasing Jim Simons. The opportunity is
so big
that I feel like I can share everything
along the way because I don't need $31
billion.
You over-delivered.
I want you to stop staring at these
charts all day. I want you to stop
trying to guess if the price is going up
or down. I want you to stop being
stressed out. I want you to stop wasting
your time with your loved ones.
You can still have exposure to these
markets. You just have to approach it
from an automated stance. And I'll get
you caught up to speed and we will get
your trading bots live and I will be
there every single step of the way. I
have explained this to hundreds of
people. We're going through these
testimonials here. You can go to
moondev.com/testimonials
if you want to go ahead and look at them
yourself.
Yeah, the funny thing is is MoonDev has
the attention of hedge fund companies
copying his scripts.
Six doors that opened six months that
opened doors I never thought possible.
And I'm not I'm nothing special, dude.
I'm just here I'm just here to show you
everything cuz my bet is this. And it's
worked out so far. I've been here for
six years. My bet has always been if I
do this the exact opposite of what
everybody else does, I'm going to build
the best algorithmic community in the
world. I'm going to give people that are
smarter than me everything I know and
let them absolutely cook. And guess
what? I'm connected to them for life.
Business partners, people that are
working in the Discord helping me out.
Like I've accelerated probably 15 years
in this five years because I've shown
everything. I believe in abundance. So
if you believe in abundance, keep
giving, dude. Keep giving. When you get
in here and you learn, you're coming
with ideas. Give that back to the chat
if you feel feel like it. If you don't,
that's fine, too. Take everything I
know. He says, "The boot camp was the
kick in the ass that I needed."
And you really got two choices, dude.
You're still here, so I know you want to
have trading bots trading for you 24/7.
Don't be that guy that just makes up
some excuse, dude. I shouldn't be here,
either. I got the This is the flu game,
dude. This is the flu game. I'm going to
bed after this. I have to.
But I'm still locked in because I made a
commitment. I made a commitment, dude.
I'm locking in every single day.
I'll show you everything. I know a lot
of people are weird about money. I get
that.
$1,500 might be tough right now. Pay in
two payments of 777. That's okay.
You have 90 days to get your money back.
So if it doesn't do everything you
expected and more,
it's a free trial. It's a free trial.
I know people are weird with money, but
money is good. It's just a tool.
It's just a tool of exchange.
Think about it.
What else does money do for you? It's
just paper. It's just sitting there,
number in a bank account.
But you can actually turn that number in
a bank account to something much bigger
if you use it to unlock something you
don't know. If I know something you
don't know,
you'd be crazy to not pay me for it.
It's 90-day money-back guarantee. It's
not even paying me. It's not even going
to hit your credit card for 30 days.
You can check everything out. If it's
not for you, you get your money back.
And we all have some sort of disposable
income.
It's just where are you going to place
that tool of money?
Are you going to have it unlock doors
for you? Are you going to have it
accelerate you five years or are you
just going to have it sit there?
Money replenishes, dude. It just keeps
coming back and you know that. But the
thing that doesn't come back, time with
friends, family members. People die. It
just is what it is.
This guy says, "I'm paying I'm saying in
front of MoonDev, I'll pay the refund if
you truly cannot profit from this
course."
A powerful and supportive start to my
algo trading journey.
We all got bad habits. I spend way too
much money on Uber Eats. If I stopped
spending money on Uber Eats, I'd pay
this off in half a month.
So think about your bad habits. We all
have them. It's okay. We're all humans.
Just tighten up here and there. Allocate
a little bit of that tool that you have.
You have some cash. You have some
credit. If you're actually going to step
on the gas here, like I said, I spent
two grand when I didn't have it. I was a
college kid, broke.
No money. I I couldn't even think about
it. I like two grand was out of my
realm.
This guy was only two years ahead of me.
He changed my life. He taught me exactly
how to build apps without knowing how to
code.
Changed my life.
That's why I put this at 1795 because if
a broke college kid could pay 2,000 and
change his life, then
what's your excuse?
But I get it. There's two types of
people in this world. There's money
makers and excuse makers. That's it. So
if you don't join today, I know which
one you are.
I don't think that's you, though,
because you locked in for multiple hours
here and you keep coming back.
You keep coming back. So take me up on
this Easter discount. It's 300 bucks
off.
Two payments or one payment. You see all
of the proof here.
There's hundreds of people just like
yourself. He says, "Moon, I got to say
thank you for sharing all this. It's
really hard to find this kind of info
organized anywhere."
Alex says, "Anyone in doubt, it's
definitely worth it. I was in doubt
myself, but when I pulled the trigger, I
was happy I did. It's not a sales pitch
by any means. Just a personal opinion.
The boot camp put me six months ahead."
So if you want to be six months ahead,
then jump in.
I would argue it's even more because
I've been here for five years and
I show you everything. When I find
something new, I show you it.
It's already making 3K a week. Your
videos motivated me during those winter
days. There was no end in sight.
Life-changing education. I've never
received this much value from any course
before. I'm a software developer, front
end mostly. I'm flexible and tackle
whatever. I've never coded for trading
bots, so your content is literally a
treasure for me. Thank you.
You're welcome. I'm 73 years old.
He's 73. You thought you were too late?
He's 73.
Doesn't matter how old you are, dude.
You're going to be trading for the rest
of your life. You're going to be on the
computer for the rest of your life,
right?
You either make money or you make
excuses.
Let me know in the chat. What's the
reason what's holding you back?
Tied on cash?
What's holding you back, for real? Don't
trust me? There's a 90-day money-back
guarantee.
There's Klarna options as well. You can
get it down to like 72 bucks a month.
That's pretty good.
My best advice for anyone trying to
build a bot, buy his course.
The boot camp was the kick in the ass
that I needed.
This is a great course for learning way
more than you ever wanted.
Yet more evidence why there's such a
buzz around you. Incredible customer
service, truly.
I'm saying in front of MoonDev, I'll pay
the refund if you truly can't profit
from the course. That's a nice gesture,
but you nobody has to pay the refund
because I'll pay the refund. I'll refund
you.
The 90-day no questions asked money-back
guarantee. And I'm so sorry for all the
sniffling and sneezing in your ear
today. I really do apologize. I'll be
back.
I'll be back healthy
continuing to step on the gas. I'm on
the fence about buying the boot camp.
Should I take the risk? I'm starting
from ground zero coding knowledge.
Looking for the push here. I need
someone to sell me. If you're starting
from zero, you should do it. Just know
it's not a magic pill. You have to put
in the work, but MoonDev has laid
everything out so you can get up to
speed very fast. He cuts your learning
curve a lot. So that's really your
option.
Be like, "Oh damn, this is so sick. I
can't wait to have my bots trading on
Polymarket and all these exchanges
here." And then just your option one is
to leave and do nothing. or option two
is take me up on a small investment in
yourself,
a new approach to trading where it takes
all the stress away,
all the emotion,
and you get a major discount here for
Easter. So, happy Easter to you.
The course is a gem, man. Thank you for
putting it together.
I got to say, listen to Moon Dev, I too
have been doing this for around 3 years.
And I only started getting somewhere
after listening to him.
Few years later, have not found a better
price or quality.
Much appreciated. When one of your team
of doctors said you were 7 months past
when you were projected to pass away, it
kind of puts into perspective that
there's people that deserve to know that
I probably would have passed if it
wasn't for people like you. My bots I've
made from your ideas, combined with
mine, paid off $186,000
of medical bills the last quarter of
2023. So, I just really got to say, out
of everyone I've ever come across,
you've done the most to keep me alive
and out of millions in debt. And I won't
ever forget that. So, much love to him,
dude.
He went through the boot camp. The boot
camp that you have access to starting
today. Plus, you have all of these
bonuses. The AI master classes will show
you exactly how to do have AI do all the
heavy lifting. And the algo trade camp,
that shows you exactly how to get your
bots live.
From a place of not knowing how to code.
So, if you don't know how to code right
now, don't worry. I didn't either. I had
to learn it the hard way, and I make it
easy for you. AI master classes will
show you how to have all the AI do all
the heavy lifting.
Plus, you got the Solana courses.
Plus, you got the Polymarket course.
I show you four different bots there. I
also dropped four bots into the Quant
Elite section, and you get Quant Elite
for life.
So, if you're paying $297 a month right
now, or you joined one of these pieces,
this right here is worth it cuz this is
$3,500 a year that people are paying
right now. So, if you're in this or any
of these pieces,
upgrade right now.
Because this discount will not be here.
It's 4 days, 13 hours, and 51 minutes.
Think about it, but in reality, you have
4 days plus 90 days to become an
informed buyer. You can just
join today. Say you're still on the
fence. Go absorb everything, learn
everything, get all my code, get the API
key for life, get the vault, get both
GitHubs, and the Moon Dev app access. If
you have questions,
moon@algotradecamp.com.
Text me, call me, DM me, whatever, dude.
You got a question, let me know in the
chat. I'm here.
You can see hundreds of people just like
yourself took me up on this offer, and
you actually get something much better.
You get all those bonuses that you saw.
I don't need to keep going over them. I
actually need to get into bed. Let's be
real.
Heal up, and then I'm going to keep
stepping on the gas every single day.
What I figure out
What have I What I figured out over the
last 5, 6 years, you know in short,
concise videos here. Did you like the
tutorials today? If you did, you're
going to love the tutorials in the algo
trade camp because I go back to square
one.
Back to when I did not know how to code.
I pretend I don't know how to code, and
I show you exactly how to code.
I'm on a regular standpoint, not some
super nerd. Like, I'm not super smart.
I've told you that over and over again.
You can hear it in my voice, dude. My
English is not good,
even though I grew up in America.
Just a regular dude
with a big vision.
Thank you for your dedication. Hope you
feel better soon. Thank you. Thank you.
Thank you, dude.
Much love to you guys. You have the
link, moondev.com/easter.
I don't have anything else to share with
you. Much love. I hope you have a
wonderful day. Let me go ahead and see I
know I missed a lot of chats today, so
let me go ahead and scroll through the
chats before I get going. If you have
any other questions, let me know. K8
likes my dog. I like her a lot.
I'm going to scroll through all this
chat here.
See if there's anything. Do you have a
Telegram chat for programmers to join?
Woo says, I've got a Discord chat, so
we've got a members-only section here,
members chat, that you will get access
to.
And you can see we're just chatting all
day, helping each other out, so
feel free to jump into that. We see the
future, Kelly says. We do. Let's get it.
And Kelly's been absolutely cooking on
the leaderboard.
So, if you want to compete with him, he
learned everything from me, but he took
it to the whole 'nother level, and
that's why I'm so confident about this
is because I have the proof that people
have learned the things that I've taught
them and then taken it to a whole
'nother level, and that's the beautiful
part about this.
We can all step on the gas.
Dixie says, "You're teaching, sir, not
yapping. I appreciate you."
Are you using the open-source Claude?
No, I'm using the regular Claude code.
Get well soon. Thank you. Take care,
Moon. Get some rest. I appreciate you,
papa. Dedication, dedication,
dedication. That's all it is. Let's get
it. Much love, L. Good to have you here,
dude.
I feel like this would change my life,
Chad Bunny says. I feel like if you're a
hand trader right now,
I feel like it would change your life as
well.
I know it. I've seen it over and over
and over again.
Is it pretty easy to follow? Like, it
guides step by step. I don't know
anything about coding.
Yeah, so I go from absolute square one.
You know, I think I'm probably the best
teacher in the world for this stuff
because I'm not one of those
big-head developers that like looks down
on you for not knowing how to code
because they all looked down on me my
entire life. Oh, I don't know how to
code. I build apps, but I don't even
know how to code. Oh, idiot. And then I
get in this industry, and they all make
fun of me for being an AI coder, but now
in 2026, they're all AI coders. So,
am I an innovator? Maybe.
Like,
it's okay, dude. It's okay to not know
how to code.
It's okay to be scared of that. It's
scary. It's intimidating. I was scared
for my whole life.
Like I said, I didn't start this till I
was 30 years old.
So, you're not too late. You're right on
time.
He said, "I'd rather spend 5 years
building systems than ever learn about
some BS ICT." Exactly, dude. There's so
much BS being spewed at you guys on
YouTube. So, like, I'm not here to give
you one way to trade
or another way to trade. Like, I'm not
going to say, "Hey, trade ICT" or
liquidity zones or whatever. No, all I'm
doing is showing you over the shoulder
the approach to trading I'm taking. It
still comes down to great ideas, though.
I give you a framework. I show you where
to get those ideas.
You know?
Uh you get 2 days off, Dixie says. Thank
you. Thank you.
Kelly says, "That is true. I remember in
the first year I sent you a mail saying
that the way you teach with your voice
was calm and soothing." I remember that,
dude.
Kelly's been here for years, and he's
cooking.
Moon Dev has taught me everything I know
about coding. I wish I had started
sooner, so don't wait. That's what
Useless just said. So, that's so far,
dude. Don't wait because the way I
looked at this, dude, was simple.
I could spend a year trying to figure
out how to code and get my
try to get bots live.
Best case scenario, which I'm grateful
happened,
was I'd have trading bots trade for me
24/7. But this was when I got started. I
didn't know how to code. I was scared,
intimidated, just like you guys.
But I knew the worst case scenario is
that I spend a 6 months a year learning
to code. The worst case scenario is I
know how to code for the rest of my
life. But it just got better and better,
right? Because then we got AI, and now
I'm actually cooking as a senior
engineer instead of just a junior, so
I don't know.
If you truly want to be a trader, if you
truly want to continue to trade, I
always say either stop trading or
automate it cuz it's the only way.
Look around, dude. Look around.
If he can do this, I can do this.
Exactly, dude. All I needed was an
example of somebody just a regular
person, and I met that regular person.
He was smoking a joint on the couch. He
had the windows open and the air
conditioning on like an idiot, like
wasting money, okay? He can waste that
money cuz he's a billionaire,
but he's no different than me. Jim
Simons, yeah, I've never met him before.
I know for a fact he's no different than
me now, but only because I met that dude
in person. I kicked it with him. He's a
homie.
You know? So,
I hope, you know,
us conversating today, I mean, these
showing you these examples, giving you
these tutorials,
I hope it does encourage you that you
can do anything in this world that any
other man or woman can do, and you can
do a lot of things that nobody's done
before. The 4-minute mile, dude. The
4-minute mile. Nobody thought they could
break the 4-minute mile. You know that
story?
Let's Let's go ahead and look into it
because
I think the 4-minute mile story is very
interesting for people thinking that
they can't do something nobody's done
before because Yeah, just tell it short
and concise.
4-minute mile in running had never been
broken before. Nobody had ever done a
4-minute mile.
For dec- For decades, experts declared
running a mile in under 4 minutes was
physically impossible.
So, all the crowd right now, it's
physically impossible to build a trading
bot if you didn't go to Harvard. That's
what they say. That's what Wall Street
wants you to think. They don't want you
to compete, dude.
Some even said the human body would
break down attempting it. Then in 1954,
Roger Bannister did it in 3 minutes and
59 seconds. The remarkable part within
46 days, someone else broke it, too.
Within a few years, dozens had done it.
Today, high schoolers run 4-minute
miles.
Nothing changed physically. The barrier
was purely psychological.
Once one person proved it was possible,
everyone's mental ceiling shattered.
The lesson, many impossible limits,
they're just beliefs.
Once someone breaks through, it gives
everyone else permission to follow. The
hardest part is being the first to
believe it can be done.
I believe in you, dude.
I believe in you. I believe I can fly. I
believe I can touch the sky. I think
about it every single night and day. I
spread my wings. I fly away. Come on,
dude. I've been listening to that since
I was nine.
I still It's on my playlist right now.
It's on my playlist right now, dude.
It's on my playlist right now. I believe
I can fly.
I believe I can soar. I see me running
through that open door.
If you can see it, you can do it, dude.
Every single day, my parents still hate
this song.
They still hate this song. My sister
still hates this song.
Night and day.
Damn. I believe I can soar.
And I believe in you, too, dude.
There's nothing that's impossible. And
if it's impossible, just try it.
He says, "I might be wrong, but I think
MoonDawg was held back in the seventh
grade."
He says, "Not sure if I'm right, but I
think MoonDawg was held back in the
seventh grade."
Oh my god. You guys don't have Cricket
in Finland, either. Okay, you live in
Finland?
That's far. Hello, anyone here? I'm
here.
Anonymous Fish is a uh
a hater, and that's okay. I need that. I
grew up uh I grew up underdog, so I like
I like doing this live because I get a
lot of people who are saying I can't do
stuff, whatever, yada yada. And that's
fine.
Also, I dropped four I dropped 40 when
people in the stands called me monkey
boy. So, it's like I'm They're not new
to haters. I need them. I love them.
They light a fire. So, it's us versus
them. Us versus Wall Street. Most of
them are sent from Wall Street.
Haha. They're like, "Okay, get into
MoonDawg stream, yada yada."
Talk some [\h__\h] Haha.
Try to try to egg him on. Try to rage
bait him. Nah, you can rage bait me.
I'll just cook you.
I'll just cook you, dude. I love it. I
love being the underdog. Tell me what I
can't do, and I'll show you how. Thank
you, Jan.
I've met so many great people through
this chat, and it's because you guys are
actually interested in automating your
trading, and so you watch me do it. And
that's That's beautiful. It's beautiful.
Tennis is lit.
Lol, he says.
Okay, so if there's no more questions
here, I'm just going to go ahead. I'm a
manual trader, and I hate it. Chad says,
"Dude, it sucks. It's a waste of time.
It's a waste of life."
Manual trading is literally the biggest
waste.
All right. Well, I'm going to go
recover, dude.
I'm going to recover. If you don't hear
from me, you know that you have a couple
days here to join the Easter special.
Happy Easter to everybody. Happy Good
Friday. Enjoy your friends. Enjoy your
family. Get away from the charts.
Get away from the charts for a bit.
Here's the link. You have everything.
777 to you, Kelly. Thank you for coming
through. You guys have the link to
everything here, and um I've got nothing
else for you except sending you my love
and happy Easter.